Diagon Alley Pile Up

This is Potter Manor—a beautiful red-brick building in the English county of Dorset, just on the outskirts of Puddlemere.

Not for the first time in the last week, the lady of the manor was sat in one of the many comfy arm-chairs in the large manor library, although she was hardly in the right state of mind to appreciate this. If she were sitting any further forward on the edge of said arm-chair, she’d be sitting on the floor.

“Oh, wow, Harry.” Lily Potter leaned further over the low table that separated them.

Harry smiled and held up the glass statue of a hippogriff he’d just wandlessly conjured from thin air. “Do you like it?”

“Yes,” Lily breathed.

Harry put the glass statue on the table and leaned back in his chair. “What else would you like to see?”

Lily picked up the glass hippogriff and turned it this way and that. “Can you do people?”

Harry pursed his lips. People were tricky. Unlike animals, the conjurer needed to get the likeness just right. Human minds were designed for facial recognition. He closed his eyes and concentrated, felt the magic flow through his finger tips as glass formed in the palm of his hand. He opened his eyes, now holding the glass bust of a girl.

“Who’s that?”

“Hermione Granger.”

Lily smiled knowingly. “That’s the pretty girl who almost beat your marks.”

“She is.”

Lily gazed at the statue and her smile faulted. “She’s also a vassal of Lord Slytherin.”

“Yes.”

“All your friends seem to be under Slytherin’s influence.”

“They are my friends.”

“And Slytherin?”

Harry frowned. “You know I’ve said I won’t talk about that.”

A pained look flashed over Lily’s face and she looked away. “Harry, I know you feel indebted to this man, but—” She turned back and stopped.

Harry now held a bouquet of glass flowers—lilies and grasses, each petal and stem perfectly formed, delicate and intricate. It caught the light from the windows that flowed into the dusty room and fractured into a thousand star-like points around the books and shelves. Harry smiled a sheepish smile.

Lily’s serious face slowly melted. “You …” She carefully took the bouquet. “Words fail me, young man.”

Harry grinned.

Lily huffed and stood up. “Well, I suppose I’d better do something with this.” She nodded to the glass flowers. “Do try to spend some time out of the library before dinner. It isn’t healthy to stay indoors all day.”

“I will try.”

Lily gave him a final, lingering, side-ways look before walking off.

Harry listened to her light footsteps leave the library. The far away door shut with a click.

Harry’s smile gradually faded to a more neutral expression. He reached out to the table in front of him, picked up the book he’d been pretending to read before he’d been interrupted, and shut it with a definite thump.

Right, he thought. Now that that’s out of the way …

Catlike, he leapt to his feet, stepped over to the third row of bookshelves, and shimmied up the ladder. He reached the top shelf without stopping and rested a cautious hand on one of the books. Pureblood rumour said that old families tended to hide their family libraries behind special books, poetically appropriate if possible. Voldemort believed it. Harry also wouldn’t be surprised if it was true.

He let the book’s magic brush against his finger tips, feeling for a hint that this was the book out of all the many thousand that surrounded him.

It wasn’t.

Harry reached for the next book and painstakingly checked that one too. Nope. Resigned to the slog, he continued moving along the row of books at speeds that would bore a flailtail snail. He’d been at this for a whole week now and he’d still only finished the first two bookshelves. He wasn’t likely to find anything before he left for Hogwarts, but the promise of instant advantage over his enemies was mighty tempting.

And advantage was certainly what he needed. At the end of last year he’d lost to Voldemort while trying to acquire the philosopher’s stone. It was only luck and a still unexplained mystery that had stopped the episode turning into a disaster. The monster’s words constantly echoed in his head.

“Obviously, as soon as I suspected there was someone out there who had all my knowledge, I started developing new methods. What kind of fool would try to use only tricks the enemy already knows?”

Of course, that went both ways. With the exception of some of his occlumency and a handful of tricks Voldemort had learned in his past future, all Harry’s methods were Voldemort’s too. Harry needed new magic, and he only had so much time to get it in.

The sound of the door clicking open sounded through the still library like a curse. Harry jumped off the ladder, landed as light as a feather—because, for a fraction of a second, he was—and grabbed a random book from the shelf. Only too late did he realise it was a ‘boy who lived’ adventure book.

“You!” Harry’s fellow time-travelling twin, John Potter, stood at the end of the row.

“Me.”

“What are you doing?”

“Reading. Say, do we actually get royalties for these?”

John took one look at the book in his hand and sniffed. “No. The lawyer said that ‘boy who lived’ wasn’t an official legal title or name.”

“Shame. I could do with some gold.”

John ground his teeth.

“Is there anything else you wanted?” Harry asked.

“Yes! I want you to stop sucking up to Mum!”

“Pardon?”

“All the time now, it’s Harry this, and Harry that, it’s making me sick!”

“Awww, is the little lion cub jealous?”

“You’re doing what ever it is you did to my Ginny!” John’s face was getting as red as his robes. “Stop it, or I’ll make you regret it!”

“Still don’t know who this ‘Ginny’ you’re referring to is.”

John all but screamed. “She was at Alex’s birthday party!”

“Oh, yeeeeah.” Harry snapped his fingers. “That Ginny. Cute girl. Maybe I’ll ask her out.”

John struggled to contain himself. “It doesn’t matter,” he spat. “As soon as she’s sorted into Gryffindor, I’ll see to it that you never get near her again.”

Whine, whine, whinge, whinge. This had been John’s general attitude ever since Harry had returned to Potter Manor for the first time in over ten years. Harry didn’t feel even a tiny bit guilty for stealing Ginny and Hermione away from him—not when John had been instrumental in sending him to Azkaban in both of the previous timelines for ten years of dementor filled hell, even when he’d known he was innocent.

His twin brother’s mood hadn’t improved by the time dinner rolled around and wasn’t likely to get better.

“And why does he get to go out every—other—day?” John asked, pointing to Harry across the table, who saluted with a bread roll. “It’s not fair.”

“He’s not going out,” said Lord James Potter in a firm voice from where he sat carving beef onto Lily’s plate. “He’s only going to Sirius’s place to visit Alexandra. You can go too, if you want. Pass the gravy please, Harry.”

“Yes, Father.”

“Yes, Father,” John parroted, doing an recognisable impression of Draco Malfoy.

Lord Potter frowned. “Please don’t do that, John.”

John made a disgruntled face and bent down over his plate.

“Not so keen on Alexandra anymore?” Harry asked.

“She won’t shut up about Lord Slytherin.”

“Well, she is at that age. Having crushes is normal.”

“And you’d know about that, would you?”

“All my friends are girls, so yes, I would.”

James Potter let his otherwise serious face slip. “Do I need to start picking out intention gifts for you?”

“Well, there is a very pretty muggle born girl in Slytherin whose thirteenth birthday is coming up.”

John slammed his hands on the table, causing a silver sauce boat to spill over the table.

“John!” Lily barked.

“You can’t have Hermione!”

“Why?” Harry asked with a raised eyebrow.

“I’ve already started courting her. I was first.”

“Hermione didn’t even accept your intention gift. And you then threatened to burn it in front of her if she didn’t.”

“John!” Lily shrieked. “Is that true?”

John mumbled something along the lines of, “sorta.”

“That book is priceless!”

“I wasn’t going to actually do it! I was just being playful. Like Dad said I should.”

Lord Potter put a hand over his eyes.

“That’s no excuse,” Lily said. “If you can’t be respectful to both the girls and the gifts then you’ll get no more from us to court with until you’ve hit your own thirteenth birthday.”

“What?!”

“You’ve clearly shown that you’re not yet mature enough. There’s a reason this is usually left until children are older. I’m sure Miss Bones will understand.”

“What about Harry?”

James and Lily Potter shared a meaningful look. James cleared his throat. “If Harry continues to show the level of maturity and responsibility he has so far, then yes.”

“That’s not fair!”

“John!” James Potter had clearly had enough. “I am your father, your head of house, and your lord. I will decide what is and is not fair. My word is your law. Your wand is my gift. Go to your room and don’t leave until you see fit to comport yourself in a manner befitting the heir of an ancient and noble house.”

John stared at his father in wide-eyed shock. He then pushed his chair back and sullenly stamped off, closing the dining room door behind him with a loud bang.

Dinner was a lot quieter after that. Harry didn’t see John again that evening. He didn’t see him at breakfast the next morning either. Or afterwards, when he stood at one of Potter Manor’s several floo places. He tossed a pinch of floo powder into the roaring flames.

“Twelve Grimmauld Place.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Deep within number twelve Grimmauld Place, inside the fideliused Black Library, there was a blackboard. It hung from one of the many bookcases and hid several shelves of boy who lived adventure books, which the young lady of the house, Alexandra Black, had quarantined in case stupidity was contagious.

On this blackboard someone had drawn a large table in chalk, each row and column perfectly straight, and exactly the same width apart.

Missions

Bring Draco to the Gray—Alexandra/(Luna?)

Muggleborn project/Guardianship—Hermione/Lord Slytherin

Acquire/Destroy diary—?

Get Ginny properly equipped—?

Seal off chamber until basilisk can be killed—Lord Slytherin

Animagus project—Harry

Beside each of these boxes, at the very top of the table, the same someone had written S.W.O.T in neat curly writing.

“No, Alex, you’re not getting it,” Hermione Granger huffed, standing at the blackboard with a whippy looking cane and a piece of green chalk. “Our earpiece communication mirrors are a strength, not an opportunity.”

Alex tried to sit up and shrug from where she lay with Luna, half-engulfed in a massive beanbag, but all she managed to do was shift her weight around. “What about—omff!” She recoiled from an arm smacking into the side of her head. “Luna!”

“Sorry.”

“—What about Luna’s plum trees? You know, the one’s that make people more gullible?”

“Another strength.”

“And they don’t actually make people more gullible,” Luna added. “They make people more willing to believe the extraordinary.”

“What’s the difference?” Daphne Greengrass asked. The last of the four girls present was sitting a few feet away in a high-back chair, posture straight, hands resting in her lap, legs crossed at her ankles, handbag resting by her feet, not a single long blond hair out of place.

“Magnitude. They only help people believe truly incredible things.”

“What about all the cool Black family magic I’ve been learning?” Alex asked, turning back to Hermione.

“Another strength.”

“So what would be an opportunity?”

“Us knowing that Lucius Malfoy might have the diary on him when he goes to Flourish and Blotts is a good example.”

“Okay, umm …” Alex frowned. “How exactly do we know this? And why’s this diary so important, anyway?” She felt a soft hand grip her arm and give a reassuring squeeze.

“Slytherin family secrets, Alex,” Luna said. “Hopefully you’ll learn soon.”

Alex’s face firmed in determination. “Right—Slytherin secrets—right. Prove myself—got it.”

A quiet dong sounded throughout the library as a clock struck nine. A change spread throughout the group—a subtle shifting of expressions. In Daphne it was a softening—in Hermione it was a faint reddening of the cheeks—and with Luna it was a slight unfocusing of the eyes. Alexandra had come to recognise these changes over the last week and knew they meant only one thing. Slytherin’s most trusted and most powerful student—Harry Potter.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Harry arrived in twelve Grimmauld place in a swoosh of soot. The moment he stepped through the floo, a perfectly manicured hand presented him with his fifteen inch yew and thestral hair wand, which he neatly took and waved in a long arc, cleaning all the dust from his robes. “Thanks, Daphne.”

“How did the chamber of secrets go?” Daphne whispered as they started making their way through the house.

“Not so good.” Harry hit a painting up ahead with a stunning spell. “The chamber won’t carry a charm itself and I’ve hit the limit to the number of secrets a caster’s soul can anchor.”

“How many?”

“Seven. I was surprised I could even cast the spell that many times. Old Tom could only ever do one.”

“Are you going to deactivate some of your other charms?”

“Maybe one or two—still need most of them.”

“So what are we going to—Eep!”

Harry had taken her firmly by the shoulders and steered her into one of the many empty rooms, where upon he started casting privacy charms. “I warded the rest of the entrances with some heavy duty enchantments tied to Hogwart’s own. It’ll take some effort to slip through them and I’m pretty sure the diary hasn’t the skills.”

“You haven’t had any more thoughts on how the other horcruxes did the swap thing last year, did you?”

Harry sucked in through his teeth. “A few, but …” He grimaced. “I’m leaving it for the moment. There’s a … thing. I don’t want to start second guessing myself.”

Daphne nodded slowly, but with a slight frown.

“Anyway, I also ran into Snape on the way out,” Harry continued. “He suggested he should be a spy for me against Dumbledore.”

Daphne sucked in her breath. “You’re not going to trust him, are you?”

“Merlin, no. I trust Snape as much as I trust Lily—who, by the way, also appears to be a Dumbledore spy.” Harry frowned in thought for a moment before brightening. “What about you?”

Daphne reached into her handbag, pulled out a small stack of envelopes, and handed them over. “Mostly the usual—although Arthur Weasley has requested a meeting with Lord Slytherin about your ‘dealings’ with the Weasley family.”

“Hmmm …” Harry opened the letter in question and scanned it. “This could be about either my partnership with the twins or my teaching Ginny—more likely the twins—not entirely a surprise. I’ll have to arrange something either way … and speaking of the twin’s partnership, I spoke to the Grangers. We’re thinking of developing a commercial submarine prototype, so we’re going to need to send out proposals to people who have the gold for that sort of thing.”

Daphne clicked her tongue, reached into her handbag again, withdrew a small black book and a tiny quill, licked her finger tip, flicked through the book, and made a small note. “Even with the amount of gold you pulled in over the summer, we only have liquid funds for another eighteen months,” she warned. “Large scale projects would drain us dangerously low.”

“I know. We’ll just have to keep outrunning the red line.” He smiled. “You’ve been doing your part very well.”

Daphne blushed. “Thank you.” She hesitated. “Um, Harry?”

“Yes, Daph?”

“I don’t want to sound selfish, considering everything that needs to get done, but I was wondering if we could go exploring somewhere sometime? We haven’t done that in ages. I’ve been feeling quite shut in recently.”

Harry blinked. He tried to think back to the last time he’d taken Daphne anywhere. It had been quite a while. Damn. He looked into her ice blue eyes, which gazed back at him with perhaps just a hint of nervousness. He smiled. “Of course, Daph.” Damn, damn, damn, he was supposed to be better than this.

Daphne’s face lit up. “I like it when we go places.”

Harry’s mind raced through countless time slots, appointments, and commitments … but there were just so many of them, he didn’t—“Ah!” An idea struck him. “What about your birthday—October 24? It’s even on a Saturday—we could take the whole weekend.”

Daphne seemed to consider this. Then she nodded, smiling softly. “I’m happy with that. For my birthday, you will take me somewhere amazing.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Alexandra Black watched Harry Potter receive his traditional enthusiastic greeting from Hermione and Luna before he walked over to the black board and picked up the chalk. She couldn’t help noticing that Hermione had happily relinquished her spot at the board even though only a few minutes ago it would have been difficult to manage such as feat with a team of wild dogs.

“Animagus project is going well,” Harry announced, making a note next to the appropriate box. “We’ll start on mandrake leaf in October, so long as we can get hold of it. Incidentally, thank you for the loan of the book, Alex—it was most useful.”

Alex nodded.

“You’ll all need to learn the sticking charm before then,” he continued. “Otherwise you’ll find it difficult to not end up swallowing your leaf. Yes, Hermione?”

Hermione had her hand up. “I looked up how to cast a small enough notice-me-not and I’m certain I’ll be able to do it by then.”

“Excellent, well done.”—Hermione beamed—“That’ll be a lot of help for when I’m not around. Yes, Daphne?”

“Did you decide whether we were going to register or not?”

“Not yet. It depends on what forms we get. Any other questions?” No one said anything.

“Right,” he continued. “Last item before I let you get back to planning Ginny’s shopping trip—”

Alex’s eye twitched at ‘before I let you’.

“—Lord Slytherin has decided we’ll start training in group combat—”

Alex perked up.

“—so you can take down far more dangerous opponents as a team. We’ll start as soon as we get to the castle.”

Wow, Alex thought. That’s going to be awesome. “Who’s training us?” she asked. “Is it Slytherin?”

“Nope, it’s going to be me.”

Alex blinked. “What? You’re the ‘really dangerous opponent?’ ” her voice radiated doubt. Sure, she’d seen his performance at the duelling tournament towards the end of last year, and it had blown her away at the time, but …

“Why not?” Potter was smiling now.

“Why not?” she repeated back, her voice gradually rising as her incredulity set in. “Have you seen how much arse Ginny and Luna kick! I bet they’ll also be able to clear every duelling opponent by the end of the year, just like you and John did! And I’ve got a lot better too! I haven’t got spell swatting down yet, but I’m close! And Hermione and Daphne beat a troll before, and that was almost a whole year ago! Do you really, really, think you’ll be a challenge for all of us—all at once!?”

Potter continued to smile.

There was silence in the room. Daphne was busy inspecting her nails.

Alex turned to Luna. “Back me up here, Luna. This is dumb!”

Hermione exploded. “Why you little—!”

“—Hermione,” Harry said in a warning tone of voice.

Hermione instantly cut herself off.

“It’s a perfectly reasonable question.”

Alex stared wide-eyed at Hermione, who despite her silence still looked like she wanted to jump at her.

“Yes, Alexandra,” Harry finally answered. “You will find me a more than adequate teacher.”

Alex looked back to a serene looking Luna who’d put her hand on Alex’s arm and was giving it another reassuring squeeze.

“I understand your doubts though, so let’s say if you do manage to pass my first test, I will communicate to Lord Slytherin that it is my belief that you are ready to be fully taken into his confidence.”

Alex’s eyes widened again. She grinned. “Fine.”

They continued to plan Ginny’s shopping trip after that. Alex was a little annoyed that she wasn’t going to be able to go, but, as Luna pointed out, if she was supposed to be infiltrating the Dark this year, she couldn’t very well be seen to be hanging out with the Gray, could she?

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A few days later, a girl stood among the many trees, both magic and mundane, that made up the Burrow’s orchard. Her eyes were closed, her head held up, her long red hair flowing down to the small of her back, body totally still … except for her fingers—they twitched at her side with barely contained magical intent.

Off to the right, a breeze detached a leaf from a magical elm. The girl’s eyes shot open. The leaf got only another foot down to the ground before an invisible slash of magic sliced it clean in two.

The girl lowered her hand and breathed out.

The two pieces of leaf settled on the ground and another gust of wind picked them up and blew them away.

“Ginny? Ginny! Where are you?” The voice of Molly Weasley called across the Burrow grounds.

Suddenly, where before there had been a girl, now there was just a faint outline in the air. The girl had been quiet before, but it would have been theoretically possible to hear the breath from her lungs and the beating of her heart—now, not even that was possible.

The vague shape in the air made its way out of the orchard far faster than one would expect from something only four foot eight, and vaulted over the fence surrounding the chicken coops. The girl shimmered back into view, cancelled the silencing charm on herself, and picked up one of the startled hens. “I’m here, Mum!”

“Oh.” Molly Weasley appeared around the corner that lead to the house. She put her hands on her hips. “Well, make sure you finish up soon. We want to make sure we get into the Alley nice and early so we can finish our shopping before Lockhart’s book signing.”

“Yes, Mum.”

When Molly Weasley had left, Ginny gave the hen a fond stroke before hugging it and putting it back down, where upon it immediately started pecking at the ground. She then started gathering eggs and putting out new feed while thinking about the day ahead.

Gilderoy Lockhart’s book signing. That was when she’d picked up the diary in the last timeline according to Harry. She’d begged to be allowed to deal with it of course, but Harry had put his foot down. It wasn’t that he doubted her, he’d said, but dealing with Malfoy required an experienced hand, not merely a skilled one.

She’d sulked about that for days, but eventually got over it, helped in no small part by the knowledge that she would be getting all new things for Hogwarts. She’d never had all new things and wasn’t sure exactly how this was going to happen. Harry had just told her to ‘be ready for it,’ whatever that meant.

After eggs, breakfast, and a general mad Weasley dash to get ready, Arthur Weasley pulled Ginny aside where none of the others could overhear them. “Looking forward to shopping?” he asked.

“Yes, Dad,” she said, dutifully.

Her father looked unusually uncomfortable. “Listen, Ginny, I know you haven’t had the best year—what with being grounded, but I don’t want you to go off to Hogwarts with us still like this. This has gone on for far too long already.”

Ginny didn’t let her face reveal anything.

“I’ve spoken to your mother about this, and she doesn’t like it, but we have decided to lift your grounding.”

Wait, what? Ginny hardly dared to believe it. “You mean …”

“Yes, you can go to your friends houses during the holidays and to Hogsmeade when you’re old enough.”

Ginny’s face broke into a wide smile. She leaped forward and hugged her father for what felt like the first time in forever. She sniffed and felt her eyes moisten. “Thanks, Dad. You’ve no idea how hard it’s been—”

“Shh, shh, it’s fine.”

They stayed like that for a while, just enjoying the moment. Eventually he pulled back, reached into his robes and withdrew a small bag. His voice lowered another notch. “Not a word to Molly.”

Confused, Ginny took the bag, opened it, and gasped. A dozen gold galleons gleamed up at her. “I—” She struggled for words. “You—I—How?”

“Shh, Ginny, it’s fine. Get yourself some nice things, but make sure you leave enough for a wand.”

“Won’t Mum know?” she whispered back.

“Don’t worry about it. Just leave that to me. Now c’mon—your brothers will all be ready soon.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Daphne, Hermione, and Luna were all sat in cheap chairs on a balcony overlooking Diagon Alley. Behind them, through silenced, tall glass doors, the massive printing press of Quibbler Headquarters whirred and clanked away, manned by a half dozen wizards who were doing an excellent job of pretending not to be interested in what they were up to. Hermione was looking down the end of a telescope.

“Anything?” Daphne asked. She had an open picnic basket by her feet. Luna was already halfway through a paper plate of jam sandwiches (without crusts).

“No. But we can’t assume things will turn out like last time. Time is like a butterfly flapping its wings to create a storm.”

“Pardon?”

“I read the book that the movie we watched was based on. It had a lot more in it about that stuff. You change one small thing and the effect ripples outwards, like a stone thrown into a pond.”

“What happens if you throw a butterfly into a pond?” Luna asked.

Hermione took her eye away from the telescope to glare at her.

“My dad always says time’s more like cheese,” she added.

“No, no.” Hermione shook her head. “Look, there’s a lot of research that’s been done about it—magical too—it’s called chaos theory.”

Luna bit into another jam sandwich, swallowed, and smiled. “Sounds like fun. Could I borrow the book?”

“Err …” Hermione put her eye back to the telescope. “Sure, although it’s not really a proper book. It’s fiction. Oh!” She made a frantic waving motion with one hand. “There’s Ginny and the rest of the Weasleys.”

“Wonderful.” Luna put her plate down and stood up.

“Are you sure you want to be the one to do this?” Hermione asked.

“I know Ginny best. We’re sisters.” Luna paused. “Well, not yet obviously.” She paused again. “I mean, obviously you’ll be one day too, but I still know her best.” And with that, she turned and walked through the big glass doors.

Hermione watched her go and felt a heat grow on her cheeks. “Um, Daphne?” Her breath became shallower. “What, exactly, did Luna mean by that?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“In here, Ginny dear.” Molly Weasley steered her youngest into a second hand clothes shop. “Now, just stay there while I see what we can do.” She started pulling robes off a rack. Most of them, to Ginny’s eyes, looked far too large for her. The ones that didn’t all had strange marks and stains on them.

“Here you go,” her Mum thrust a robe into her arms, which had a huge tear down the side. “Don’t worry about that. I’ll be able to sew it up in a trice. Now, off you go to try it on while I see about skirts for your uniform.”

Ginny nodded in resignation, trudged to the back of the shop, pulled open the curtain to the dressing room, felt concealment magic, and instantly sent a stunner towards the hidden figure. The hidden figure swatted back the spell and several volleys later, the red spell smacked harmlessly into the ceiling.

Luna shimmered into view.

“Lu—”

Luna grabbed Ginny, pulled her in, and whipped the curtain shut behind her. “Shhhh.”

Ginny nodded quickly.

Luna whipped out two vials and handed one to Ginny. “Polyjuice.” She uncorked her own vial and plucked a hair from Ginny’s head.

“Ow,” Ginny hissed.

“Here,” she handed Ginny a hair of her own. “You have one hour. I have more. Meet at Flourish and Blotts for the swap back.”

“Got it,” Ginny whispered, shimmying out of her old and faded summer dress. “Don’t you dare get caught!”

Luna had already stepped out of her summer robes and downed her vial of polyjuice.

Ginny picked up the robes from the floor and pulled them down over her body. The silk felt smoother than anything she’d worn before. She drank her own vial and felt the strange sensation of changing into someone else. Moments later, it was Luna’s reflection that stared back at her from the changing room mirror.

Luna, now wearing Ginny’s body along with the old school robes, giggled.

“I don’t giggle like that!” Ginny whispered, fiercely.

Luna winked in a very Ginny-esque way. “No, only when you’re with Harry.” And before Ginny could say anything in retaliation, Luna had skipped out of the changing room.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Harry stood by the floo in Potter Manor.

“There you go, Harry,” said Lily Potter, flicking an imaginary speck of dust from his robes. “You’re looking very smart.”

“Thank you.”

John made a sick face as soon as Lily’s back was turned.

Harry rolled his eyes.

“Alright!” James shouted, stepping up behind them and taking a pinch of floo powder. “Diagon Alley awaits!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Up on the balcony, Hermione’s face was redder than an oversized star. “You don’t really think that—I mean, Harry is—I mean—that he—with me—”

“Hermione,” Daphne said, sitting back in her chair. “If Harry doesn’t get you a declaration of intention gift on your birthday, I will eat my hat—and you know how big a witch’s hat is.”

“It’s just …” Hermione’s brain had finally managed to break through the initial barrier and had started on all the implications. “Well, for starters, I’m a muggleborn!”

“It’s not nearly the first time a muggleborn has been courted by a lord. Look at Ladies Potter and Davis.”

“I … I …” Hermione buried herself back into the telescope to hide her flustered state, no matter how much of a lost cause it might have been. “Has Harry actually told you he’s going to start courting me?”

“Not in so many words.”

“Then you don’t know! It might be nothing! It might be—” Hermione stopped in mid-rant. She sucked in her breath. “The Malfoys have just arrived in the alley from the Leaky Cauldron.”

“Really?”

“Yes. There’s Lord and Lady Malfoy. There’s Draco. …” Hermione frowned. “… And there’s a girl with them, maybe Luna and Ginny’s age—looks kind of like a Malfoy.” She paused. “But I don’t recognise her at all …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Now, I have to get this absolutely perfect, Arthur Weasley thought, as he edged towards his wife and daughter. One misstep, and it won’t go nearly as well as I’d like. He put on a big smile. “Molly.”

“Oh, Arthur, thank goodness, quickly, which do you think would be better for little Ginny?” She held up two equally battered looking cauldrons.

“I think what little Ginny needs is some ice-cream. It’s far too hot out here.”

Little Ginny grinned up at him. “Ice-cream!”

“What?” Molly looked momentarily nonplussed. “Arthur! You’re going to spoil her!”

“Oh, don’t fuss so, Molly.” He crouched and tried to pick up a squealing little Ginny. “Uff! You’re getting heavy!”

Little Ginny pouted. “Did you just call me fat?”

Arthur laughed before putting her back down.

Molly huffed. “Fine, but don’t be too late. We don’t want to miss the queue for Lockhart.”

Father and daughter walked away towards the ice-cream parlour, before taking a detour and ducking into a side-alley. Arthur winked down at his daughter. “Excellent acting, Ginny.”

“Thanks!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Draco Malfoy was feeling pretty smug. This was quite a normal state of affairs for him, but just now he was feeling it more so than usual. He was sitting outside one of the better Diagon Alley cafes, in front of his friends, who were staring at him like he’d grown a second head, and beside his newly found little sister, Virgo.

“Virgo?” said Theodore Nott, as though he hadn’t quite heard it the first time.

“She’s our answer to Potter,” Draco replied, while Virgo ate a chocolate eclair with tiny bites in just the way their mother had spent the last two weeks drilling into her.

“Is she really?” asked Pansy. “She doesn’t look much.”

Draco winced.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Now what’s going on?” Daphne asked.

“Not sure,” Hermione replied, one eye firmly fixed to the telescope. “But Theo and Pansy look like they’re wetting themselves.”

“That’s odd.”

Hermione sucked in her breath. “Oh, this is going to be interesting.”

“What?”

“Lord Potter and the fraud who lived, are on a collision course with Draco and co.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo Malfoy, previously known as Tom Riddle, let his aura fade slightly, not caring that several adult wizards and witches had been caught in it as well.

You’re bullying them,thought the voice of Julia in his head, the Swedish muggleborn whose body he’d stolen.

I am showing them the power that I wield, Virgo thought back. It is necessary.

They can’t be as bad as you make out.

I assure you, girl, that if I do not take a firm stance now, I will pay for it later. I do not have the full power of my adult form, even as I was before I became the diary.

Nott and Parkinson had settled down now. They’d carefully taken seats by him and Draco, and started asking him questions in a cautious and respectful tone.

If you’re so desperate for respect, why don’t you just tell them who you really are?

Because I am not a fool. Information leaks. I cannot risk others knowing of my true nature. I do not particularly wish for even my other self to know of me. Who knows how he might react.

It must be terrible to not trust even yourself.

Virgo then caught sight of two wizards walking down the street whose faces he’d committed to memory. Lord Potter and one of his twin sons—Possibly Harry Potter, who in turn, might be another horcrux. He nudged Draco and leaned into him. “Introduce me to them.”

Draco nodded slowly, called out, and did so.

“Virgo?” The boy, who turned out to be John Potter, looked dumbstruck.

Lord Potter clicked his tongue. “No one told me you had a sister, Mister Malfoy.”

“Virgo was cast out of the family for being a squib,” Draco drawled. “Much like your own son, Harry. My father sent her to Sweden. When he saw how your Harry turned out to be so gifted he sent for her, and it turned out that, like your Harry, she wasn’t nearly as much of a squib as we all thought. And much to my mother and father’s delight, she is now more than ready to take up her responsibility to the family.”

John wore an expression that suggested he was trying on this explanation for size, almost as though it were a set of clothes.

“Well, pleased to have met you, Miss Malfoy,” Lord Potter said in clipped tones. “C’mon John—we need to get a move on if we’re to finish before lunch.”

John nodded slowly before departing, seeming to accept whatever conclusions he’d reached.

Virgo frowned. John Potter seemed like a highly intelligent boy. He’d generally only seen that look on people quite a few years older.

Yeah, and he’s kinda cute, too.

Oh, hell.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Mmmm … your second wand is proving far more tricky than your first, Miss Lovegood. Perhaps, we should try … these ones.”

Ginny watched as Mister Ollivander climbed down from the ladder propped against one of the many stacks of wand boxes, holding yet another box. He placed it in front of her and lifted off the lid. Two wands were displayed on deep blue velvet—same length—same floral carvings on the handles—only a slight difference in shade. You’d have to be really paying attention to tell them apart.

“The one on the right is cypress, thirteen and a half inches, dragon heartstring from a common welsh green. Go on, give it a swish.”

Ginny bit her lip. Would something so girly really fit her? She picked up the wand and waved it about a bit. Nothing. Despite herself, she felt a tiny pang of disappointment.

Ollivander watched her like a hawk. “It seems not, Miss Lovegood. Why don’t you try the next one?”

Resigned, Ginny reached for the wand on the left, but as her hand neared, she felt a heat start to creep down her finger tips. Her breath caught. She closed her fingers over the handle and felt the sheer power flow through her body, far quicker and easier than anything she’d ever felt in all her countless hours of training. It felt incredible! It felt like she’d had a huge weight lifted off of her. She felt unstoppable! She thrust the wand out in front of her and it blasted out a stream of green sparks so dense that the whole shop was momentarily filled with an emerald mist.

Amazing.

Ollivander pursed his lips. “Hmmmm, curious.”

“What’s curious?”

“I remember every wand I’ve ever made, Miss Lovegood.”

There was a tingle of a bell.

“Strange that this wand should have chosen you, when once upon a time, I sold a wand with the exact same specifications—thirteen and a half inches, yew, phoenix feather—

A door closed with a thump.

“—to the man who would one day claim heirship over the house that your betrothed now leads.”

Ginny’s mind froze. Tom. Voldemort. That … That couldn’t—

“Luna!” said a cheerful voice, horrible in its familiarity.

If Ginny’s mind had frozen before, now her heart stopped too. She turned slowly to find Luna beaming at her, still in Ginny’s body, while her dad, Arthur Weasley, looked between Ginny and the floral wand in her hand with an expression of mild horror.

Before Ginny could think of anything to say, Luna darted forward. “Oooo! Flowers!” She reached for the other, stylistically-identical wand in the box.

“Miss Weasley,” started Mister Ollivander in a tired voice. “It is the wand that chooses the—”

Luna plucked the wand out of the box and a shower of light blue sparks filled the room.

“… Wizard.”

There was silence for a moment. Then Ginny threw seven galleons on the counter and fled.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Flourish and Blotts bustled. The aisles of the dozens of book shelves thronged with wizards and witches—many of them, especially the witches, could only charitably be called shoppers.

In the middle of the shop, where customers could normally sit down and put their feet up on a collection of assorted chairs and chintzes, there was instead a large square curtain, covered in silencing charms.

A queue was already forming.

Behind this curtain, a man with the most perfect smile this side of the Atlantic was busy charming his hair to give it just the right amount of bounce. He inspected himself in a fold up mirror and frowned at the result. Then he flashed a brilliant smile and gave his reflection a saucy wink. He frowned again, then repeated the smile and wink five more times before snapping the mirror shut and dropping it into the pocket of his plum silk robes.

The man now trotted to where the queue on the other side of the curtain would approach the table, crouched down, and inspected the books, posters, and yeti skull from every possible angle. One of the book piles had titles like, ‘Gadding with Ghouls’. The other had titles like, ‘The Boy Who Lived and the Three Headed Crup’. He made a minor adjustment.

“Getting it just right, Gilderoy?”

An old man had entered through a door in the curtain.

Gilderoy Lockhart stood up and flashed the man the same smile he’d just been practising, sans wink. “It’s all about the show, Lord Blott.” His voice echoed around the booth rather too loudly for such an enclosed space. “Even the smallest details can make a huge difference to sales. How you are seen—how you present yourself—is everything.”

Lord Blott, one of the lords of the Light, smiled an indulgent smile and inspected several of the many posters pinned up to the massive backboard behind the table—posters such as …

SIGN UP FOR THE LOCKHART OWL LIST! LEARN THE 55 SECRET WAYS TO STAY SAFE THE AURORS DON’T WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT, ABSOLUTELY FREE!

And …

THE BOY WHO LIVED AND THE MUMMY’S WRATH! AN ALL NEW ADVENTURE WITH THE NATION’S FAVOURITE BOY HERO!

And, finally …

MAGICAL ME—HOW TO BECOME AN UNSTOPPABLE MAGICAL BADASS AND LOOK GREAT DOING IT

“Which is going to sell more?” Blott asked.

“Mmm? Oh, the boy who lived series sells better, but the margins aren’t as high.” Lockhart straightened a pile of flyers. “They’re great transition books, though. Parents buy them like chocolate frogs!” He beamed.

Lord Blott nodded. “Well, I hope you’re ready for this. There’s practically a horde out there—and Malfoy should be here soon, too.”

Gilderoy laughed. “Not to worry! After all..” He flashed his smile again. “I am Gilderoy Lockhart, order of Mer—”

“Yes, yes, yes.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Barefoot, Ginny ducked into a side alley and neatly stepped around a much larger wizard going the other way. The wizard hadn’t paid any attention to her. She was invisible. Her polyjuice had run out, and so she’d carefully put away her satisfyingly girly, yet horrifyingly ominous new wand, disillusioned herself, and wandered over to Twilfitt and Tattings, after checking to make sure that neither her father nor mother were anywhere nearby.

Ginny had spent the last hour guiltily buying everything Harry said she’d need to make waves in Slytherin House—the best of everything—even a magic trunk—far more money than the twelve galleons her father had given her from Merlin only knew where.

The only thing she hadn’t yet bought were clothes, and that was only because she’d needed to wait until she had her own body back. She hopped out of the other side of the alley and pushed her way into the clothes shop, so apparently exclusive that it advertised its exclusivity by displaying not only a lack of prices, but a lack of clothes too.

The woman behind the counter glanced up only long enough to take in the cut of the robes Luna had forced her into. “Can I help you?”

“I’m here to buy clothes for Hogwarts.”

“The Hogwarts bespoke package is thirty galleons and includes five sets of robes, two cloaks, ten sets of underwear, socks, all in your style of choice, and a hat. We’ll also have someone sent for a purse and a handbag if you know what you want, although the price for that varies.” The woman finally looked up over the counter and properly inspected her. “You need shoes too?”

Ginny was holding Luna’s low heeled shoes, which were now one size too small for her. “Yes?”

“Fine. Lose the robe, up on the stool, and behind the curtain. Up, up ,up.”

Twenty minutes later, Ginny was awash in a sea of fine silks, cotton, wool, and cashmere. A small army of charmed tape-measures, paper, and chalk made measurements while the woman babbled out an unending stream of fashion talk, constantly asking questions on her preference for this and or that, and only getting a firm answer one time in five.

The door bell ting-aling-alinged, and Ginny poked her head through the curtain as another girl stepped in. A man stepped in behind her. Ginny just managed to stop herself from gasping.

The woman straightened up from where she’d been waving her wand over a roll of material.

“Ah, Clarissa,” said the man in a silky voice. “This is my daughter, Virgo. Get her full sets of everything, would you?”

“As it pleases you, Lord Malfoy.”

Ginny felt a shiver go up her spine as the girl, Virgo, walked behind the curtain, disrobed, and stepped up onto the stool next to her as though she were stepping up to accept an order of Merlin. Ginny was sure that Lord Malfoy did not have a daughter.

The girl turned and looked her up and down. “Hogwarts too?”

“Yes.”

“I don’t recognise you.” It was a statement, but also a question, bordering on an accusation.

Ginny cleared her throat. “I am Ginevra Molly Weasley, of the Ancient House of Weasley.”

Virgo’s lip curled upwards. “I wasn’t aware that the Weasleys could afford to shop here.”

“I have a patron.”

“Really?” Now Virgo looked fascinated. “Pray tell.”

Ginny said nothing. There wasn’t anything to say—certainly not to a stranger of dubious origin.

Virgo didn’t seem perturbed though. She merely smiled.

And then, Ginny felt something shove itself into her mind with the force of a battering ram. Her eyes narrowed and the battering ram smashed into a three-foot thick concrete bunker with all the effectiveness of a pencil stabbing a brick wall. There was an intake of breath, a crash, and the next moment, Virgo was on the floor and the stool was half way across the room.

Ginny flashed a smirk.

“Oh, dear!” The woman started fussing around Virgo. “Are you alright, girl?”

Virgo recovered easily, picking her self up and rubbing a small scrape on her elbow. “My apologies. I appear to have slipped.” And moments later, she was back on the stool as if nothing had happened.

Getting fitted was more than a little awkward after that. The girl kept throwing her furtive and suspicious glances, and Ginny couldn’t help feeling that despite not recognising Virgo, and despite being sure the Malfoys didn’t have a daughter, that somewhere, somehow, she still knew her.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Up on the balcony at Quibbler headquarters, the picnic basket that had once contained lemonade, jam sandwiches (without crusts), and incy-wincy sausage rolls, was now empty.

Daphne gazed down the telescope. “The queue at Flourish and Blotts is snaking out the door.”

Hermione didn’t look up from Year With A Yeti. “Do you think Lockhart actually did all this stuff?”

Daphne snorted. “Harry doesn’t think so. He says it’s just good theory wrapped around fantastical story telling.”

“But that’s dreadful! Writing about stuff you don’t know from personal experience—just using someone else’s knowledge—it’s like stealing! It’s—”

“You know, Harry is talking about writing a book.”

Hermione shut her mouth. Then she opened it again. Then she closed it again. Eventually she said, “That’s different.”

Daphne smirked. “Oh?”

“Of course! Harry isn’t just copying out of a book!” She lowered her voice. “He wrenched knowledge straight out the old Tom’s head.” She hesitated, then in a normal voice said, “Umm, why is Harry writing a book?”

Daphne stepped away from the telescope. “We’re on a timer, Hermione. We have been ever since Old Tom learned Lord Slytherin’s true identity. We can’t let our lord’s secret get out in an uncontrolled manner. It would be a disaster. We need to be in control when it happens. So we’re going to start slowly bringing people on board over the next eighteen months.”

“My parents.”

“They’ll be among the first, yes.”

“What’s this got to do with Harry writing a book?”

“Right now, people don’t know much about Lord Slytherin. We might know that Harry is amazing, but the public just think they know it. They’ve built up this fantasy around Lord Slytherin and when it’s revealed he’s only a boy—well—things might not go so well. We’ll need to quickly re-establish Harry’s credibility among a lot of people and fill an information gap with our own story before the media does. A well written best-selling book will help.”

Hermione sat there gaping.

Daphne raised a single eyebrow. “Did you hear anything just now apart from, ‘Harry Potter—Best Selling Author’?”

Hermione snapped her mouth shut, blushed, and quickly stood up. “I’m not even supposed to be up here!” She pointed to the queue outside Flourish and Blotts. “I’m supposed to be down there!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The bookshelves of Flourish and Blotts stretched nearly all the way from the floor to the ceiling, creating a sliver of space in-between. If someone were sufficiently athletic and nimble, they might be able to climb all the way up to the top, but they’d have to have a frame normally associated with ribbons, pleats, and the kind of fluffy ornaments stuck on the tops of pencils, in order to squeeze inside.

Invisible, flat on her stomach, and gazing out and down across the space in front of the still-closed Gilderoy Lockhart booth, Ginny Weasley surveyed the milling throng.

There were the Potters, with Harry looking more awesome than John ever could. She couldn’t for the life of her understand how Harry was keeping himself under control. If it had been her in his position, she’d still be chewing out Lord and Lady Potter at the top of her lungs. As it was, Lord Potter stood tall and dignified, while Lady Potter busily checked her hair for the fourth time in so many minutes while glancing towards Lockhart’s booth.

At that moment, Hermione walked into the shop like a witch on a mission. Ginny allowed herself a silenced snort as she watched the older girl sidle up to a bookshelf, stick her face in a seemingly random book, and casually edge her way up to the front of the queue.

“Mum, can I go browse books, pretty pretty pweese?”

Ginny whirled around—or rather, she tried to. She didn’t have much space.

“Okay, Ginny dear, but don’t pick up anything too expensive.”

Luna! Ginny squeezed her way out of her hiding spot and shimmied down the bookcase, careful not to land on anyone as she jumped, catlike, from three book shelves up.

She ducked around another row, found Luna, tapped her on the shoulder, and together they made their way out of the shop.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Harry watched the crowd from the magical history section, his eyes just above an open ‘History of the Second Magical British Empire’, like a lion gazing over long grass. Getting hold of the Dark Lord’s first horcrux had been gnawing at him for quite a while now. Even with Lord Malfoy thinking Lord Slytherin might be Voldemort, he didn’t dare straight up ask him for the diary. He wasn’t sure just how firmly Malfoy believed it. He was also under no illusions about the probability that this, waiting in Flourish and Blotts, would work. Too much stuff had changed. But even so, there was almost no cost to being here anyway, just in case. His target then entered the shop, along with his wife, son, and a girl he didn’t know—an overseas cousin perhaps. The Malfoys certain had plenty of them.

Lord Blott shook hands with Lord Malfoy with the air of a man who is being put upon and then disappeared back into the booth.

Nothing happened for several moments. Then there was a slight dimming of the lights and a booming voice sounded out across the store. “Lords and ladies, wizards and witches!” A plume of coloured smoke shot out from the curtain causing the nearest startled witches to cough and wave their hands about trying to clear it. “

“Order of Merlin, Third Class!”

The curtain started to raise.

“Honorary Member of the Dark Force Defence League!”

The curtain was half way up now, more smoke pouring out as a multicoloured spotlight struck the floor.

“And five times winner of Witch Weekly’s Most-Charming-Smile Award!”

Someone let loose a swam of butterflies that flew around the crowd to delighted shouts and squeals.

“I give you—GILDEROY LOCKHART!”

The crowd went wild.

Lord Malfoy put his head in his hands.

Harry couldn’t help smirking.

“Hey!” Harry turned. John stood right beside him staring with a deeply suspicious look. “What are you doing?”

“I am reading.”

John looked between him and Lord Malfoy, and, with obvious horror, understanding dawned.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The moment they were in the witch’s public bathroom, Ginny dropped her disillusionment.

“Ginny!” Luna hugged her. “I can’t tell you how much fun I’ve had. Being you is wonderful.”

“Good to hear it,” Ginny answered as they both started stripping and swapping clothes. “There weren’t any problems were there?”

“None.” Luna stepped into her own dress. “Although, if Fred and George start worshiping you it’s probably best just to go along with it.”

Ginny froze. “Luna,” she started with barely concealed dread. “What did you do?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“You can’t interfere!” John hissed.

Harry looked at him with incredulity. “Why not?”

“The timeline—”

Harry clamped his hand around his twin’s mouth and pulled him into a deserted row of books. “Don’t talk about it in public!” he whispered, fiercely.

John glared at him.

“There is absolutely no reason why anyone should have to suffer under that thing,” Harry spat.

On the other side of the bookshelf, unseen by either boy. A short figure creeped closer.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was so crowded, thought Julia.

What were you expecting? Virgo thought back. The man is a celebrity.

Virgo had moved away from the packed mass surrounding his newly adopted father and was now stalking through the aisles, looking for differences between his own time in the forties, and now.

He does look very dashing.

Virgo could practically feel Julia blushing. He groaned. Did girls really use the word, ‘dashing’?

S-Shut up! I’ll use it if I want to.

Virgo made to strengthen his occlumency barriers again, to at least keep some of his thoughts to himself. He’d had trouble focusing ever since the girl from the clothes shop had flung him out of her mind with a force of will that no normal eleven year old should possess.

Serves you right! That’s what you get for trying to peer into girl’s heads, you pervert!

Virgo was half way through projecting conciliatory and comforting thoughts to the girl when he noticed something.

Potter—both of them.

He sidled over to the shelf, behind which they were both crouched, doing his best to appear as graceful as possible in case anyone saw him, and peered through a tiny crack in the books. They were practically identical, except one had a lightning bolt scar on his forehead. That would be ‘Harry’—possibly another one of him—a horcrux in the flesh.

Their voices were low. Far too low for any normal person to hear over the bustle of the shop. But Virgo was no normal person.

“The diary must be destroyed,” said Harry.

Virgo froze. A stab of fear passed through her.

“Why?” asked John. His voice sounded harsh, angry, almost frustrated. “It would be better to let events happen. That way we know what will be.”

“Are you a fool? We don’t want things to happen the way they might.”

“You can’t take the diary!” John sounded almost frantic now. “You’ll just make everything even worse! It’s already bad enough!”

“I will do what I must.”

“Then so will I!” And with that, John marched off into the crowd towards Lord Malfoy.

Virgo pushed his back up against the bookshelf and tried not to breath as he listened to what was very obviously not his horcrux curse and walk off after his twin. What the hell!?

You’re frightened.

Virgo ignored the thought and dashed away, trying to find the most remote, most isolated place he could.

I’ve never seen you frightened before.

He ducked into an alcove made up by two bookcases, steadied himself against the wood, and tried to think. They knew about the diary. How? He would never wish himself dead, so Harry was obviously not him!

Maybe your older self told them.

But they’re just children! My older self has been out of it for almost as long as they’ve been alive!

Maybe they weren’t talking about your diary.

No. Impossible. It was. They must have been.

What happens if they destroy the diary? Would I get my body back? There was a touch of hope in her thoughts.

Nothing would happen! Virgo snapped. This is my body now! That’s not the point—the point is they want to kill me!

Then you’re fine aren’t you? Stop whining! No one knows you’re the boy from the diary.

THEY MIGHT!

Virgo was finding it difficult not to panic.

They already know too much! They’re both extremely intelligent for their ages. They could make the connection! I’ve seen them fight! They’re both as powerful as I am, if not more! And I don’t have my most important rituals! They want to kill me!

John doesn’t.

Virgo stilled. He forced his breathing down. That was right, wasn’t it. John didn’t want to kill him. Only Harry wanted to kill him. His mind worked through all his plans, recalibrating them around this new information. He still needed to find out what was going on with Harry Potter and Lord Slytherin, now more so than ever, but perhaps a slight change in approach was in order—a slightly safer approach. He nodded to himself. If it was possible, a slightly more red and gold approach.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“It can’t be John Potter!”

Harry couldn’t help smirking as John’s feeble attempts to scout out Lord Malfoy for the diary resulted in his being pulled onto the small stage behind the book signing table by a beaming Lockhart.

The crowd started whispering excitedly.

Lily Potter was actually clapping and bouncing on the tips of her feet. To his credit, James Potter was looking rather more stoic, although that might have been more to do with Lily’s behaviour than anything else.

“Lords and ladies, wizards and witches! What an astonishing moment this is! John Potter!”

The crowd burst into applause.

“The inspiration for my best selling book series! The hero of our world! A boy already making a name for himself as a powerful duellist, ready to defend against the forces of evil!”

With every additional sentence the crowd’s reaction was building. The dedicated clerk ringing up book sales off to the side was working as fast as he could to bag coins and wrap books. Lord Malfoy stood up near the stage looking grim.

Lockhart’s voice lowered and the crowd quieted.

“Now, he might be just here looking for my latest book for some helpful tips and tricks on how to get even better … but!” His voice lowered to a whisper and the crowd leaned in to catch every word. “He had no idea, that he would be getting much, much more than that.”

John smiled nervously.

Lockhart leaned backwards and gave John a hearty shake around the shoulders. “Lords and Ladies,” he continued in a more normal voice, which nevertheless promised it would not remain normal for long. “Wizards and witches, I have always prided myself on my ability to inspire others to greatness through my own great works and deeds. A little magic, a perfect smile …”

He flashed a smile and a witch in the front row fainted. Harry couldn’t help notice the wand tip poking through the curtain.

“… And a great deal of courage—that is what our children need. And I’m happy to say that that is what they are going to get, because I have been asked, and have graciously accepted, to step into one of the most important roles in our world at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry—Headmaster!”

The crowd erupted.

Lord Malfoy took his cue and walked up onto the stage to shake Lockhart’s hand as the cameras starting flashing again, all while holding an expression as flat and wooden as a bench.

“I and the board have great hopes for Headmaster Lockhart,” Malfoy said to the crowd in a dead voice. “I look forward to working with him.”

Harry smiled. He wasn’t the only one.

It was quite a bit later when the Potters finally made their way out of Flourish and Blotts. He’d cast a surreptitious wandless summoning spell on Malfoy as he passed, just in case he did have the diary, but nothing. He hadn’t expected it, and had not been disappointed. He’d have to find some other way.

Harry walked down the street one pace off to the side from his parents and brother, deep in his own thoughts, until a snatch of conversation brought him back again.

“Lord Malfoy—Virgo—his daughter—yes, apparently she was thought to be a squib—just like … well, you know …”

Harry frowned. Virgo? That girl with the Malfoys was Lord Malfoy’s daughter? Err … no. He was sure Lord Malfoy didn’t have a daughter. It wasn’t impossible that they’d cast out a squib—the Malfoys were certainly the people to do it, if anyone—but the timing was just too convenient. No, it had to be the diary. But how? Possession took a long time, possibly as much as a year, and even then the connection was tenuous.

He dug into the depths of his memories, trying to find something that could make this possible.

Eventually he dredged something up, but there was a problem. There was a ritual that could transfer a soul fragment to a still living body, but it was unpredictable, unstable, and most importantly, a Black family ritual. Voldemort couldn’t use it.

Harry’s thoughts stopped dead.

Voldemort couldn’t use it, but Narcissa Malfoy could.

—End of Chapter Thirty-Six—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s value.

Sticky Note: As always, if you want to stay up to date on schedule changes and other bonuses before anyone else, you can get them on my mailing list, which you can find by following the breadcrumb trail through my profile page.

Strategic Sorting

On platform nine and three-quarters, Chief Auror Sirius Black walked with his eleven year old daughter, pushing her trunk in front of him. On top of the trunk rested Alex’s cat carrying container, with Amethyst, her jet-black cat, asleep inside. The air was full of awkward. Alexandra was entirely too calm. She’d been entirely too calm all morning—far too much like his cousins. Sirius hadn’t been like this on his first day of school. No, he’d been practically bouncing off the walls. It had driven his father spare. He smiled. Ah, fond memories. He looked down at the head of long, black hair bobbing along beside him. “Exciting, isn’t it?” he tried.

“Yes, Dad,” came the dutiful response.

“Buck up, Alex! It’s your first day of Hogwarts!”

Alexandra looked up at him. “I am looking forward to it, you know.”

Sirius’s shoulders slumped. “You could at least look a bit more like it.”

“I am our house’s heiress.”

Sirius groaned. “Promise me you and Harry and Luna will at least try to have fun together. No spending all your time in the library, or anything like that.”

Alex seemed to consider this. “Okay. I promise.”

Sirius grinned and spread his arms. “Hug?”

Alex seemed to consider this too.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Alexandra Black dragged her feather-light trunk up the corridor back the way she’d come on the platform. Her father had insisted on walking with her all the way to the end of the train where the Light children usually hung out before hugging her and sending her on her way.

She didn’t have anything against hugging. She liked Luna’s hugs, but her father’s hugs didn’t feel like Luna’s. When her father hugged her, it was all tension and stiffness, like he was waiting for her to turn on him.

Alex passed by the Gray’s compartment with barely a glance inside. She marched up the rest of the distance, all the way to the front of the train, to the very first compartment, and opened the door. It was empty. The others had to be running late. She parked her trunk under one of the benches, fished out a book from the pocket of her standard black Hogwarts robes, and had just gotten into a nice flow when the door slid open with a noticeable swish.

“So you are here.” Draco Malfoy stood in the door way looking smug. “I hoped you’d know how to choose friends wisely, although …” his gaze roved over her clothes. “… Maybe your father just didn’t tell you what sitting here means.”

And so it begins, Alex thought. She looked up from her book and sneered. It was a good sneer. She’d been practising all summer. “Are you going to stand there posturing all day or are you going to sit down?”

Draco looked momentarily stunned before he narrowed his eyes. “This is my compartment, Black. You don’t order me around in here.”

“So you don’t want to sit down?”

“I will sit when I decide I will.” He threw her a look that suggested she was less than the shit on the bottom of his boot. “You don’t have your daddy to protect you here, Black. I should have known better than to think you’d know how to behave around your—”

Alex’s wand came out fast enough to cut Draco off in mid-sentence. “—My what, Heir Malfoy, of the mere Noble House of Malfoy?”

Draco glared at the wand pointed at his chest.

A bored sounding female voice from the corridor behind Malfoy said, “Well, this is all very interesting,”

Alex’s eyes flicked to the back. A blond girl her age stood there, watching Alex’s wand like a cat watches a mouse.

“And you are?”

The girl moved forward and bobbed the slightest curtsey Alex had ever seen. It was barely even a bow. “Virgo Malfoy of the, yes, Noble House of Malfoy.”

Virgo Malfoy. Alex’s mind flipped through the warning Harry had passed to her a few days before—enemy—powerful—dangerous—legilimens—manipulative—treat with caution. So naturally, the first words out of her mouth were, “The squib?”

The girl’s eyes flashed, Draco flinched, and magic instantly filled the compartment—raw oppression pushing and pressing down on Alex from all sides like she’d been buried in wet sand.

It was impressive …

Of course, it would have been more impressive if Lord Slytherin hadn’t already taught Ginny, Luna, and Harry the same trick, and if she, Alex, hadn’t already learned a Black family magic spell that did something similar, if a bit more dementor-ish.

The magic faded.

Virgo watched her with an expectant look on her face.

Alex tilted her head. “Okay, I guess?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The Hogwarts Express had pulled out of platform nine and three-quarters, and now the suburbs of London were giving way to fields and hedges. In the middle of the train, Ginny Weasley stared at Harry in horror and disgust. “Virgo Malfoy is the diary?”

“She is,” Harry replied.

“Ew! Ew!” Ginny wrapped her arms around herself. “That thing saw me naked!”

“I’ve already warded all the entrances to the chamber. As soon as we get to the castle, I’ll ask the twins for a loan of the map and then, when a good opportunity presents itself, I’ll—”

“—I want to do it,” Ginny cut in.

Harry frowned. “Absolutely not. I’m clearly the best suited for this task.”

Ginny didn’t look mollified. “What’s the point in all my training if I don’t ever use it? Isn’t this what I’ve been working for? For nearly three years? The diary is my fight!”

Luna looked up from her book.

“Be that as it may—”

“—I think you should consider it,” Luna said.

On the other side of the compartment, Hermione and Daphne raised their eyebrows.

“You said the diary wouldn’t have the benefits of the unforgivable ritual,” Luna continued. “Nor many of his other rituals. It’s Riddle, yes, but it’s a sixteen year old Riddle, not a seventy year old Riddle. Ginny is ready. So am I. “

Ginny blanched. “Luna, I want it to be me who destroys the diary.”

“I think you should let Harry do it,” Hermione said. “If he says it’s the best way then that should be good enough. Isn’t that right, Daphne?”

Daphne made a non committal head wobble.

Harry’s eyes flitted between the girls. He then stood up and stepped over to the door. “Luna, walk with me?”

“Yes, Harry.”

Harry led Luna down the train and into a bathroom, shutting and locking the door behind him.

“Cosy.” Luna giggled. “I didn’t think you’d be pulling me into these places for a few years, yet.”

Harry finished casting the rest of his privacy spells. He turned to her. “Okay, Luna. What you’re suggesting is obviously not optimal. Care to explain your logic?”

Luna nodded. “One day you will probably want to start sending me and Ginny up against far more dangerous threats than the diary. The diary is a useful way to ease us into that role. Experience requires experience.”

Harry frowned. “I know you and Ginny are both scarily competent at the limited number of techniques you’ve been mastering—much more so than Riddle was, even at sixteen—but the diary is still dangerous in the variety of magics it knows.”

“Of course, but you can mitigate that risk.”

“How?”

“Influence Lockhart into creating portkeys that work inside Hogwarts—make it his own idea. Then have him gift them to someone in the Dark, steal them, and frame it on the Light.”

“… So that if you or Ginny have to use them to escape, it would look like a Light assassination attempt.”

“Exactly.”

Harry leaned back on the sink and thought about it for several minutes. Then he kicked off. “If we can’t get those portkeys then I’ll do it myself—you two will have to settle for support roles.”

Luna nodded and the two of them made their way back to the middle compartment.

They arrived to find the window open, and Macavity—Lord Slytherin’s large and majestic sooty owl—snuggling up to Hedwig on her perch. Daphne’s marmoset familiar, Freekey, hung from the overhead luggage compartment, playing with Ginny’s stuffed dragon teddy bear.

Ginny herself was busy making notes in a small yellow book. Harry gave her a nod, which caused her to grin from ear to ear. He then raised a questioning eyebrow at Daphne who was going through several letters that Macavity had clearly just delivered. “Anything?”

Daphne nodded. “The Hogwarts board has confirmed a meeting for this Tuesday.”

Harry sat down and drummed his fingers on the small compartment table. “Okay, this will be a perfect opportunity to get the muggleborn guardianships all handed over to us.”

“That’s moving very quickly,” Hermione warned. “I’m not sure how some of the older ones will take that.”

Daphne snorted. “Most of them don’t even know they have a magical guardian.”

“But they will if this makes it to the Daily Prophet,” Hermione pointed out.

“Harry can lean on Malfoy to lean on the Prophet. Besides, we don’t have time to wait around.”

“I’m not saying we shouldn’t do it.” A tone of exasperation leaked into Hermione’s voice. “I’m just saying that I might have to answer some uncomfortable questions.”

“Oh? You’re always saying how much they trust you.”

“Yes, the muggleborns our age!”

Harry sat back and let it wash over him. After several minutes of back and forth he cut in. “And the second thing, Daphne?”

Hermione and Daphne froze in mid argument.

Ginny sniggered.

Daphne coughed and picked up the parchments again. “Yes, MaCUSA are interested in our magical submarine pitch. They say they want a full proposal sometime in the next eight weeks.”

Harry nodded to himself. “We can do that.”

Eight weeks was enough time to sort that out. He glanced at his watch and out the open window. It was getting on for time, and he had another, rather more critical meeting to get to. He looked over to where Ginny and Luna were in deep conversation.

“It’s a muggle book?” asked Ginny.

“It’s about a muggle dragon sanctuary that gets overrun by the animals they’re trying to breed.”

“How do muggles have dragons?”

“They find them in tree sap.”

“Muggles—found dragons—in tree sap?”

Harry stood up. “Girls.”

Daphne, Hermione, Ginny, and Luna all turned to him.

“I’m heading off now—probably be back in a few hours.”

Ginny bit her lip. “You’re off to talk to my Dad?”

“I am.”

Ginny nodded. “Good luck.”

Harry walked to the window, giving Ginny’s shoulder a reassuring squeeze on the way. He then disillusioned himself and threw himself out of the train, straight into a blasting sixty mile an hour wind. The wind quickly became a gentle breeze as he slowed down in the air and floated just above the track.

The Hogwarts Express gently chugged off into the distance.

Harry felt for the thin membrane of space-time magic that separated the Hogwarts Express line from the rest of the country, donned the invisibly cloak, and silently slipped through it. Once on the other side, he started apparating at speed back south. This was an important meeting. He’d prepared for it for days, studying his target and crafting the perfect line of attack. It was time to put all that work into effect.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back on the Hogwarts Express, in a compartment about midway between the Light and the Gray, Fred and George Weasley poured over rune plans for the oxygen recycling plate they’d designed and sold to Lord Slytherin’s friends last year. The Settlers now wanted a new and improved version—smaller—more powerful—and they wanted it fast.

“Not asking for much, are they?” Fred muttered.

George shrugged. “They’re paying for what they’re asking for. We still have a list of things to try.”

The door slid open. The plans vanished into Fred’s pocket.

John Potter stood in the door, a faint smile on his face.

“Well, hello, Heir Potter.” George gave a theatrical bow. “And to what do we humble pair owe the honour?”

John Potter stepped into the compartment proper and grinned. “Would you like to know about Prongs?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The air surrounding the Burrow was calm and peaceful. The family Ford Anglia was safely parked in the shed, along-side several hundred other muggle projects, which the part-time patriarch of the house, Arthur Weasley, played with on a regular basis.

Said part-time patriarch was currently sat in the kitchen, straightening the cuffs of his best tweed suit.

“I don’t like this Arthur,” Molly Weasley said while directing the unwashed dishes from breakfast into the sink. “How do you know you can trust him?”

“I don’t,” he answered in a calm voice. “That’s why I’m having lunch with him.”

“I wish you would at least tell me what you plan to talk about.”

Arthur sighed.

Suddenly, a loud roar of something passed over the Burrow. Arthur leapt to his feet and dashed to the window, Molly right behind him. The two stared as a muggle flying device slowly landed in the field one over from them, its rotors kicking up dust and grass and making enough noise to cause birds to take flight as far as the eye could see.

A figure hopped out, tiny at this distance—a figure wearing a black suit of the kind Arthur often saw muggles wearing in the city. The figure started to make its way over to the Burrow, the muggle flying device still roaring behind it, and as it got closer, it became obvious the man was wearing a mask that covered the top half of his face.

“Arthur—” Molly started in a warning voice.

“It’s one of them!” Arthur said, delighted. “The muggle flying machines that go up and down! A heliflopter!”

“Arthur!”

Arthur turned to see Molly staring at him.

“Be careful, Arthur.”

Something in his wife’s voice got through to him. He nodded, face serious, gave Molly a peck on the cheek, made his way to the back door, shoved his way through it, and half-trotted across the lawn to the back gate.

He reached the masked man halfway across the next field. “Lord Slytherin?”

The man took no time to slow down. “Mister Weasley.” He turned smartly back around and started walking away. “We’re late. Follow me.”

“Late?” Arthur tried to adjust his gait to the taller man’s but found himself having to half skip to keep up. “I say,” he tried, “what are we late for?”

“We have a reservation.”

“Reservation?” Arthur called out. They were getting closer to the heliflopter now. “Why are we using a heli—”

“Wands away, Mister Weasley,” Slytherin called back to him. “Muggle territory now.”

Arthur hastily patted down his coat, making sure his wand was secure. The heliflopter was really quite close now. He had to shield his face with his arm to block the wind.

“This is Robert!” Slytherin shouted, pointing to the man in the front seat of the heliflopter who waved at them. “Ex-Royal Air Force! He’ll be our pilot!”

After a fascinating encounter with what Robert the muggle called a ‘safety buckle,’ the door slid shut with a loud clunk sound. They both donned tight-fitting ear muffs and the machine started to lift up into the air, Mister Weasley clutching the seat for dear life. “But how does it work?” he shouted, staring out of the window in awe as the country-side sped away past them.

“No idea,” Slytherin replied. “Needless to say, it does.”

“Differential air pressure between the blades powered by a Rolls Royce engine!” Robert called out helpfully.

Arthur glanced away from the window, towards the muggle, bit down the thousand and one questions he had for Lord Slytherin, and tried to figure out what the long, red, cylindrical, metallic device under his chair could possibly be for.

Half an hour later, they’d left the green fields of the West-Country far behind them, and were flying over the streets of London.

“Here we are!” Robert announced as the heliflopter descended on one of the tall building’s rooftops.

The moment Arthur’s wobbly feet hit the ground another muggle in a suit and a moustache greeted them and guided them into the building, away from the machine’s constant roar.

“I hope your trip was pleasant, Mister Slytherin?” Their guide asked.

“Quite pleasant, thank you.”

They were led into a large elegant room filled with tables, in which dozens more muggles, were eating. The place reminded Arthur very much of the occasional time he’d been invited to one of the manor balls. Their guide led them past all the diners, out of a pair of large glass double doors, and onto a balcony. A table was set for two.

“Please, Mister Weasley.” Slytherin gestured for him to sit.

Arthur did so.

What followed was a singular exercise in frustration and fascination as he waited for them to finally be alone from the many muggles waiting on them. Whenever he thought they were finally done, another would pop out of nowhere to make some tiny adjustment or ask a question and then, of course, he’d just have to ask his own, which they seemed only too happy to answer.

“Summer fruits wine, Sir.”

Slytherin inspected the bottle’s seal before nodding and allowing the waiter to pour Arthur a glass.

Arthur took a sip. “Mmm … strawberry, raspberry … plum?”

“It wouldn’t surprise me.” Slytherin sipped on his own glass of dry red.

The food arrived shortly thereafter and they were finally alone.

Arthur swallowed a slice of perfectly cooked steak, put down his fork and knife, and let out a long, deep sigh. “As interesting as this all is, I can’t help feeling it all rather elaborate. Do you normally treat all your lunch partners like this?”

Slytherin shook his head. “No, but I can only guess at what you wanted to discuss. I thought it would be a good idea to talk where there was no possibility of the Rotfang Conspiracy overhearing us. Nargles do not make for good lunch partners and everyone knows they are allergic to the hair products muggles use.”

Arthur nodded his understanding. It seemed obvious now it had been said. He picked up his fork. “My twin sons came to me a while back with a very interesting proposal.”

“I know.”

Arthur hesitated. “I wasn’t expecting you to be so forthcoming.”

“In all honesty, I expected you to demand a meeting sooner.” Slytherin took another sip of wine. “Might I ask how you figured out that I am their patron?”

“Molly and I have a standing order with Gringotts to apply the five percent maximum tax rate for the members of my house—something my working sons are quite happy with, and I have a useful contact in the department of trade who knew about a recent deal between Nimbus and your house. I was rather surprised when I received my Gringotts statement earlier this month.”

“Ah, yes that would do it. So, what would you like to know? I hope you’re happy with Fred and George. They are quite the amazing pair and it would be a tragedy if their talents were squandered.”

Arthur shook his head. “I have no problems with that, per say, although I do find your whole cloak and dagger way of doing things more than a little unsettling.”

“I have good reasons.”

Arthur observed the man in front of him carefully. Unlike the magical mask Slytherin was known to wear, this muggle one showed his eyes as well as most of his lower face, although Arthur had to assume he also wore a glamour. “Do your good reasons have anything to do with your unasked for interventions in my daughter’s life?”

If Arthur was hoping for any kind of immediate reaction, he was disappointed. Slytherin finished bringing a morsel of food to his mouth, chewed it, swallowed, cut himself another slice, and inspected it as thought it were the most interesting thing in the room. Slytherin looked up and caught his gaze. “Go on.”

Arthur gave Slytherin a wooden expression. “My wife has a clock—a Prewett family artefact. It tracks the location of all members of the Prewett line through the Albion family magics. When Molly’s brothers were murdered by you-know-who the clock became matrilineal and passed to her. Molly hasn’t noticed, but I have. Ginny spends far too much time outside when she should be in the Burrow, slipping past wards that no eleven year old could.”

“I’m surprised you didn’t cotton onto your twin sons’s excursions the same way.”

“Blu Tack.”

“Sorry?”

“Blu Tack. It’s this muggle stuff that sticks to things. I found it behind the twin’s spoons on the clock.”

“Resourceful.”

“Ah, yes, yes, very resourceful.”

They continued to eat in silence, each occasionally throwing the other glances as thought waiting for the other to bite first. Eventually Slytherin put down his fork and knife. “What do you know about Fate?”

“Fate like destiny?”

“Like Fate with a capital F.”

Arthur gave Slytherin a cautious look. “The mythological magical being from who prophecies supposedly originate?”

“That’s the one.”

“That was pretty much everything—look, where is this going? If you’re going to tell me that Ginny has a prophecy—”

“She does.”

“I haven’t received any word from the department of mys—”

“—The prophecy was not made in Britain.”

Arthur shut his mouth with a loud click. He put his elbows on the table and rubbed his temples. He then picked up his wine glass, brought it to his lips, and took rather more than a sip. The glass hit the table with a small thump. “And you heard this prophecy, did you? Ready to share the memory?”

Slytherin shook his head. “This prophecy was given under extremely unusual circumstances, so that won’t be possible.”

“Then how do I know you’re not talking out of your arse? Pardon my language.”

“You don’t. I can only show you that my actions up to now have all been with Ginny’s best interests in mind, and to point out that I would not invest such time and effort on a whim.”

Arthur nodded slowly, glass in hand. “Okay, what does this prophecy say?”

“I won’t give you the exact wording, but the main points are that without my intervention, Ginny would die by the end of this year …”

Arthur spat out his wine across the table and looked at Slytherin in horror.

“… That together, Harry Potter and Ginny Weasley will defeat a resurrected Dark Lord Voldemort …”

The look of horror intensified.

“… And that to succeed, Harry Potter and Ginny Weasley must be ‘bound together.’ Although that can be interpreted in many ways. They are certainly close friends.”

Arthur stared. “That all?” he said, weakly.

“Mostly, yes.”

“Why not tell me before?”

“I have enemies. Some of those enemies are people I happen to know you hold a great deal of respect and fondness for.”

“Everyone knows you and Dumbledore don’t get along.”

Slytherin slightly inclined his head.

Arthur sighed. This was going to be a long discussion.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

An hour later, Harry watched Arthur Weasley apparate away back to the Burrow. Everything had gone well. He’d gotten exactly what he needed—for the moment, at least. He’d now wait a few weeks to see if any of that information leaked before making his next move.

Satisfied, Harry disillusioned himself, snuck into the kitchens, found the open bottle of summer fruits wine, and used his wand to deftly switch out the contents into a bottle of his own. Dirigible plum was almost unique in its rareness after all—no sense wasting it.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Watching children trying to play at politics was always amusing, Virgo thought, but he did have to admit that some played better than others.

“The Black family magics belong with those who can appreciate them, cousin,” Draco said in an annoyed voice. “Surely you can understand that?”

On the other side of the compartment, wedged in between Pansy Parkinson and Millicent Bulstrode, Alexandra Black smirked. “Why not just ask my aunt?”

Draco flushed.

“Ahhhh … has mummy not deemed you ready? Oh, dear.” Alexandra lifted her feet, removed one of her low heeled shoes with her other foot, and let the shoe fall to the ground with a small thump. She then extended the sock clad appendage into the middle of the compartment. “Why don’t you get down on the floor and kiss my foot?” The other children all choked. “Then, maybe, I will teach you a spell.”

Virgo clamped down on the impulse to smile. He liked this girl.

You would, thought the soul of Julia.

Draco stared at the foot as though it were a poisonous snake.

“No?” Alexandra sighed in mock disappointment before slipping the shoe back on. “Oh, well—I guess not then—such a shame. They were such delicious magics, too.”

Alexandra would make an excellent follower given the correct incentives.

Really?thought Julia. Seems to me like she wouldn’t follow anyone.

That shows how little you understand. The girl is power sensitive. She clearly understands how the world really works, and has the drive to dominate. Such people often make the best followers once they’ve been shown they are categorically not the most powerful person in the room.

Shame you didn’t manage to convince her of that, then.Virgo could practically feel the triumphant smirk in the thought.

He scowled.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The most powerful person in the room stared at the Slytherin girl prostrating herself to him on the floor of the otherwise empty compartment.

Not five minutes ago Harry had found his way back onto the Hogwarts Express after having flooed to Hogsmeade and doubled back along the underground ward stone tunnel, which hid the Hogwarts Express line from the muggles. He’d no sooner clambered back into the Gray’s compartment when Heiress Tracey Davis had asked for a private conversation.

Tracey had been kidnapped by Lord Voldemort at the end of the last year and had subsequently learned of Harry Potters’s other identity. The girl in front of him now was quite different from the one he’d left on the Hogwarts Express a few months ago.

“Gray Lord Slytherin,” Tracey half-whispered, head pressed to the floor.

“Yes, Tracey?”

There was a silence.

“Tracey?”

“I—I’m sorry, my lord. I’m not sure how to address this.”

Harry sighed. “Oh for Merlin’s sake. Get up, Tracey.”

Tracey looked up, then got to her feet.

“Sit down.” Harry pointed to the chair opposite him.

Tracey sat.

“Now, go slowly, and talk to me.”

Tracey took a deep breath. “It’s about Grandfather. I’m sure you must know him—what with you both being lords. I’ve heard him talk about you—he respects you—sort of—but over the summer I’ve heard my mother arguing with him when they thought I couldn’t hear. I think my grandfather wants to betroth me sooner rather than later—”

Ahh, Harry thought.

“—He’s very traditional like that. I don’t think I’d even know until it happened. Mother sounded furious, but ultimately it wouldn’t be her decision, and Dad tends to go along with my grandfather.” Tracey’s fists gripped her robes. “I know it’s not fair, given what happened with you and Daphne, but I really don’t want to be betrothed to someone I didn’t choose. I was wondering—I mean, what with you being The Gray Lord—if you could—I’ll do anything, Harry.”

Harry idly chewed his tongue. Persuading Lord Davis to let his grand daughter be courted normally was probably doable, but it wouldn’t be without cost. “What anything?”

“Anything!” Tracey hesitated. “Well, anything short of that.”

Harry sat in silence for a moment considering his options before speaking. “Would you be willing to pledge yourself to my service for the remainder of your time at Hogwarts?”

“I would.”

“Would you be willing to listen to my advice about your betrothal prospects?”

“My lord?”

“Only listen, Tracey, not give up the final decision, or anything like that. I doubt your grandfather will agree without my offering to oversee the process and report back to him.”

Tracey nodded slowly. “I understand.”

“Go on then.”

Tracey looked momentarily confused before understanding dawned and she got back down on the floor. “Lord Slytherin, in return for the freedom to choose my own future husband, I pledge myself to your service for the next six years.”

“Tracey Davis, Heiress of the Noble House of Davis, I accept your pledge in the spirit in which it is given. Now stand.”

Tracey stood. Her body looked like a weight had been lifted off of it.

“I also now give you official permission to use the possessive along side my title.”

“My lord?”

“You may call me, ‘my lord.’ ”

“Oh.” Tracey smiled. “Thank you, my lord, you’ve no idea how much this means to me.” She brushed her robes down. “What would you like me to do now?”

“I suspect Hermione and Daphne are going to be buried under work for me this year. You will assist the two of them to the best of your abilities. Report to Hermione for a briefing on her projects.”

“Yes, my lord.” And with that, Tracey curtsied low to the ground, turned around and left.

Harry sighed. He kinda missed the snarky Tracey from last year who’d call him ‘Potter’ and get all frustrated when he didn’t do what she wanted. Maybe he could gradually tease that Tracey back out once she’d gotten used to taking orders from him …

Moments later, Daphne stepped into the compartment and shut the door behind her. “What was that about?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Students up and down the train had started calling it muggleborn HQ. It sat a dozen compartments away from the middle of the Hogwarts Express. Not close enough to the Gray to give people the wrong idea, but close enough to make a point. It was also cramped as hell.

Hermione looked around, taking metal notes. Hogwarts had a muggleborn quota. Five of the forty new students each year had to be muggleborn. She and the rest of the founder’s club—the muggle born support group that Harry had guided her to build—had gone up and down the train and rounded up the first year muggleborns. Three girls, two boys.

She’d introduced herself and the group, then partnered up the first and second years with each other.

Dean Thomas had taken a squeaky, photography obsessed boy named Colin Creevey, who’d needed rapid deprogramming from the romantic notions some boy-who-lived crazed fool had shoved down his throat in Diagon Alley.

Kevin Entwhistle partnered with his younger sister. Kevin came from a lower class muggle family and had spent a lot of the last year adjusting to life at Hogwarts. He stood taller than Goyle and wider than Crabbe, but unlike them, hated unfairness when he saw it—a classic Hufflepuff. His sister, Annabel Entwhistle, was tiny by comparison. The two of them looked like they’d perfectly divided up all the big and small genes in their family between them.

In comparison to the huge difference between Kevin and Annabel, Hermione and Sophie partnered with Violet and Marigold Chesterfield—twins. What was it with the wizarding world and twins, Hermione wondered. The Weasleys, the Potters, the Patils, the Carrows, and now these two? They were brown-eyed and brown-haired, and seemed more in sync than even Fred and George.

That left Justin Finch-Fletchley with Alan Gage, an average looking boy of average height and average wit—normal and unremarkable in every way possible—just one more body in an already bustling compartment.

If the compartment only held the second and first year muggleborns, then it wouldn’t have been nearly so cramped, but word had spread while they’d been rounding up the first years, and a handful of older muggleborns had somehow managed to find space too, cramming up on benches, on the floor, table, or, in the case of one fourth year Hufflepuff, lying on his tummy in the overhead luggage rack with his head and one arm dangling over the edge.

“Here’s a list of people you can go to if you have serious problems,” Hermione said, passing out the parchment packages to the first years.

Sophie leaned over and giggled. “Why, Hermione, on your list, have you outlined Harry’s name in little hearts?”

Hermione flushed furiously and stuffed the list into the pocket of her robes. “And the first meeting of the founder’s club will be at the start of October,” she continued, as if nothing had happened. “If you want to learn more about Lord Slytherin before then you can read the packages.”

“Will this club improve our ministry prospects?” asked the Hufflepuff in the luggage rack.

“It’ll get you better marks if you stick with it,” Kevin said. “Can’t say anymore than that. We’re under contract.”

“Would you work around Quidditch practise?”

Justin looked up in surprise. “You’re on the Quidditch team?”

“Well no, but I’d like to be.”

Dean sniffed. “This is like football. All the quidditch players spend all summer practising on their local village pitch—that’s what I’ve heard.”

The luggage rack Hufflepuff huffed. “More discrimination.”

“Good point,” Hermione said, searching in her bag for a quill. “I’ll add broomstick fields to the introduction package.”

“Doesn’t help us now.”

“There’s a good reason we can’t just fly any old place,” Hermione countered. “We’re not here to complain, we’re here to help each other. Besides, you’re in Hogwarts. That’s already a huge advantage.”

“I suppose.”

The door slid open. It was Tracey.

“Ah,” Hermione began. “This, first years, is Heiress Davis. She’s on the list. What can we help you with?”

“Can the formality, vassal. I’ve been demoted.”

“I beg your pardon?”

“Our Lord Slytherin has assigned me to be your assistant.”

This drew incredulous looks from all the non-first year muggleborns in the compartment. Their faces all suggested the same thing—an heiress serving a muggleborn—well, well.

Hermione hesitated for only a moment before rallying and pulling out a trunk from under the bench for Tracey to sit on and work from. The two then whiled away the next few hours reading, comparing project notes, and fielding endless questions from both the younger and older students (Tracey proved invaluable for some of the more detailed questions) and soon enough, the sky outside had darkened, and a loud voice announced that they were nearing Hogsmeade Station, and that they should ‘leave their luggage on the train’—a command that the more than handful of students with shrinkable trunks, totally failed to obey.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The dark platform was a mass of black clad students, mostly shuffling towards the carriages, or to where Hagrid the gamekeeper was shouting, “Firs’ years! Firs’ years over ‘ere!”

John Potter creeped through the crowd, eyes sharp for his target—for his Ginny. He spotted her through a gap in the throng, milling around with a group of other first year girls, her long red hair flowing out behind her.

John pointed his wand and whispered, “Accio, diary.”

There was a pull, an “Eep!”, and a yellow diary, small enough to fit into the palm of his hand, sailed towards him, landing on the ground at his feet. He stared at it in mild dread.

Slap!

John staggered backwards, face stinging.

Ginny stood in front of him, enraged, and snatched up the small yellow book. “You bastard!”

John rubbed his cheek and stared. He hadn’t even seen it coming. Was it possible for people to move that fast? “Look, Ginny, this isn’t—” He wasn’t sure what excuse he was actually going to use, but he didn’t get a chance to use it before Ginny turned on her heels and stalked away, back towards the first year boats.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“I don’t know who she thinks she is,” said the shrill voice of Pansy Parkinson. Pansy, Draco, Theo, and Milli were all sat in one of the carriages slowly making its way up to the castle. “It’s like she thinks she can just waltz in here—as though Lord Black hasn’t spent the last ten years dragging the name of Black through the mud.”

Draco said nothing—just stared out the window.

“You need to put her in her place, Draco,” she continued. “A good hard sting is what she needs.”

“Oh?” Theo snickered. “Like with Granger, last year?”

Draco did his best not to grimace. Opening a prank spell war with the mudblood had turned out to be a bad idea. It had taken him months to rebuild his credibility after he’d come limping into the Slytherin common room looking like the joke metamorphmagus from one of wizarding Britain’s stranger magical theatre productions. That Alexandra Black sought out the Dark was good, but …

Pansy sniffed.

Draco tore his gaze away from nothing. “Don’t worry,” he said, voice far harsher than his normal bored drawl. “I have already taken steps to ensure she will be brought up to speed on what is required of her. You can be sure of that.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

If Ginny thought her mood was going to improve once she’d gotten away from John ‘let-my-girlfriend-get-possessed-by-the-dark-lord’ Potter, then she was sorely mistaken. She stormed down to the boats, Luna almost sliding to keep up (“No more’n four to a boat!”), and was joined, moments later, by Alex, along with the last person on Earth she wanted to spend the ride with.

“Hello, Alex,” said Luna in a chipper voice. “Who’s your friend?”

“Virgo Malfoy,” said the diary, sitting down opposite Ginny. “And I believe we’ve met before, Miss Weasley.”

A shiver ran up Ginny’s spine. Just a few minutes alone, she thought, as the boats all pushed off together. Just a few seconds, and me and Luna and Alex could dog pile it—drown it in the lake—and feed the body whole to the giant squid.

Of course, that would mean having to explain to Alex exactly why they were trying to murder their eleven year old classmate …

Unfortunately, no such opportunity presented itself. Ginny’s boat stayed firmly in the middle of the small armada, and as they rounded the corner, Hogwarts Castle loomed in the distance. Everyone made thematically appropriate Oooooooh noises.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ooooooooh, thought the soul of Julia.

Beautiful, isn’t it? Virgo thought back.

It is.There was a pause. But I still hate you!

Virgo sighed.

It wasn’t long before the boats drifted into the alcove he remembered from his first year, leading up to the castle proper. A stern faced witch introduced herself as Professor McGonagall, and then gave them a speech about their house being like their family. She seemed to be in a rather bad mood. Virgo listened with only half an ear, purposefully ignoring the occasional pouty glares of the Weasley girl. Honestly, he thought, try to mind rape someone just once and they never let it go.

Julia’s soul made a horrified spluttering sound.

Whoops, did he think that inside?

Yes!

McGonagall then left them to ‘get ready.’ The other students started whispering the moment the door closed.

“Draco actually had the balls to suggest I might one day join his harem,” Alexandra Black said to Luna Lovegood. “Can you believe that?”

“Draco Malfoy has a harem?”

Alexandra snorted. “In his dreams.”

Virgo couldn’t help notice two twin girls standing behind Alexandra Black, both with long black hair, both eyeing the Black heiress up the way a pair of wolves might eye up a rabbit. Hestia and Flora—the Carrow twins—one of two sets of twins this year—although which was which was anyone’s guess.

Which witch is which!

Yes, very witty.

The side door opened again and Professor McGonagall ushered them inside. Halfway into the great hall, Virgo caught sight of what hung behind the headmaster’s chair. He stopped dead, causing the rest of the first years behind to bump into him with many ows and complaints.

A twelve foot tall banner featuring the beaming visage of Gilderoy Lockhart dominated the front of the hall. Virgo stared in horror.

“What are you waiting for?” snapped McGonagall, still not looking very happy. “Hurry up!”

Virgo quickly lined up with the children and stared out across the hundreds of students. Many of the rather mixed gazes weren’t on them, but up and back, clearly on the smiling, blonde abomination behind him.

The hat was brought out and sung its song, a few student’s names were shouted out, and then …

Black, Alexandra!

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Darkness enveloped Alex and a voice in her head said, [Let’s see what we have here.]

Lord Slytherin said I was to go to Slytherin.

[Yes, yes, I can see that, but perhaps—]

Slytherin said!

[I know, girl, but I am a guide, and the ultimate choice has to be yours. I can see muchof interest in your head.]

No! Slytherin. Slytherin. Slytherin.

[You are brave. You tend to rush in without thinking things through—reckless, oh, so reckless. You fight for your house’s honour.]

Slytherin. Slytherin. Slytherin.

[You would do well in Gryffindor.]

Slytherin!

[Both your parents were Gryffindors], the hat wheedled. [It could be the start of a new Black tradition.]

NO!

The hat sighed in her head. [Oh, very well. Better be] SLYTHERIN!

Sweating, Alex took the hat off her head and walked over to the table of green and silver. She sat towards the Dark end with Draco and Pansy and watched while the first set of twins, Flora and Hestia Carrow, were sorting into Slytherin, followed quickly by the second set, Marigold and Violet Chesterfield, who were both sorted into Hufflepuff. Eventually, Luna was called, sorted into Slytherin, and sat down at the opposite end of the table with Hermione, Daphne, and Harry.

A part of Alex wished she could join her.

Up at the teacher’s table, Lockhart was clapping and beaming to each and every sorted student. Alex’s eyes trailed sideways. She couldn’t help letting a small groan escape when they fell on the woman sitting next to the hooked nosed man. She’d already known, of course, but nevertheless, she would have liked to have escaped from Lady Lily Potter.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Malfoy, Virgo!”

A few whispers spread throughout the hall. Mostly along the lines of, “I didn’t know they had a daughter.” He noticed with disgust that some of the older boys had thoughtful looks on their faces.

That’s your fault for choosing to be a girl.

Lord Malfoy would never have accepted me being male, he thought back. It would have been far too risky.

The hat fell across his eyes.

[ … That’s one end of a conversation I never thought I’d be party too.]

What!? Who’s this?!

Calm, girl.

[Yes.]

It’s the sorting hat.

[As Mister Riddle says, I am the sorting hat. Or maybe that’s Virgo Malfoy now.]

It is.

Humpf.

[Now where to put you … ]

Gryffindor, if you would.

[You’ve got to be joking.]

I am not joking.

[You are one of the most Slitherest Slytherins who ever Slithered into Slytherin.]

Am I not brave? Do I not fight for what I believe is right?

[You fear death so much your ripped apart your soul with the life of a true love! And your beliefs in muggle and muggleborn inferiority stem from bitterness and rage!]

She betrayed me!

[She was only following her parents orders, and you murdered her!]

What?!

Enough! Gryffindor!

Who? Who did you murder?

We are not discussing this. Gryffindor! There will be no argument. You, Hat, are required to sort based on the student’s ultimate choice. I choose Gryffindor.

There was silence for a moment. Then, in an extremely grumpy tone of voice, the hat said, [I suppose Julia, at least, is brave and noble—although I fear it will not be enough.] GRYFFINDOR!

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

At one end of the Slytherin table, face impassive, his fingers interlocked under his chin, Harry raised one single, solitary eyebrow.

At the other end, Draco spluttered in horror.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

John Potter clapped softly as the Malfoy girl was sorted into his own house of scarlet and gold. Under the table, the Marauder’s Map lay on his knees. It had taken a good bit of work to persuade the Weasley twins to lend it to him, even for only an hour, but he’d managed it. He couldn’t understand why they were so reluctant. In the last timeline, they’d practically thrown it at him when they learned who Prongs was.

John was quite happy to know he wasn’t stupid. When Virgo had suddenly turned up out of nowhere, it had been rather obvious she might not be who she said she was, given that she hadn’t been around in the last timeline. Even if her story checked out, which it did, he wasn’t going to rely on that.

No, he was going to rely on the Albion family magics. You couldn’t fool the Albion family magics.

He carefully leaned back, glanced under the table, prodded the parchment with his wand, and whispered, “I solemnly swear that I am up to no good.”

The map blossomed into being, focused on the great hall.

A dot marked Virgo Druella Malfoy moved to only a few seats away from him across the table, and sat down.

John looked up and caught her eye.

She gave him a cautious smile.

People up and down the table gazed at her with everything from naked curiosity to outright hostility.

John snorted. As if Lord Voldemort would ever be sorted into Gryffindor.

The sorting went on for quite a while longer, and then …

Weasley, Ginevra!

John’s heart leapt.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

[Hello, Miss Weasley]

Hello. Slytherin for me, please and thank you.

SLYTHERIN!

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo made sure to keep his expression as demure and unthreatening as possible while observing his target’s face on the opposite side of the table. It had gone from joy to shock to despair to rage, all in just a few seconds. Now it settled into simmering anger with a touch of manic obsessive.

Do you think he loves her?

Virgo mentally rolled his eyes.

I feel bad for him.

I feel, Virgo thought, that he has a weakness.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Hi, Ginny.”

“Hey, Harry.” Ginny plopped herself down next to him. “So nice of you to save a seat for me.”

“Only the best for our new seeker.”

Ginny grinned impishly at him.

On the other side of the table, Captain Flint’s head shot up. He gave Ginny a look that said, “Over my dead body,” and opened his mouth, presumably to say as much.

“Boys and Girls!” The whole hall quietened. Flint reluctantly shut his mouth. The last first year sat down at the Ravenclaw table and Headmaster Gilderoy Lockhart’s magically enhanced voice boomed through the room. The huge Lockhart banner behind him flashed them all a wink. “Welcome! To another year at Hogwarts!”

Many of the teenage girls were staring at the Headmaster with dreamy expressions.

“Unfortunately, Headmaster Dumbledore decided to no longer be with us, but fear not! For I, Gilderoy Lockhart! Order of Merlin Third Class, honorary member of the Dark Force Defence League, and five times winner of Witch Weekly’s most charming smile award, have boldly stepped into the breach!”

Snape looked like he wanted to strangle something. Lily Potter didn’t seem to notice this as she warmly smiled across the packed students.

“Unity and solidarity! That’s the important thing! We are all students here, yes, even me! I know it might seem incredible that someone as well known and famous as me needs to learn, but it’s true, you know. And I know that we sometimes have our little squabbles,”—his eyes roved between John Potter and Draco Malfoy before finishing on Daphne—“but I’m sure we can all come together as one big family, learn to happily live together, and get on with what’s really important … learning!”

Face as stoic as a statue, Daphne turned, caught Harry’s eye, and in that instant several thoughts and counter thoughts passed between them with the clarity and rapidity of a mountain stream—mostly along the lines of, “what a twit,” and, “it was necessary,” and, “so long as he knows how to take advice—your advice.”

Lockhart beamed. “Now, I know what you’re all thinking. Why is such a well known and famous best selling author running Hogwarts? But I am a teacher as well as a student! And with you as my students nothing is impossible. Why, there was one time in the Levant …”

This went on for quite some time before Professor McGonagall made a loud coughing noise into the sleeve of her robes.

“What? Oh, yes! Announcements! Now, I know you were all expecting a new face for defence against the dark arts, but I’m afraid you’ll just have to settle for our very own fearsome, Professor Severus Snape!” He winked again. There were more than a few groans from the students and a few of the younger years looked like they might have a panic attack.

“But don’t worry about being left high and dry in potions,” Lockhart continued, “for we have a more than adequate replacement for you all—the beautiful Lady Lily Potter!”

This announcement got a rather more positive response, particularly from the older boys. “Damn, I’d like to have private lessons with her,” Flint muttered, not quite under his breath, before giving Harry a slightly panicky look.

Harry just waved it off.

“The Forbidden Forest is forbidden,” Lockhart continued, still beaming widely. “And while I know some of you might like the idea of me having to rescue you, I urge to you restrain yourselves.”

McGonagall’s face couldn’t look more stony if she’d been petrified.

“And finally, quidditch and duelling tryouts will be in September and November!” Headmaster Lockhart opened his mouth as though to continue speaking, but in that moment, someone’s stomach made an audible rumbling sound.

Lockhart laughed. “But first, the feast, I think, don’t you?” He clapped his hands and food appeared all across the room.

The sounds of cutlery and chatting broke out around the hall.

It wasn’t long before everyone was engaged in their own conversations.

Flint was loudly telling a fellow sixth year how there would never be any girls on the Slytherin quidditch team while he was captain, which a scowling Ginny did her best to ignore.

Daphne, Hermione, and Tracey were whispering between themselves, while Luna continued to read her book.

“Looking forward to duelling, Potter?” asked some random fifth year.

“Maybe, maybe not.” Harry answered in a noncommittal voice.

“Maybe? Why would you not?”

Harry shrugged. In truth, he was seriously considering not bothering with the duelling club this year. It had served its purpose last year—to give him a very public venue to advertise his worth to Magical Britain. Giving Ginny or Luna or even Alex the opportunity to prove themselves might be more worthwhile.

On the other hand … he looked towards the Gryffindor table, to where the diary seemed to be trying to engage a reluctant looking John in conversation. … Denying the enemy opportunities to make themselves look good was also important …

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

After the feast and yet another long winded speech by Lockhart, the first year students all filed out of the great hall, led by their house prefects. “This way, Miss Malfoy,” Percy Weasley called out in a pompous tone of voice.

Virgo soon found himself in front of the portrait of a rather large woman in Gryffindor Tower.

“The password is wattlebird,” the Weasley said, and stepped inside.

Virgo looked around with mild curiosity. He’d never been in the Gryffindor common room before.

“The boys dormitories are on the left, the girls are on the right. Boys are not allowed in the girl’s dormitory. The stairs are trapped. Please make sure you are up early enough for breakfast before classes.”

You’re not really going to sleep in the girls dormitory, are you? Julia thought.

Why not? Virgo thought back, heading for the stairs.

You’re a boy!

Virgo rolled his eyes and stepped onto the stairs. They shivered. He froze, causing the girl behind him to stop and ask what was going on. Virgo took another tentative step, and the stairs shivered again, but didn’t activate whatever gender based trap they contained. She then quick-climbed up the rest of the stairs, breathing rather more heavily than usual when she reached the top.

Clearly I am female, he thought, and felt Julia sniff in disapproval.

“You’re weird,” the girl said when she’d caught up.

Virgo didn’t say anything as he ducked into the first year girls dormitory, closed the curtains around his four poster, and started getting undressed for bed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Far below in the dungeons, Alexandra walked into the Slytherin first year girls’ dormitory. The beds were arranged in a circle with a large pillar in the middle. The pillar had stone snakes curling up it. She quickly claimed the bed closest to the massive underwater window and started unpacking her trunk, beginning with Amethyst—the violet-eyed cat Luna had once given her for her birthday.

Behind her, Alex heard a giggle. She turned.

Flora and Hestia Carrow had claimed the beds directly on either side of her, while Luna and Ginny had taken the beds on the other side of the room.

Alex tried to identify who had laughed, but everyone wore carefully blank faces—everyone except for Luna of course, but casual dreaminess practically was her blank face. She turned back to her trunk and withdrew her nightdress.

Someone giggled again. It sounded creepy. It had an edge.

Alex didn’t turn around immediately this time. She carefully laid the nightdress on the bed, then looked around.

Hestia was using her wand to fluff her pillow … with stinging hexes.

The almost invisible spells beat against the pillow like a drum. Alex didn’t take her eyes off the wand tip. She could feel the magical intent pulsing across her skin with each tiny magical build up. Her lessons with Luna to master spell swatting her progressed quite far, even if she hadn’t fully grasped the skill yet.

Yet again, someone behind her giggled.

Alex didn’t turn around. Instead, she eased her wand out of her wand holster and let it slide down into the palm of her hand.

Behind her, the voice of Flora Carrow said, “Heir Malfoy isn’t very happy with you, Black.”

Alex’s heart sped up. Oh, wow. This was actually happening. Her eyes flicked over to Luna and Ginny. They both watched with feigned disinterest, although she thought Ginny’s hands looked a bit twitchy.

“There’s a pecking order in the Dark, Black,” Hestia said, now stroking her wand the way someone might stroke the edge of a blade.

Luna flashed Alex an encouraging smile, so brief she almost thought she’d imagined it.

Alex let out the tiniest of snorts. “That’s Heiress Black to you two. You should practise what you preach.”

Behind her, Flora giggled again. “Respect is only for those who earn it, Black. Your father has done much to undermine the pureblood cause.”

“I am not my father. And I will not grovel to anyone weaker than me, no matter who his father may be.”

“You think yourself stronger than Heir Malfoy?” Hestia giggled. The giggle exactly matched her sister’s. “That’s cute.”

“We’ve known Draco all our lives,” Flora said. Alex still had her back to her. “He’s had private tutors since he was five.”

“He knows more curses, hexes, and jinxes than most seventh years,” Hestia added.

Alex sniffed. “And yet, he leaves chatting with me to you two.”

“Of course,” Flora said. “After all, he might wish to court you one day—hexing you personally would be terribly bad form.”

“That’s messed up.”

Hestia shrugged, and in the moment between her shoulders rising and falling, Alex felt a jelly-legs jinx forming behind her. It was the work of a moment to throw a shield behind her, leap over the bed towards a startled Hestia—who didn’t even her wand ready—grab her by the arms, spin her around with ritual enhanced strength, pin her arms behind her back with one hand, and fire a stunner at Flora with the other. Flora crumpled, unconscious, onto her bed.

“Nyah!” Hestia struggled. Her wand fell to the floor with a clatter. “Let me go!”

“Sure, once I’ve tied you up.”

“You’ll regret this!” Hestia’s voice carried a hint of panic. “We all sleep here! You can’t be ready all the time.”

“There’s a pecking order in the Dark—that’s what you said, Carrow. I am merely showing you where I am in it.”

“When word of this gets out, you’ll be sorry!”

“Maybe,” Alex said, now clearly amused. It had been so easy. She pushed Hestia onto the girl’s bed and straddled the back of her lower waist, paying no attention to the way the girl uselessly tried to wriggle away. “But always remember that you have to live in here with me.”

“Flora and I watch each other’s backs!”

“Didn’t help much this time, did it?”

Hestia said nothing.

“But you know,” Alex continued. “I can certainly see the value in such teamwork. You two will be of great use to me.”

The hint of panic became a general tremor. “We’re not helping you.”

“No?” Alex leaned over to whisper into Hestia’s ear. “I promise I’ll take care of you—you and your cute twin sister.”

Hestia was silent for a moment. Then, in an almost grumpy tone of voice she said, “You don’t have balls nearly large enough to take on the rest of the Dark. Not like this.”

Alex smirked. “I think a good hour of tickling will have you seeing things quite differently.”

Hestia eyes widened in fear. “You can’t use the tickling hex that long! You’ll get in big trouble!”

Alex giggled. “Who said anything about any hex?”

And as the sounds of forced laughs, shrieks, and unheeded begging filled the room, Ginny and Luna finished changing, charming their teeth, and doing whatever else they needed to do to get ready for their first full day at Hogwarts.

Ginny climbed into her four poster, sat her stuffed dragon teddy bear by her pillow, and cast a basic protective ward around her bed. “Pretty brutal, these Dark witches,” she commented.

Luna smiled. “I’m sure they’re okay once you get to know them.”

Ginny grinned, weaved a third year silencing charm around herself, and the high-pitched squeals abruptly cut out, leaving only peaceful, relaxing quiet.

—End of Chapter Thirty-Seven—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s value.

Sticky Note: As always, if you want to stay up to date on schedule changes and other bonuses before anyone else, you can get them on my mailing list, which you can find by following the breadcrumb trail through my profile page.

The Little Trials of Virgo Malfoy

In every large building where people live and work in close proximity, there are always crossroads that conspire to draw together people who’d much rather keep their distance—teachers and students, upper years and lower years, rival quidditch teams, even the occasional ‘I’m-never-talking to-you-ever-again’ situation involving two people of the opposite sex who will nevertheless soon be found together, in a broom cupboard, wearing between them rather less than the regulation amount of clothing for just one of them.

The Hogwarts owlery is just such a crossroad. Most everyone needs to send letters and the morning of the first day of school is always particularly busy.

Holding a sealed letter in one hand, Virgo Malfoy stepped aside for yet another pair of students descending the long set of stairs that he was busy ascending. Annoying, he thought. By the time he’d put himself into the diary, fifty years ago, people had been stepping aside for him.

The soul of Julia did the mental equivalent of tiredly rolling her eyes, then went back to sleep. The girl had settled down a bit since leaving Malfoy Manor, but not by nearly enough for his liking.

Last night had been a good example. He’d been sitting in his scarlet and gold four poster bed, busily planning how he was going to attack the problem of Harry Potter and Lord Slytherin, when she’d kicked up an almighty fuss over a stray murderous fantasy. They’d argued about it for ages before he’d eventually managed to persuade her that wanting to find out more about someone who wanted to kill you wasn’t evil just by itself.

So that was his plan, find out about Harry Potter. And for that he needed John Potter. The Heir of the Potter family was the key, of that he was sure.

Another two sets of footsteps approached down the spiral staircase above him. Virgo almost considered just holding his ground and demanding they get out of his way, until he saw it was Professor Severus Snape and Lady Lilly Potter. Maybe not then. He stepped aside. Snape’s sharp eye caught Virgo’s as they passed and he felt the lightest of light touches brush against his occlumency barriers.

Traitor.

He made his way up the rest of the stairs and pushed the door open. The owlery was still bustling, even this close to breakfast. Almost a dozen students from all houses and ages were busy tying envelopes to the various birds that flocked around the room, or else finishing off their letters at the small, crap covered, central table.

Virgo quickly spotted the large screech owl his new adopted father had bought him and called it down. It alighted on the edge of one of the windows next to another owl being attended to by a girl in his year—a girl wearing radish earrings, dirty blond hair, and expensive, Slytherin green robes. Heiress Lovegood. Future consort of Lord Slytherin.

Perfect.

Virgo took a length of string from the ball on the table and stepped over beside her. “Good morning. I don’t believe we’ve been introduced.”

Lovegood looked up. She smiled. “Good morning. You are correct. I am Heiress Luna Lovegood. You are Miss Virgo Malfoy.” She went back to her bird.

“I am.” Virgo carefully watched the other girl humming quietly to herself as she stroked her owl’s feathers. She needed some point of common ground. Something of an in. “I don’t suppose I could ask your advise, could I?”

“You may.”

“How do you handle it? Being betrothed, I mean. What’s Lord Slytherin like? I know my father could choose to contract me if he so chooses. It scares me.” Not really, of-course. Lord Malfoy wouldn’t dare, but there wasn’t any need for anyone to know that.

Lovegood continued to stroke the owl’s feathers while looking thoughtful. Then she looked Virgo straight in the eyes and smiled kindly. “The best way is to just accept it. You are the daughter of a noble house and that comes with certain responsibilities and obligations.”

Virgo nodded.

“And that means,” Lovegood continued, “that you are a future lord’s fuck toy.”

Virgo’s nodding froze.

Julia’s soul went from sleepiness to full wakefulness in less than a second. Wha—?

“It means that boys are soon going to start trying to get into your knickers, regardless of what you want, and eventually one will succeed in sticking his penis into your vagina—” she pointed at Virgo’s crotch “—and making little wizard babies grow in your tummy.”

Lovegood smiled widely as though she’d just delivered some profound ancient wisdom.

What—the—hell?!

Virgo’s eyebrow twitched. He stared at the girl for a few seconds longer before answering. “Is that what you want? With Lord Slytherin?”

“Oh, yes!” Lovegood titled her head to the side. “Why? Are you interested? Would you like Lord Slytherin to stick his penis in your vagina?”

Around the owlery, more than one of the other students were listening in with a kind of horrified fascination.

“No, I’m fine, thanks,” Virgo ground out.

“Oh.” Lovegood went back to her owl and finished tying her letter to its leg. “Are you sure? If you don’t find a cute boy to fuck you, you might end up with some old wizard who can’t even get up the strength to give you a proper spanking.”

A Hufflepuff fifth year dropped his quill.

“Spanking,” Virgo said, each word careful and deliberate, “is not required for the procreation of the wizarding race.”

Lovegood’s owl leapt off the window’s balcony.

“Of course it is, silly,” Lovegood chirped. “I said it before—you have to accept your inevitable fuck-toyness.” She walked over to the other side of the room and waved cheerfully. If you ever change your mind, just let me know. I’m sure I can persuade my lord to find a collar for you somewhere.” She left.

Virgo paid no attention to the cacophony of whispers that immediately broke out around him, nor to the unbelieving rant Julia was kicking up in his head. Instead, he fought down the urge to go heiress hunting with a rusty breadknife, added a quick postscript to his owl, and sent it on its way.

Father,

I have been sorted into Gryffindor. My remote observations of H confirm my beliefs that he is not the one I am looking for, which makes S’s involvement with him all the more worrisome. J is intelligent, but hides his emotions poorly. Despite not being who you thought, I continue to suspect there is more to both of them than meets the eye. My immediate plans are to befriend J and gain his confidence.

Withdraw all support from S immediately.

- Virgo

P.S. Have mother send me any books you might have on the magical limitations of Albion Family Magic betrothal contracts, particularly as they relate to the mind control of those who already possess noble house rings. If Lord Slytherin approaches you with any offer of betrothal you are to inform me immediately. If you do not, you will have an extremely displeased ‘daughter’ on your hands.

There. Virgo brushed his hands clean. Now it was breakfast time. John Potter would be there. It was time to get to work.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the Great Hall, breakfast was in full swing. Harry sat at the Slytherin table and watched Hedwig swoop down to the Gryffindor table. In one talon she held the small note Harry had written not thirty minutes earlier.

J,

Virgo is the D,

H.

John took the note, read it, met Harry’s eyes across the room, snorted, shook his head in what could only be described as a condescending manner, and tore it up.

Harry sniffed. Well, he had warned him. No one could say he hadn’t. He tore his gaze away from the inevitable train wreck just in time to see the Carrow twins bend down to whisper something in Draco’s ear. They did not look happy.

A few moments later, Alexandra sat down a few seats away from Draco and nonchalantly started spreading jam on her toast. The Carrow twins stared daggers at her while Draco looked pensieve.

Interesting.

“Morning, Harry.” A rather chipper Ginny sat down beside him, slightly red in the face and breathing deeply. She wore her gym clothes and had her hair tied up in a ponytail.

“Morning, Ginny. So, what happened last night?”

Ginny lowered her voice. “The Carrows tried to hex Alex. Didn’t work out very well for them.”

“I bet it didn’t. I hope she didn’t use anything too bad.”

“No—just a stunner, bindings, and non magic tickling.”

“Good.” He looked up. “And good morning to you too, Hermione.”

Hermione had appeared on the other side of the table lugging two huge magical tomes and one smaller muggle book, quite apart from her usual school bag. Unlike Ginny, she was already dressed in her black, green, and silver school robes. “Good Morning, Harry.” She sat down opposite him and proceeded to open and strategically prop up the books around her, creating a mini fort of learning—Rapid Healer Diagnostics - Fifth Edition, Niche Mind Arts You Never Knew you Needed, and Storming the Gates - Managing Revolutionary Groups in Times of Change.

Ginny leaned closer to him again. “Quidditch trials are next week. What are we going to do about Flint and the Quidditch team?”

“Don’t worry about it. I’ll handle him when the time comes.”

“Oh?” Daphne sat down at the head of the table. There was a ripple as the two-dozen-ish children of the Gray momentary switched their attention to her. “You know Draco has wanted to be seeker for years.”

“That is unfortunate for him.”

Apparently satisfied that no earth shattering pronouncements were to be made, the assorted students slowly went back to their breakfasts.

Daphne lowered her voice and leaned closer to Harry. “What are we planning to do about Angelystor?” Angelystor was the ghost Harry had brought to Hogwarts the previous year to teach the girls the lost magic of divination. “Will I continue my studies with her?”

“Yes, soon, but I also want to bring the others—see if any of them might also have the knack.”

“Knack?” Luna leaned over Harry’s shoulder.

“The inner-eye, Luna.”

“Ooooh. We Lovegoods are well known for that—and Mum is a Lovegood and a Vablatsky.”

“You have one?”

“I don’t know. I’ve never tried. I guess I won’t know until I do.”

“Wouldn’t shock me,” Ginny muttered. Then she brightened and poked Harry playfully in the ribs. “We could win money betting on how much we’re going to win the Quidditch Cup by.”

Harry snorted and continued to eat his breakfast. On the other side of the hall, Virgo was now trying to talk to John—unsuccessfully by the look of it. John may not believe that Virgo was the diary, but it seemed he still didn’t like the fact that she was a Malfoy.

“See you at lunch, Harry!” Ginny waved as she and Luna finished their breakfast and made their way to their first class. Harry waved back before he, Daphne, and Hermione, made their way to their first class—double History of Magic.

Binns hadn’t gotten any more interesting since either last year or fifty years ago when Tom Riddle attended Hogwarts. Both the Slytherins and the Ravenclaws had long ago started treating History of Magic as a free sleep session. All except Hermione of course, whose note taking was as neat as her listening was careful—but Hermione was just awesome like that.

The bell for Lunch rang and Harry happily packed up, then followed Daphne down to the great hall. This time, Virgo seemed to be trying to make nice with Seamus Finnigan, while having about as much success as last time.

“What’s it doing?” Hermione asked.

Harry shrugged. “Trying to build a power base, I’d guess.”

Hermione frowned. “I don’t like it.”

“Neither. Although I have my doubts about its ability to keep a cool enough head to make any progress—given what Gryffindors tend to do to those they don’t like.”

“Won’t that be dangerous?”

“Possibly.”

But regardless of what Harry felt about the potential dangers of a Gryffindor Tom Riddle, he had to accept there wasn’t much he could do until he’d moved events along some more. Charms that afternoon had them working on arresto momentum, a spell that Daphne and Hermione had both mastered before the Winter Festival the previous year.

“Oh, well done! Miss Granger—Miss Greengrass—two points each to Slytherin.” Professor Flitwick beamed at the two girls. “Oh, yes, you too, John Potter—Two points to Gryffindor.”

It wasn’t until he got back to the Slytherin common room—when Harry was able to sit down with Daphne in the small group of sofas and chairs that made up the court of the Gray, next to the large, and currently empty, snake-decorated throne he’d placed the year before—that he was able to start on the real work of the day.

On the other side of the snake-like throne, sat the Dark, presiding over their own little court. Alex had dragged over a large chair of her own and wedged it in-between two of the sofas—something Pansy in particular seemed to have taken offence at, judging by the way she sniffed and folded her arms every-time she glanced at her.

After several hours, Harry finished up the last piece of parchment work for the night and made his way up to bed. There, he put on his pyjamas, climbed into bed, and as he drifted off, focused his occlumency on a point, some four metres below and twenty metres off to the right—to wear Ginny was already asleep, wearing the dreamscape necklace.

Harry connected and the dreamworld opened up to him.

He appeared in a jungle clearing. A massive Mesoamerican pyramid stood behind him.

“Harry!” Ginny leapt and wrapped her arms around him. She was dressed in her nightdress and still held her fluffy dragon teddy bear in one hand. “Transfiguration was awesome!”

Harry grinned. “Good to hear it.”

Ginny let go of him and danced backwards, whipped out the dream version of her wand and pointed it at the floor. “After all those boring notes, it was just like, haha! I have a nail, and now it’s a spoon! Bam!”

A stone on the floor turned into a wooden spoon.

“And then Professor McGonagall was all like, ‘I am raising my eyebrow at you, Miss Weasley’—and then I’m like, Bam! Spoon into nail, then Bam! Nail into spoon! Bam! Bam! Bam!—And then she’s like, ‘carry on, Miss Weasley.’ Hah! I’m sooo glad we spent sooo much time on our occlumency now. This is easy!”

Harry smiled. “Excellent. You ready to move onto some more serious work?”

“Hell yeah!”

“Okay.” Harry waved his hand and the dirt ground was replaced with castle flagstones. Ginny’s nightdress turned into duelling robes. Her teddybear floated off to one side. “I’m going to do my best to limit myself to the spells, skill, tactics, and physical capabilities of the diary. You are going to try and kill me.”

“Right.” Ginny jumped into her duelling stance.

Harry conjured a handkerchief, let it fall halfway to the ground, then opened up with a sudden barrage of basic curses.

Ginny didn’t bat an eyelash. She swatted them back and countered with a chain of stunners, stingers, and cutting spells.

What followed was a lesson in how a fight evolves when one side realises the other can counter their basic repertoire. Harry’s spells quickly turned from point and shoot to controlled transfiguration. Ginny’s counters changed into physical shields and dodging.

The final exchange of the match came quickly after that. Harry conjured a dagger and sent it sailing straight at Ginny, who caught it in a shield, grabbed it by the handle, and sent it flying back at Harry, hiding a switching spell in the dagger’s shadow. Harry shielded against the dagger, but the switching spell sailed on through and hit a rock just behind Harry. Ginny switched position with the rock, and a split second later, Harry had a wand jabbing him in the side and a triumphal Ginny smirking at him. “I win.”

“Yes, you do. Now tell me what you’ve learned.”

Ginny looked to think. “The diary adapts. It saw that it couldn’t get to me with direct spells so it started using indirect ones, instead.”

“Yep, anything else?”

“It’s more powerful than me.”

“It is. Riddle is older than you, his skill may be that of a sixteen year old, but that soul piece is still nearly seventy years old. This is countered by the fact that he only has a slice of his soul. What else?”

Ginny looked blank.

“It’s okay. You wouldn’t have been able to pick up on it in that short exchange. Here’s the thing—you are far fitter than Riddle is. I don’t know much about this muggleborn that the diary consumed to get this new body, but I’m willing to bet that they weren’t nearly as physically active as you, and we know that they weren’t as magically active. If your fight should ever go beyond, say, fifteen minutes, you will easily have the advantage. She’ll start suffering from magical exhaustion. You’ll still have plenty of fight left in you.”

Ginny nodded. “Makes sense.”

“But your fight shouldn’t last anywhere near that long. Just something to keep in mind.” Harry readied his wand again. “Ready?”

“Y—”

Harry attacked.

Three hours later, Ginny stood with her wand pointed at Harry’s head … again. She’d won every single exchange, even the ones in which Harry said he’d really push what the diary was capable of. She smirked. “I guess I’m more than ready.”

Harry smiled. “Yes. As much as I’m loath to send you into real danger—yes, you are now fully capable of defeating the diary.”

She flipped her pony-tail over her shoulder. “I’ll have this all wrapped up as soon as you get those portkeys.”

Harry frowned. “Remember not to get too overconfident. Look at what’s happening with John.”

“What is happening with John?”

“I sent him a warning about Virgo being the diary, but for some reason, he doesn’t believe it.”

Ginny scoffed. “What a dumbass. He’s been a nightmare. He still won’t shut up about saving me from you.”

“I dunno.” Harry grinned. “I can be quite devious.”

Ginny grinned back. “Yes, I know. That’s what I like.”

“Good, because I do have one more preparation task for you.”

“Oh?”

“Yes.” Harry took something out of his robes and handed it to Ginny. It was a dagger.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The morning sun was rising up over the trees of the forbidden forest. Virgo sat by the window next to his bed in Gryffindor Tower. Down on the grounds, the Slytherin Weasley, Ginevra, was running clockwise around the Black Lake. She wore what looked like muggle exercise clothes. On the other side, John Potter was running anti-clockwise.

Virgo had tried to talk to some of the people she’d identified as being close to John yesterday, with little success. Ginevra’s older brother, Ronald, had gone so far as to blame her for his sister not being in Gryffindor. “You took the last Gryffindor girl slot,” he’d said.

It wasn’t actually a bad point. Each house took exactly five girls and five boys. Considering that Weasley was so close to the end of the alphabet, it was amazing they’d all ended up in Gryffindor so far, but then, Virgo didn’t know much about how the sorting hat algorithm worked.

Virgo continued to watch as John Potter ran into Ginevra Weasley about half way around the lake and proceeded to have a visibly large argument with her. Most people wouldn’t have been able to see so far from so high up, but Virgo wasn’t most people. The argument only ended when Ginevra turned her back on him and ran away at a speed that was, quite frankly, scarily impressive. John didn’t look pleased about this.

Virgo filed this away for future consideration, and stepped towards the showers. As the water washed over him, he reflected on his dorm-mates. They’d been standoffish and mildly scornful since his sorting. He wished he could put them in their place, but that would not endear him to his target. After drying off, he wrapped the towel around him and walked back into the dorm to get dressed. His fellow dorm-mates were only now just getting up.

It didn’t take more than a few moments to realise something wasn’t right. He sorted through his carefully folded clothes and frowned. All his underwear was missing. Could the house-elves have taken it by mistake? No. That was about a likely as them accidentally confusing sugar and rat poison.

Somewhere in the room, a young, female voice sniggered.

Virgo narrowed his eyes. “Accio underwear.”

Four cries of alarm issues from four throats as a several dozen sets of underthings shot across the room from inside trunks and on beds. Virgo calmly picked up his own pilfered underwear from the pile and banished the rest back into the middle of the room.

The four girls glared at him.

“Then don’t steal my things,” he said, as fiercely as an eleven year old girl could, and was about to add, ‘Or I will kill you,’ when Julia shouted at him in his mind to stop. He snapped his mouth shut and instead started getting dressed.

The other Gryffindor first-years traded looks among each other before going back to ignoring him.

You can’t threaten to kill them! Julia thought.

You’re right, Virgo thought back. I must be patient. I can punish them when they are eventually bowed before me in abject terror.

That’s not what I meant!

Virgo smirked.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Hermione glided into the defence classroom, carefully putting away her breakfast reading, even as she slid into her seat beside Daphne and took out her copy of Basic Defence Against the Dark Arts. At the front of the room, Snape had arranged several of the more disgusting specimens in jars from his former potions dungeon. Hermione wondered about the man’s loyalty. Could they ever trust a man who claimed to be a triple agent, twice over, for three separate sides? Almost certainly not. He was, without a doubt, out for just himself. Hermione wrinkled her nose. Not like herself. She was Harry’s most hard-working, most dedicated student—and even if the likes of Ginny or Luna might be stronger than her, she’d never give up the title of most loyal. Behind her, Draco spoke with Theodore Nott in a low voice. She caught the whispered name, “Alexandra,” and made a mental note to inform Harry as soon as possible.

At that moment, Snape barged into the room, swept down the middle aisle, reached the front, and whirred around to face them all. “Magic,” Snape said, “is an ever changing, ever growing beast.”

Every student watched him in utter silence as the opening speech started.

“The more wizards use a spell, the easier it becomes, like a muscle growing to lift heavier and heavier prey. The first spell takes power, will, concentration, and purpose, so great as to exclude all the but the most capable. The second spell takes less. The third less still. A thousand years later, even a child can manage a basic lumos. Such is the need for light—a need that has stayed unchanged for the better part of human existence, as sure as the darkness of night itself.”

He paused and looked around the room.

“But there are other needs that humanity has—far less wholesome needs. When the world turns against you, and the dark mist of rage descends, it is the need to hurt, to maim, to control, and to kill, that gives magic its form. These are the Dark Arts—varied, ever-changing, and eternal. Fighting them is like fighting a many-headed monster, which, each time a neck is severed, sprouts a head even fiercer and cleverer than before. And when magic attacks with intent to destroy, there is no need greater than to fight against that magic—to protect and to heal.”

“This is the struggle between dark magic and light magic, separate from any political ramblings or ideological banner waving—a magical arms race, which it is now my solemn duty to induct you into.”

As much as she hated Snape, Hermione had to admit that he certainly knew how to give a speech. The class then split up into pairs to practise the disarming charm.

“Oh no, I don’t think so,” Snape bit out, striding over to where Harry and John had been ready to square off against each other. “I still want some classroom left at the end.”

Daphne nodded to where Hermione now stood off to one side. “Ready?”

Hermione bent her knees into her duelling position. “Ready.”

Five disarming spell exchanges later, Hermione succeeded in ripping Daphne’s wand from her hand.

Daphne scowled. “Again.”

Hermione smirked. “Yes, my lady.”

At the end of the class, Snape waved them all back into their seats. Hermione was sweating, but satisfied. She’d managed to handedly defend her position as top witch of their year against a now moderately sulking Daphne. As they left the classroom for lunch, she nudged Hermione in the ribs. “Enjoy it while you can, Vassal. We’ll be training with the rest of the girls soon.”

Daphne’s sulk didn’t last long. She perked back up not long into lunch when Harry whispered to them both that they’d be starting back on divination in the next few weeks, and that Lord Slytherin had a meeting with Lockhart that evening. It would be the perfect opportunity for him to arrange the portkeys for Ginny and Luna before the Hogwarts board meeting on Wednesday.

They had a free period after lunch. Hermione met up with Tracey and together they made their way to the empty classroom that had become the unofficial muggleborn common-room. Harry joined them not long after and together they worked on homework, house work, and prepared for the first founders’ club meeting of the year, until the final class ended, and a small swarm of their class-mates arrived.

Every one of the new muggleborns had shown-up, along with the ones from their year, and even some of the older ones, as well. While Hermione got the pensieve and portrait ready, the Chesterfield twins—Violet and Marigold—happily chatted away with Alan Gage and Kevin’s sister, Annabel. Interestingly—with the exception of Colin Creevey, who’d enthusiastically barged into the room just in front of Dean Thomas—every one of the new muggleborns had been sorted into Hufflepuff.

Once the portrait of Elizabeth Greengrass, Daphne’s Grandmother, indicated she was ready, the first years all crowded around to listen to her rather more in-depth introduction to the magical world while the second years worked together on their occlumency.

“How am I, Hermione?”

Hermione slowly withdrew from Sophie Roper’s rather basic mind-scape. “Not bad,” she answered. “You should be ready to start on wandless magic before Winter Festival.”

Sophie beamed. “Brilliant! I’m already doing much better in classes. I’m so glad you’re helping us.”

“It’s Lord Slytherin you should thank, Sophie.”

“Well, thank him from me again next time you see him, but you should remember to give yourself some credit too.” Sophie smiled.

Hermione’s eyes explicitly did not flicker over to where Harry was explaining the finer points of how to effectively use the cutting charm against an armed opponent to Justin Finch-Fletchley. “I will make sure to do that,” she said. “And thank you—I do try.”

After all, Hermione added to herself, she was Harry’s most loyal student, and that was certainly credit worthy of taking.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

There was still a good few hours of sunlight outside as Virgo made his way up the stairs to Gryffindor Tower. It still felt weird to head this direction rather than to the dungeons after class. He’d had to catch himself going in the wrong direction more than once. It wouldn’t be any good getting caught doing that. He was already disliked by just about every one of his classmates. Only Colin Creevey didn’t seem hellbent on ignoring him, ironically, but that had turned to be more of a curse than a blessing.

Oh come on,thought the soul of Julia, he’s not that bad.

Virgo didn’t dignify that with a response. He instead merely projected his utter disbelief towards the girl.

Well, okay, he’s a bit loud, but that’s no reason to hate someone.

Virgo sniffed. It wasn’t an issue at the moment at least. Creevey had run off with some older boy the moment classes had finished. But it still didn’t change the fact that he’d made no good progress in making inroads into John Potter’s circle.

“Password?” asked the fat woman in the portrait.

“Wattlebird.”

The portrait swung aside, Virgo stepped inside, and a gallon of something heavy, viscous, and sticky splashed all over him.

Shock. He hadn’t sensed any magic. It had come out of nowhere.

Yeugh! This stuff is horrible!

Laughter. All around the common room, several dozen students were falling over themselves on sofas and armchairs as she stood there, dripping, in what turned out to be diluted honey.

We’re going to need to get clean now.

The laughter burned his ears, and it didn’t stop. Anger flowed through him. This was too much. He would not stand for this! He took one gooey step forward, wand held tightly in hand. He’d show them all what it meant to fuck with—

Holy crap! Calm down!Julia’s thoughts felt panicky.

Calm down? Calm down! Look at them!

What are you going to do?! Curse someone in front of everyone?! Look at John!

Virgo hesitated and glanced around until he found the face of John Potter who was watching with a small smirk from among his group of followers and closed his eyes and took a deep breath. The girl was right.

See?

He needed to plan around this. It wasn’t any different to his first few years in Slytherin—not even as bad, actually. He’d just gotten used to having everyone’s fear and respect. Plan first. Act second. Revenge third.

No, that’s …

And so, with the continued laughter of the Gryffindor common room ringing in his ears, Virgo made his way to the girl’s dormitory with as much dignity as he could, each ascending sticky step causing the stairs to shiver.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In a long, ornate room, twelve wizards sat around a table, almost as long and equality as ornate as the room it sat in. A large green eyeball floated above the table, invisible to all except the masked figure of Lord Slytherin. The eyeball zipped around the room casually inspecting secret papers and notes, even as their owners held them close to their chests, or shielded them behind obscuring charms.

Headmaster Gilderoy Lockhart was just finishing up his analysis of the previous year that was in no way influenced by the masked lord sat half way down the table. He preened. “… And so, I, Gilderoy Lockhart, after a great deal of thought, have found the perfect solution to these pressing security concerns! Behold!” He whipped out three small boxes from under the table. “Special VIP portkeys!”

There was a murmur of faint surprise up and down the table.

“Yes!” Lockhart beamed. “The wards give me, Gilderoy Lockhart, the Headmaster, special permission to create exactly six portkeys, and I’m gifting these to you. These one time use necklaces are charmed to take their wearer straight to the hospital wing.” He winked as he passed the boxes to Lords Malfoy, Potter, and Slytherin. “I set the activation word to Darksafe, Lightsafe, and Graysafe. I’m sure you can guess who has which boxes.”

Lord Potter opened his box and drew out two small metal spheres, each about the size of a marble, and each hanging on the end of twin gold chains. He handed one to Lord Sirius Black who started waving diagnostic charms over it.

Lord Slytherin pocketed his box.

Lord Malfoy left his box untouched, instead leaning back slightly in his chair. “Well done, Headmaster.” He looked up at Gilderoy. “I must admit, I was not expecting you to adjust to the job quite so quickly.” Left unsaid was the general view that most of the room hadn’t expected the man to adjust to the job at all.

The chairman, Ambrosius Flume stood up. “Thank you, Headmaster, you may now take an observer seat.”

Lockhart flashed a smile, sat down on one of the hardback chairs by the wall, pulled out a stack of what looked suspiciously like fan mail, and started going through it.

Flume continued. “We will now carry on the matter of reallocating all current and future muggleborn guardianships from the Headmaster to Lord Slytherin. You all have copies of the proposal. Would anyone like to make any comments before we move to a vote?”

“Yes,” Lord Potter said in a firm tone. Resolutions at the last two board meetings had been passed in favour of the current Dark/Gray alliance and it obviously scraped on his nerves. “I still don’t see why we are even bothering with this. There is no good reason to give him,”—he jerked his finger towards the impassive form of Slytherin—“guardianship of anyone, let alone a group of young, impressionable children!”

“The proper protocols have been followed, Lord Potter.”

“He’s obviously up to no good!” Lord Potter waved his hand desperately. “It’s moustache twirlingly obvious!”

“Nevertheless—if there are no further comments? Lord Slytherin?”

Slytherin shook his head “I think everything that needs to be said has already been said.”

Lord Potter scowled.

Lord Malfoy kept his face utterly blank. He instead fingered the small, still unopened portkey box in front of him, gently turning it around and around on the polished wooden tabletop.

“Well then, all those in favour of the motion?”

Four hands rose—Lord Slytherin, Lord Greengrass, Lord Woodcroft, and Lord Smith—Four out of Eleven.

James Potter shot the still blank looking Lucius Malfoy and Lord Parkinson a startled look, while the still mostly unseen eyeball zipped over to aggressively inspect the two Lords of the Dark faction.

Lord Slytherin’s expression was, of course, hidden under his mask.

“And against?”

All the other hands rose.

“Four to five, the motion is rejected …” Flume shuffled his parchment in front of him. Around the room, the assembled wizards could practically feel the alliances shifting, yet again, for whatever reason.

“Let’s move onto other business—item four—the ministry is requesting a general audit of Hogwarts’s finances …”

The meeting continued on. The edge of Lord Malfoy’s lips tugged upwards slightly as though relaxing a long held tension. He stopped his slow spinning of the portkey box beneath his fingers, facing the lid so it would open outwards, and lifted the lid. “What is this!”

Lord Blott paused in the giving of his opinion of just where the minister’s undersecretary could stick her audit request. “What?”

“Is there a problem, Lord Malfoy?” Flume asked.

“There are no portkeys in my box!”

There was a murmur around the room. Several Lords around Malfoy leaned in and confirmed that there were indeed no portkeys. Everyone turned to the Headmaster.

“Whaaaaatttttt?” Lockhart had stood up looking flustered. “No, that can’t be. I put them in there!” He walked over and started at the empty box. “But I did!”

“Stolen?” Slytherin asked.

Lord Malfoy snarled. “I want replacements.”

“But … but … I can only make six!” Lockhart wailed.

“Out of the way there!” Lord Black had moved around the table to the small crowd gathering around Malfoy. “If this is theft, then that’s my responsibility as Chief Auror—and what’s this?”

He flicked his wand at something caught on the edge of the box. A tiny hair levitated out and, seconds later, Lord Black had it wrapped in a small conjured bag.

“I was fiddling with it for several minutes,” Malfoy said, rather defensively.

Lord Black grinned back. “No worries there, Lucy. I’m sure it all checks out.”

Lucius looked rather put out. “I demand all the portkeys returned!”

“Why?” asked Lord Hawking. “If you can’t have them then no one can? Stop being childish.”

“This is an outrage!”

Lord Slytherin snorted. “I’m more worried that someone unknown now seems to have two instant access portkeys to the Hogwarts hospital wing.”

There was a silence around the table.

“Umm … never fear!” Lockhart said, although his confidence seemed shaken. “We will just have to … err … increase security—yes, that’s what.”

The assembled wizards looked at him with half-lidded eyes. “Yes, Headmaster,” said Lord Blott. “You do that.”

It was an even more cautious meeting after that. Members kept giving each other suspicious looks. Several agenda items and a couple of rejected resolutions later, the meeting closed up. Not long after, Lord Slytherin ducked into an empty class-room, threw up a few privacy charms, withdrew his shrunk trunk, opened it up, and climbed inside.

“No luck then.” Daphne sat in one of the armchairs in the middle of the trunk with her eyes shut. The large floating eyeball swivelled around to look at him before it winked out of existence. Daphne opened her eyes.

“No.” Harry pulled off his mask and started undoing all the charms and transfiguration on his person. “It was probably Virgo. She must have realised I’m not Voldemort and tipped Malfoy off.”

“So now what are we going to do?”

Harry dropped into the armchair opposite Daphne as he shrunk back to his real biological age. “We’ll keep looking for opportunities to get more board members on our side. In the meantime we can still get some of the guardianships, if we persuade both the parents and the headmaster to sign off on it.”

“Should be easy on Lockhart’s end. That wasn’t your hair on the box, was it?”

“No, it was my father’s.”

Daphne chuckled. “That’ll go down well.”

Harry shrugged. “They won’t be able to pin anything on him with that alone. I’ll cast some concealing spells of my own and hand the portkeys off to Luna and Ginny. You didn’t pick anything of interest up with your eyeball did you?”

“Not during the meeting, but I did get something interesting last night.”

“Oh?”

Daphne nodded. “Draco was writing a letter in bed to Lord Malfoy. He was asking for help in getting some of the Dark families to work with him on ‘putting Alexandra Black in her place.’ Apparently many of the people he spoke with were reluctant to help without approval from their parents first. They probably remember what happened last year.”

“Mmm … well that gives us a breathing spot, but it sounds like we’ll have to speed up our work with Alex, anyway.”

“Yes.” Daphne frowned. “I’m not all that thrilled about keeping her in the dark about all our secrets, you know.”

Harry sighed. “I know. But it’s not like with you and the other girls. I had months working together with Ginny, Hermione, and Luna before I told them, and you and I were already betrothed. Hell, even Tracey accumulated a good chunk of time with me over the last year before she found out. I’ve hardly had any opportunity to spend serious time with Alex.”

“She’s pretty obsessed with Lord Slytherin.”

Harry nodded slowly.

“Soon?”

Harry seemed to think before nodding, this time rather more firmly. “I think that after we’ve gone through helping her survive the smack down from the Dark, we can bring her in.”

Daphne smiled brightly. “Wonderful. And with any luck, the diary won’t be an issue soon either.”

Harry nodded. They cleared up a few other pieces of business and Harry escorted Daphne back to the trapped stairs leading down to the girl’s dormitory before making his way back to his own dormitory to sleep. He’d added the ward that limited the number of portkeys the headmaster could create to six himself. It was the most he could do, but hopefully the most would be enough. He didn’t particularly want Lord Malfoy to get another portkey he could give to the diary, after-all.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was the next day. Classes had come and gone, and the older students had settled back into the normalcy of another school year. Virgo Malfoy marched up the grand staircase towards the seventh floor, a faint anger bubbling through him. The previous evening, his house mates had pranked him, again. Afterwards, he’d pretended to accept the sympathy of the older wizard Colin Creevey had run off with on Monday—a boy called Dean Thomas—another muggleborn. He,the future Lord Voldemort, had been consoled by a muggleborn. It drove him nuts.

And the only progress he’d made towards his goal had been to realise that John spent quite a bit of his time outside classes with the Bones Heiress, Susan. They seemed quite fond of each other. Together with the Slytherin Weasley, they seemed like the most probable way to get an in with John. But first, he had to do something about the rest of the house.

Virgo reached the seventh floor, breathing heavily, and made his way to the tapestry of Barnabas the Barmy, teaching trolls to dance. He walked in front of the tapestry while thinking, I need the room of lost things.

The door opened. The inside was just how he remembered it from fifty years ago. The walls rose on all sides like a cathedral. Beams of light shone through high windows, through the dusty air, and onto massively high shelves.

Woowwww, thought the soul of Julia.

Virgo quickly made his way to the place where he hoped the stuff he’d left here fifty years ago would still be. There was, after-all, no guarantee that his other-self hadn’t already taken it for some other purpose. He stepped in front of the shelf that looked no different from the countless others and nodded in satisfaction. There, among piles of second hand books that must have piled up in the two years after he made the diary, was an old and battered violin case.

Wait, seriously?Julia thought.

You are surprised? Virgo thought back.

Well, yeah.

Virgo picked up the case and opened it. The instrument inside had already been well used when he’d stolen it from one of the older girls at the orphanage one summer.

Can you actually play it?

I can, he thought. There are many similarities between it and a wand—between music and magic. He quickly applied a tuning charm.

The walk to the common room felt longer than normal. The violin was not pleasant to hold. It brought back memories—memories he’d already locked tightly away, tight enough that not even Julia could pick up on them.

“Password?”

“Wattlebird.”

The portrait swung open and Virgo stepped through. This time, the build-up of prank magic was noticeable. He took one more step forward and antlers sprung from his head.

Just like before, laughter rang out through the common room. Those who weren’t doing so openly were hiding their poorly concealed smiles behind hands or books.

Virgo ignored them. Instead, he walked right into the middle of the room and stopped. He looked around.

The laughter slowly died down.

He pointedly withdrew the violin from the case he carried, fixed it under his chin, and drew back the bow.

Someone sniggered, but was quickly hushed.

And then he played. It started slow and simple, leading from the introduction, through each of the three individual movements. To those listening it was a song of sorrow and loss, each long note stirring some painful memory within them. But to Virgo, each note brought forth not sorrow, but anger—a kind of simmering resentment and rage, which he barely managed to keep hidden as he approached the conclusion. After several minutes of playing, in which no one in the entire common room had moved, the final note played, and silence fell.

He lowered the bow and looked around again.

Several groups of witches were quietly sniffling to themselves. Many of the boys looked uneasy and guilty. Heir Longbottom was trembling in his seat, hunched over and trying to look small.

Virgo’s anger started to fade, quickly replaced by satisfaction. He drank in the looks of sadness and guilt like a fine wine.

Julia’s thoughts felt both resigned and disgusted. Only you could take something like music and turn it into a weapon.

Beautiful, isn’t it?

By the fire place, John Potter looked rather uncertain.

Virgo let the violin hang at his side. Everyone was still watching and waiting. He took a steadying breath. It was important to get the level of fear and righteous indignation in his voice just right.

“I am not evil,” he started. “I spent most of my childhood in Sweden. For a long time, I was Virgo Olsen, not Virgo Malfoy. When I returned, I learned a lot about magic and the wizarding world from my new family. I knew what was expected of me by them, but I never forgot the muggles who’d raised me before. When I came to Hogwarts, the hat told me I would do best in Gryffindor—that Gryffindor was where I truly belonged. So I went there, and now here I stand in front of you—I can do nothing else.” Virgo let a tiny part of the anger he’d been feeling for days leak into his now trembling voice. “Do you have any idea what it’s going to be like for me when I go home for Winter Festival!” She glared around at them all, then, without waiting for a response, stormed off to the girl’s dormitory, still wearing the set of prank antlers that no first year should be able to remove by themselves, leaving behind an extremely uneasy common room.

The next morning, something fundamental had changed. When Virgo left the dormitory people nodded at him, some gave him encouraging smiles—a couple even apologised for the way they’d been treating ‘her’. The oldest Weasley, Percy, removed his antlers with a wave of his wand and commented on how everyone’s behaviour had been disgraceful, while Dean Thomas had given him a big, cheesy, thumbs up. No one really invited him into their groups, but no one turned him away when he asked if he could sit with them for a while either.

It was during one of these informal chats when he learned that Susan Bones was, apparently, a passionate dueller, and that the Hufflepuffs had duelling practise on Friday evenings at the duelling arena. John Potter still wasn’t looking very comfortable around him. Maybe it would be a good idea to extend some feelers into other houses. Susan could be perfect, but Virgo could easily think of one other who’d also be a prime candidate to befriend.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Alexandra Black sat in her first potions class waiting for Professor Lady Lilly Potter to arrive. The Carrow twins sat on either side of her as though they were guards containing an especially disruptive prisoner. Alex wasn’t blind. She’d seen the looks she’d been getting from the children of the Dark over the last few days. She snorted. Let them come. She’d gang up with Luna and the other witches to crush Harry Potter in training, and then she’d use her Black family magic to cow anyone in the Dark who tried anything with her. Lord Slytherin would be impressed.

Over in the middle of the classroom, Ginny was happily chatting away to Luna. The distance between her and them seemed far too large.

At that moment, Lilly Potter walked into the room and up to the front. Alex frowned grumpily. The woman always treated Alex like she had brain damage or something. She turned around to face them all. “Welcome. I am Professor Potter and here you will be learning one of the most useful and powerful skills available to wizards … potions. Why are potions so powerful?”

Lilly Potter waited for a few moments for anyone to raise their hands. No one did.

She turned and wrote on the board.

POTIONS ARE THE ULTIMATE EQUALISER

She turned back. “It does not matter how powerful your wand is. It does not matter how well your body can process magical toxicity. It does not even matter how much raw power you can channel. So long as you can use magic, you can stand among the greatest potioneers who have ever lived, if you have the smarts for it. That is what makes potions so powerful.”

Alex suppressed the urge to snort. That didn’t make potions powerful. In fact, that made potions far less powerful. If everyone could do it, it wasn’t much of an advantage.

They soon started on a simple potion to cure boils. Alex was partnered with Hobby Harper, a dark-skinned boy with extremely short hair, who seemed to be trying to impress her. She focused on prep—cutting, mashing, and dicing the ingredients into the exact specifications noted by the recipe, while Harper manned the cauldron, loudly counting out stirs in-between boasting about his quidditch skills.

Some time into the process, Lilly passed Alex’s cauldron and stopped by Ginny’s. “Oh, well done, Miss Weasley. You’ve got the viscosity and colour just right. Two points to Slytherin.”

Ginny nodded curtly. Lilly moved on and Alex craned her neck to see inside Ginny’s cauldron. Their potions were identical. She scowled and passed the latest batch of perfectly sliced sniffle-cups to Harper.

“Oh, and you too, Miss Malfoy—wonderful—three points to Gryffindor.”

At that point, something went wrong. The cauldron Harper was manning started to spit.

Alex’s eyes darted to, and fell on, the stirring rod. Harper had left it in the guard while adding the sniffle-cups. Idiot! She snatched it out of the cauldron just as the last of the sniffle-cups went in, but by then the damage had already been done. The potion’s perfect green colour had faded into a kind of sick yellow.

“Oh, that’s no good.” Lilly Potter was standing behind them with a concerned look on her face. It was as though she’d teleported there from the other side of the room. She looked at the stirring rod in her hand. “Alex, you should never stir while adding grasses in this potion.”

“Yes, I—”

“Well, you know for next time. I’m sure you’ll manage it if you try really hard.” Lilly then gave her an encouraging smile and walked away.

Alex only just resisted braining herself head on the desk in frustration.

Harper muttered an apology, but that did little to stem Alex’s annoyance.

By the time class ended her mood had reached the boiling point. She was among the last to pack up, and when she stormed down the corridor towards the dungeons, it took all her instincts not to immediately hex the slight figure that stepped out from behind a statue. “What do you want?”

Virgo Malfoy smiled at her. “Annoying, isn’t it? I saw what happened back in class.”

“Good for you.” Alex continued on walking.

Virgo stepped up beside her. “That’s not the only thing I’ve seen.”

“Oh?” They were now walking together down the corridor with Virgo on Alex’s left.

“I notice my brother’s trying to stir up trouble. It can’t be easy on you right now.”

“I’m just fine.”

“Are you sure you wouldn’t appreciate help?” Virgo leaned slightly closer. “I know many Malfoy secrets.”

Alex gave her a suspicious look. “Why would you want to help?”

Virgo sighed. “I’m a Malfoy in Gryffindor. My family might not soon be the most supportive of allies. I need new ones.”

Alex thought in silence for a moment while the two girls continued to walk. Lord Slytherin wanted the Dark students at Hogwarts on his side. Surely bringing Lord Malfoy’s daughter into the fold would be equally useful. She slowed her pace a fraction. “Well …”

“Hi there!”

Alex and Virgo both jerked around.

“Luna!”

“Alex!”

Alex found herself looking into her best friend’s large grey eyes from only a few feet away. She’d appeared on her right like a ghost through a wall.

The moment Virgo realised who it was, she took several steps backwards as though afraid of catching something.

Luna grabbed onto Alex’s arm and pressed herself up against her. “I’ve been looking for you.” She leaned over to gaze at Malfoy. “Hey, Virgo. Have you thought at all about what we talked about on our first day?”

“No.” Virgo said, rather bluntly.

“Not even a little bit?”

“No!”

“You can’t run from it forever.” Luna’s voice was practically sing-song by this point.

Alex found herself being gently pulled further and further away from where Virgo now stood.

“My offer’s still open.” Luna giggled. “Special deal—order now—while supplies last—before it’s too late.”

Virgo said nothing.

And then they’d turned around and were walking away from their Gryffindor classmate. They continued on walking until they’d turned several corners and were clearly and obviously alone.

“Um, Luna?” Alex lowered her voice and leaned in closer. “Not that I’m not happy to see you, but aren’t we supposed to not be seen together in public?”

“I missed you.”

Alex felt something ping in her stomach. She looked away. “Yes, well.” She grasped for something else to talk about. “What were you talking about with Virgo?”

“Oh, I was just playing with her. It’s so much fun—like a kitty with a mouse.”

“She was offering to help with our project.”

Luna’s face turned serious. “Don’t accept it. Don’t trust her. In fact, don’t even let yourself be alone with her. Trust in Lord Slytherin.”

Alex hesitated, then smiled. “Right.” Just having this small time with Luna made her feel miles better than before. “And we’ll crush Harry on the weekend.”

Luna frowned. “About that. I have a family obligation that I have to take care of. My father’s coming to take me from Hogwarts on Friday evening. I won’t be back until late on Sunday.”

Alex’s face fell. “Oh.”

“Don’t worry.” Luna put an arm around Alex’s shoulders. “We’ll find more time to hang out together soon, I promise.”

Alex smiled again.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Damn Lovegood. What the hell was wrong with her? Virgo walked down to the duelling arena fuming mildly. She’d been so close before that little whore had shown up.

Normally this would be the point he’d expect Julia to start kicking up a fuss in his brain, but, oddly enough, on this one she actually agreed with him.

Virgo walked into the duelling arena and stood at the railings looking down as the Hufflepuffs started trickling in.

“Hey!”

Virgo looked up. An older male Hufflepuff was marching towards her. “You’re in Gryffindor, right? You can’t be here.”

Virgo frowned. That had never been a problem fifty years ago. “Are you sure? I won’t be any trouble. I just wanted the opportunity to practise with people who aren’t from my house.”

“No, absolutely not.”

At that moment, the twin muggleborns from Hufflepuff house arrived on either side of the boy—the Chesterfields. Virgo had grouped with them during herbology when everyone else in her house had ignored her.

“Aww, C’mon Cedric,” wheedled the one on the left. She wore gold ribbons in her hair, as opposed to purple, which meant that this was Marigold.

“Indeed,” said the one that, by process of deduction, had to be Violet, the far more subdued of the pair. “If she wants to practise against us, I don’t have a problem with that. It’s not like we’re that important.”

The boy folded his arms. “That’s not the point.”

“What about what it means to be a Hufflepuff ?” Marigold pouted up at him. “Don’t you remember what you told us? Puffs help people and make friends everywhere. Go Puffs!”

Cedric grimaced before theatrically throwing his hands up in the air. “Fine, whatever. You take care of her then.” He turned around and walked off in a fake huff. It was obviously fake because he first gave them both a smile and a wink.

Virgo watched the whole exchange with a kind of disdainful fascination. I’m constantly finding myself relying on muggleborns recently, he thought. It’s pathetic.

I’m sure if it’d been me, I’d have been awesome, thought the soul Julia. And it’s not pathetic!

“C’mon!” said Marigold, pulling her towards the other Hufflepuffs.

Thus it was that, twenty minutes later, Virgo found herself facing off against the niece of the head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement, Heiress Susan Bones. She studied him with an air of deep suspicion.

Violet threw a handkerchief into the air. It slowly fell to the ground. It hit.

The exchange didn’t last long. Susan’s spells were fast and precise. She’d clearly spent many hours practising. Virgo let a disarming charm catch her after a mostly static thirty seconds of spell trading. “Wow, you’re good.”

Susan glared at him. “Don’t give me that bullshit.”

Virgo blinked. “Sorry?”

“You don’t think I can’t tell? You threw that!”

Damn, the girl was sharper than he’d thought. “Umm …”

“Why?” Susan demanded.

“Err …” Virgo dropped his head. “It’s my house mates.”

“What?” Susan walked closer so she could hear his now rather quieter voice.

“They’ve been treating me like crap all week—because I’m a Malfoy in Gryffindor. They only stopped yesterday when I shouted at them all in the common room. I guess I’m afraid that if I stand out too much their going to think I’m dangerous or something. My father was training me ever since I came back from Sweden—I might be a bit too advanced.”

Susan’s features softened. “You know, if you have problems, you can always talk to John Potter. He’ll sort it out.”

Virgo smiled weakly. “I tried. He wasn’t having it.”

Susan’s eyes narrowed. “Oh, really?”

Virgo raised both his hands in what he hoped was a convincing, half-panicky gesture. “Please don’t get angry at him. He wasn’t the one dumping honey on me or anything. I don’t want him to get mad at me.”

Susan pursed her lips.

Urgh, thought Julia.I think I’m going to be sick.

After apparently considering his words for a few moments, Susan said, “but he didn’t help put a stop to it, did he?”

“Well, no.”

Susan sniffed. “Stupid boys.” She looked Virgo in the eyes. “I’m not going to think you’re evil. Are you going to fight seriously now? I need another good opponent.”

Virgo nodded quickly. He’d have to be far more careful this time—maybe up his game to that of a mildly competent second year. Susan was better even than that, so she’d still win, but it would at least give her the impression of fighting a first year prodigy—someone valuable. Then he’d be able to let his skills improve slowly over time until he could use them fully in front of her.

They jumped apart and readied their wands.

Marigold snatched up the handkerchief on the ground and threw it up into the air. “Begin!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Grand Central Terminal, New York City, United States of America—a vast concrete and steel monument to muggle pragmatism, and hidden somewhere inside, the MaCUSA International Portkey Terminal—an equally vast goblin-iron monument to wizarding secrecy. Special Auror Jackson Collins sat on one of the many iron benches, reading his newspaper and watching the arrival circles—three large pits dug into the marble floor. Each pit was filled with several inches of sand and featured stone steps around the circular sides leading up and out.

Bing-Bong!

A cheerful sounding female voice rang through the hall. “Arrival of the six o’clock portkey from Tokyo to pit number two—please stand clear. Thank you.”

There was a whoosh of air, a blur of coloured shapes, and then over a dozen people stumbled across the sand of the middle pit. Almost half of the arrivals immediately threw up. The others didn’t look much better.

Jackson ruffled his newspaper. Damn Brits. Damn their suspicious shit. But, most of all, damn his boss who’d decided their damn suspicious shit mattered. He’d been called into her office early yesterday afternoon, just when he’d been winding down for the weekend, and been told he was now on special assignment.

“These are the Lovegoods,” his boss, Ruby Goldstein, had said, pushing a file with a picture paper-clipped to the front across her desk at him. “They’ll be arriving in the country early Saturday morning.”

Jackson looked down at the family picture of a tall, blonde man, his wife, and his young daughter. “And why is this important?”

“Because they are associated with a person of interest to MaCUSA.” Goldstein threw another file at him, this one far thinner than the last. “This man—the so-called ‘Lord Slytherin.’ Procurement is talking with him about magical submarines. The higher ups are fed up with the kelpie situation in the Great Lakes.”

Jackson flipped through the file. He made a face. “Arranged marriages—yuk.”

“That’s what you get so close to the Albion.”

“And these Lovegoods are also British aristocracy. You think they’re what? Industrial spies?”

“Their visa application says they’re here for tourism, but their school term’s already started. They’re bringing their daughter with them. It’s only for the weekend, so she wouldn’t miss any classes, but nevertheless, it’s suspicious.”

Jackson had groaned, which had gotten him a scowl from his boss. Her suspicions had landed him in hot water more than once over the years, but he wasn’t about to argue it. And so here he was, waiting at the crack of dawn for a trio of British wizards. They’d probably portkey off again to who knew where, dragging him along with them, and forcing him to spend a good chunk of his own weekend in portkey recovery.

Bing-Bong! “Arrival of the six-fifteen portkey from London to pit number three—please stand clear. Thank you”

There was a whoosh of coloured air and seven wizards stumbled onto the sand. The Lovegoods were instantly recognisable. They stood together and were the only ones not to immediately throw up, although that wasn’t to say that they looked fine—far from it. They staggered up the stone steps, clinging to the railing and each other, and made their way over to the lines of sleep booths—luxurious recovery spaces, complete with sleeping potions—something only well off travellers could afford.

Jackson groaned. He was obviously in for a long wait.

He wasn’t wrong. For the next six hours, he kept his eye on the exit to the booths, keeping himself occupied with the cross-word, and even a copy of a muggle newspaper. Apparently the muggle government had confiscated a massive dinosaur skeleton from some people who couldn’t decide who owned it. It caught his eye because he’d been part of the team that had raided an excavation site in Utah some years back. The muggle bone diggers had discovered a fossilised dragon and mistaken it for one of their own massive extinct beasts. He was sipping on a cup of ever-warm coffee when the Lovegoods walked out of the booth space, looking far better rested, and made their way towards customs.

Jackson folded up his papers and followed at a distance, coffee cup still in hand. He saw the customs agent talking to the trio, saw them all show her the rings they wore, saw the agent wave her wand over the rings, saw them hand over their wands, saw the agent register them, and saw her place the little girl’s wand in a storage box that he knew would be returned to her when she left the country. Then they walked through customs and out into the portkey terminal proper.

Jackson hurried up to the customs agent. “Excuse me, Ma’am,” The woman looked up. “Special Auror Jackson Collins.” He flashed his ID.

The woman straightened. “Yes, Auror?”

“The entry papers of the three you just processed, if you please.”

“Ah.” The woman fumbled on the desk, found them, and handed them over. “Here you go.”

“Thanks.” He looked over the documents. “Washington D.C. — a muggle hotel. They didn’t say anything about why they were going there did they?”

“No.” The customs agent shook her head. “The girl pouted a bit when she had to give up her wand, though.”

Jackson took another sip of coffee. “I bet she did. Any idea when the next public portkey to Washington is?”

“One-fifteen, Sir.”

“Thanks.”

Jackson then arranged for a MaCUSA portkey to take him to the capital ahead of the Lovegoods. He found the hotel the Lovegoods had put down on their entry papers and sat down in the lobby to wait. It was a whole hour later when the Lovegoods finally arrived, looking a whole lot more muggle than when they’d portkey’d in wearing their incredibly European wizarding robes.

By the time the Lovegoods finally emerged from their hotel room, it was almost a quarter past two in the afternoon. This time though, they clearly meant business. The adults were dressed in muggle formal wear, while the girl was more casually dressed in jeans and a t-shirt.

The apparent disconnect between the parents clothing and their daughter’s soon became understandable when they dropped her off at a kids activity centre—complete with trampoline and climbing wall. At this point, Jackson had to make a choice, and the choice was obvious. The kid was an eleven year old girl who didn’t have a wand. The adults were two highly capable wizards, with wands, who together owned one of the most powerful British media organisations. Naturally he chose to follow the adults.

Having said all that, Jackson couldn’t help feel that this whole exercise was a huge waste of time. This feeling didn’t decrease as the happy couple, which is obviously what they were, happily strolled up the national mall over the next hour, past the Smithsonian, past the Washington monument, stopping briefly to take in the Lincoln Memorial, before walking over to the JFK Centre, where, surprise, surprise, they pulled out two tickets to the opera and entered. Jackson grunted. He hated opera.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Luna Lovegood was a natural leader. This was the conclusion that Jennifer Rushings, head supervisor at the activity centre, came to after watching her interact with the other kids for the better part of an hour. Maybe it was the pure Britishness she seemed to radiate, but the other children—and especially the boys, whom she wouldn’t normally have thought old enough to notice—treated her like royalty—like a princess—no, even more than that, like a queen. They followed her around on whatever game she felt like playing and leapt to her commands like little soldiers. It was both impressive and darn adorable.

Said game at the moment seemed to involve stationing guards at all the windows, as though the activity centre was a castle on the lookout for potential invaders. She walked over to the girl and smiled warmly. “Everything going well, your majesty?”

Luna smiled back. “Quite well, Ms. Rushings.”

“The fort is secure then?”

Luna seemed to consider this question carefully. She looked around the centre, then back at her. “Yes,” she finally declared. “It would seem it is.”

Jennifer clapped her hands together. “That’s—”

And then Luna was pointing a length of wood at her, ornately carved with flowers and vines.

“Confundo.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In one of the JFK Centre’s concert halls, Jackson Collins tried to make himself comfortable. He wasn’t having much luck. The seats were too close together, the place was too dark, the music was too loud, and the muggle in front of him was wearing a hat that was too big.

The Lovegoods sat two rows down from him and six seats across, apparently quite enjoying themselves. Jackson tried to spot if anyone might be secretly communicating with them, but it was useless. This job really needed a whole team of field unspeakables, not just his own measly self.

He supposed it could be worse, though. He could be babysitting their brat.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Not far away, at the J. Edger Hoover Building, Derick Thomson finished changing into his security guard uniform and clocked in for his shift—he’d be working late tonight, mores the pity. He’d been really looking forward to catching the game later on. He walked into the lobby and took up position by one of the main doors. Nothing strange—nothing unusual—just another boring as heck shift.

“Imperio.”

Elation. Happiness. Freedom. Derick blinked. Only it wasn’t him that blinked. It seemed to be a good idea to go along with it though. His body patted himself down and found the ID that hung by his belt. His body inspected the card. It then reached into his pocket and pulled out the wallet Mandy had bought him for their fifth year anniversary. It riffled through the contents and looked at all the cards. Apparently done with the pockets, it then turned and made its way back the way he’d come.

Every so often his body would inspect the signs that plastered the walls. Derick had the vague feeling it was looking for something, not that it mattered, of course.

“You, okay there, Derick?”

His body whirled around. It was his friend, Alan. “Yeah, I’m fine,” his body said.

“Aren’t you on lobby shift?”

Derick felt something in his brain, something quite different from before. While before was elation and freedom, this was nakedness and vulnerability. It reached for answers to questions and pulled information straight from his brain like candy-floss from a machine and suddenly he understood. He was a prisoner in his own body. Some demon was possessing him! Panic bubbled up, his fingers started to twitch to his command, but then, just as quickly, the thing in his brain retreated, and the happiness returned. This all happened in less than a second.

“Rodger asked for me to see him in his office before shift,” said his body.

“Oooo.” Alan made a face of sympathy. “Have fun with that.”

“Asshole,” said his body.

Alan grinned, punched his body on the shoulder, and left.

After that, it was a quick walk through two levels basic of security. Each time, his body pulled out his security card and swiped it through the doors, with a small green flash. On the third door, the security swipe flashed red. His body frowned. He felt the happiness slowly drain from his body. For one disconcerting moment, he had back a kind of dizzy control. But then, something red hit him, and his world went dark.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Rachel Wayland stepped out of her bathroom stall, making the final adjustments to her tights as she went. She walked over to the sinks, washed her hands, checked herself in the mirror, quickly reapplied her lipstick, and tucked her Celtic knot necklace deeper into her blouse. Some of her more traditionally religious co-workers got a bit weird about her being a self proclaimed pagan. Satisfied, she made for the door. Her hand closed around the handle, and utterly failed to turn.

She frowned. Locked?

She tried harder, but still nothing.

“Sorry about this.”

She whirled around. A girl. Short, black-haired, Asian features, t-shirt, jeans, stick of wood pointing at her. No, her mind corrected itself, not a stick of wood, a wand—symbol of male virility—channeller of air and fire. She mentally shook herself. Not important. “What are you doing here? Why is the door—” But that was as far as she got before something hit her and all her arms and legs snapped together, her mouth snapped shut, her neck went totally stiff. Magic! The thought ploughed through her like a shocked and triumphal freight train. Real Magic! OMG!

Her totally unresponsive body floated forward, spinning gently, until her upside-down face was only a few feet away from the girl’s.

OMG! OMG! OMG!

“Legilimens.”

Memories flew through her mind like a hurricane. Memories of work, of projects long ago completed, of her co-workers, of the layout of the warehouse she helped admin, of the recent delivery of a huge-ass dinosaur skeleton, and finally, of passwords and usernames to the building’s security systems. It was that last memory that succeeding in breaking her out of the crazed elation at her discovery, and dumped a bucket of cold water all over her.

This little girl was in the middle of FBI headquarters, using magic to break in! She was ripping critical security data right out of her head and there was nothing Rachel could do to stop it. Sweat poured down her face as she tried to will the tide of memories to stop, but it had about as much effect as a single sandbag trying to stop a flash flood.

Eventually the memories stopped.

The girl smiled at her. “Thank you.”

Unable to say anything, Rachel just stared back, wide-eyed, fearful, and desperately trying to remember every little detail for later, assuming, of course, that she managed to get out of here alive.

“Obliviate.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Stop!” In the FBI surveillance room, Daniel Davis jabbed his finger at the video screen. “Right there. Rewind it again.”

Daniel’s closest work friend, Carl Turner, who was far larger than Daniel, rewound the tape and together they watched. There, before their eyes, a door in one of the high security areas opened and closed all by itself, without anyone using a security card or punching in a security number. “Okay, that’s fucking weird.”

“I told you I didn’t just imagine it.”

“So, what do you think it is? A ghost?”

“Oh, please, get real.” Daniel jerked up and starred at another of the many security cameras that surrounded the two of them. Most of the others had already gone home, for the day, leaving just the skeleton crew. He pointed at the screen that caught his attention. “There! Another one.”

“What, for real?”

“Yes, for real. Get the tape. I swear I saw something else this time too.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Sometime quite a bit later, somewhere among many hundreds of shelves in the depths of the building’s basement, a barely visible outline moved about unseen and unheard. The outline stopped occasionally, as though reorienting itself, before carrying on again. Eventually, it found itself in front of a series of high shelves, each one several feet tall, and on these shelves, were stored hundreds upon hundreds of fossilised bones.

The outline glided like a whisper until it reached the shelf that contained the beast’s skull, a ridiculously massive thing, longer than the outline stood tall, longer even than longest dragon skull, and packed deep with dagger-like teeth, some of them as long as a man’s forearm.

In front of the skull, for all to see, someone had put a small plaque which simply read, ‘Sue.’

Two of the teeth then yanked themselves out of the skull and slowly floated forward. As soon as they reached the outline, they all but vanished, becoming little but an outline themselves.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Daniel ran a hand through his hair. “Okay, this isn’t funny anymore. We need to tell someone.”

Between them, he and Carl had found four more incidences over the last hour of self opening and self-locking doors. The tapes were all piled up on the table. One of the more scary episodes was playing repeat on the main monitor. This wasn’t just a cute incident anymore, this was a real security problem.

“Yeah,” Carl nodded. “Let’s handoff to Sammy. He’ll know what to do.” He stood up. “You’d never think we needed something like this in the procedures manual.”

“No kidding.”

Carl reached for the door handle. “Imagine the newspapers, ‘FBI building haunted.’ ”

Daniel groaned. “Don’t even joke about it.”

Carl wrapped his hand around the handle and turned. Or rather, he tried to. “Locked.”

“What?” Daniel stood up.

“It’s locked,” Carl said, a bit louder.

“Here,” Daniel stepped forward with his keys. He stuck one in the lock, gasped, and drew his hand back. What remained of the key dribbled down the front of the door.

Daniel and Carl looked at each other.

“Okay, don’t panic,” Daniel said. He pointed at the phone. “Call for help.”

Carl picked up the phone and held it to his ear. “Dead.”

“What do you mean, ‘dead?’ ”

“I mean there’s no tone!”

Daniel growled. “This had better not be someone’s idea of a practical joke. Right, we break the door.”

Carl nodded and together they gave the door everything their shoulders had, which, despite their combined quite considerable weight, wasn’t nearly enough.

Daniel stood back and ran his hand through his hair, looking around the room again. “Window!”

His friend looked up at the tiny window near the roof. “Are you sure?”

“Do you have a better idea?”

“Fair catch.” Carl hauled a fire extinguisher out from under the desk, then climbed onto the desk, and used his powerful arms to lob it straight at the window. It bounced off with a sound like a palm hitting a rubber mat—very much not the sound some fifteen-odd kilos of steel makes when hitting a thin sheet of glass—before crashing to the ground … like a feather.

The two looked at each other again.

“Okay, this shit really isn’t funny now.” Daniel started pacing. “What the hell is this?”

It was at that moment that things went from worrying to terrifying.

All at once, Daniel found himself with no control over any of his limbs. His arms and legs snapped together, his mouth snapped shut, and his neck and spine went stiff as a board. Only his eyes could move. They swivelled around desperately, only to see that Carl was in the same situation as he, and that both of them were now floating almost a foot off the floor.

A girl appeared in front of them from nowhere as though she’d stepped through a hole in the world—young, Asian, black hair, jeans and a t-shirt. There might have been more scary things to be faced with in this situation, but Daniel honestly couldn’t think of one.

“I’m so sorry about this,” the girl said, and genuinely sounded it. “This might feel a bit uncomfortable, but it will make my work more accurate.” She pointed a length of wood at him.

“Legilimens.”

Memories flashed through Daniel’s head. Memories of his family, of his friends, of going to see the Redskins’ first game of the season just the other day. The memories quickly focused in on the events of the afternoon, and then further onto his sudden unexplained curiosity at a seemingly unimportant event on the security cameras.

His and Carl’s entire ghost hunt flashed before his eyes, like a dream on fast-forward, but somehow slower as well. Then the memories stopped and he was able to take a metaphorical deep breath.

The girl considered the pile of tapes on the table before turning back to him and Carl. “Thank you,” she said. “This will make everything much easier.” She then pointed what he could now only think of as her wand at the pile of four tapes and said, “obliviate.”

Nothing seemed to happen until he looked at the video monitor which was still playing the fifth and final tape constantly on repeat. He wanted to gasp. There, before his eyes, the door on the screen closed shut sooner than it should have … and stayed shut. The tape rewound itself, started playing again, and this time the door didn’t open at all.

Sweat poured down Daniel’s face. This girl was either a demon or a god, and he’d never believed in gods.

The wand then turned on him, and in his mind, it turned on him as slowly and with all the inevitability of a destroyer’s main cannon being brought to bare on a small dingy, until he was looking right down the shaft. It had flowers on it.

“Obliviate.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back at the opera, the lights finally came back on, and Special Auror Jackson Collins was finally able to get out into the fresh air again. Mr. and Mrs. Lovegood seemed in no hurry to go anywhere though. They ambled back the way they came, apparently at total ease in the world. Eventually, they found their way back to the activity centre they’d dropped their daughter off at.

He watched Mr. Lovegood hug his daughter as though they hadn’t just been gone for a few hours, and the kid hugged him back the same way. Urgh, he thought, this really was the most pointless assignment.

By the time he’d spent another three hours watching the Lovegoods trying Pizza and all sorts of other very normal foods at one Washington’s many muggle eateries, he was ready to write a very pointed report to his boss about how reliable her suspicions tended to be, office politics be damned.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The classroom was large. The desks were piled up at the back. The windows sat deep into the stonework, Sunday morning sun streaming through in long beams. Daphne sat by one of these windows, fully dressed in dragon-hide duelling robes, and feeling more than a little inadequate.

In the middle of the room, Ginny, Alex, and Hermione were warming up. In Ginny’s case, this involved rapidly switching between pebbles scattered around the room while Alex shot stunner after stunner at her, far faster than Daphne could have managed, and even then, not a single one of them connected.

By contrast, Hermione stood off to one side doing jumping jacks in-between practising basic spell chains.

It really drilled home just how much of a gap had opened up between them. So much so that Daphne wasn’t all that sure what she could usefully add to their effort to ‘take down’ Harry.

After several more minutes, Hermione wandered over. “You don’t know what Luna is up to do you?”

Daphne shook her head.

Alex stopped trying to stun Ginny and turned towards them. “She told me she had a family obligation.”

A small pebble by Daphne’s feet vanished and Ginny appeared where it had been. “She told me she was going to America.”

“Out of the country?”

“Yeah.”

At that moment, the door opened.

They all turned to it.

“Morning.” It was Harry. He wasn’t dressed in duelling robes, but rather his normal everyday clothes.

“Harry!” Ginny grinned at him. “You don’t know what Luna is up to, do you?”

“She said something about getting reagents for a Lovegood family ritual.”

“What ritual?”

“No idea. She didn’t want to ‘spoil the surprise’. I’ve no doubt we’ll find out soon enough. Now,”—Harry stepped up beside them and looked around at them all—“you ready for this?”

“Hell yes,” said Alex. “I’ve been waiting for this forever.”

“Okay then. I’ll give you a few minutes to plan among yourselves. Come at me however you will.” Harry wandered over to the other side of the room and sat down with a book.

Daphne, Ginny, Hermione, and Alex all went into a huddle.

“How are we going to do this?” Hermione asked.

“He’ll try to go for the biggest threat first, which is me,” said Ginny. “I’ll go invisible and switch out to a random pebble. You distract him. Then I’ll go in for the kill.”

“What about my family magic?” asked Alex.

“No dark spells on Harry,” said Hermione firmly.

Alex grunted.

When they were done talking, Harry was standing in the middle of the room, pebbles strewn all around him while Daphne, Hermione, Alex, and Ginny all stood by one of the four walls, wands in hand and ready.

Harry conjured a handkerchief and levitated it up to the ceiling. He let it fall. The moment the handkerchief landed on the ground, many events happened in quick succession, so fast that Daphne barely had time to register them all.

Ginny flickered into invisibility.

Hermione and herself both started casting a spell—a stupefy in her case.

Alex actually did cast a stupefy, which sailed towards Harry.

Every pebble in the room rose off the ground and shot towards Harry far faster than Alex’s stunner.

A bubble of shimmering light flickered around Harry.

She and Hermione finished casting their spells.

Every pebble smashed against the bubble.

Alex’s spell was swatted away by Harry’s wand.

One of the pebbles vanished, switching with a visibly surprised and, more importantly, visibly visible Ginny, right in front of Harry—right where Harry’s other hand was already placed, palm open and pressed into her stomach. There was a flash of red.

Daphne and Hermione’s spells were swatted away.

By the time Daphne had fully registered all this, Ginny had fallen to the ground in front of Harry, unconscious. There was a moment of stillness, then movement, and Daphne’s world went dark.

When Daphne awoke, it didn’t take long to remember that obviously every time she and Harry had trained together, he’d been massively holding back.

“I told you,” Alex said to Hermione. “We need something with more oomph.”

“We’re not using extremely dark magic against Harry!” Hermione hissed.

“We wouldn’t be using it all for real,” Alex argued, “just to help us move him where we need him.”

Hermione folded her arms. “If Harry knows it’s just a bluff, it won’t work.”

Ginny seemed a bit more subdued than before.

Alex scowled. “You don’t even know what spells I had in mind.”

“Fine, give me an example.”

“Black chains. They restrict the target’s movement and drain their will to fight on contact.”

Hermione thought about this for a moment. “Okay then,” she eventually conceded. “I guess we can try that.”

If anything their next attempt went even worse than their first.

Alex’s Black chains certainly looked impressive, but didn’t stand up well to the whip made of pure flame conjured from the end of Harry’s wand. It wasn’t long before they were all huddled together again.

“It’s not like this even counts,” Alex muttered, mostly to herself. “Luna isn’t here, so we aren’t at full strength.”

“Well, what did you expect?” Hermione bit back. “He’s Harry.”

Alex practically snarled. “Will you please stop saying his name like that. You need more than power to be a great wizard.”

“What? How dare you!”

Daphne rubbed her temples as the two continued their argument while Ginny stood off to one side, not really contributing. Eventually, something inside her snapped. This was not the way things should be. “Will you two be quiet!”

They both paused mid rant and turned to her.

“I can’t hear myself think!”

Hermione and Alex’s eyes didn’t leave her as she started pacing. Right, she thought, focusing in on the task at hand. Harry wasn’t helping them, which obviously meant he thought they could do more by themselves than they currently were. They couldn’t physically get better or learn new spells, so that just left how they were using their spells—strategy, in other words.

Daphne looked out over the room, still filled with pebbles.

They started out surrounding him, which was strategically advantageous … She barely got any further into that thought when it hit her. She slapped her forehead. Of course, she thought, one of the basic rules of strategy—concentrate your forces. What was it Harry had once said? ‘Always seek to defeat your enemy in detail.’ They all had different strengths and capabilities, so surrounding him was in fact the worst thing they could do. It left them completely open for Harry to turn to any of them and defeat them in detail however he wished!

Daphne turned back to Hermione and Alex. She waved Ginny closer. “Okay,” she said, with a small and confident smile, “Here’s what we’re going to do. We’re all going to start off standing like points on a diamond. Ginny, you’re going to be in front. Your job is to swat away any direct spells that Harry casts at us.”

Ginny nodded, eyes suddenly more focused.

“Alex, you’re going to be on one the sides, your job is to harass Harry with your chains, keep him moving, and, if the opportunity presents itself, lock him down.” Alex nodded.

“Hermione, you’re on the opposite side of Alex. Your job is dedicated offence, as much as is possible. You’re the best of us at transfiguration, and Harry will just swat away most spells, so it’s best you focus on that.”

Hermione nodded.

“And finally, I’ll be in the back, casting finite incantatem on anyone who gets hexed or stunned, shielding anyone who needs shielding, and harassing Harry with simple spell chains when there’s nothing else to be done. Anyone have anything else to add?”

Alex, Hermione, and Ginny traded glances before shaking their heads.

Daphne smiled and her eyes lit up. “Excellent.” She then called Harry over and announced they were ready for the next round. They didn’t end up winning it of course, but they did a lot better than before, and by the end of it, Daphne felt far surer of herself. This was definitely something she could add.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

And already it’s Sunday, Virgo thought—the end of a long, first week. He walked through the Hogwarts library on the lookout for a certain someone. In the back of his mind, Julia was still sleeping after a whole morning reading an advanced theory of magic book.

Ah, there. He spotted his target and made his way towards her. At one of the many library tables, piled high with books and lined with students, Susan Bones was happily chatting away with Heiress Hannah Abbott and Sally Smith, daughter of a branch house of the Noble House of Smith. “Hello,” he said.

Susan Bones looked up. “Oh, Virgo, it’s you.” She looked surprised to see him. “What’s up? Duelling stuff?”

The other girls watched with interest.

“I was just wondering if I could join you?” Virgo held up a second year book. “All my classmates are rather behind me, so I don’t really study well with them. I promise not to slow you down.”

Hannah and Sally looked at each other.

Susan considered this before glancing at her friends, who shrugged. “Sure, why not.” She started making room for him.

Virgo smiled and sat down.

“I don’t think you’ve met my friends,” Susan continued.

Virgo relaxed as the second year Hufflepuffs introduced themselves. It wasn’t a large step, he had to remind herself, but it was a step, and if he ended up building his power base among the Light instead of the Dark … well never let it be said that he wasn’t resourceful.

—End of Chapter Thirty-Nine—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s value.

Sticky Note: As always, if you want to stay up to date on schedule changes and other bonuses before anyone else, you can get them on my mailing list, which you can find by following the breadcrumb trail through my profile page.

Alexandra Black, Meet Death’s Champion

Birds tweeted in the trees. A centaur, out for morning archery practise, sniffed the dew-filled air. Morning light shone onto the Black Lake, reflecting shimmering patterns as the water bobbed and ebbed. Some of that light passed through the surface and down into the depths—at first with ease, but as light blues gave way to darker, less cheery shades, it struggled more and more, until the morning sun consisted of only a few lonely photons in the deep, inky blackness. It was pretty dark down there.

Continue on just a bit further though, in just the right direction, and the blackness surrenders to a faint green glow—light from dozens of windows, each one embedded into a sheer underwater cliff-face. The largest of these windows belonged to the Slytherin common room, and students inside might occasionally expect to see schools of fish, or kelpies, or even the occasional whisper of the giant squid, but right now the outside waters were empty—empty and calm. Not so inside the glass.

“Come on, I do not wish to be late!”

“My homework! Oh Merlin, Snape’s going to kill me.”

“Hey, did you hear what happened to Judith in Herbology?”

“Bluhhh, too early.”

And so on and so forth.

Near the middle of the room, Draco Malfoy relaxed at the head of his court. Unlike the rest of the room, no one in this small circle was moving fast or seemed to be in a hurry. Far from it in fact. The Malfoy heir held a set of five cards right up to his face in a manner suggesting that any attempt to rush him would see him take even longer, just because he could.

“Fold,” said Theodore Nott, throwing his cards on the table. The cards started complaining loudly.

“I’ll raise by three knuts,” said Pansy.

Draco stared fixedly at his cards while in the background a sixth year couple argued all the way to the common room door. “I call,” he said. The door closed with a loud thumphf.

And at the back of the common room, down the enchanted flight of stairs that led to the girl’s dormitories, down to the very deepest level, a door flung itself open and a red headed girl burst out.

“Ginny, wait for me,” Luna called from inside the room.

Ginny laughed. “Should have dressed quicker then!”

Moments later Luna appeared and made a theatrical grab for where Ginny no longer was.

“Hah!” Ginny giggled and danced away, Luna following close behind.

And in the first years girls dormitory proper, at the very back of the room, in a green and silver four poster bed with the curtains shut tightly, Alexandra Black sat, crosslegged on the bed, stroking a purring Amethyst with one hand, while her other hand held a quill, poised on empty parchment. An open letter lay on the bed next to her, the contents of which had greatly disturbed her.

Her hand trembled.

‘Dear Father,’ she began.

She shook her head slowly, crossed the line out, and wrote, ‘Dear Daddy.’

She’d barely finished writing the ‘y,’ before she shook her head much more vigorously, crossed out that line too and replaced it with, ‘Dear Dad.’

Then she crossed out the ‘Dear,’ leaving only the ‘Dad.’

Frustrated, Alex ripped up the parchment and threw it in a small pile. She wondered why this had to be so hard before starting again with another sheet.

‘Hi Dad,

I’m fine! Yes, I’ve been sorted into Slytherin house. Don’t let the rumours get to you. I’m still friends with Harry. Yes, I’m working hard and yes, I’m keeping an eye out for Snape. You don’t need to worry so much. No, I don’t know what library you’re thinking of—’

Alex paused and bit her lip. Her hand was still shaking. It seemed that Lord Slytherin had been right about Lord Black wanting to purge the Black Library. The mere thought of something so horrible happening to her library made Alex sweat, but that wasn’t the only thing. Way at the back of her mind whispered a niggling question. How could Slytherin have possibly known? He’d warned Alex way back at the last Winter Festival and for a while she’d started to think he might have been mistaken. But he hadn’t been. Slytherin’s gaze seemed to reach as far as starlight. It was unreal. Far more like a character from one of her many story books than a real person. And he had not only seen, but also acted, unlike her father who Alex never saw do more than the bare minimum for the family. She continued writing.

‘—,but if I remember anything I’ll be sure to let you know. Hope everything is going well,’

Alex then wrote and crossed out several forms of signing off on a spare piece of parchment before simply settling on, ‘—Alex.’

She checked the letter several times before folding it up, tucking it away, nuzzling a mewling Amethyst on her cold nose, and leaving the dormitory. Most of the other students seemed to have already left for breakfast, so it was a surprise to find cousin Draco, along with Pansy and Theodore, sitting in a hunched circle. She wandered over.

“Four of a kind,” said Draco, setting down a set of cards. “Robes.”

Pansy and Theodore groaned.

“I was sure you were bluffing,” Theo said.

Alex sat down in the one free seat at the low table.

“Black.” Draco acknowledged her with a nod.

Alex looked at the table as Draco pulled a small pile of knuts towards him. “Bit early for this, isn’t it?”

Pansy sniffed. “We were behind on our homework. Mother said if we didn’t keep up with our lessons she’d see to it that our allowances were cut.”

Alex carefully kept her face blank while a mild feeling of resentment swelled up in her. Poker as homework. Of course. They’d probably been playing since they were old enough to hold cards. They’d probably been trained to identify tells before they’d learned to read—no, probably before they’d finished potty training. Alex had never played the game in her life. She didn’t even know how to play.

“Want to be dealt in?” asked Draco, “There’s still time for one more round.”

“I’ll just watch,” Alex quickly said, while her mind scheduled an appointment with Luna to get hold of a book of rules, and preferably lessons too.

“Suit yourself.”

The round opened with two knuts from Pansy and continued from there.

“You wouldn’t believe what my father sent me the other day, Black.” Draco said, mid round.

“Oh?”

The corner of Theodore’s lip curled upwards.

Pansy rolled her eyes.

“Seven Nimbus 2001s—for the Slytherin quidditch team.”

Alex raised her eyebrows. “That’s a lot of gold.”

“Yes, it is, isn’t it.” Draco smiled while not looking at his cards. “You’re looking at Slytherin’s newest seeker.”

“Really?”

“Yes,” Draco drawled. “Flint was very impressed. The latest model is far more efficient than the old 2000 ever was—faster too.”

Alex couldn’t help remembering a conversation between her and Ginny in which Ginny had firmly stated that she was going to be Slytherin seeker or else. Alex wasn’t entirely sure what the ‘or else’ would be, but she hoped it wouldn’t interfere with her own plans to take over the Dark for Lord Slytherin. Which, incidentally, was a plan that she intended to put into effect right about … now.

“I’m sure you will astound us all,” Alex said, and allowed a small pool of magical intent to pool on her finger tips. She’d found the spell in a Black family magic book ages ago. It was named the stress jinx by an unimaginative ancestor who’d been experimenting with dementors. The spell enhanced anxiety in the target towards things the target was already anxious about, and was undoubtedly dark magic of the most insidious kind, slowly worming itself deep into the victim over multiple applications. It took a long time to wear off, and was supposed to affect the caster just as bad as the target. Strange that, since she’d never felt anything bad from using it.

Alex let the magic snake out, undetected, across the gap between them and sink into the Malfoy heir.

Draco stiffened and his breath hitched, but otherwise he seemed unaffected by the Black family spell, at least not outwardly. “Of course I will.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“C’mon, make a move. I know you want too,” Ginny muttered to herself while glaring in frustration at the Marauder’s map. A dot labelled, ‘Virgo Malfoy,’ sat in the library in a circle of other dots, one of which was labelled ‘Susan Bones.’

“Still nothing?” Luna asked.

“No. It’s sticking to Bones like glue.”

The two were walking through the corridors after classes had finished. Harry had called a general meeting.

“Are you sure you’re ready for her?” Luna asked. “This isn’t like practising on chickens.”

Ginny felt a small pang of guilt that had nothing to do with Riddle and everything to do with Hagrid’s chicken coops before firmly squashing it. “I’m sure.”

Not far away, unseen behind several corners, two older boys in Gryffindor robes were on a collision course with the two girls.

“What do you think Harry wants?” Fred asked. He was idly spinning a protractor on his index finger.

“Probably news from our unknown benefactor who definitely isn’t Lord Slytherin,” George answered.

“You think?”

“Sure.”

Fred grinned. “I bet it’s about becoming animagi.”

“How much do you bet?”

“A sickle.”

“Done.”

The two pairs turned opposite corners on opposite sides of the next long corridor and stopped at exactly the same time, leaving them facing each other like twin duellists at the O.K Corral.

“Well, well,” said George sticking just his thumbs into the pockets of his robes in mock imitation of a teenage boy trying to be tough. “If it isn’t the prodigal sister.”

“The first Weasley ever to be sorted into Slytherin,” Fred added. “For shame, little Ginny.”

Ginny snorted. “Didn’t the sorting hat offer either of you Slytherin?”

“That’s for us to know and you to find out.”

Luna smiled. “If it’s for Ginny to find out, then asking those who know seems like a good idea to me.”

The twins looked at each other. “She’s got us there, Fred.”

“Too true, George. Very well then, please allow us to clarify, your Heiressness Heiress Lovegood. We ain’t telling.”

“Oh.”

Ginny rolled her eyes. “I assume there’s a reason you two are here.”

“Harry called us.”

Ginny gestured to the door in the middle of the corridor. “Us too.”

“Then after you, little sister.”

It was the same classroom the girls and Harry trained in. Harry was already there, along with Hermione and Daphne. He got up and shook Fred and George’s hands as they filed in. “I have news from our patron,” Harry said, closing the door behind them while Ginny and Luna moved over to Hermione and Daphne and started conversing in hushed tones.

“Oh, yes?” George grinned.

Fred huffed, shoved a hand into the pocket of his robes and slapped a large silver coin into George’s hand.

“Yes, Nimbus wants to make adjustments to our efficiency rings for next years model.”

Fred nodded. “You know, Harry, you don’t need to be so mysterious about our patron, it’s incredibly obvious who he is.”

The girls all looked up sharply.

“It is?” asked Harry.

“Yes, it is.”

“Do tell, then. There are none here not in the know.”

George pointed. “Daphne Greengrass and Luna Lovegood—both betrothed to Lord Slytherin—and you disappear for the whole summer with the prophet constantly hinting that Lord Slytherin ‘kidnapped’ you.”

“Okay, I guess it’s not all that hard to work out.”

Fred smirked. “That and we got an owl from Dad last week telling us everything, but we were sure we knew even before that.”

An unreadable expression passed over Harry’s face. “When you say everything …”

Fred and George looked at each other. Then George said, “That we’d been dealing with Lord Slytherin and our partnership is official and that Dad supports us, but that we shouldn’t tell Mum about it until he says it’s okay.”

There was a pause.

“… Yes.” Harry eventually said. He smiled. “Yes, that probably just about covers everything. Right then.” He clapped his hands together. “We’re just waiting for our last member and then we’re going to get down to business.”

Hermione put up her hand.

“Yes, Hermione?”

“What exactly is our business? You didn’t say.”

“Animagus training.”

Fred gave his brother a victorious smirk.

George snorted, reached into his pocket, grabbed the same silver sickle his brother had just given him and slapped it back into Fred’s hand. He then fished out a small bag of bronze knuts and handed it over with a theatrical flourish.

At that moment, they all heard the sounds of footsteps rapidly approaching through the corridor outside. The door opened and Alexandra burst in.

Ginny couldn’t help wondering what sparks would fly when her childhood friend was finally let in on Harry’s secrets.

“Sorry I’m late,” Alex said. “I had to shake the Carrows.”

The Weasley twins looked at each other again. “Was not expecting that, oh brother of mine,” said George.

“No indeed not.” Fred turned to Harry. “Isn’t she a little … Dark?”

“Nah, she’s one of mine.”

“Hey! I am not one of yours, Potter. I’m—” Alex hesitated, her gaze flickering back towards the Weasley twins.

“It’s okay, Black,” Daphne piped up. “They also work with Slytherin.”

“Well, okay then.”

As far as Ginny could tell, Harry’s process of becoming an animagus sounded a lot simpler than the normal version. He explained that the first step would be exactly the same—keeping a mandrake leaf in their mouths for a whole month—but that after they’d identified their animal form, they’d not bother with the aligning their soul to their inner animal through rigorous self transfiguration, which could take years, and instead each would build a special mindscape for their animal, before conducting a large group ritual involving themselves, seven massive clay pots, a pensieve, and enough phoenix ash to block a fireplace. They’d live the life of their inner animal all the way from birth in the blink of an eye, and die on the claws of the other six. Something about phoenix ashes ability to bend time and space and the way consciousness flowed in a okay, thought Ginny, as Harry finished up his rather lengthy explanation. Perhaps ‘simple’ wasn’t the best way to think of it.

“Hang on a second,” Fred said, frowning slightly. “You say seven pots because seven is a critically important number in soul magic. There are eight of us.”

Everyone looked around, counting heads. There were indeed eight people present—Harry, Daphne, Hermione, Ginny, Luna, Alexandra, Fred, and George.

“Yes,” said Harry. “There are two ways we can handle that. My hope is after this we can repeat the ritual for the muggleborns a year from now. They’re learning the needed occlumency as we speak. It might be helpful to have someone who’s been half way through the ritual already to guide them through that …”

The twins crossed their arms in unison.

“The other way,” Harry continued, ignoring the belligerent looks they were shooting him, “is to stuff the two of you into one pot and see what happens.”

“And what might happen?” George asked.

“If you have the same animal, you might simply be born in the same litter and grow up together. Or you might fuse into some hybrid monstrosity, like a two headed cerberus—like Orthrus.”

The twin’s broke out into wide grins.

“Or the whole ritual could just not work and we’d have to try again. Or we could all die—although I have my reasons to doubt that would happen.”

The twins exchanged looks then retreated across the room to whisper among themselves. After a few moments they returned. “We think,” said George, “that we should find out what our animal forms are first and then decide.”

“Sound thinking.” Harry stood up. “Well, that was all. I’ll let you know when I have the mandrake leaves. They’re quite hard to get hold of at the moment.” Everyone started to file out. “Oh, Ginny, a word please.”

Ginny held back. The door closed as the last other students walked through.

“I heard from Luna you did the chicken killing training last night. How are you feeling?”

That twinge of guilt twisted itself in Ginny’s stomach again. “Fine.”

“You sure?”

“Yes, I’m sure.”

Harry didn’t look all together convinced.

“It’s fine, Harry, really.”

“Well … okay then.”

Ginny let out a small mental sigh of relief. “Anything else?”

“Yes, Quidditch tryouts are tomorrow afternoon.”

“Flint’s going to make trouble.” It was a statement more than a question.

“Not as much as he might have,” Harry said. “I had a quiet word with him the other day. He agreed to give everyone a fair trial.”

“How’d you manage that?”

“I calmly pointed out to him the benefits of allowing meritocratic placement to his future sporting career.”

Ginny gave him a disbelieving look.

“I may have pointed this out while holding a pointy sword, pointing vaguely in his direction—I think he got my point.”

“That does sounds more likely.”

“I also slipped him a bag of gold to counter Malfoy’s buying the whole team nimbus 2001s.”

At that point several thoughts flew through Ginny’s head. The first was, ‘that Malfoy rat-face scumbag,’ the second was, ‘it doesn’t matter anyway, because Harry outsmarts him without even trying,’ and the third was, ‘oh wow, oh wow, when I get on the team, Malfoy will have, in fact, unwittingly bought me, Ginny Weasley, a brand new nimbus 2001.’

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The new broomstick gleamed. The wood was polished, the handle smooth, a magic efficiency ring hovered behind the seat, and each individual twig in the tail bent out elegantly before sweeping back in a manner reminiscent of gull-wing doors on a muggle sports car—not that the broomstick’s current owner would have appreciated the comparison.

“Impressive, isn’t it?” Draco said, brushing an imaginary speck of dust from the tip.

Despite herself, Alexandra couldn’t help feel a pang of annoyance. It really was a nice broomstick.

“It’s so impressive, Draco,” Pansy simpered. The girl turned to Alex. “Isn’t it impressive, Black.”

“Very impressive.” Alex said dryly. She fired another hidden stress jinx at Draco. “Better make sure you win the cup. Daddy won’t be happy dropping so much gold on a failure.”

For just a moment Alex thought she detected a flicker of worry on Draco’s face before it snapped back to his aloof mask. “You need to be more careful how you insult people, Black,” he said. “You don’t have your family on your side here.”

Alexandra shrugged. Nothing new there, she thought. She was used to dealing with things on her own.

The three of them were on their way to the Slytherin quidditch tryouts, Draco already holding the nimbus 2001 he’d claimed from the seven his father had sent in. Alex walked a little way ahead of the other two, not wanting to give the impression she was hanging off Draco’s arm the way Pansy practically was. They made their way outside and wandered down to the pitch.

Six nimbus 2001s were lined up on the grass. Harry and Ginny were already there, along with some other hopefuls and most of the previous year’s Quidditch team. Alexandra broke away and went to find herself a good spot to watch from the stands.

Draco sneered at Ginny as he arrived in the middle of the pitch. “First years aren’t allowed, Weasley. Push off.”

Flint cleared his throat. “As a matter of fact, Malfoy, the baron has given Miss Weasley permission to try out so long as her broomstick is held by another.” The bloody baron had replaced Snape as head of Slytherin house the previous year after Snape got petrified by the basilisk.

Draco looked Ginny over. “Well I suppose having a Weasley under my thumb wouldn’t be too—”

“As seeker, Malfoy, not just chaser,” Ginny cut in.

“What? I’m Slytherin’s seeker.”

There was a noticeable silence. Ginny smirked.

Draco whirled on Flint. “You promised me seeker!”

“No, I promised you a spot on the team. I’m not stopping you from trying out for seeker, but if someone does better than you, you’ll be a full-time chaser.”

“She’s a girl!” Draco pointed at Ginny. “You never let girls …” He trailed off. He turned to Harry who’d been silently watching the entire exchange.

Harry tilted his head in a half acknowledgement.

Draco’s eyes widened. He then whirled back on Flint. “You! You Gray-faced bastard! Have you no honour? People who are bought should stay bought!”

Flint shifted uncomfortably. “After we’ve chosen four chasers, we’ll release eleven snitches—whichever chaser catches most will be seeker.”

“I’m not being led by a Weasley!”

Flint’s eyes hardened. “Then you’d better not lose then, had you?”

Draco scowled before seeming to calm down. “Fine. Like I’d ever lose to a girl anyway.”

Way up in the stands, Alexandra heard none of this. She sat with her hands under her chin, looking bored, but carefully watching Malfoy for further signs of cracking. It was difficult to tell this early in the game how much of that little outburst had been her doing and how much was just Malfoy’s own personality. Surely it had been her doing. At this rate she’d have the Dark wrapped around her finger by Winter Festival. Something Harry hadn’t been able to achieve all last year.

The logic made perfect sense to Alex. Harry Potter was immensely powerful—everyone knew that. He’d also spent almost all of last year distancing himself from the Gray, just like she was doing now. What had he been doing during that time? Nothing, as far Alex could tell. And yet, here she was now, being asked by Lord Slytherin to take over the Dark—something she was sure could be achieved in under a week if she had Harry’s powers. So how had he failed what for him should be such a basic task? Because he didn’t want to use his powers?

Alex snorted to herself. The players down on the field were now throwing several quaffles about to each other several feet above the ground.

I mean, look at this, Alex thought. Harry could have Ginny on the quidditch team if he wanted to in an instant. All he had to do was put pressure on Flint, who was already Gray, and bam! But no, what was it Ginny had said to her before?

‘Lord Slytherin has arranged something for me.’

Lord Slytherin! Not Harry! Why was someone like Slytherin having to stoop to arranging positions on quidditch teams when he had someone as obviously powerful as Harry, supposedly running the show down here? It made her sick.

Harry Potter seemed to be very much like her dad in that respect—powerful and influential, but unwilling to use that power to make what needed to happen happen. Or even like Dumbledore, if she believed the whispers.

And so, here she was, having to clean up someone else’s failure. Still, it gave her the opportunity to prove herself to Slytherin, so she wasn’t complaining at all.

Oh, speak of the devil …

Harry ascended the stairs towards her, looking as calm and cheerful as he always did—cute too—though she’d rather die than admit it—just one more thing that pissed her off—him being cute that is, not her determination to never let anyone know she thought so.

“Knut for your thoughts?” Harry sat down beside her.

“My thoughts are worth a lot more than a knut, Potter.”

“Suit yourself.” Harry pulled out a small bottle of orange juice from somewhere, popped the top, and took a sip.

“Why aren’t you down there?” Alex waved her hands to the speeding broomsticks. “Ginny says you’re better on a broom than even her.”

“I’d like to, but I’ve got other stuff to do. Bubble water?” He held a can to her.

Alex took it. “Thank you.”

They drank in silence for a few moments while Ginny scored twice in the time it took Draco to score once.

Then Alex asked, “What were you doing last year?”

Harry thought for a moment before answering. “Keeping my head down mostly. It wasn’t a good time to be me.”

“Why? You’re so powerful, you could easily squash anyone who got in your way.”

“It is sometimes better to hide your true powers. Unrestrained enthusiasm has a way of coming back to bite you later.”

Alex snorted. What a Harry Potter response. What was the point in him hiding his powers now? Everyone knew his powers—knew them, and knew he didn’t use them.

“Oh?” Harry leaned forward slightly. “What do we have here?”

Alex turned to follow Harry’s gaze. A group of Gryffindors were walking onto the pitch, each one clutching very familiar looking brooms, Nimbus 2001s. Alexandra watched as Flint landed and started a loud argument with Wood, presumably about who had the right to the pitch. She watched as Draco landed in front of John Potter, followed by a lot of angry pointing between brooms and smug looks from John. She watched Ginny land not too far off. John eventually noticed her, standing there wearing Slytherin quidditch gear, and utterly lost his shit. Finally, she watched Harry next to her, calmly studying the unfolding drama with his fingers lightly steepled together—doing nothing, just watching.

Yes, Alexandra thought. Harry would be far better put to use under the command of another. Far better to have someone else be leader of the Gray at Hogwarts. That would be a good thing to work towards, even if only to make sure Greengrass got the position. Daphne was Slytherin’s betrothed after all, and already led the Gray in public. Surely she wouldn’t squander Harry’s many talents.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

For Hogwarts students, sneaking out at night shouldn’t be easy. What it should be is a terrifying ordeal with unknown threats lurking around every corner. Paintings, ghosts, teachers, prefects, house elves, they all should form a security system so tight as to make even an animagus gnat think twice about breaking out. And that wasn’t even taking into account the caretaker, Argus Filch, whom, despite being a squib, nevertheless seemed to have the magical ability to turn up exactly where ever out of bed students might be, never mind the fact that the castle bent space in such a way as to make his beat several times larger on the inside than the outside—and Hogwarts wasn’t a small castle to start with. Sneaking out at night shouldn’t be easy.

“Pass the crisps, Daphne.”

“Ooooo, look, he restocked the fridge.”

“Do you mind? Some of us are trying to do homework.”

“C’mon Hermione, it’s hardly a long trip.”

“You don’t have healer classes, combat lessons, and teaching the muggleborns.”

“I do have combat lessons—we have them together!”

“You know what I mean.”

“And I have seeker training now too. Flint was all like, ‘I’m going to work your cute little arse right off!’ ”

“He didn’t really say … ?”

“No, of course not. Who’s got the peanuts?”

*Sigh* “Well, I guess there’s no point in working now. Where does your eye show us, Daphne?”

“We just reached the grand staircase.”

“I’d love to be able to do that. Oh, thanks, Luna.”

“Don’t get your hopes up. Hermione, Harry, and I all tried last year and only I was able to open my inner eye. It’s not a common ability.”

*Munch* “Luna will be able to.”

“I might be able to. It’s always hit or miss with us Lovegoods.”

“Hey, Daphne, have you ever used that to spy on Harry in the showers?”

“No! I—have—not!”

*Munch* “Ever been tempted?”

“No! Besides … Harry can sense magic, so he’d know it was there.”

“Aha! So you have thought about it!”

And so on and so forth.

Not too much later, there was a tapping on the lid of the trunk. The girls all quietened and looked up. The trapdoor lid at the top of the stairs opened and Harry stuck his head inside. “We’re there.”

Sneaking out at night shouldn’t be easy, but most students don’t have a two-hundred galleon shrinkable trunk, the ability to fly, and a cloak able to hide the wearer even from the gaze of Death himself.

“Daphne! Hermione!” A beautiful ghost with a slight baby bump glided over as the two girls climbed out of the trunk. “I’ve missed you!” It was Angelystor.

Daphne and Hermione both smiled. “You as well,” Daphne said. She couldn’t help thinking the ghost looked a lot more solid these days. So much magic in the air had to be doing her good.

Angelystor turned to the others. “And who are these two?” she asked with a warm smile.

“My lady,” said Harry, “may I present Luna Lovegood, of the Ancient and Noble House of Lovegood and Ginny Weasley, of the House of Weasley.”

Luna and Ginny both gave slight curtseys.

“A pleasure.” Angelystor turned back to Harry. “Is Heiress Black not with you?”

“Alexandra couldn’t make it. Next week, I hope.”

“Right.” Angelystor clapped her hands together and motioned for the girls and Harry to gather round. She then spoke of the wondrous magics of divination, mostly for the benefit of the two newcomers, both of whom listened with rapt attention. She spoke of the many spells she learned as a student at the Shoe, and of after her death—of the rise of Muggleborn Light Lord Dimwiddy, the role both divination and the ever-strengthening Albion Family Magics played in his Second Magical British Empire, and finally of his eventual defeat, the chaos that followed, and the subsequent establishment of the ICW.

Daphne had heard it all before but that didn’t matter. Angelystor spoke with more passion and strength of purpose than Binns ever did. After the introductory lecture, they split up and set to work on their individual projects. Hermione and Harry sat off to the side working on homework, Daphne practised controlling her inner eye with the large mirror set off to one side, and Ginny and Luna sat in the middle of the room with Angelystor, wands out, crystal balls in front of them, looking either giddy with excitement or relaxed with dreamy dreaminess. If by this point you need to be told which witch was which, then you haven’t been paying attention.

“The wand incantation is ‘videt immino,’ ” Angelystor said, repeating exactly the lesson she’d given the previous year. “the wand movement is three jabs diagonally upwards to the right, and a single small left spiral, along with the intention to know the severity of the threat you will face, all passed through your inner eye before being released from the tip of your wand and into the crystal ball at the exact end of the final spiral.” She smiled. “Remember, finding your inner eye is by far the most difficult part, so go slow and try to feel it out.”

Five minutes later, Luna Lovegood was rolling on the floor, screaming her lungs out, writhing in pain, eyes literally on fire.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Nearly four hundred miles away, in a dimly-lit room, deep, deep under London, a woman dressed all in grey with a hood that magically hid her entire face, jerked up sharply. On the shelf high above her desk, several arcane looking implements—dusty and squeaky after years of non-use—started, ponderously, to move.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Remember, finding your inner eye is by far the most difficult part, so go slow and try to feel it out,” Angelystor said. She floated backwards and studied the two girls carefully.

Daphne couldn’t help but be curious. She lowered her wand from the mirror in front of her, and turned to watch. Only then did she realise that Harry and Hermione had also set down their quills. Harry in particular seemed especially interested.

“Videt immino,” said Ginny, poking her wand into the crystal ball.

Nothing happened. Ginny pouted.

Luna still had her eyes closed.

“Try again,” Angelystor suggested.

Ginny raised her wand.

And then Luna’s eyes flew open, glowing white so brightly that shadows flickered across the dimly lit room.

Daphne gasped.

As though he’d been waiting for exactly this, Harry leapt to his feet, chair crashing to the floor behind him, just as Luna started to speak in a voice that was not her own. The words weren’t many, but by the time they were over, Daphne couldn’t help smiling. They were good words.

She stopped smiling when she saw Harry’s face.

Harry wasn’t smiling. His face was instead the colour of pure chalk.

“I need to go,” he started, but just as the last word left his mouth, all hell broke loose. Luna let out an ear piercing scream and the light in her eyes flared—brighter than the sun, brighter than burning magnesium. It filled the whole hut and moments later, she was on the floor, rolling around, screaming her head off.

Luna’s eyes were on fire.

“Luna!” Everyone scrambled to do something, but it was Harry who got there first. He grabbed the girl and forced away her hands—hands which had been engaged in a spirited attempt to claw out her own eyeballs. He jabbed his wand at her face, shouted an incantation, and dragged away the burning fire the way one might drag away a lassoed animal. Moments later, water splashed into two empty eye sockets.

Daphne flinched away. It wasn’t a pretty sight.

Luna kicked one last time and then went limp in Harry’s arms. She’d fainted.

“Hermione!” Harry shouted in a firm voice. “Help her!”

Hermione hurried over, waving and jabbing her wand like she was trying to swat a fly. Daphne recognised the spells as healer diagnostic chains.

“She’s not going to die for at least thirty seconds,” Hermione said quickly. “No, a minute—no five minutes—no, she’s good for at least thirty minutes, I think, although there are some signs here I don’t understand.”

“Anything you can do?”

“No, this is way beyond my level.”

“Take her to Madam Pomfrey. Contact me on our rings if anything critical comes up. There should be just enough range.” Harry marched towards the door.

“Where are you going?” Daphne asked, while Hermione continued to wave her wand over Luna.

“I have to make sure that only we hear what Luna just said.” And with that, Harry threw Daphne the trunk containing the spare broomsticks, shut the door behind him and shot up into the air, heading straight towards the nearest floo point to the shrieking shack,

The floo, despite what people who rarely use it are led to believe, is not instant. It might indeed only take a few minutes to get from the Burrow to London, but the Burrow is actually quite close to London. Hogwarts, on the other hand, is not. But fifteen minutes is still quicker than the next best alternative, and certainly quicker than say, broomstick or thestral.

Harry had snuck out of Hogwarts dozens of times before, but if sneaking out of Hogwarts shouldn’t be easy, then it is nothing compared to how easy it should not be to sneak into, say, the Department of Mysteries, which is why Harry Potter, now ducking into the floo of his Hogsmeade apartment, had no intention whatsoever to sneak.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

To the ministry at large he was Ian Mikenther—Cornwall Academy drop out, and ‘that cleaner guy’ they occasionally saw in the bathroom or canteen. That is to say they saw him using the bathroom and eating in the canteen, not cleaning them. But he had to be a cleaner—it stood to reason—he wore the uniform, a dust grey robe purpose made for getting grubby.

It never occurred to the vast majority of them that there was something fundamentally wrong about having human cleaners when they already had a large team of house elves—nor that there was,in fact, another group of people who walked around in dust grey robes—the only difference being that they always kept their hoods up.

It was way past midnight. The large entrance hall was filled with the eerie silence unique to places people expect to find loud and bustling. Ian blew on his cup of hot chocolate and made his way to the janitor’s service door, each foot step echoing in the empty space. He opened the door, walked to what looked like a perfectly normal stretch of corridor, and tapped on a bit of wall. The wall swung inwards to reveal a set of stairs.

When he reached his office, Ian sat down on his cheap swivel chair, took a sip of his hot chocolate, and got back to work on the rather finicky arithmancy calculations required to predict last quarter’s spread of the Albion Family Magics. Cornwall Academy hadn’t taught arithmancy. That had frustrated Ian no end. What it had taught was that muggle born students who experimented with magic not on the curriculum got a one way ticket to mind wipe street. It had been only sheer luck that saved him from waking up in a muggle coma ward.

The room was totally silent except for the ticking of the clock on the wall and the scratching of his magic quill on the paper. He focused on the work in front of him. F(x) becomes the derivative of the perenelle equation …

He’d only been working on the numbers for a few minutes when he heard footsteps in the outside corridor. They stopped outside his door. He didn’t look up. His office door opened with an unusually enthusiastic bang. Then he looked up. A not-plump but not-athletic woman poked her bespectacled head through. “C’mon! What are you still doing here?”

“Mary?”

“You’re going to miss it!”

“Miss what?” Ian stood up.

“You heave’t heard?”

“I was getting hot chocolate.”

“A prophecy’s coming through!”

“What?!”

“C’mon!”

Ian stumbled towards the door, all thoughts of arithmancy left behind, and tried to follow the rapidly retreating woman, his mind revving up into high gear. “How long has it been?” he asked. “Three years? Four?”

“Four years, one month, and twenty-four days,” Mary replied as they marched through an eternally revolving door and into the hall of prophecies. “We averaged one a week for a thousand years, and then, suddenly, nothing, and now … something!”

“Who gave it?”

“Well, we don’t know yet. The magic hasn’t got that far.”

They exited the hall and made their way down another corridor. The whole department seemed as empty as the rest of the building, which certainly wasn’t normal. Unspeakables often treated the idea of work/life balance as something to be optimised by merging the two as completely as possible. They tended to date only among their own, often through the ministry’s signature flying notes, which also spared the trouble of actually having to meet face-to-face. The reason for the department’s emptiness soon became apparent.

“Standing room only?” Ian said, loudly enough to be heard over the eight other people all pressed into the tiny office. Most of them were crowded around the desk, where an arcane piece of magical machinery was busy blowing smoke through a series of glass tubes, all twisty and turney like a muggle roller coaster.

“Ian!” shouted one of the mass, standing by a large cork board on the wall. “Want to update your bet before the orb rolls out?” The cork board was filled with newspaper clippings, official reports, and hand written notes, all attached with strings and randomly pointing to each other, giving the impression that a spider shitting string had tripped on LSD.

One official looking paper started:

Report on the Great Accounting Incident

July, 1989—September, 1989

A newspaper headline next to it read:

Daily Prophet

Lord Slytherin Takes his Seat

December, 1989

And what looked like an excerpt from a meeting transcript pinned over the top said:

“The centaurs have cracked, I tell you, Barty! Now they’re saying the stars themselves are wrong!”

In the middle of the cork-board someone had pinned up a piece of A4 printer paper titled, ‘The ‘Who is Lord Slytherin?’ Pool.’

Current odds

Long lost descendant of Salazar Slytherin—1:3

Jacob Greengrass or other high ranking member of the Gray—1:10

Non Human (half-breed)—1:15

Son or other relative of ‘He Who Must Not Be Named’—1:20

YouKnowWho—(This is not funny. Don’t even joke about things like this.)

Gray Lord Tebola—1:30

Nicholas Flamel—1:35

Incubus—1:40

Horcrux of Salazar Slytherin—1:50

Rogue Unspeakable—1:65

MaCUSA agent—1:70

Reincarnation of Salazar Slytherin 1:80

The Mafica—1:85

Abe no Seimei—1:98

The Emperor of the Magical Roman Empire—1:98

Quetzalcoatl—1:98

Dracula—1:105

Dimension traveller—1:150

Time traveller—1:165

Fate—1:195

Other Higher Power 1:225

Alien—1:500

Ian shook his head. “No thanks. I’ll stick to Occam’s razor. The simplest explanation is usually the right one.”

“Ah, but that’s the trick, isn’t it? Figuring out what is the simplest explanation.”

A voice from the table shouted, “It’s starting!”

All heads spun around.

Ian leaned in to see better.

A glass orb dropped out of a hopper and started to fill with smoke. In the middle of the desk, a small piece of parchment settled into the middle of the table. A quill dipped itself into a small pot of ink, moved over to the parchment, and started to write. In the silence of the room, the quill’s painfully slow scratching had the same general effect on the audience as being forced to watch paint dry, water boil, and wait for one of those old fashioned toasters that refuse to pop until you look away.

17th September, 1992—Heiress Luna Lovegood …

“Lovegood,” someone whispered.

“Aren’t they necromancers?”

“That was ages ago.”

… to Heiress Daphne Greengrass, …

From a long way away, through several layers of wall, a faint voice started to fade into hearing range. No one paid it any attention

“Both the Slytherin girls,” said an older woman Ian recognised by sight at the table.

… Vassal Hermione Jane Granger, …

The voice was getting closer, vaguely squeaky.

“And the Slytherin Vassal,” the woman said. “This is totally about him.”

… Ginevra Molly Weasley, …

“Damn, just how many people heard this thing?”

… and Lord …

Nine pairs of lungs breathed in sharply.

There was a loud ‘bang!,’ a rush of air, and the orb and paper ripped away from the table, just as the quill finishing writing …

… and Lord H—

A trail of ink scribbled down the paper at the end of the H as it flew towards the door.

“My Lord! You can’t just barge in here without an appointment!”

Nine faces turned towards the door. Ian’s stomach dropped at exactly the same moment as the magic washed over him. Lord Slytherin stood outlined in the doorway, tall, imposing, and exuding more raw power than he’d ever felt in his life. In that one moment, he seriously considered upgrading his bet to ‘Other Higher Power.’ Just behind Slytherin, a much smaller man wearing a security guard uniform bounced up and down, clearly trying to stop the masked lord, but without doing anything so bold as, say, actually pulling a wand on him.

“I believe in efficiency,” Slytherin said. He turned to leave and froze. Then he spun round again, waved a hand, and wandlessly summoned the betting pool right off the cork board.

Nine pairs of lungs forgot to breath.

The masked wizard read the paper thoroughly for several moments. Then he snorted and slapped it onto the nearest wall, where it stuck. “Keep up the good work, boys,” he said, and left, the security wizard slowly trailing behind him.

There was utter stillness. Then, once it was clear they weren’t all about to take a one way trip through the veil, everyone starting talking over each other. Theories were updated, numbers crunched, and the co-worker who ran the betting pool started to update the odds.

“You want in now, Ian? Fate’s been reduced to 1:145.”

Ian shrugged. He thought about his hot chocolate waiting for him in his office. “Put me down for four sickles.”

On the way back to his office he came across the security guard, nervously milling around with the air of someone who’s never been in a place before and can’t quite believe they’re there now.

“You need help finding your way out?”

The man jerked on hearing his voice. “What? Oh no, I … I think I’m okay. It’s this door right here, isn’t it?” He pointed to the door that led to the public entrance, rather than the secret entrance Ian had used earlier.

Ian nodded.

“Good. Good, I just wanted to be sure.” He wiped his brow, then looked Ian up and down as though he’d only just noticed him. “Wow, unspeakables really are untidy aren’t they?”

Ian tilted his head.

“I mean,” the man continued. “They must be, to need so many of you lot down here.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Daphne sat next to Luna’s bed in the hospital wing. Luna still hadn’t woken up. Ginny and Hermione had both left for the Slytherin dorms, ushered out by a truly baffled Madam Pomfrey. Daphne managed to finagle permission to stay by playing the sister betrothed card. On the other side of the bed, Pandora Lovegood softly stroked Luna’s hair.

Behind her, Madam Pomfrey was having a conversation with Lord Lovegood. The conversation was almost out of hearing range, but not quiet.

“Utterly shocked, your lordship. I assure you this wasn’t anything to do with us.”

“I believe you. What else can you tell me?”

“We’ll be able to re-grow her eyes, no problem, but it will take time and be very painful. Eyes are nothing like bones. Bones just need a dose of skele-gro. Eyes need continual careful wand work.”

“How long?”

“Around a week, but …” The ‘but’ hung in the air like a noose.

“… But what?”

“I’m sorry to have to tell you this, but whatever happened to your daughter caused a huge magical surge through her body and it wasn’t only her outer eyes that were damaged. It also totally shattered her inner eye, and there’s no known way to fix it. Any talent that she might have had for divination is gone.”

“I see.”

Daphne clenched her hands on her knees. If she closed her eyes, she could still hear Luna’s screams ringing in her ears. It had been so loud.

Plenty of things happened over the next ten minutes, all of them triggered by Luna waking up. The first words out of her mouth were, “Can someone please turn on the lights?” followed quickly by, “Umff! Is that you, Mum? I assume it is, because Ginny doesn’t have boobs that big and Harry doesn’t have boobs at all.”

Immediately following, Madam Pomfrey cast several diagnostic charms, Lord Lovegood took up station by his wife’s side, and Daphne whispered where Harry went into Luna’s ear when no one else was watching.

Daphne was just walking back to the Slytherin Dorms after being finally dismissed by Madam Pomfrey when a hand wearing the Slytherin Lordship ring appeared out of thin air and motioned her into an alcove.

“My Lord?” Daphne asked, once she’d stepped inside.

“How’s Luna?” Harry’s voice asked.

Daphne told him.

There was a rush of cloth, and the invisibility cloak enveloped her, pressing her right up against Harry. Daphne’s breath caught.

“I want to talk to her,” Harry said. “I want you to be lookout.”

Daphne nodded her understanding and together they made their way back to the hospital wing, soon arriving again at Luna’s bedside. The room was bathed in total darkness.

Daphne cast her magic eye and sent it into Madam Pomfrey’s office.

Madam Pomfrey was sitting at her writing desk, nose deep in paper.

“She’s busy,” Daphne whispered.

“Daph?” Luna whispered.

“And Harry,” Harry whispered.

Daphne thought she felt Harry cast a privacy spell.

“You’re back.”

“I am.”

“Daph said you went to the Department of Mysteries.”

“I did.”

“Does that mean I gave a … ?”

Daphne felt like slapping herself. Of course. Those who gave prophecies didn’t remember giving them.

“You did.”

“And is everything okay?”

“You mean, apart from the obvious?” Harry asked.

The image of Luna’s eyeball-less face flashed through Daphne’s mind again.

“Yes,” he said. “I got there in time to grab it before anyone else heard it or connected me with him.”

Luna let out a relieved sigh. “That’s good. Was it a good prophecy?”

“Yes,” said Harry, his voice containing only a hint of uncertainty. “I think so.”

“What did it say?”

Daphne’s voice left her mouth as little more than a murmur. “Where the land meets the wind, find the sign of the dragon’s roar. There awaits you in the silt, ancient magics and gold and more.”

They weren’t words easy to forget, especially with what happened immediately afterwards. She’d been turning them over in her mind at every free moment she had, trying to spot any kind of meaning apart from the brain dead obvious one.

Luna giggled. “It rhymes.”

“Yes, more poem than prophecy,” said Harry. “And not in anyway ambiguous.”

“We could really use a financial wind fall,” Daphne said. “So long as we’re paying off the debt on the manor, it’s like we’re constantly fighting with our hands tied behind our back. We’ve had to turn down so many good opportunities.”

“Indeed.”

Silence descended on the room.

Daphne watched Madam Pomfrey re-ink her quill before starting on another piece of parchment.

“Luna?” said Harry’s voice.

“Yes, Harry?”

“You know I value your council, right?”

“Yes, Harry.”

“And you know I trust you, right?”

“Yes, Harry.”

“Is there any thing we need to talk about right now?”

Silence again.

“Yes, Harry.”

“What?”

“Alex.”

Silence.

“What about Alex?”

“You’re going about her the wrong way.”

“Go on.”

“Tell me about when you first met her.”

“You mean this time around or before?”

“This time around.”

Daphne listened in interest as Harry recounted in detail about how he first met Alexandra outside number twelve Grimmauld Place—how she’d refused to study occlumency with him and then made a deal with Harry to trade books from their respective libraries. She’d obviously gotten a lot better since then, but Daphne could definitely still see bits of the little brat Harry now described.

“I’ve known Alex all my life,” Luna eventually said when Harry had finished. “You couldn’t have handled that first meeting any better, given what you then knew about her.”

“I didn’t know if I could trust her.” Harry’s voice sounded rather quiet and not because he was whispering.

“Alex will not submit to anyone until they have earned her respect. Right now, she respects me and Ginny more than you. Lord Slytherin is like a rock—sticks that attack him break themselves on him. Harry Potter is like a stream—a stick smacked into him does little to either the stream or the stick. Alex respects the rock more than the stream.”

“I smack her around a lot in combat training.”

“She knows you are powerful. She knows lots of people are powerful. Power by itself isn’t what matters.”

“I can’t tell her I’m Lord Slytherin until she respects me as Harry Potter.”

“Then the next time she refuses to follow you as Harry Potter, you must be the rock rather than the stream. You will have to unify the two eventually anyway—when you go public as Lord Slytherin.”

Harry went silent.

In her office, Madam Pomfrey stood up from her chair and stretched.

“Harry,” Daphne said urgently. “We might be having company soon.”

“Understood.” Harry paused again before speaking. “Thank you for your council, Luna. I believe you are right.”

“I serve only you, my lord.”

“Night, Luna,” Daphne whispered, and the two of them made their way out of the hospital wing.

They were some way away before Harry whispered, “Do we have any more details of Draco’s plans for Alex?”

And so Daphne spent the rest of their walk back to the Slytherin Dungeons updating Harry on the details she’d gathered about how Heir Malfoy was planning to deal with Alexandra Black.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny lay on her front in her four poster bed, pouring over the marauders map with the countenance of a bored channel surfer. The most interesting thing going on was Percy in an empty classroom with a girl called Penelope Clearwater. Both their dots were right up against the wall and had been like that for some time. Ginny filed that under ‘perfect blackmail material’. In another part of the castle, headmaster Lockhart was pacing in his office.

The dot marked Virgo Malfoy had been sitting in its dormitory for hours now. Didn’t the thing ever move?

Her thoughts drifted to the dagger hidden in her trunk and another twinge of guilt pinged through her, but she shook it off. One night in her dreams, Harry had handed her a copy of that exact dagger and spread his arms wide.

“Are you sure you want to do this?” he’d asked.

“Yes,” she’d replied.

“Okay. Then do it.”

Ginny darted forward and thrust the dagger straight at Harry. It needed a surprisingly large amount of force to pierce his robes, but once through sank into him like, like, well like a hot knife.

Ginny winced as the blood oozed over her hands and Harry gasped out in pain. She kept herself together by constantly telling herself that it wasn’t real, that this was just a dream, that she wasn’t really killing Harry. They both collapsed to the ground, Ginny forcing the dagger in further, putting all her weight onto it. Harry gasped one final breath, then his eyes closed, then his body went limp.

“Well done.”

Ginny’s heart leapt into her throat. She jumped up and whirled around. “Don’t do that!”

Harry—another Harry that is—smiled at her. The Harry on the floor faded away.

“How did that feel?” Harry asked.

“Horrible.”

“Are you still sure you want to do it?”

Ginny glared at him. “Yes! It was only horrible because it was you. You’re not the diary.”

Harry nodded “We still need to get you some real world experience before you go after it though, so sometime in the next few days, I want you to sneak out at night, go down to Hagrid’s chicken coops, and do to them what you just did to me.”

Ginny had looked at the dagger in her hands and frowned. Then looked back and nodded.

She hadn’t done it. She’d snuck out, gone down to Hagrid’s coops, broken in—just to prove to herself that she could—and then headed back. Killing the chickens just didn’t feel right. Her family kept lots of chickens at the Burrow, and she’d helped prepare countless of them, but killing them just to prove she could didn’t feel right. It was needless killing. She knew she could already, but she had a feeling Harry wouldn’t see it that way. And afterwards, when she got back, she’d told Harry she had done it. It was that one little fib that now gnawed away at her like a wood beetle through old teak.

In the Gryffindor first year girl’s dormitory, the Diary still hadn’t moved, but it wasn’t in bed. Ginny glared at the map. What the hell could a teenage dark lord be doing for so long in there?

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the Gryffindor first year girl’s dormitory, Virgo Malfoy sat in his trunk, stirring a cauldron of bubbling potion with the precision of a German robot watch maker. The young girl in his mind was being annoying again, insisting that girls his age should be building friendships, not trying to tear them apart. He ignored her, although with every passing day that little feat was becoming more and more difficult. In front of him, a stained potions book was set open to a page marked hate potion.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was the end of another school day at Madam Goose’s Home for the Magically Gifted. In the large steel toe, students were forming an orderly queue in front of the school’s main floo place. In the heel, a couple of rather elderly house elves cleaned classrooms with the exaggerated slowness that comes with age and indifference. And up behind the laces, the boarders—over half the student body—were throwing bags onto floors, flopping down onto pastel coloured patchwork quilts, and saying thing like, “Finally,” followed shortly by, “Oh god, please don’t tell me we still have homework, as well.”

In one dorm room, several older girls already had their books open and their notes strewn around them, although there didn’t seem to be much actual work going on.

One girl said, “I’m hoping to get a job with the ministry. It’d be fascinating seeing how the wizarding world is run.”

Another girl said, “I’ll probably end up with Honeydukes, or WitchCo, or one of the other big houses. My grades aren’t good enough for anything else.”

A third girl said, “Paul told me he’d help get me into Kings Cross. He said I’d be perfect for it.”

The second girl gave her a weak smile. “Must be nice having an older boyfriend. I don’t think I’m pretty enough for the portkey port.”

“Oh, Jane, no! You’re beautiful!” said the first girl. She was the kind of person who believes that true beauty is a function of confidence and that everyone would be a lot happier if they just believed in themselves. After all, she went out without make-up or properly done-up hair all the time and boys still tripped over themselves to please her.

Jane shifted uncomfortably.

“Clare, tell her she’s beautiful!”

The fourth occupant of the room looked up from where she’d been nose deep in a loose leaf folder, sitting crossed-legged on the shaggy rug that covered the room’s floor from wall to boot-leather wall. She had an iron collar fixed around her neck with no sign of clasp or hinge. Clare Cooper pursed her lips. “Jane, all jobs have requirements, but you can’t truly know what they are until you apply. If you don’t apply, you will needlessly limit yourself.”

The first girl looked appalled. “Clare! What the hell?”

“Also, you need to stop letting your mum dress you. She has terrible taste.”

“Clare!”

“No, it’s okay,” said Jane, quietly. “She’s right.”

“She’s not ‘right’!”

“Yes, she is!” Jane snarled.

The first girl reared back, shocked at the force in the girl’s words.

“There are potions,” suggested the girl with the older boyfriend.

“But they’re expensive,” said the first girl. She was looking at Jane as though she’d never quite seen her before.

“Yeah, but they work. And they only take seconds to drink in the mornings—not, like, an hour. She could skip the ones for her hair and figure. They’re the most pricy ones. She just needs to even out her face a little bit. Look there’s an article all about them in Witch Weekly.”

Jane took the magazine and started reading with the intensity of a blowtorch channelling fiendfyre.

“I suppose it can’t hurt,” The first girl finally conceded. Her name was Sarah and she’d been the de facto leader of most of the girls in her year group since they’d first been introduced to the magical world six years ago. Clare’s friends had graduated at the end of the previous year leaving the mysterious woman unattached. Inviting her into her circle had been a spur of the moment decision—one that certainly had nothing to do with her connections with one of the most powerful lords in the country. No, Sarah thought to herself, she would never be that mercenary. “So, what are you reading?” she asked the woman in question. “That’s not a school book, is it?”

Clare shook her head. “Notes from defence against the dark arts class.” The girl with the older boyfriend frowned. “I’ve never heard of that class.”

“It’s taught at Hogwarts.”

“Oh,” the girl said, “Hogwarts.”

“What’s it about?” Sarah asked.

“Mostly about how to defend yourself against dark spells and creatures.”

Sarah frowned in confusion. “But if we have problems like that we’re supposed to go to St. Mungo’s or call the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures.”

Clare shrugged.

“Are you thinking about getting a job there?” Sarah asked.

“Probably not.”

“How’d you get those notes anyway?”

“My guardian’s daughter gave me copies. She’s going through Hogwarts in the same year I am. I have notes from charms, transfiguration, and potions too.”

“Not culture or safety? What about lit?”

“Hogwarts doesn’t teach those classes.”

“It doesn’t?”

“I think the assumption is if you’re going to Hogwarts you already know that stuff.”

“What does Hogwarts teach?”

“That Shoe doesn’t? Defence, arithmancy, ancient runes, astronomy, healing, and care of magical creatures.”

Sarah looked horrified. “You’re not studying all of that are you?”

“No, just defence.”

Jane looked up from Witch Weekly. “But what does studying defence actually look like? I mean, what do you learn?”

“Mostly you learn the counters to all sorts of dark spells. Or you learn the magic to control various pests and other dark creatures. You also learn some of the lesser dark spells yourself, so you have something to practise on.”

The three girl’s looked at her with widening eyes. “You know dark magic?” Sarah asked in a whisper.

“A bit.”

“I’ve heard rumours about dark magic,” said the girl with the older boyfriend. Her name was Henrietta. She looked around the room before lowering her voice to match Sarah’s whisper. “I’ve heard there’s a spell that completely locks up your body so you can’t move even a muscle. You can still see and hear and everything, but you can’t do anything else.”

“That sounds like the full body bind.”

Three pairs of eyes grew wider.

“Can you do it?”

“No, I haven’t got that far yet.”

“What can you do?”

“Well, there’s this spell that causes your legs to turn to jelly. Not literally,” she quickly added, on seeing their horrified expressions. “I mean it makes you fall over. Your legs just give out from under you.”

“Oh, that doesn’t sound too bad,” Sarah said.

“Could you show us?” Henrietta asked. Her eyes gleamed.

“We’ll get into terrible trouble if someone finds out.” Jane looked around nervously. “We’re not supposed to play with magic.”

“No one would find out,” Henrietta said. “You can reverse it, Clare, right?”

Clare nodded.

Henrietta grinned. “Do it on me, then, I don’t mind.”

“You sure?”

“Yeah.”

“Okay then.” Clare withdrew her yew wand from the inside pocket of her robes.

The other girls eyed its movement the way a group of isolated pacific islanders might eye a smartphone they’d been told was about to ring.

Clare concentrated and moved her wand in slow, careful strokes—up, down, cross, swirl right, swirl left, flick. The movements were slow, deliberate, and took several seconds to complete. She pointed her wand at Henrietta and said, “locomotor wibbly.”

Henrietta let out a small squeak and fell over backwards.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It really was frustrating how slowly everything progressed here, Clare thought, making her way through the leather corridors towards the floo in the toe. Hermione’s notes showed just how quickly Hogwarts students moved by comparison, and her being around a decade older than her classmates wasn’t helping matters. It depressed Clare no end to see the suspicious looks her teachers threw her for achieving what she knew full-well to be a normal learning rate. Hell, compared to Hermione, she was practically a tortoise, and wasn’t that just the cherry on the top of the magical cake? Easily out-paced by a thirteen year old.

Clare reached the floo, threw a pinch into the flames, and said, “Granger Cottage.”

As she rushed through the warm air like a pingpong ball through a vacuum pump, she pulled a book from her bag and paper-clipped the current page. One of the few advantages of living right at the very end of the floo line was that you didn’t have to pay attention to where you needed to get out.

One and a half chapters later, she stepped out of the floo in the Granger’s house on Gairsay island.

“I’m home!”

There was no answer.

Clare wandered into the kitchen, put her bag down on the counter, opened the cupboard, pulled out a WitchCo forever-ready meal, popped it in the oven, and tapped said oven with her wand. A pillar of flame shot out from a hole in the top. Twenty seconds later there was a little ping noise, the flame stopped, and the oven door opened. Clare retrieved the now piping hot meal and was about to turn her back on the oven when a hitherto unnoticed panel in the front opened, and what looked like a wooden toy lizard in a tiny wizard’s hat popped out on the end of a spring.

“We’re very sorry,” the lizard said, “but you appear to have salamanders in your oven. Please contact your nearest ministry representative for immediate removal. Failure to do so will void your warranty. Thank you.” The wooden lizard bounced back into the oven and the tiny panel shut.

Clare stared.

She eyed the oven door and then the meal in her hands with considerable suspicion. Then she made her way to the door that led to the basement.

It wouldn’t be unfair to say that Clare Cooper had a bit of a chip on her shoulder about the ministry. The prisoner collar around her neck was a ministry prisoner collar. During her time in the wizarding world, Clare Cooper had seen many things, many of which she’d much rather not have. Many of those things had been people, usually in various states of undress, and many of those people had worked for the ministry.

In fact, her feelings towards the ministry didn’t constitute so much of a chip on her shoulder, as a whole McCains frozen oven bag, and were just about as cold.

Having said that, and despite what a reasonable person might be led to believe, Clare hadn’t come out of her ordeal in Knock-Turn Alley with a pathological loathing of sex itself. Far from it. Which was just as well, because life with the Grangers when Hermione wasn’t about was one large amusing incident after another.

She did try to be polite though.

As Clare descended the stairs to the basement, she made loud stamping sounds with her boots. Half way down she paused and coughed loudly. When she reached the large wooden door at the bottom, she spent far longer than necessary rattling the door handle.

When she finally entered the massive machine-filled cavern with the small lake and tunnel, it was to find Dan standing to one side nonchalantly while a flushed Emma smoothed down her robes.

“Afternoon,” Dan called to her in a far too cheery a voice.

“There are salamanders in the oven,” Clare called back, walking over to the main work area, pausing only to bend down and snatch up a pair of knickers lying on the floor.

“That’s the second time,” Emma said, pocketing the now proffered underwear with mild embarrassment.

“I’m pretty sure Clare’s seen you without your knickers on more than—”

Clare hurriedly cleared her throat.

Dan smirked.

“Salamanders?”

“You were at school,” Emma said. “We called Jacob and he took care of it.”

“You called a wizarding lord to do pest removal?”

“He didn’t come by personally. He sent a woman. I think I have her floo address somewhere.”

“Oh, good.” Clare shuffled. “I hate still being so useless.”

What she really meant, but which was left unsaid, was that she really hated being so vulnerable. The Grangers understood though.

“You’ll get there. How are Hermione’s notes helping?”

“So much,” Clare said, suddenly far more animated. “It’s crazy how much better Hogwarts lessons are.”

“Really?” Dan pointed to a letter on a table. “She sent the latest set, by the way.”

“Fantastic.” Clare scooped up the package. “And how is Hermione doing?”

Dan and Emma exchanged a meaningful look.

“Fine,” Emma said. “We’ll see how she’s doing after her birthday.”

“Why? What’s happening on her birthday?”

“Wizards start formally dating then.”

Clare considered this. “That seems pretty normal, all things considered. Thirteen is about when girls and boys start noticing each other, right? I was noticing boys far earlier than that.”

Dan indicated a stack of letters next to the package Clare had just picked up. “Let me put it like this,” he said. “When we first had Hermione, I never thought that one day, while Hermione was dating boys, Emma and I would be dating their parents.”

“Oh.”

“Many of them aren’t sure what to make of us. We confuse them. Are we like them, with all their knowledge and understanding of wizarding culture? Or are we ignorant muggles who wouldn’t know which end of a wand is which? Some assume one, others assume the other, and we’ve had some who switch back and forth, even within the same paragraph. Those ones tend to be the most patronising.”

“What are you going to do?”

“Work through them with Slytherin when he gets back from where ever he always disappears off to,” Dan said.

“And if he doesn’t show in time, I’ll ask Lady Greengrass,” Emma added.

“But he should do,” Dan said. “We have some stuff he asked us to acquire.”

Clare nodded and looked around the cluttered workshop. “So, how’s the sub project going?”

Dan’s face went from seriousness to boyish enthusiasm in a heart beat. “Oh! Oh! Oh! We’ve had a breakthrough! It’s awesome!”

“We think we’ve had a breakthrough,” Emma corrected him. “Clare, be a dear and get changed, would you?” She handed Clare her swimsuit.

“Seriously?” Clare eyed the chilly water of the underground lake.

“And here’s the details for the warming charm.” Emma thumped a thick book onto the table. “It’s pretty advanced, but they say motivation is a great aid to learning.”

It took a couple of hours—a couple of frustratingly cold hours—but eventually Clare succeeded in casting the warming charm on herself. “Now what?” she asked.

Emma unclamped something from the inside of a large milling machine and handed it to Clare. It was a broomstick.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

He’s late, Alex thought. For someone with so little apparently to do, Harry Potter could certainly keep people waiting.

“Luna should be out of the hospital wing soon,” Hermione said. “Healer Pomfrey still doesn’t have any clue what caused her magical surge and I don’t blame her. I haven’t been able to find any reference in any of my healer books to such a thing happening during prophecy before.”

Alexandra, Hermione, Ginny, and Daphne were all sitting in one of the many abandoned classrooms in one of Hogwarts’ upper spires. Each one had a pumpkin pasty they’d saved from lunch.

“That’s good,” Alex said, halfway through her pasty. “It isn’t the same without Luna.” She’d gotten so used to Luna being close that the dorm room felt strangely empty without her.

The door opened and Harry walked in. “Ready girls?”

Ginny, Hermione, and Daphne all got to their feet, followed shortly after by Alex. Half-eaten pasties found their way into pockets and bags. Alex took out a single compartment shrinking trunk, unshrunk it, tossed her pasty inside, and quickly shut the lid behind her, smirking to herself as she did so. Combat training was getting too predictable. She had a surprise for Potter this time.

“Ready,” Ginny said, bouncing on the tips of her toes with her wand already out.

Harry nodded. “Before we begin. We need to talk about the situation with Alex.”

Alex perked up. “What about it?”

“Draco has been petitioning the various families of the Dark to help him deal with you, and he’s nearly got enough of them on board. Probably sometime in the next few weeks, Heir Malfoy will approach you in the Slytherin Common room and give you an ultimatum—swear yourself to his loyalty during your time at Hogwarts, or get the living shit kicked out of you.”

Alex nodded to herself. She’d been expecting something like that. She’d have to speed up her plans, but she could handle it. In the worst case, she’d take the punishment and simply refuse to submit.

“Obviously, this isn’t optimal,” Harry continued, “So when Draco approaches Alex, the rest of us will be hiding under cloak and disillusionment nearby, and when he—”

Alex’s thought’s screeched to a halt. “Hang on!” she interjected. “This is my project.”

You could have heard a pin drop.

Hermione opened her mouth to say something, but Harry waved her quiet. “No. Alex, please do go on.”

Alexandra hesitated. Something about the way Potter had said that last sentence seemed subtly different from normal. She ignored the feeling and plunged on anyway.

“I’m in charge of this project. Slytherin gave it to me. It’s mine. I already have a plan and I’m perfectly capable of completing it on my own, thank you.”

“What is this plan?”

“I don’t have to tell you.”

More silence. Then, “I think I am going to have to insist.”

“Insist all you want, I’m not telling.”

“Alexandra, this is a team effort. If you’re not willing to work together, then I will have to take steps.”

“Oh, what are you going to do? Go whingeing to Slytherin?”

“No, actually. This has nothing to do with Slytherin. Let me guess. Your plan was going to be something like, ‘take the beating and not give in?’ ”

“What of it?”

“Well, if that’s your plan, then I feel the need to test your ability to pull it off.”

A little voice in the back of Alexandra’s mind told her this wasn’t going the way it usually did. She ignored it, crossed her arms and scoffed. “You don’t have the balls.”

There was a subtle shifting in the room. She looked around. Ginny and Daphne were backing away from her, Daphne leading a worried looking Hermione in one direction while Ginny retreated in the other, leaving Alex alone in the middle of the room. She turned back to Harry.

“Submit,” Harry said.

“No.”

The magic slammed into Alex like a tidal wave and sent her spinning across the room. She hit the ground hard and jerked her head up, adrenaline surging through her body as her whole being went into fight mode. Her wand leapt to her hand without her even thinking about it. “Tumultus irrumator!”

Black chains shot out from her wand. She leapt to her feet, only to be blasted off them again moments later. Pain stabbed through her. Anger flowed. She shielded herself and charged towards her enemy. If she could get ahold of him …

Again she was blasted off her feet. She rolled on the floor before falling to a stop.

“Submit.” The voice was as hard as diamond.

Alex clenched her fists on the floor and raised her head. “No!”

Spells fired towards her. Not raw magic this time, but real hexes and jinxes. Alex snarled and shielded and dodged and countered. Everything felt clearer, the room seemed so bright, the colours vibrant, the pain making everything clear as crystal. A jelly-legs jinx flew towards her. She dodged it be mere inches. A slug belching hex splashed into the floor where she’d been standing only a split second earlier.

An expelliarmus ripped her wand from her grasp. She caught it in a summoning charm while it was only half way to him, but not before a stinging hex zipped past it, heading straight for her face. Time seemed to slow down. Magic intent pooled on her finger tips. She pushed it outwards and swiped.

The stinging hex bounced off her fingers.

Her wand flew back into her hand.

She looked at the wand in her hands, then at her fingers. Triumph roared through her. She’d done it! She’d swatted a spell! She laughed, loud and clear in the middle of her battlefield.

A flurry of spells shot towards her and she could see them. Everyone of them! After trying so hard for so long! Her arm became a blur, catching each and every one of them. “Hah! Yes! Suck on that, Potter!”

The floor in front of her melted and a giant stone lion leaped at her. She had just enough time to scream in fury before it crashed into her, pinning her to the ground.

“Submit.”

“Fuck you!”

The lion picked her up and threw her across the room. “Tumultus irrumator!” Her black chains wrapped around the monstrous statue. His flame whip shredded them. “Bombarda Maxima!”

The front of the lion exploded only to reform moments later.

Another wave of banishing magic slammed into her, sending her tumbling across the room again. She rolled and skidded and came to a stop right in front of her trunk. Potter still hadn’t moved from where he’d started. Well this would make him move. Alex scrambled up off the floor, gripped the edges of the trunk, and threw open the lid.

The latent connection in her mind snapped into sharp focus. She sent out a command.

A leg appeared from the trunk, followed quickly by the large body attached to it, squeezing through the much smaller opening in utter defiance of the laws of geometry. It was furry, had five legs, a manically grinning human-ish face—filled to the brim with dagger like teeth—and most importantly, was highly magically resistant.

The inferius quintaped skittered beside her and stood perfectly still.

Potter hadn’t lowered his wand. He gave no sign of surprise or fright at the XXXXX inferius magical beast in front of him.

Alex snarled, leapt on its back, and commanded it to charge.

It did.

It leapt through the air straight at Potter. It’s trajectory, a perfect arc, all the way from one side of the room to the other. Alex shielded herself behind her steed’s mass, waiting for the inevitable banishing charm. But the banishing charm never came. They crashed down onto the space where Potter had been standing. Alex jerked her head up, turning it this way and that, looking for her target.

“Submit.”

Alex felt a chill straight down her spine. The voice was right behind her. Before the shiver had time to reach the bottom of her spine, something grabbed the collar of her robes, and yanked her roof-wards. She screamed.

Beneath her, the stone lion pounced on her quintaped.

She reached up behind her, grabbed the wrist holding her, and tried to crush it, but all this resulted in was a warning spark of elemental lightning straight through her body.

She gasped and craned her neck to see behind her.

Potter was flying in mid air.

“Submit.”

“Not going to!”

Potter threw her.

She screamed as she once again fell, landed heavily, and skidded across the floor. She came to rest, and slowly clambered back up to her feet, flinching and wincing, her wand held tightly in a hand that hung limply. Her body ached. Her clothes felt like sandpaper on her skin, dipped in vinegar and salt. Everything hurt. But she couldn’t give up. She couldn’t. She mustn’t. But it hurt so badly.

He descended back down to the ground like a dementor from a horror book. In between them, off to one side, the stone lion had her quintaped pinned to the floor.

She looked into his eyes and saw nothing but hardness. No mercy. And in that moment, Alex understood. He would not stop until she’d said the words—even if he needed to keep going all night. It was hopeless. Anger welled up in her. Frustration, bitterness, resentment, but most of all disgust—disgust at herself for being weak. Potter was only a year older than her. She shouldn’t lose to him this badly.

She felt the disgust mould itself in her chest, felt it add to the anger, the humiliation, the unfairness of it all, channelled it all into the tip of her wand, pointed it her enemy, and screamed, “CRUCIO!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“CRUCIO!”

Hermione gasped. Her wand flew into her hand.

“No!” Daphne’s hand gripped her wrist.

“But she’s—!”

“—Look at Harry.”

Hermione looked. Harry wasn’t writhing on the ground in pain. “But she did try to cast it!”

“Yes. It’s wonderful!”

That made Hermione stop. She turned to Daphne and found triumph sparkling in her eyes. “I don’t understand.”

“She trusts us, Hermione. In front of four witnesses she cast an unforgivable. Don’t you see?” Daphne smiled a tiny smile. “Before, Harry wasn’t sure if he could trust her. Now he knows he can. Whatever happens from now on, no matter what, Alexandra Black is ours.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The grounds of Hogwarts castle were quiet and peaceful, giving no hint that up in one of the towers, a battle of wills and magic was raging.

“CRUCIO!”

Alex felt her last chance leave her wand, travel straight at Potter, and strike him clean in the chest. Nothing happened. FUCK!

“Oh, Alex.” The voice was deep and powerful and hauntingly familiar. “That spell requires a lot more than mere frustration.”

The rage still flowed through her, but tinted with something else now—apprehension.

“Perhaps you need to see how dark magic is really done.”

The air was getting heavier, the light from the windows, dimmer. Alex wanted to shiver. She wanted to give up and submit. Everything hurt and Potter was as unbreakable as a mountain. Nevertheless she managed to pull herself together, straighten her back, look right into his hard eyes, and say, “Show me.”

Potter flicked his wand up, flicked it back, flicked it forward, and to Alex’s horrified disbelief, yelled, “Malus ignis totalus diabolus!”

Fiendfyre. Alex knew very well what fiendfyre was, and just how dead they all now were. It raged out from Potter’s wand, roaring and burning, billowing outwards and upwards, searingly hot, and from the main fireball, animals surged, eating each other, turning in on themselves in a fury of cannibalistic rage, each victim feeding the victor, growing larger and larger, until finally, a huge flaming snake, larger than any beast Alex had ever seen, emerged and hissed in the roar of the fire. It dived to the side, and consumed her quintaped in an instant, melting the stone lion until it was nothing but slag on the floor. Then it reared over her. Alex couldn’t move. She couldn’t breath. She was the mouse before the snake and every part of her mind screamed in terror.

A warm stream ran down her inner thigh.

“sssssSSSSSssss!” Harry hissed.

The beast dived at her. Alex flinched, shut her eyes, and just managed to scream out, “PLEASE!” before heat wrapped all around her.

After several moments of not burning into oblivion, she snapped open her eyes to find herself in the coils of the fiendfyre snake, not close enough to burn, but close enough to slowly cook. The snake’s head was looking down at her from only a few metres away.

“You submit?” Harry asked.

She screamed out, “YES! YES! I SUBMIT! PLEASE!”

“To Harry Potter?”

“YES!”

The snake tilted its head at her.

Harry hissed something at the snake. It backed off, but not before giving her one last hungry look.

Harry waved his wand and the fiendfyre slowly shrank, growing smaller and smaller, until it finally winked out of existence.

Alex felt her breathing, hard and fast, her heart still pounding, her limbs shaking.

Harry looked at her from across the room and said, “Crawl to me.”

Even on hands and knees burning from heat and batted from bruises, Alex scrabbled to obey. She ignored the pain and when she reached him, kept her head down, looking at his feet.

“Kiss my hand.”

Alex raised her head, sought out his hand, found it, and without hesitating, kissed the back of it with trembling lips.

Then she stopped and stared. There was a ring on Potter’s hand. In fact, there were several, but the other’s weren’t important. This ring was though. This ring … but that was impossible. To have this ring, Potter would have to be …

Alexandra slowly raised her head to search out Harry’s eyes. She found them. They weren’t cold and hard any more, rather they told a tale of weariness and understanding.

And in a small, quiet voice, Alex said, “Oh.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Five minutes later, Hermione, Ginny, Daphne, Alexandra, and Harry were safely ensconced in Hermione’s trunk. Ginny and Daphne sat off to one side, watching as Hermione prodded away at yet another of Alexandra’s massive bruises. Alex winced as it slowly faded away. They’d already had to apply liberal quantities of huntsman’s sorrow on her cuts and scrapes. It was a good thing wizards were naturally more robust than muggles or else she’d for sure have a lot worse than that.

“I still don’t see … how?” Alex asked.

“Patience,” Harry said. He was fishing memories out of his head and into the pensieve Hermione used to teach the muggleborns.

Alex lapsed back into silence.

When he was done, Harry beckoned Alex over to him, they both touched the liquid, and disappeared into the pensieve with a loud whoosh sound.

The three remaining girls all looked at each other.

“Wow,” Hermione breathed. “I knew Harry was powerful, but, wow.”

“I nearly wet myself,” Ginny said.

“Alex did wet herself,” Daphne supplied.

“I don’t blame her.” Hermione stood, walked over to the pensieve, and looked down into the swirling memories. “You don’t think we went too far, do you?”

“No,” Daphne replied quickly. “Alex needed that, even if it was terrifying.”

Ginny grinned. “I thought it was kinda hot.”

“Oh, ha ha. How long have you been waiting to say that?”

“Since he casually waved his hand and dismissed a friggin’ fire demon.”

Hermione rolled her eyes.

“He was all like, ‘Yeah, I’m done with you now, thanks.’ ” Ginny put on a snooty face and dismissively waved her hand.

Daphne and Hermione both smiled.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Alex landed with a jolt. She looked around. They were still in the castle, but now they were in the dungeons. Moments later, Potter—no, Lord Slytherin, landed beside her.

“Hogwarts?” she asked.

“Fifty years ago. Look.”

Alex looked. In front of them, a student was crouched over a box, except the student in question was huge.

“C’mon … gotta get yeh outta here … c’mon now … in the box …”

Suddenly, an older boy leapt from behind a corner—a Slytherin prefect. “Evening, Rubeus,” the boy said in a sharp voice.

A door slammed shut. “What yer doin’ down here, Tom?”

“Bringing you to justice, that’s what.” The boy had tears in his eyes and the same jet black hair as Harry. “Everyone knows how I felt about her, and you—! You—!”

Alex narrowed her eyes. Those tears looked fake.

Rubeus’s own eyes widened. “That weren’t never me!”

“No.” The boy’s voice went from angry to cold. “It wasn’t. It was your pet. Monster’s don’t make good pets.”

“It never killed no one!”

They continued to argue several moments longer, then the Slytherin prefect attacked. An acromantula burst out from the door Rubeus had been guarding and fled down the corridor. Tom tried to get a spell off on it, but Rebeus bellowed, “NOOOOOOO!” tackled him to the ground, and seized his wand.

Poor situational awareness, Alex thought. Luna or Ginny would eat him for breakfast.

The world swirled around her and she found herself standing next to Harry in an empty room.

“What was that?” Alex asked.

“The start of Lord Voldemort.”

Alex gasped. “That was him? He didn’t seem anything special.”

“He had a lot of catching up to do. He was raised in a muggle orphanage. His first few years at Hogwarts were not pleasant. It took him till fifth year to get the respect he craved, which, as a half-blood muggle-raised of dubious origin in Slytherin house, was quite a feat.”

“So, what was that with the acromantula?”

“In his fifth year, Riddle—that was his name—opened the chamber of secrets and unleashed the beast within, attacking several students. He needed to solidify his place in Slytherin house, and this was the best way he had to go about it. There were rumours going around that he was courting a Ravenclaw muggleborn three years his junior.”

“Was he?”

“Yes.”

“I bet Slytherin house didn’t think too much of that.”

“They didn’t, but it was something they were prepared to overlook provided he went about it properly. By this time, Riddle had internalised many of the customs of the wizarding world, something that Myrtle Warren hadn’t. When her parents learned what was going on, they dug into Riddle’s background and found out he was an orphan bastard without a penny to his name. A muggle family these days might have been more understanding—at least about his background—but these were different times. They forbid their daughter from seeing him, and when they found out she’d disobeyed them, decided to pull her from Hogwarts. Riddle can be quite possessive. He did not take this well.”

“So that with the acromantula …”

“That was Riddle framing Rubeus Hagrid for the murder of Myrtle Warren after he’d killed her and used her death in not just one, but two dark rituals.”

Harry made a gesture in the air. “Ready for the next memory?”

Alexandra nodded. She then watched with wide eyes as a brief history of Voldemort played itself out in front of her, right up to his war against Magical Britain, which ended with his death while trying to murder John Potter.

Dumbledore regarded the lightning bolt scar on Baby Harry’s face. “So he chose Harry …”

If Alexandra had been drinking, she’d have sprayed it out all over the room. “Y-You! You’re the boy-who-lived!”

“Guilty.”

“That’s how you have the Slytherin lordship! Right of Conquest!”

“Indeed.”

“… But you’re still too young.”

Harry held up an index finger in the universal symbol for patience.

Alex settled back down.

The next few memories were confusing. They featured events that were clearly real, but which made no sense. Like Hermione being in Gryffindor, or Luna being sorted into Ravenclaw.

Then, suddenly, they were in a prison cell. Dirt clung to everything and it was difficult to tell the difference between the fixtures and the single occupant on the raggedy cot.

Alex stood waiting for something to happen. Nothing did. Eventually, unable to take it any more, she asked, “what is this?”

“This is where I spent ten years of my life, from the age of twelve, to the age of twenty-two.”

Alex ran this statement through her mind, trying to find a way for it to make sense given what else she knew. “You’re from the future.”

“I am.”

“You somehow managed to find a way to come back into the body of your younger self.”

“Yes.”

Silence.

Then, into the silence of the Azkaban prison cell, Alexandra started to laugh. It started out quiet, tentative, but once the laugh found a crack to slip through, it burst out of her like a busted dam. Alexandra laughed and laughed and laughed some more, the sound echoing throughout the memory of the worst prison in the world. Implication flowed into implication in an ever expanding river, washing away the old valley of understanding, and replacing it with the new. This boy, Harry Potter, had pulled off the greatest plot she’d ever encountered, even from her vast collection of fiction novels. He’d slipped back in time and built an empire from nothing but a mask and a name. Incredible. Alex laughed so hard her legs gave out for the second time in less than an hour and she slowly sank to the floor. “No wonder I never stood a chance! You jerk!”

Harry stood watching her with obvious amusement. Eventually her laughs subsided. He helped her to her feet. “You ready for the next bit?” he asked. “I think you’ll find it just as amusing, if not more so.”

Alex looked at Harry incredulously. She didn’t see how that was possible, but she couldn’t wait to find out. “Show me.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The pensieve glowed.

The girls all perked up.

Harry and Alexandra spun out of the pensieve and landed heavily, Harry holding Alex by the shoulder to stop her falling. Alex broke off from him and took a few steps back.

Hermione, Daphne, and Ginny all watched them with different levels of owlishness. It was hard to pinpoint the exact look on Alex’s face—perhaps something between mild awe and extreme embarrassment.

“You are the champion of Fate and Death.”

“So it seems, young necromancer.”

“You’re going to defeat he-who-must-not-be-named—the Dark Lord of the lords of the Dark.”

“Yes.”

“And conquer Magical Britain.”

“If needed, yes.”

“And you want me to help you.”

“Yes. I trust I can rely on you?”

“Trust? Rely?” Alex seemed to be struggling for words, eventually settling on. “Of course you can!” And once the floodgate was open she didn’t seem able to stop. “Are you insane?! This is like every story book I’ve ever read! No, it’s better than that! And you’ve already done so much! You trained Ginny, and Luna, and the others. And the Gray, and …” Her voice dropped to a whisper. “You stole the Dark Lord’s memories, everything he has, straight out of his head, and he has no idea. That’s just …” She trailed off.

Daphne cleared her throat. “If that has all been settled, Alex, we still have to go through our lord’s plan for how to handle your situation with Malfoy. I believe we got as far as ‘we’d all be hiding nearby under disillusionment.’ ”

Alexandra blinked. “Oh, yes, that’s right.” She looked embarrassed again. “Your plan, my lord?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Draco Malfoy inspected his allies, inconspicuously scattered around the Slytherin common room in ones and twos, and found them to be good. The last few weeks had been torturous. He’d lost his rightful position as seeker to Weasley, who turned out to be a devastatingly good flyer, Lovegood had returned from whatever mysterious ailment had her up in the hospital wing for a whole week, and whenever he so much as looked at Black he couldn’t help feeling a seeping feeling of dread. It was time to nip at least one of those problems in the bud.

“How long will it take her to crack, do you think?” Theo asked after playing a pair of lords into his set of three wands.

“She’s stubborn,” Pansy said, pushing two knuts into the middle of the low table. “I think she’ll hang out for at least three minutes.”

“How much do you bet?” Goyle asked.

“A sickle.”

“Done.”

Crabbe grinned and cracked his knuckles. “Not allowed to beat up girls often. Will be fun.”

Draco turned his attention away from the game and back onto the common room door. He was down twenty knuts to Pansy already, but right now he just couldn’t focus. Ah.

The door swung open and Black walked through.

“That’s my cue.” He dropped his cards on the table and walked to intercept the first year girl. “Stop right there, Black.”

The babble around the common room dropped. Around the room, many older students shifted in their seats.

“What is it, Malfoy?”

“Your attitude. It has to stop, right now.”

Black scoffed. “Oh, get out of my way.” She made to get around him, but stopped when he pointed his wand at her face.

“I don’t quite think you understand, Black. You’ve pissed off a lot of people over the last few weeks.” Draco felt that slight feeling of dread wash over him, but he shook it off. Around the common room, his allies were slowly standing up from armchairs and sofas, stretching their muscles and reaching for wands. He carefully watched Black’s face, waiting for the dawning moment of horror as she realised her situation.

Black looked around. “So that’s it, is it?” She started counting. “eleven, twelve, no, thirteen wizards to take on one little girl?”

“Best think of this as our little wizengamot. Each one of my friends here comes from a well respected family, Black, just like you. This is to show that, in this case, the few are acting on behalf of the many. This is the will of the Dark. The Ancient and Noble House of Black must be raised to it’s rightful status, once again. Submit to us, and take your honoured place among our ranks.” Draco allowed himself a smile. The twelve other students stepped away from their seats.

“Submit? To you?”

“Yes. Submit.” Draco’s eyes turned hungry. Here it came. If she was smart she’d submit, if not …

Black looked thoughtful for a moment. She pressed one finger to her lips as if trying to solve some kind of fascinating, but unimportant puzzle, as if her next words would have no greater significance than choosing between sweets on the Hogwarts express. She smiled cheerfully. “No.”

And then everything went wrong for Draco Malfoy.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Screams, bangs, explosions, smoke, chairs turning into attacking animals, animals turning into attacking chairs, students flying through the air and slamming into walls, frantic attempts to fight back, frantic attempts to retreat, chains, whips, curses, hexes, jinxes, and in the middle of it all, an eleven year old girl in a whirlwind of magic and destruction, spell swatting almost everything that got within range and shielding anything that got past that.

“Magic flush,” said Theo, laying his cards on the table.

“Rats,” said Pansy.

Theo pulled the pool towards him with theatrical care and dealt the two of them another five cards each. “I wonder if—”

A particularly loud, blood-curdling scream cut him off.

Pansy raised an eyebrow.

“—I wonder if we might have been a bit hasty,” Theo continued.

“It’s a point of view, certainly. I’ll start us with four knuts.”

“That is a bold opener.”

Somewhere in the chaos, Gregory Goyle managed to claw his way into grabbing range, but found himself inexplicably thrown onto a nearby sofa by an arm that didn’t look like it had ever even heard of push-ups. Said arms then turned both him and the sofa on their heads, trapping him underneath it.

“It was Granger’s birthday last week,” Pansy said, a little later into the hand.

“Yes, It’s surprising for a muggleborn to get so many intention gifts, but then, perhaps Granger is an exception.”

Next to them, a rug turned into a rabbit the size of a wolf and started hopping after a crying fourth year witch whose hands had been transfigured into cabbages.

“I don’t suppose the House of Nott has anything going on there?” Pansy asked, casually edging their table out of the way as the rabbit bounded past.

“Me? Hell no. I’m not about to throw away my family’s linage for some mud—I mean, for some upstart muggleborn.”

“I doubt you’d have a chance anyway. Have you noticed the way Granger’s been blushing every time she looks at Potter?”

“I might have. Definitely something interesting happened there.”

The general chaos seemed to be dying down by now. The smoke that had been drifting around the room started to thin. Most of the room was in ruins. Furniture was smashed, ash from the fire place covered everything, and all around them came the whimpers and groans of the soundly thrashed. Many Dark students had gotten over enthusiastic at the start, even though they hadn’t even been part of the disciplinary team, and were now sorely regretting their uncharacteristic Gryffindorness. Most of the others, Dark and Gray alike, were huddled in a protective corner, right up against the unbreakable glass to the Black Lake, staring at the destruction with wide, disbelieving eyes.

“Tempus.” Pansy flicked her wand, careful to keep it pointed well away from the combat zone. “Oh, look, I won the sickle.”

“I’m not sure if this counts under the terms of your bet.”

Somewhere on the other side of the room, Goyle made little bubbling sounds under his sofa.

A grinning female figure landed on the sofa beside Pansy. It was Black. “Room for another?”

Theo nodded respectfully. “Certainly. Wonderful performance, by the way.”

“Thank you.”

“Where’s Draco?” Pansy asked.

“I think he’s having a nervous breakdown in his dorm room.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the middle of the common room, a shape in the air nimbly climbed down from the top of one of the many supporting pillars, using the stone serpents that entwined them from top to bottom as convenient handholds. When it reached the floor, it made it’s way to the front of the common room and quietly slipped outside. That was so much fun, Ginny thought. Her spell repertoire may be limited, but she liked to think she’d more than pulled her weight in the general chaos. And now Harry and the others could handle the aftermath. She had other responsibilities.

Not that it seemed to matter. The diary still hadn’t budged a single inch from any of its usual haunts. It was being almost Hufflepuff-like in it’s unwillingness to split off from its ‘friends’ when outside of Gryffindor Tower. Ginny fished out the map from her robes, ducked into a convenient alcove, quickly scanned it, and gasped. The dot labelled Virgo Malfoy was alone, finally, and heading straight for the girl’s bathroom on the second floor.

Ginny’s heart beat faster.

Still under disillusionment and silencing charms, she fished in her other pocket for her trunk, unshrunk it, climbed inside, drank several potions, attached a mask firmly to her face, checked all her toys were in place, packed back up, and left for the castle stairs at a swift clip. It was time for Tom Riddle to meet Ginny Weasley.

—End of Chapter Forty—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: A bunch of fans on Twitter got together and set up a discord server for DP&SW where you can discuss the latest chapter, ask questions, or just chill with other people who like DP&SW. You can find the invite link through my website, which you can find through my profile. They also set up a Wikia project and filled it with tons of DP&SW information for quick access. So if you need to look something up, that’s the place to go.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s value.

Sticky Note: As always, if you want to stay up to date on schedule changes and other bonuses before anyone else, you can get them on my mailing list, which you can find by following the breadcrumb trail through my profile page.

Ginny’s Decision

Chapter Notes

See the end of the chapter for notes

[Two weeks ago]

It was midnight at the Rookery, along with everywhere else on this particular time-zone. Behind the chess piece shaped tower, the orchard was mostly still, save for the rustling of the autumn leaves, a random, non-magical owl, and three figures standing around, talking to one another.

Two of the three figures were naked and shivering slightly in the chill night air. The other stood off to the side, looking much more comfy in her long flowing robes.

“It should be time now, right love?” asked Lord Xenophilius Lovegood, rubbing his shoulders in an attempt to keep warm.

Pandora Lovegood smiled, flicked her wand, and nodded. “Yes, midnight exactly.”

“Good.” Luna Lovegood crouched down and retrieved the two massive fossilised T-Rex teeth from a bag at her feet before tossing the now empty bag over to her mother. “I’m freezing my tits off.”

Pandora caught the bag. “Are you sure you want to do this now? It isn’t something to be taken lightly and you’ve only just recently got your eyesight back. We could always take you out of Hogwarts again next weekend.”

Luna steeled her gaze. “It’s for Harry.”

“Of course it is.”

Xeno chuckled. “And I don’t have any problems. It’ll make hunting a lot more interesting when I eventually make use of it.”

Luna handed one of the teeth to her father who placed it down on the ground—a large circular slab of slate, cleared of leaves and covered with chalk runes and symbols, all drawn in interlocking patterns, a hypnotising mosaic of faux fractal beauty. Luna mirrored his movements, placing her own tooth down just in front of where she stood in a small chalk circle clear of runes or symbols.

“I’ll leave the two of you to it then,” Pandora said, turning to leave.

Lord Lovegood nodded to his daughter, who nodded back. They both then stretched their hands up into the air, letting magic flow through their bodies, out into the circle, and slowly, rhythmically, started to chant.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

[The present]

Harry walked with a purpose through the halls of Hogwarts, face grim, eyes alert, heading for the classroom that he and the girls usually trained in. It wasn’t curfew yet, but it was near. It had also been fifteen minutes since they’d finished helping Alexandra curb-stomp the Dark—fifteen minutes since Ginny had gone into ‘stealth’ mode to get the jump on the diary.

He’d received another set of pulses on his lightning bolt ring from his little ninja in training only a few minutes ago—and it hadn’t sounded great.

Harry made his way up the stone staircase, ignoring a grumbling Filch who tried to harangue him about it being nearly curfew, and found his way to the empty class-room. He pushed open the door.

Ginny was sat on the other side of the room, on the floor, up against the wall, arms around her knees—knees pressed to her chest. Her face was hidden by her hair, which was coal black rather than its normal flaming red.

Harry stepped inside and closed the door behind him, letting a bit of his magic seep into the room so she’d know it was him. Then he walked over to Ginny and sat down beside her so their shoulders were touching. “Hey,” he said, softly.

Ginny didn’t stir.

Harry didn’t push her. If there was anything truly urgent, Ginny wouldn’t hesitate to tell him, so there was no need to force things. He put a comforting arm around her shoulders.

Then Ginny lifted her head up, choked, and threw her arms around him. “Harry,” she half moaned. “I’m sorry, Harry.”

Harry held her. “Shhh, It’s okay,” he said. “What happened?”

Ginny made a sound somewhere between a whine and a hiccup. “I was following the map, when …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny’s heart beat heavily in her chest—not loudly though—silencing spells saw to that. She crept up the stairs heading to the second floor girl’s bathroom, mind like a needle, the entirety of her attention focused only on the task at hand, invisible, masked, black-haired, and aged up by just enough for her to pass as a sixth or seventh year.

Footsteps approached down the corridor. Ginny pressed herself up against the wall as Professor Lady Lily Potter passed by, carrying a stack of papers and looking harried. Ginny waited for her to disappear before moving on.

The important thing would be the first strike. The diary could sense magic to a certain degree, even if it couldn’t spell swat, so she wouldn’t be able to just slip a dagger in its back from the shadows. But that didn’t mean she couldn’t manufacture the element of surprise.

Ginny approached the bathroom. She glanced at the map. The diary was still there, standing by the sink that led to the chamber of secrets, clearly not able to enter because of the wards Harry had placed.

The door to the bathroom was ajar. If she opened it, and it squeaked, it would give away her position. If she cast a quieting spell on the hinges, that might also give away her position, opening the possibility of being ambushed inside. If she switched herself with something in the room, that too would give away her position, but it would at least leave her inside the room and ready to attack. But, if she just walked in, and the door didn’t squeak, she’d be in a perfect position to attack, but only if the diary didn’t sense her plethora of stealth spells. She could also wait outside the bathroom and attack it when it was finished failing to get into the chamber …

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Sounds like just walking in and hoping the door didn’t squeak would be the best option in that situation,” Harry said.

Ginny nodded into his chest. “I know. That’s what I did.”

Harry squeezed her shoulders. “You’ve come a long way since we first met.”

Ginny didn’t say anything.

“So what happened next?” Harry asked.

“I opened the door, and …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was a long bathroom that stretched out at a right angle to the door, toilet stalls on one side, sinks and mirrors on the other. It felt grimy—unused—uncared for. There was water everywhere, which made effective stealth suddenly very unlikely. Ginny edged her way in anyway and stood just in front of the corner leading to the rest of the bathroom. In one hand she held her wand. Her other itched to unsheathe the dagger hidden in her robes. It was just on the other side of this corner. Her muscles tensed.

“Hello.”

Shit. Ginny cursed to herself. The voice sounded just like any other eleven year old girl. She’d heard this particular one often enough in class, usually followed by such things as, “Oh, well done, Miss Malfoy! Two points to Gryffindor!”

“I know you’re there,” the voice said calmly. “I should warn you that the Noble House of Malfoy does not take kindly to people creeping around unannounced.”

Ginny didn’t say anything.

“Are you a student? Those are some pretty high level charms you’re using. Disillusionment, silencing—yes, I certainly know you are there. Why don’t you show yourself and state your business?”

An ambush was out of the question now. She could try to talk and get the jump on it when it wasn’t expecting it, but that also left her open to getting jumped too. No, best just to surprise it with an unrelenting attack.

“I warn you,” the voice began, starting to sound annoyed, “do not try my—”

Ginny attacked.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“And?” Harry asked gently, “What happened next?”

Ginny sniffed and wiped her nose with the sleeve of her robes. “Just like when we practised. She tried all the tricks you said she would. As soon as she realised that I could spell swat, she put up shields and used transfiguration and conjuration instead of direct spells. She was actually a little stronger than you thought—least, that’s what it felt like. Her wand wasn’t the sister to mine, by the way, so that wasn’t an issue.”

Harry nodded. The diary carried a wand of yew, which looked around the right length, but apparently either didn’t carry a phoenix father, or wasn’t exactly 13½ inches.

“The bathroom got pretty messy,” Ginny continued. “Blasted rubble everywhere. One of the pipes broke. The water was up to our ankles. And then …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The diary was losing. Ginny could see that the diary knew it was losing. It’s eyes darted back and forth, desperately looking for an exit point—a way out that Ginny had no intention of granting it.

“Wait!” it shouted.

Ginny nimbly side-stepped a banished rock, and banished one of her own in retaliation. She cast a switching spell on the rock as it dropped towards the diary’s head, exchanging it with a much larger rock on the floor by her feet.

The diary dived forward to avoid it, splashing into the water, and closing the distance between them. It choked and spluttered, but still kept up its guard, now down on one knee, wand pointing forward, maintaining its shield.

They were now so close there wasn’t time to even think about fancy spell work—just pure instinct—thrust and counter.

“Who?” it shouted again.

And Ginny saw her opening. A stone behind the diary momentarily flashed with magic, and, in the blink of an eye, Ginny was there instead, kneeing the diary in the back, and dropping it to the ground with a loud splash.

The diary screamed, rolled over onto its back, and tried to raise its wand, but Ginny was there, kicking the weapon out of its grasp and straddling its waist.

The diary desperately lashed out and Ginny’s wand went flying across the room in the opposite direction. There wasn’t time to even think about summoning it back. Ginny snatched the dagger from the inside of her robes, pressed the terribly sharp edge right up to the girl’s neck, and looked deep into the girl’s terrified eyes.

Fear.

Pain.

Pleading.

The room filled with silence, save the soft gurgling of the broken water pipe. Ginny felt the water she was kneeling in seep up into her robes. The magical torches on the wall caused shadows to flicker back and forth.

This is for killing me, bitch.

The words flashed across Ginny’s mind, rolled up onto her tongue, and, before they could be said, slowly, horribly, died.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“I couldn’t do it!” Ginny wailed, burying her face into Harry’s chest. “She just looked so scared. I’m sorry, Harry.”

Harry held Ginny close to him and made comforting noises while in the back of his mind, he thought through the implications. Dealing with this now was certainly the better strategy. Luna had been right, again. The diary was small fry in the grand scheme of things. If Ginny was going to be a killer, far better learn to do it now while it wasn’t such a big deal. Either that, or he needed to redirect her talents and training towards some other purpose.

He waited until she’d calmed down a bit before gently prodding her again. “And then?” he asked.

Ginny looked down. “I kinda panicked a bit and pushed a wandless stunner into her. Not enough power to last very long at all, but enough for me to get my wand and leave without getting caught by anyone.”

“You didn’t by any chance grab any of her hair while you had her there, did you?”

Ginny’s voice dropped to a murmur. “I did do that, yes.”

Harry smiled. “Well, that’s something.”

“But what do I do now?” Ginny asked, looking up at him again, eyes wet with tears. “I trained for so long, and I couldn’t even … I feel so useless!”

“Shhh … for starters, not getting it right on the first time is okay. Secondly, even if you find you don’t want to go down that path, there are lots of other paths we can take you down that will make use of everything you’ve been training for.”

“Like?”

“I’m sure you’d make a kick-ass bodyguard.”

Ginny looked Harry in the eyes, then snorted. “Sorry, but the idea that you need a bodyguard is just silly.”

“I was thinking about other people, not necessarily myself.”

“But I want to be with you.”

“You knew that you might have to be away from me for long periods of time, even if you continued on the path you’re on now.”

“True, but that doesn’t mean I have to like it.” Ginny wiped her eyes and pushed herself up from where she’d been laying against him.

Harry decided she needed distracting. “Enough of that. How would you like to hear a fresh off the press, not yet released, little titbit of news?”

Ginny gave a small smile. “Sure.”

Harry pulled a plastic bag out of his pocket. The bag contained a small pile of indistinct brown leaves.

Ginny’s eyes widened. “You got the mandrake leaves!”

“I did.”

“When are you going to give them out?”

“Right now, if you’re up to it?”

Ginny nodded.

Harry sent out a series of pulses on his lightning bolt ring. “I also have another little task for you tonight, Ginny.”

Ginny’s eyes steeled and she nodded again.

“When we’re done, take these to your twin brothers in Gryffindor tower and return to Slytherin dungeon. Do not be seen by anyone.”

Ginny took the smaller package and pocketed it. “Yes, Harry.”

They didn’t have to wait long for Daphne, Hermione, Luna, and Alexandra to show up. They piled in through the door, laughing and joking.

“And did you see Barber’s expression when Potter got him with that animate transfiguration?” Alexandra said with glee.

“But it was nothing compared to—” Hermione started, but trailed off as they all felt the mildly sombre atmosphere in the room.

“My lord?” Alexandra asked.

Daphne stepped forward. “Ginny? Are you alright? What happened?”

“Later.” Harry stood up from where he and Ginny had still been sitting with their backs to the wall, pulling her up with him. “Right now, we have these to give out.” He held up the bag containing the mandrake leaves.

There was silence for a moment.

Then Hermione actually let out a little squeal and trotted over to peer at the bag. “Oh, I’ve been so looking forward to this! I can’t believe it’s finally time!”

“How did you get them?” Daphne asked.

“With difficulty.”

Luna moved to stand beside Hermione. “I’ve been betrothed to a drug dealer for years now—it’s about time I got some.”

“Just the one month, Luna.” Harry said. “We don’t want any of us becoming addicted.”

Luna smiled dreamily. “Of course, Harry.”

“And its former drug dealer,” Hermione added.

“Oh?” Luna titled her head. “What’s this then?”

“This doesn’t count.”

Harry opened the bag and handed out a leaf to each of them in turn, finishing with his own. They all stood in a circle, popped the leaves onto their tongues, and then carefully charmed their leaf to stick to the roof of their mouths.

“Whoa,” Ginny said, swaying slightly.

“The first wave wears off quite quickly, but is rather intense to the uninitiated,” Hermione quoted with slightly glazed eyes.

“This is so cool,” Alexandra said.

“An interesting experience, certainly,” Daphne added.

Luna said nothing for a while as they all swayed under the force of hallucinogenic magic rushing throughout their bodies, before finally adding, “Anyone fancy a run down to the local chippy?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Not long after delivering the mandrake leaves to Fred and George, Ginny climbed into bed and lay there, listening to the sound of the Carrow twins drifting off to sleep.

She did not know what to do. She hadn’t not known what to do for ages. She’d been training to be a fighter ever since she’d known Harry, which felt like forever, but what good was a fighter who couldn’t kill?

Harry said it was okay if she took a less brutal role in their little group, but could she really accept that? The thought made her uneasy.

A second wave of dizziness hit her.

She snuggled down into the blankets and tried to ignore the school of silvery fish swimming through the dorm window to the black lake, gliding and darting around above her bed to the rhythm of her slowly relaxing breathing.

They’d be gone by morning … hopefully.

Darkness fell.

Time passed.

Ginny slowly came to and sat up. The dormitory had gone, but where she would normally expect to find Harry’s dream-scape, there was instead just empty space as far as they eye could see, and her, floating in the middle of it.

Okay, Ginny thought, first things first, she’d need some ground—that much was pretty much a given regardless of what kind of animal form she had. Even sea creatures needed land to put water into.

It shouldn’t be too difficult now. She’d never managed to materialise anything in her dreams before, but the mandrake leaf coursing through her body should make creating things out of thin air almost comically easy.

Ginny concentrated, hard, and ground appeared below her—far, far below her.

“SHHIIIIIIITTTTTT!” she screamed as she plummeted downwards.

Ginny thunked. And woke back up in the dark Slytherin dorms, panting and sweating. How long had she been asleep? An hour? Two?

Dizziness hit her again.

“Messed up the ground?” came Luna’s quiet voice from behind two sets of bed curtains.

“Jurst a bits,” Ginny slurred back. Her conscious mind felt fine, but she was having difficulty stringing thoughts to actions.

“At least you didn’t shout out like Alex did. Startled the Carrow twins something terrible. I think they’re really regretting their actions at the start of year now.”

“I didn’t hears that.”

“You were asleep. Don’t worry. It won’t be so bad tomorrow.”

Ginny looked up. The fish had changed colour from silver to metallic pink. Her head flopped back down onto her pillow and darkness, once again, fell.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On the other side of the castle, in a trunk hidden next to another first year girl’s bed, a body housing two individuals was not having a good time.

We nearly died! Julia shouted hysterically into Virgo’s head. She was going to kill us. You didn’t tell me people were going to try and kill us!

Virgo was sitting in a chair, head in his hands, trying to fight off a colossal headache, while failing to clamp down his occlumency shields to keep the girl out. He’d always managed to keep at least some semblance of separation between them, but that dagger at his throat had been the last straw.

I did tell you, he snapped back at her. Don’t you remember what happened at the book shop? At least one person wants us—wants me—dead.

But Harry’s just a boy! They were almost grown up! I was soooo scared!

Virgo groaned and looked up. Nothing for it but to wait until she calmed down.

How can I calm down!? What if she comes back! She was stronger than us! Some ‘Greatest Wizard’ you are!

SHUT UP! Virgo roared, pointing his wand at his arm and casting a mild torture jinx.

The pain speared through him like a sword in the arm leaving him gasping.

Julia whimpered and started sobbing. Tom, please don’t do that—please.

I wouldn’t have to do it if you’d just let me think! I’m trying to keep us alive, and I can’t do it if you’re being hysterical!

Julia quietened down, leaving him freedom to do said thinking, even while his body continued to shake and quiver. He needed to get close to John Potter, now more so than ever, for three very good reasons.

Firstly, walking around by himself was apparently too dangerous. He needed a powerful patron for protection until he was strong enough to deal with the threats himself—it was the same strategy he’d used at the start of his career in Slytherin house.

Secondly, the entrances to the chamber of secrets were warded. That suggested Lord Slytherin’s continued involvement. He was the only person, apart from one of his other selves, who might do such a thing. That made collecting information on him even more important.

And thirdly, John Potter had a Hogwarts functioning portkey. Lucius had told him so in one of his regular owls. Virgo needed that portkey, but just taking it wasn’t an option. No, he needed John to give it to him. And that wasn’t going to be easy. But it would be much easier if Virgo could gift wrap one of the girls he coveted.

Bones and John Potter were already close, but the other one—the female Weasley—the same one he’d met at the robes shop …

A small mirror on the desk opposite caught his attention. He frowned. Something wasn’t quite right. He stood up on shaky legs, walked over, and stared into it. “My hair!” he shouted, appalled. Someone had sliced a chunk out of her lovely, long, blond—sliced a chunk out of his …

My hair! Julia shouted.

Virgo shook himself.

My lovely hair!

Never mind our hair, he thought sharply at her. This is bad. There’s so much dangerous stuff you can do with people’s hair, it’s not funny. Old families teach their children to guard their hair like they would their blood.

Is that why you were trying to summon Harry’s hair from around the castle before? Is it for the hate potion?

Yes.

Oh. I was wondering. But you didn’t get any.

No.

And that was another thing he’d have to sort out. The younger Potter twin was being surprisingly cautious about his hair, but there was always another possibility. The boy had been thought a squib and raised by muggles (And how the hell had that happened?) which meant he would have a footprint in the muggle world. That footprint might well be an angle that could bare useful fruit—one that his dear ‘father’ should be able to arrange.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lily Potter looked over her second year Slytherin-Gryffindor potions class, sitting attentively and waiting for class to begin. There had been changes.

Usually, Miss Granger and Miss Greengrass sat together, but today, for some reason, the former was pairing with Miss Davis while the latter paired with Mister Zabini. Harry—her son, Harry—was sitting with Miss Parkinson.

Lily wasn’t particularly happy about that. She’d spotted the Parkinson Heiress bullying other students on no less than three occasions since she’d arrived. Regardless of what else she thought about the man, at least Slytherin seemed to have taught Harry to be polite. That could easily be ruined if he fell in with a bad crowd, and Miss Parkinson certainly counted. But she couldn’t do anything about that right now. Not here.

John was sitting in the back with Ronald Weasley—that at least, hadn’t changed.

“Today we’re going to be going through a minor sleeping draft, please study the notes on the board carefully before you begin. I will be attending you in a purely supervisory role today.”

The class got underway and Lily walked around the room correcting student’s efforts where they needed correcting.

She stopped at Miss Granger’s cauldron and looked down, surprised. “Miss Granger … your tubers. Can you tell me what’s wrong with your tubers?”

Hermione Granger turned her gaze to the tubers on her cutting board before squinting at the blackboard, cursing quietly under her breath, and sweeping them into the bin beside her. “Sliced, not diced.”

“Yes. I’m surprised. I think that’s the first time I’ve seen you make a mistake like that.”

Miss Granger muttered something that she couldn’t quite catch.

“Well, do try to stay focused. You know how important staying focused is here.”

Not five minutes later, Lily watched in shock as Heiress Greengrass knocked over a bottle with a carelessly placed elbow. The bottle stopped just before it hit the ground and floated back up, placing itself on the girl’s desk. Harry lowered his wand and nodded. Greengrass blushed.

“Good reflexes, Mister Potter,” Lily said. “Miss Greengrass, please be more careful.”

It seemed like something was jinxing her best students for the rest of the class. It was a wonder they turned in any potion at all, let alone produce ones with the perfect shades and textures she’d come to expect from that little group. In any case, it was a perfect excuse to hold Harry back at the end of class.

“Is something wrong with your friends today, Harry?”

“No, Mum.”

“That’s Professor while we’re in school.”

“Yes, Professor. No, Professor, I don’t think there’s anything wrong with them. I haven’t noticed anything, anyway.”

“Mmmm …” Lily tapped her chin. “Well, if you do learn anything that might affect their safety in potions class, you’ll let me know won’t you?”

“Yes, Professor.”

“By the way, I see you partnered with Miss Parkinson today.”

“Yes, Professor.”

“And you’re happy with that?”

Harry smiled the smile of a child that thinks he’s spotted an adult doing something against the rules. “Are you asking as a professor? Or as my Mum?”

Lily chuckled. “As your Mum, Harry.”

“Well, Mum, I know she can be a bit spiky, but didn’t Dumbledore always say that to win the war the Light must show the love that the Dark does not dare to?”

“I thought you hated Dumbledore?”

“That doesn’t mean everything he says is rubbish. Pansy is a nice girl—just a bit misguided.”

“What about your other friends?”

“They are still my friends. I just want lots of friends. We’ll go back to our old partners eventually. We just thought it would be a good idea to stir the pot a little.”

Lily nodded. That seemed fine. It certainly didn’t seem to be something that risked the control over her son the prophecy required her and James to have.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Alice Spooner had just clocked in for her shift at St. Peter’s Hospital, when a very unusually dressed man walked through the front door, disdainfully looked around as though he’d just entered a sewer pipe and not a thoroughly modern hospital, and started to walk towards her. Alice couldn’t help feeling that there was something about the man that was familiar—the blond hair, the gloved hands, the sharp features—but for the life of her, she couldn’t remember where she might have seen him. He stood imperiously in front of her and rapped his silver snake’s head cane on the floor.

“I need you to retrieve all the medical records, teeth, blood samples, and any other body parts you might have for one Harry James Potter, immediately.”

Alice felt a sinking sensation in the pit of her stomach. An utter loony. Wonderful. She sighed. “Sir, we can only release patient information to the patient, a legal guardian, or someone with power of attorney.”

The man pulled on his cane and whipped out what looked like an orchestra conductor’s baton. He waved it in the air. “Listen, muggle, I am Lucius Malfoy, and I have the authority—go and fetch me what I asked for immediately.”

At that moment, two distinct thought-processes started in Alice’s brain. The first went something like this—‘Of course, how silly of me, why would I ever question someone who is so obviously my better. I need to go and get anything I can find right away. Rules are only there for normal people, after all, and Lucius Malfoy is no mere ordinary man.’

The second went something like this—‘Oh, fuck! Lucius Malfoy! The wanted drug trafficker! I knew I’d seen him somewhere before. All over the news papers! I need to go and call the police!’

Both thoughts warred with each other, one driven by magic, the second driven by terror, but both thoughts were agreeing on one thing. She needed to leave right away.

Alice nodded respectfully and slipped through the doors leading to admin. The corridor split—records in one direction, the nearest phone in the other. The back of her neck started to sweat as the two thought processes continued to battle for her actions. Records or phone?

Back in the lobby, Lord Lucius Malfoy waited for the disgusting muggle to return. He didn’t like getting his hands dirty, but there really wasn’t much choice this time. That was fine … occasionally. One confundus, one obliviate, and his new daughter would have exactly what she needed for whatever plot she was hatching in Gryffindor Tower.

A snake among lions? More like a basilisk among kittens.

When he and his wife had first adopted Virgo, they’d intended her to become a leader in the snake pit to counter Lord Slytherin’s over powered little minions, but in the end she’d chosen red over green. He’d been a bit put out at the time, but it turned out for the best—Virgo in Slytherin as well would have been a waste.

He chuckled, remembering the memory his son had sent him two nights ago.

His wife’s niece—Alexandra.

Black blood, it seems, always did run true.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A little while earlier, under the streets of central London, Chief Auror Sirius Black made his way down from his office towards the ministry restaurant to meet with his lunch partner.

Something hadn’t been right for the past several days. Whispers followed him wherever he went. A couple of pureblood interns had giggled as he passed. People he hadn’t spoken to since his childhood gave him winks and random thumbs up, and when he questioned them about it, always got some cryptic comment on the lines of, ‘playing the long game, huh?’

On the other hand, some of the looks he was getting from people he thought of as friendly acquaintances suddenly weren’t nearly so friendly—they were instead full of distrust and suspicion.

He walked through the ministry canteen and towards where those who traditionally sat above the salt ate. Sirius didn’t eat at the ministry restaurant often. He much preferred sitting with the other aurors, but if there was one thing Le Petit Magik was good for, it was privacy.

“This way, Lord Black,” the maître d said, leading him through the other diners towards a private booth near the back. “Your guest has already arrived.”

“Thank you.”

The booth was set for two—wine glasses, grasses in flower pots, enough cutlery to keep an etiquette teacher busy all afternoon, the whole spell chain.

“Sirius.” Arthur Weasley stood up and took the hand Sirius extended to him.

“Arthur.”

They sat.

“So, what did you want to talk about,” Sirius asked, when the waiter had taken their orders. He’d known Arthur Weasley for over a decade and the two were on good terms.

“What’s your assessment of the current state of things in the Wizengamot?”

Sirius groaned inwardly. This was supposed to be James’ thing, not his. “Very basic, I’m afraid. The Light and the Dark are at stalemate on just about every major issue and only the Gray can break it one way or another, but they’ve been refusing to do so for years now.”

“That’s a good basic assessment, yes.”

“So?”

Arthur leaned forward. “Everything we talk about here will be in absolute confidence, yes?”

“If you want.”

Arthur nodded. “A few months ago, I met with Lord Slytherin.”

“Really?”

“Yes.”

Sirius leaned slightly forward too. “What did you talk about?”

“I’m afraid I can’t tell you. It’s in absolute confidence …”

There was a pause.

“… But?” Sirius suggested.

“But I drew certain conclusions from the conversation that I feel it is important to talk about.”

“What kind of conclusions?”

“Firstly, Slytherin really doesn’t like Dumbledore.”

“I thought that much was obvious.”

“No, I mean he really doesn’t like Dumbledore. Not just a bit—he outright hates him. And for some reason, the feeling is mutual. But! And this important—he also has little love for the Dark.”

“Okay. What else?”

“I believe Slytherin is genuinely pro-muggleborn.”

“What about pro-muggle?”

Arthur hesitated. “I’m not so sure about that. But the political implications …”

Sirius thought about it and reached a conclusion. It wasn’t a difficult conclusion to reach, even for him. “This is about your muggle protection act, isn’t it?”

“Something needs to happen. If it doesn’t, we could be in very big trouble. Our laws are not keeping up with the state of affairs on the ground.”

“Arthur, I don’t want to sound discouraging, but we’ve been trying to get laws through the Wizengamot for four years now. We tried this very act last year. It didn’t work then. What’s changed that you think it’ll work now?”

Arthur Weasley looked triumphant. “Because, now I have an in.”

“An in?”

“With Lord Slytherin. Like I said, I can’t talk about it, but I can say that there is a matter on which we both need to work together on—one on which he puts a lot of importance.”

“You think Slytherin will support your new act?”

“I think we might have to modify some bits of it, add in a few extra clauses, tone down some of the more extreme Light sided ideals, but yes. I think we have a chance.”

Sirius considered this. Breaking the deadlock on the Wizengamot in the favour of the Light would be a considerable political coup. He didn’t know much about it, but that much was obvious.

“Chief Auror!”

The two wizards looked up.

Nymphadora Tonks, Sirius’ niece, and the department’s newest auror trainee was panting, by the booth’s door.

“Yes?”

“The muggle police reported your wizard drug dealer in a muggle hospital. Shacklebolt apparated over there and brought him in. He’s in the cells right now.”

Sirius leapt to his feet. “Thank you, Tonks. Sorry Arthur, but we can continue this another time.”

“Wait, Sirius!”

Sirius turned back to Arthur, half way to do the door.

He hurried up to him and motioned his ear.

“I need to give you an official tip-off, as chief Auror,” Arthur whispered. “From an anonymous, informed source.”

“What tip-off?”

“An old foe rises.”

Sirius frowned. “Who?”

Arthur grimaced, said nothing, and then mouthed the words, ‘you—know—who’.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Sirius’s head swam as they quick marched down to the ministry holding cells. Arthur wouldn’t joke about that. What had he heard that he couldn’t tell him? Was he missing something? Voldemort was rising again? How?

“Boss,” Tonks hissed.

He shook himself free of his thoughts. “Yeah?” They’d just left the public area and were now in an empty corridor.

“I didn’t like to say up there—but the prisoner—it’s Lucius Malfoy!”

“What! It’s actually Lucy?”

“Yeah!”

That made things a lot more complicated, if a lot more amusing. “What was he doing in a muggle hospital?”

“Trying to get the medical records for Harry Potter—you know, John’s brother—the one who smacked me down at the duelling tournament last year.”

“Yeah, I know Harry. His records?”

“And any blood or hair or anything else like that they might have.”

Sirius’ grin faded. “Oh, really?”

“Yeah! Will you be able to get him?”

“Probably not on illegal muggle-magical trading. He didn’t have any drugs on him, did he? No, I didn’t think so. Like I said, muggle drug dealing isn’t his style. And trying to acquire hair or blood isn’t illegal by itself, though it damn well should be … maybe muggle baiting? Breaking the Statute of Secrecy?”

“He used magic on a muggle, called her a muggle, and then let her out of his sight without modifying her memory or calling the obliviators.”

Sirius’ grin was back. “Well, that’s a class C breach if nothing else.”

“Will he go to prison?”

“A lord? For a class C? Unlikely. But we’ll see what we can do.”

“Yeah! And you can taunt him about Alex stomping his son’s friends into the dirt.”

Sirius stopped so quickly, Tonks was forced to spin around to face him.

“What?” he said.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo was not in a good mood. He’d been summoned to the headmaster’s office the previous night, along with his new older brother. Once there, Narcissa had told them both that their father was currently in a ministry holding cell and that if anyone asked them, that it was, ‘an outrageous miscarriage of justice, that would soon be cleared up.’

Apparently, his simple request had turned out to not be so simple.

Add to that the fact that John Potter was still brushing off his every attempt to make nice with him, and Virgo was more than a little annoyed.

But he didn’t have the time to just wait around for Lucius to be released, so, while the boys were engaged in a rather rowdy chess match, he’d sat in a corner of the Gryffindor common room, thinking deeply until he’d come up with a possible solution to his Harry Potter problem.

Your Hairy Potter problem.Julia sniggered.

You know, he thought back, for an eleven year old, for whom English is their second language, that was a surprisingly impressive bit of word play.

Thank you.

But if you do it again, I will torture us.

Not right now you won’t.

Virgo sighed and continued to make his way down to the dungeons, his senses on high alert for any kind of ambush. Quickly in and quickly out, that was the way. After a few minutes of wandering, he ducked into an alcove, took out a polyjuice potion, and gulped it down.

The effect was fast and immediate. He gained a couple of inches in height, his hair shortened—turned black, his muscles got a little firmer, but apart from that, there wasn’t too much difference without a mirror—except for the obvious big difference, naturally.

Hey! We have a boy’s thing! You didn’t tell me we were going to do that!

Oh, shush, he thought back. I’ve had to put up with being in a girl’s body for months now. You can deal with being in a boy’s for an hour. Why do you think I dressed in unisex robes?

Virgo ignored Julia’s grumbling answer, choosing instead to walk up to a row of armour standing next to a picture of a wardrobe, took off his witches hat, and placed it on the third suit of armour down the line.

The wardrobe picture swung aside, leaving a hole large enough for a wizard to climb through.

Virgo smoothed his now messy hair over the spot where Harry Potter’s scar would be, if it had been Harry Potter’s hair he’d used in the potion. He then climbed inside. What lay beyond was just like he remembered it from all those years ago. A large stone-floored space held dozens of massive copper tubs, all full of gently steaming water. Piles of clothes lay everywhere. Huge spoons were mixing sparkling powders in the air above. And even as Virgo finished his sweep of the room, another load of clothes fell onto the main pile via a massive pipe in the ceiling.

The Hogwarts Laundry.

A dozen eyes turned to him.

Oh, yes, also house elves. Lots of house elves.

One of them squeaked, “John Potter!” and moments later a half dozen of the little wretches were clustered around him.

“Actually, I’m Harry Potter.”

The excited squeaking died down a little, but not by much.

“Harry Potter. Yes, Harry Potter, Sir. What is you be wanting here, Sir?”

“I left something in my clothes that I need, can I get them?”

“Yes, Sir, Harry Potter, Sir!”

Moments later a large bundle of clothes was thrust into his arms. He looked down at the beaming faces. “A little privacy?”

“Yes, Sir!”

They scattered.

I can’t believe they bought that, Julia thought.

That’s because they’re brainless idiots, he thought back.

Now left alone, Virgo ducked behind a large vat and started carefully going through the bundle. If Potter’s clothes did indeed have some kind of hidden anti-summoning enchantments or runes on them, then he’d just need to do it by hand. It was the kind of thing someone who’d been used to magic all their lives would never think to do.

It took ages, but he was not about to give up. Quite a bit later, Virgo smiled in triumph, tweezing a single black hair from one of the hoods.

Smiling, he left the laundry, and was just closing the painting behind him, when he felt the change. His hair was starting grow and his skin starting to bubble. Virgo swore. That had been close. Far too close. And he’d been so engrossed in finding Potter’s hair that he’d lost track of time. Not good.

He quickly marched through the labyrinthine dungeons, and was nearing the stairs to the upper floors, when a shiver shot down his spine.

Danger.

He felt a large pulse of magical power, a hand from nowhere grabbed his throat, pain shot through the back of his head, and the next thing he knew, he was pinned up against the wall, held there by a grown woman in a mask. He hadn’t even had time to reach for his wand.

Oh, god, oh no, oh please!

Virgo swore. He’d messed up. “Wait!” He’d been alone too long. “Please!” He wriggled in the woman’s grip, but he might as well have been a worm wriggling in the beak of a bird.

“I will wait,” the woman said in a sing song voice.

The word ‘fucktoy’ flashed through Virgo’s mind before it was ripped apart, tossed aside in the quickly surging panic, and just as quickly forgotten.

“What do you want?” he gasped out.

“Your death.”

“How … how about money, instead? My father—”

“—No. Not money.” The woman giggled. “But I do know something I would like to have. Something I’ve wanted for a long time.”

And then Virgo felt something slam against his occlumency barriers like a tidal wave against a wooden fence. It ripped into his essence and ploughed straight into his memories—memories that flashed across his vision like a muggle movie on fast forward, but the memories shown were not his. A Christmas in the snow. Swimming in the summer Baltic.

Stop! Please! It hurts!Julia cried.

And suddenly, the assault stopped. Whatever his attacker had expected, it probably hadn’t been this.

There isn’t enough room in here for three of us!Julia shouted. It hurts!

The legilimency battering ram hesitated, then withdrew sharply, leaving Virgo gasping, still being choked by the neck in the woman’s iron grasp.

The woman stood as still as a statue.

Virgo gradually got back control of his breathing and stared back into the woman’s mask, desperately trying to look as small and helpless as possible.

For what felt like forever they just stood there, the woman making no move either to continue her murder or to retreat. She was obviously thinking hard about what had just happened.

And then, like a relieving force’s trumpet blast to a castle under siege, Virgo heard it. Footsteps. Rapidly approaching footsteps.

The masked witch obviously heard them too. She glanced in their direction before releasing her grip on Virgo’s neck and sprinting off down the passageway in the opposite direction.

Virgo slid down the wall until he was just a puddle on the floor. Death. His death. It had been so close. Again. He was a horcrux, not the original. If he died, that was it.

“Miss Malfoy?” A shocked voice said.

Virgo looked up. Lady Lily Potter was standing in the doorway to the stairs. A plan rapidly formed in Virgo’s mind. He calculated the time between when he’d changed from Harry Potter into Virgo Malfoy. He analysed every bit of the encounter for anything that might compromise his position in a memory, and found nothing. Then he tossed all that aside and let his emotions crash through his occlumency barriers, giving Julia as much free-reign into his consciousness as she might wish.

This at least, wouldn’t take much acting.

“Professor!” Both he and Julia simultaneously burst into tears. “I was so scared!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In transfiguration class, Professor McGonagall was frowning with the air of a drill sergeant who has discovered a scuff on one of his usually most reliable soldier’s shoes.

“Miss Granger, this is quite below the standard of work I’ve come to expect from you.”

“Sorry Professor,” Hermione said in a meek voice.

Harry watched carefully from a few seats away. All this wasn’t unexpected. It was all he could do to maintain his own control over his magic. That the girls were having difficulty was to be expected.

“And I see your notes aren’t quite as neat as normal, either.”

“I’m just feeling a bit off professor.”

Harry mentally winced. That hadn’t been the best excuse.

“Really?” McGonagall raised an eyebrow. “Perhaps you should go to the hospital wing.”

“Oh, no, professor, I’m sure I don’t need to do that. I don’t want to miss class. It’s fine, really.”

“If you’re sure.” The professor walked away.

Harry kept a careful eye on the teacher after that. This was the transfiguration professor, after all. If anyone would suspect something, it would be her—and indeed, some minutes later, when Hermione tripped on her way to hand in her homework …

“Accio mandrake leaf,” McGonagall snapped.

Nothing happened. Surprise flashed across the usually stern face.

Hermione put on a hurt expression. “Professor?”

The surprise quickly gave way to a mild fluster. Usually stern eyes quickly travelled between her wand and around the classroom, not meeting Hermione’s. The professor pursed her lips. “My apologies, Miss Granger,” she said in a clipped voice. “I should have known you would never be so foolish as to experiment with advanced level transfiguration without telling me first.”

“I don’t understand, professor.”

Harry smiled. Much better.

The class was then treated to an impromptu lecture on the animagus transformation, how dangerous it was, and how any student caught trying it without supervision would be in big, big trouble.

Harry filed out of class at period’s end to find Luna waiting for him right outside the classroom door. They quickly found an empty spot to talk.

“My lord, we might have a problem.”

“Go on, Luna.”

Luna then proceeded to tell him all about the confrontation she’d just had with Virgo, and the fact that the muggleborn girl used for the ritual wasn’t dead, like they’d thought, but was, in fact, still in there.

Harry sighed. “I really wish you hadn’t learned that.”

“Me too.” Luna was actually looking uncertain. Harry didn’t think he could ever remember a time when Luna looked uncertain.

“This is … inconvenient.”

“Yes, Harry. I’m sorry, Harry.” Luna suddenly looked close to tears.

“Hey, Luna,” Harry said softly. “It’s okay, you know.”

“It’s not okay! I inconvenienced you!”

“Luna.” He switched to a firmer voice. “I need you to be strong.”

And just like that the tears stopped. Wow.

“My lord?”

“Here’s what we are going to do. Stop all attempts on the diary for the moment. I don’t know how exactly to separate a parasite from a normal soul, but I know the basic theory, and I should be able to figure out the how with some experimentation. It’s something I needed to do eventually anyway, so it’s not even that much of a bother.” He tapped his scar.

Luna looked incredibly relieved. “Yes, my lord.”

“And if we can’t figure out how to free her within a reasonable period of time, then we bite the bullet and destroy it anyway.”

“Yes, my lord.”

“But it shouldn’t come to that.”

“Yes, my lord.”

“Don’t discuss this with Ginny until I’ve had a chance to talk to her myself.”

“Yes, my lord.”

“How are your animagi mind scapes going by the way?”

“Ginny’s is coming along well. She says she’s starting to feel the native landscape. Mostly grassland. And it’s very hot, apparently.”

“And yours?”

Luna dabbed at a stray tear from her eye with a lace handkerchief and smiled. “Can I keep it a secret, my lord?”

“Why?”

“I want it to be a surprise. A big, big surprise.”

Harry gave Luna a cautious look. “How big of a surprise are we talking here?”

“Big.”

“You already know what your animagus form is.” It was a statement rather than a question.

Luna nodded. “The Lovegoods have a family ritual that lets us choose our form before we master it.”

That was interesting information. “At what cost?”

“Your true form. The form that is really you.”

That didn’t sound too bad, Harry thought. Although he could imagine it might cause some slight personality shifts.

“That’s okay, isn’t it?” Luna asked.

Harry hugged her, on the basis that you couldn’t really go wrong with a hug where Luna was concerned. “Yes, it’s fine. C’mon, let’s go to lunch.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Before this month, it had been a long time since Virgo had been in the headmaster’s office. In his time of course, it had been Headmaster Dippet’s office, who’d been rather sparing in his furnishings. Virgo didn’t even want to start imagining what kind of lunacy Dumbledore’s office had contained, but whatever it had looked like, even Dumbledore’s furnishings couldn’t have been as bad as this.

“Don’t you worry about a thing, Miss Malfoy,” Headmaster Lockhart said with a beaming smile plastered all over his oh so punchable face. “You’re perfectly safe now. I give you my personal word. The head of the DMLE will be here soon—a close personal friend, you know. She asked my advice on how to improve the department not too long ago—naturally I couldn’t say no to supporting our brave boners.” He gave him a roguish wink. “Only don’t tell her I said that. She can be a bit sensitive about that nick-name.”

Virgo smiled weakly. He was sitting in one of the office’s many hardback chairs, trying to look how he imagined an eleven year old girl who’d just been the subject of a murder attempt would look—something Julia was, for once, being very helpful with. All around him, a dozen Lockharts all beamed down at him. Some were even sharing painting space with the various past headmasters of Hogwarts. The previous headmasters did not look happy about this. Phineas Black, in particular, looked like a man under incredible strain, barely keeping his cool. This didn’t surprise Virgo in the slightest. The Headmaster clearly had his head so far up his own arse, it was amazing there was enough room for a puppeteer as well.

I think he’s rather dashing, Julia thought in a quiet voice, as Lockhart went back to his desk, and continued with whatever he’d been doing before Lily Potter had marched them in, given the headmaster a quick explanation, and flooed to the ministry.

Dashing?!Virgo thought back.

He does have a nice smile.

It takes a lot more than a nice smile to make a great wizard.

Yes, but the nice smile helps. And at least he’s trying to be reassuring.

I can see how it might be reassuring to an eleven year old girl.

Wearean eleven year old girl.

No,youare an eleven year old girl.Iam a sixteen year old Dark Lord.

I thought you were supposed to be a Dark Lady now.

Dark—Lord,he thought, with a firmness that brooked no argument.

Fine,Julia thought, now sounding petulant.I’ll be the Dark Lady then.

Dark Ladies do not burst into tears just because someone tries to kill them.

That, apparently, had been the wrong thing to think, because Julia burst into mental tears again, and Virgo was unable to stop them welling up in his actual eyes and streaming down his face.

It was another five minutes before the floo flared green, by which time, Julia had dried up and started to petulantly annoy him again, safe in the knowledge that he couldn’t torture himself here.

Four people stepped through. The first two introduced themselves to her as Regent Amelia Bones, head of the DMLE, and Lord Sirius Black, Chief Auror. The other two were Lily Potter, and finally …

“Father!” Lord Malfoy had apparently already been released from his ministry cell. Virgo looked up and attempted to look panicky. He had only one chance to deliver the message he needed Lord Malfoy to receive and he had to get it right. “Please don’t be angry with me. I didn’t mean to go to Gryffindor. It was an accident!”

Lucius looked shocked, but damn, the man was quick on the uptake. The shock instantly faded, replaced by arrogant disdain. “Virgo!” he snapped. “We will discuss your failings later, but now I want to know why I was called here.”

“Failings,” Black muttered darkly, not quite under his breath.

Lily Potter filled everyone in on what Virgo had told them happened, which was a perfectly accurate account of the attack, minus anything to do with Julia. Regent Bones took a copy of her memory of the event and stoppered it into a small bottle. “It’s outrageous!” she ranted. “Disguised assault with declared intent to kill in Hogwarts! If I could, I’d pull every student in for veritaserum!”

“Oh, surely it’s not that bad,” Lockhart said. “The assailant didn’t actually try to hurt her, did she?”

“Mental assault,” Black countered.

“Which is not actually against the law,” Lucius said, smoothly.

“Father?”

“I mean, I can’t see any actual harm done. Children fight all the time.”

“You weren’t there, father! You didn’t feel how powerful she was! How intent she was! She was going to kill me. You won’t feel that in a memory.”

Lucius looked down at him and sneered, and inside the privacy of his skull, Virgo couldn’t help but bask in just how good this man was at this. Not for nothing was he the leader of the Dark in the absence of his older self. “I’m sure that your Gryffindor friends will look after you,” he said.

Lily Potter snapped. “You horrible, horrible man! Your own daughter was attacked! Don’t you care?”

“I’m sure, Lady Potter, that my daughter can handle herself quite well without my help. Now if you will excuse me, I have pressing matters to deal with. Headmaster. Lord Black.” He turned to Sirius, gave him a respectful nod, then turned in a swirl of robe, and left via the floo.

Black stared, wide-eyed at the now empty fireplace, while Virgo made to curl in on himself, causing Lily Potter to sit down and put a comforting arm around his shoulders. “Amelia, we have to do something,” she said.

“Yes, I quite agree.” Regent Bones nodded. “That man is just as despicable as ever.”

Maybe John Potter and Susan Bones should take care of her,Julia thought in a sarcastic tone of voice.

“Maybe John and Susan could take care of her?” Lady Potter suggested.

“A wonderful idea, Lily.”

If it hadn’t been so out of character, and if he’d actually been capable of it, Virgo would have purred.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“I think you’re being too harsh on Virgo, John.”

Susan was sitting with John at the far end of the Gryffindor Table in the Great Hall, instead of at her usual place at the Hufflepuff table. Lunch was busily going on all around them.

“I’m just not comfortable with her,” John said, shifting uneasily.

“Why? Because she’s a Malfoy?”

“Well, yeah.”

“But she was raised a muggle. She’s practically muggleborn.”

“She sure doesn’t act like it.”

“Won’t you at least try? For me?” She gave him badger eyes—large, friendly, and strategically adorable.

John sighed. “Okay, fine, but I think you’re blowing this out of all proportion.”

Susan punched the air in victory and grinned before turning back to her food.

John looked over towards the Slytherin table. There had been changes. Alexandra Black now sat in a prominent position near the head of the table. He couldn’t help wonder if she’d be in the duelling tournament this year. His eyes flicked to the other end of the table and his stomach clenched as it did every time he looked in that direction. Ginny shouldn’t be in Slytherin. She should be here with him. And was it just him or did she look more subdued than normal? His eyes narrowed. Was something going on? Were the Slytherins mistreating her? Was Harry … doing … something?

“John, Susan?”

“Yes, Lady Potter?” Susan asked.

John tore his gaze away to turn towards his mum.

“Please follow me, immediately.” She sounded rather serious.

They both nodded and together the three of them left the hall and headed up a set of stair cases that John knew headed towards the headmaster’s office.

“What’s this about, do you think?” Susan whispered from where they walked behind John’s mother.

“No idea,” he whispered back.

They soon found out.

Virgo Malfoy sat on a chair in front of them looking nervous—none of her usual arrogant haughtiness.

“Someone tried to kill you?” Susan looked horrified.

Virgo nodded.

John’s jaw had dropped. Seriously? Someone had actually tried to commit murder in Hogwarts? Who? But … he already knew who. This was the second year after all. There could only be one possible candidate. And Virgo was a muggle-raised in Gryffindor—she’d be a perfect target for … “The heir of Slytherin.”

Everyone stopped talking. Every head in the room turned towards him—Virgo, Susan, his mum, as well as Headmaster Lockhart.

There was a moment of silence. Then …

“Who?” Susan asked.

His mum gave him an odd look. “I haven’t heard anything about Lord Slytherin having children.”

“Um …”

Virgo was just staring at him with an unreadable expression on her face.

John started rapidly back-peddling. “I mean, it’s just the kind of thing Slytherin would do, right? He’s never up to any good.”

Lily Potter sighed. “John, you can’t just go around making accusation like that. In any case, Susan’s aunt and I … we want you both to look out for Virgo here—take responsibility for her—make sure nothing else happens. I know that you aren’t in the same year, but try to stick together as much as you can.”

Susan beamed. “Yes, Lady Lily.”

“But …” John began, and from the tone of his voice it was clear he was about to voice a complaint.

“John,” Lily said, sharply, cutting him off. “A word.” She pulled him to one side and whispered fiercely into his ear. “Virgo just had a terrible experience, and her father all but abandoned her when she needed him—abandoned her because she’s a Gryffindor. You remember what happened to your godfather, yes?”

John’s eyes widened. He nodded.

Lily’s voice softened. “Then I can rely on you to be my little hero, yes?”

“Yes, Mum.” There wasn’t really much else he could say.

“Good.”

When the two of them got back to the Gryffindor common room later that evening after classes, John formally brought the Malfoy girl into his circle of friends who always occupied the central position by the fireplace, getting quite a few odd looks from Ron, Seamus, and Neville, as well as the other girls. Virgo didn’t speak much for the rest of the evening, but when they were standing up to head off to bed, she caught him by the sleeve and asked if they could have a quick word alone. She then thanked him for helping her and asked about Ginny Weasley.

“What about Ginny?” he asked, suspiciously.

“You seem very attached to her.”

“I love her.”

“But she doesn’t love you back?”

“Harry did something to her.” He was having a hard time keeping a civil tone of voice.

Virgo put her hands behind her back. “You’re helping me, John Potter. Maybe I could try and help you?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In Potter Manor, Sirius Black was gazing into a glass of brandy that James Potter had just handed him.

“What’s wrong, Sirius?” James said, now pouring himself a glass.

“Malfoy was polite to me, James! Polite! Me! What did I ever do to deserve that!? I’d just hauled his arse out of a cell! He’s facing court proceedings that could last months, and he was polite to me!”

James gave his friend a sideways glance. “Well, what do you expect? With what Alex has been up to.”

“I hardly think, ‘beating up his son’s friends,’ counts as a reason to be polite.”

James took a sip from his glass. “Padfoot, have you seen the memory?”

“No?” Sirius sat up higher in his chair. “Have you?”

“I should think that by now just about every wizard with a pensieve in Great Britain has seen it—and probably plenty of those who don’t.”

“Everyone except me,” Sirius grumbled.

“Well, let’s fix that right now.” James put down his drink and called a house elf to fetch the family pensieve.

Fifteen minutes later, Lord Sirius Black emerged from the pensieve, white faced and sweating. “Alex! What the hell!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The next fortnight was not easy for Ginny Weasley. The revelation that the thing she’d done her level best to destroy had had a real person trapped inside it troubled her as much as her inability to carry out the deed in the first place.

The other girls had all reacted with similar levels of disquiet—although, having said that, Alexandra, Daphne, and Hermione all had so much going on in their own projects that she doubted they’d spent nearly so much time obsessing over it as she had.

Alexandra in particular had it difficult, since she was disconnected from Harry and the rest of them except from during group combat training. Apparently she’d had a rather intense confrontation with her father on the weekend after their combined stunt in the Slytherin common room, which had only been diffused, somewhat, when Harry stepped in and had a private word with Lord Black. Exactly what had been said though, Ginny didn’t know.

Just about the only time Ginny was able to disconnect from her full-blown early-life crisis was during quidditch training—an interesting experience under the influence of mandrake leaf. At one point, a spell of dizziness had hit her at just the wrong moment and she’d thrown the quaffle right into Malfoy’s face. It was lucky the rest of the team thought she’d just been being her usual vicious self.

It was the Thursday just before Daphne’s birthday weekend when Ginny found herself trudging her way into the Slytherin common room, mentally exhausted from fighting against not only gale force winds, but also her own magic, which at that moment had been insisting that she wasn’t even human. She made her way down the stairs and flopped onto her bed without even taking off her quidditch robes.

Darkness fell …

… And her dream scape opened.

Ginny looked around. Baked grassland stretched out in all directions. Mountains squatted in the distance, but they were so far away as to be mere dark blueish shapes against a brilliantly blue sky.

A warm breeze blew.

Relaxing. A break from her troubles.

An impulse flashed through her. It came straight from the magic whirling through her like a whirlpool in a bottle. She didn’t fight it, like she did on her Nimbus 2001. Not here. She instead raised her hands like an orchestra conductor and a tree started growing next to her, trunk thrusting up through the dry ground, up into the air, before spreading out a wide canopy of thorny leaves.

Ginny tried to twitch an ear that couldn’t twitch.

She then climbed the tree. It wasn’t easy without claws—the tree’s trunk didn’t provide many hand holds—but she managed it, eventually settling herself into a crook between the trunk and one of the lower branches.

It was relaxing up here too.

Ginny licked the back of her hand and grinned impishly.

Definitely a cat then.

She pursed her lips.

And of course, the thing about cats, was that they were cold blooded killers.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

At breakfast in the Great Hall, Virgo Malfoy watched the Slytherin table like a hunter waiting for the tell-tale rustle of leaves. The hate potion was finally ready and keyed to Harry Potter. John Potter knew Virgo was going to try something, even if he’d spared him the exact details. Everything was set.

“I can’t tell if Snape’s worse in potions or defence,” Ronald Weasley complained to John. “My arm still stings from when Bullstrode got me.”

There. Ginny Weasley and Luna Lovegood had just entered from the small side door leading to the dungeons. Virgo’s gaze tracked them as they walked up the table and sat down a little way away from Harry Potter.

“I heard Lockhart say he was going to arrange for trick or treating this Halloween.”

“Eh? How’s that going to work?”

“No idea.”

Harry Potter was deep in conversation with the Davis heiress and didn’t seem to be paying the two younger girls any mind. Perfect.

“Johhnnn,” sang a female voice. “Could you ask your mum to give us a hint on what’s coming up on the next potion’s test?”

“Lavender, if I tried that, I’d be grounded for a month.”

“Aww.”

Ginny Weasley and Luna Lovegood both loaded up their plates with food and cast several detection spells on both their food and drink with a practised ease uncommon among first year students.

Virgo’s eyes flashed. Now.

He reached into the bag by her feet and drew out a small amount of the potion. Hidden under the table, he waved his wand over the tiny vial in several complicated gestures that very few wizards would be able to pull off, levitated the liquid out of the glass, and then transfigured the magically powerful liquid into a beautiful butterfly.

Pretty.

Several more wand waves cast both silencing charms, and disillusionment charms over it. Then, finally, he jabbed the wand at the insect and whispered, “imperio.”

His world shifted into two places at once.

Ooooooooooo …thought Julia.

He flapped his wings and climbed his way up from under the table, up and out across the great hall, looking down on the mass of black clad students below through four different eyes and over six-thousand lenses.

He flittered over to the Slytherin table and flapped near the Weasley’s glass, waiting for that perfect moment just before the magic of the transfiguration would run out. Now.

He stopped beating the butterfly’s wings and let it drop into the pumpkin juice with just the tinniest of ripples to announce his arrival. The transfiguration magic wore out and he was kicked out of a head that was no longer a head.

Virgo shook his own head slightly to shake the feeling that he should be eating his breakfast through a straw in his tongue.

That felt weird, Julia thought.

Indeed, he thought back. And now, we wait.

The two Slytherin girls continued their breakfast for a little while longer, chatting and laughing among themselves, and then …

Virgo gripped the edge of the table in frustrated disbelief.

… The two girls grabbed each other’s drinks, toasted something, he couldn’t tell what from over here, and drank each other’s glasses dry.

Fuck!

At least you got the whore, Julia thought.

I don’t want the whore!He thought back.And she’s noble! It won’t work on her anyway! I’ll have to try again, but I don’t have any more of the potion on me. I’ll have to wait until tomorrow.

Virgo put his elbows on the table with his hands under his chin and pouted.

“Cheer up, Virgo.” Susan Bones sat down beside him. “Herbology first thing today. We can work together!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny and Luna quickly made their way through the corridors towards a quiet spot they knew they wouldn’t be overheard.

Ginny was fuming. How dare that bitch! How dare she! Of course she and Luna had sensed a transfigured butterfly loaded down with so much magic! They could feel and identify magical intent in the tip of an opponent’s wand in a Merlin damned duel!

And even if it had got through, a hostile hate potion now had about as much chance of fulfilling its ultimate task of getting her to hate the target as it did for Luna, but that wasn’t the point! It was the principle of the thing. Virgo had tried to rip her away from Harry! Fuck that bitch!

If there wasn’t an innocent girl trapped in there with her, she’d … she’d … Gah!

“What do you want to do?” Luna asked when they finally finished casting all their standard security spells including a fidelius sweep check.

“What do you think we should do?” Ginny asked back.

“Not much we can do unless she tries again—apart from tell Harry.”

“And if she does try again?”

“We could pretend it worked?”

“Why?”

Luna shrugged. “It would stop her trying again.”

“I don’t want to pretend to hate Harry.”

“We could let you drink the actual thing. Virgo would know then that it doesn’t work.”

“That’s even worse! I don’t want to be magically forced to actually hate Harry either! Even if it won’t have any long term effects. What about the law?”

“Unless we caught her administrating the potion itself, I don’t see how that would help. She’s sure to be careful enough not to get caught.”

“Why’s she doing it anyway?” Ginny asked. “What’s her goal?”

Luna frowned. “I don’t know.”

Ginny stared at her best friend. “I thought you knew everything.”

Luna giggled.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the classroom that played host to the founder’s club, the second year muggleborns—Sophie Roper, Justin Finch-Fletchley, Dean Thomas, and Kevin Entwhistle—couldn’t help feeling that something had been decidedly off about Hermione over the last few weeks.

“I saw her skipping the other day,” Dean Thomas said. “Does Hermione seem to you like the kind of girl who skips?”

“Not really,” Sophie said. “Kevin?”

Kevin grunted. “Annabel told me Hermione’s been a lot more approachable recently. Which is odd, because I’ve felt the opposite.”

“You noticed that too, did you?” Dean asked.

Sophie shrugged. “She seems fine to me.”

“Maybe we’re just imagining it then,” Justin suggested. “Anyone had any luck with their parents on the guardianship thing?”

They all shook their heads.

“My Mum told me not to concern myself with things like that,” Sophie said sounding despondent. “Even though I explained everything very carefully. It’s frustrating. She doesn’t seem to understand how bad our position is.”

At that point, the door opened and Hermione trotted in with the first year muggleborns in tow. “Good evening, everyone!” She beamed.

The Chesterfield twins, Violet and Marigold, made immediately for the chairs at the front of the room and sat down patiently waiting for Hermione to start, followed shortly thereafter by Annabel Entwhistle, Colin Creevey, and Alan Gage. Colin still had his camera around his neck, although he had been ‘subtly’ persuaded not to take photos of founder’s club meetings.

The second years all waved and turned around in their seats to get back to work on their occlumency training. None of them noticed Hermione stumble on her way to the podium, clutching her head as a random wave of mandrake leaf induced dizziness swept over her.

The first years did notice. It would be hard to miss.

“Are you okay, Hermione?” Marigold asked, looking concerned.

“Perfectly.” Hermione coughed before a small smirk graced her lips. “But enough horsing around—let’s begin our next lesson.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

You don’t think they knew what you were trying to do, do you? Julia asked in Virgo’s head.

They were sitting, once again, at the Gryffindor table, scanning the Slytherin table as best they could through the Hufflepuffs and Ravenclaws for their targets.

Virgo scoffed. Of course not. How would they do that? They are children.

Julia mentally shrugged.

Ginny Weasley and Luna Lovegood were eating breakfast with a speed that suggested they had other places to be. Unlike most of their classmates, who seemed to be trying to outdo each other in terms of pureblood refinement and stoicism, these two just did not seem to give a damn. Lovegood had her wand stored behind her ear, while Weasley was dressed in what looked to him like rags, but which he knew from Julia were, in fact, clothes muggles used for exercising—very different from the clothes muggles in his own time used.

At that moment, Luna Lovegood—the whore—stood up and walked away from the table. Well, that would make everything much more reliable.

Virgo slipped out a second dose of hate potion from his bag, pointed his wand under the table, ignoring the ruckus caused by the Weasley twins’ efforts to prank their younger brother with a toy spider, and began the wand motions for the butterfly transfiguration.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny Weasley glared down the Gray side of the Slytherin table. All the meat had gone. Sausages, bacon, eggs, hams, salmon—between them, Harry, Daphne, Luna, and herself had wiped the large serving platters clean of the lot of them. Luna and Harry in particular had ripped through a freakishly large breakfast with a speed that caused their older classmates to stare.

Thank Merlin all this animal behaviour awkwardness would dampened down considerably once they were all done.

Of Harry’s girls (as Ginny had starting thinking of themselves), only Hermione wasn’t fighting for the proverbial cow like piranhas at a feeding frenzy. Her plate contained mostly vegetables and grains, although she did currently seem to have a thing for apples.

Ginny glanced at the Gryffindor table and took a sip of her pumpkin juice.

And of course, she was no closer to making a decision about what she wanted to do about her training. She still wasn’t sure. What if Harry needed her to kill someone and she froze up again? The diary had been easy to think about destroying, because of what it was, but what if she eventually needed to kill a real person? Would she be able to do that?

Ginny took another sip of pumpkin juice and a wave of dizziness swept over her. Oh, Merlin. She put the glass down and gripped the edges of the table as her whole world went spinning. An overwhelming feeling of cat filled up her senses … and nothing else.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Banzai! Julia shouted as Virgo directed the disillusioned butterfly straight into Weasley’s cup.

The transfiguration ended and half of Virgo’s world snapped back into one.

Virgo smirked. My, weareenthusiastic this morning, aren’t we?

Yes, we are, Julia thought back.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Harry quickly noticed something was wrong. It would be hard not to when one of the girls he very definitely counted as a close friend marched up to him, grabbed him by an ear, and proceeded to attempt to pull him out of the great hall. He went along with it, getting quite a few giggles from the older female population as he went by. Presumably the hate potion Virgo had been trying to slip Ginny had somehow got through.

“Stop fighting you manipulative bastard!” Ginny snarled at him.

Harry wasn’t fighting it.

“Five points from Slytherin for inappropriate language!” Professor Sprout shouted from the high table as they left.

They stopped in one of the corridors outside the hall. “How’s it feel?” Harry asked.

“Horrible. I can see everything clear as day. Your manipulativeness, your calculation, the way you don’t care about anyone that you don’t consider to be yours.”

Harry nodded.

“And the way you just calmly accept all that!” she added.

“Better than screaming. And what do you think about all that?”

Ginny glared. “Obviously, I know it all already! I like your cunning, and don’t give two shits about the other stuff. But this potion. Gurhhh! Hatred, but for no reason. It’s dumb.” Her voice dropped to a growl. “I wanted to hate John. I don’t want to hate you.”

Harry glanced over her shoulder. “Don’t look now, but Virgo just turned the corner.”

The growl in Ginny’s voice turned to a snarl. “Perfect. Let’s do it now.”

Harry shook his head. “The girl, Ginny. Besides, John’s with her.”

Ginny fell silent but didn’t turn around.

“Miss Weasley?” Virgo called out as she approached. “I wonder if I might have a word with you?” She gestured towards Harry. “Away from … him.”

The slap echoed around the empty castle hall like a whip crack, and arrived at its target just about as fast.

Ginny Weasley had covered the distance between herself and Virgo in a blink of an eye and hit her so hard the whole of her body turned towards the wall, staring in shock.

“Fuck you, bitch,” Ginny snarled into her face. She then turned 180 degrees and dragged the second Potter twin out of sight. Footsteps retreated, and finally, a door slammed.

What? Virgo thought.

He slowly straightened back up, still holding his cheek in shock.

John walked up to him and put a hand on his shoulder. “Yeah, I felt one of her slaps too,” he said sadly. “Thank you for at least trying though. Whatever it was you tried to do. I really do appreciate it.”

Virgo muttered something. He wasn’t sure what—his mind was racing far too quickly—but he soon found himself being dropped off for his transfiguration class. John had escorted him there.

Virgo … Julia started as they sat down in the front row.

Yes?Virgo thought back.

That girl … the way she moved. That speed. It was just like the time in the bathroom.

Yes, Virgo thought back. Yes, I was just thinking the same thing.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

An hour later, Harry walked back into the empty classroom the hate-potioned Ginny had first dragged him into, looked around, and shook his head. The place was destroyed. Vicious looking cut marks were gouged into the walls, windows were broken, chairs smashed, desks bent. The chalk board had been snapped clean in half. All evidence of a trained fighter unloading all her frustrations onto an extremely convenient target—him.

Harry waved Lord Slytherin’s wand in a wide arc, focused his powers, and said, “Reparo.” The chairs flew back together, the blackboard fixed itself, and every shard of glass from the windows found their way back into each individual window pane’s incredibly complicated shattered mosaic before smoothing back, as good as new—or rather, almost as good as new.

Harry then made his way to the Slytherin dorms. Yes, they technically had classes, but classes could wait. This was important.

He strolled past the defences made to keep males out of the girl’s dorms, walked into the second year’s dormitory, and climbed into the trunk by Hermione’s bed.

Ginny looked up at him from the side of a small camping bed, holding a bucket in her hands, face green and sickly.

Hermione was sitting by her side.

“How’s the flushing going?” he asked, just as Ginny heaved and let loose another wave of vomit into the bucket.

“About as well as can be expected,” Hermione said.

Ginny snorted.

“She’ll be right as rain in a half an hour, give or take ten minutes.”

Harry nodded and sat down on Ginny’s other side.

Ginny looked up at him and winced. Then she turned to Hermione. “Do you mind if we talk alone for a few minutes?”

“Not at all.”

“What’s up?” Harry asked when Hermione closed the trunk lid behind her.

“I didn’t kill the chickens, Harry.”

Harry considered this. “You were afraid to tell me you hadn’t?”

Ginny nodded slowly. “I felt guilty.”

“You know I’m not going to be angry if you choose not to kill?”

“I know.”

Silence filled the trunk for just a moment before Ginny heaved again and another round of vomit fell into the bucket. Ginny coughed and spluttered before taking a deep breath.

“But I have decided,” she said, looking up at him through matted hair. “I have decided to fight—I decided to fight years ago, and, now I decide that if you need it, I will learn to kill as well. No matter how hard I find it. I swear.”

Harry hugged her. “Thank you, Ginny. You’ve no idea how much you and the others mean to me.”

Ginny hugged him back and smirked. “I think I can guess.”

The moment would have been a lot more beautiful if she hadn’t proceeded to then throw up all over him.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny slowly came to and looked out across her dreamscape.

The savannah sun beat down on her long red hair.

The grass land was now golden brown.

Thorny bushes lay scattered around where she stood.

A small river flowed through the land, carving out a tiny valley on the otherwise flat plane.

It felt … complete.

Ginny felt the urge to run—the urge to sprint. She instead jogged along a trail she found until she reached a ridge.

The ridge hid another plane, and over that …

Animals.

Ginny’s eyes widened. Thousands of animals. Wildebeest, oryx, zebra, gazelle, even a small heard of giraffes—they all grazed in a colossal herd. Birds flew everywhere. The air felt alive with insects. And out of the corner of her eye, she caught something … else.

Ginny froze. The thing was lurking in the grasses almost right next to her. Its body was low to the ground and was longer than she was tall. It didn’t seem to be paying any attention to her, which was just as well, because every instinct in that part of her brain that wasn’t under the influence of mandrake leaf—that part of her evolutionary brain that was still monkey—was screaming ‘predator’ at the top of its lungs.

Something changed. There was a shift in the herd, and the thing beside her started to lift upwards like a statue slowly grinding to life. It prowled forward, out of the long grass. Ginny’s breath hitched. The shoulders rose above the head, every movement powerfully controlled. Each paw strike on the ground suggested the pinning of a mouse. The back slung low to the ground, like a sagging suspension bridge, while the legs suggested the kind of coiled power usually found in freight train buffer springs.

It trotted forward as a great collective herbivorous maw of alarm sounded across a thousand animals. It broke into a canter as the smaller gazelle broke away from the main herd, and then, suddenly, it broke into a full sprint.

Ginny jumped forward and ran to keep the chase in sight, heedless of the general panic all around her.

The target desperately zipped this way and that, trying to avoid the killer rapidly closing in on it, but it might as well have tried to out run its own shadow. There was a loud bleet, a faint cloud of dust, and both predator and prey disappeared from view as they fell to the ground in a mass of flailing limbs and snarling teeth.

Ginny raced to where the hunt had ended and stared down at what she knew was her animal. The cheetah stared back up at her, exhausted, unable to even move, lying on the ground, lungs rising and falling in great heaving expansions and contractions, jaws firmly locked around the gazelle’s throat, which was very clearly and obviously dead.

Ginny slowly walked up to the magnificent animal and laid a tentative hand on its head. It didn’t attack. She knew it wouldn’t. Ginny felt the connection, a part of her she’d always known, but never been able to put into words. A certainty she’d been missing.

Ginny narrowed her eyes. And she nodded.

—End of Chapter Forty-One—

Chapter End Notes

Ao3 Author Note

New Year’s Eve! Wooo!

I am now running a joint chapter release schedule between my fan-fiction and my original fantasy novel chapter drafts. 2018 is looking to be awesome! So much stuff is happening. If you want to keep abreast of the release schedule, as well as any changes and the occasional piece of bonus content, you can head over to www.leadvone.com and sign up for the Gray Mailing List.

If you would like to discuss this chapter with other readers, I suggest you check out the fan-run discord server, http://discord.me/leadvone

Also, the website itself has had a major update, so it looks a lot nicer now, and links through to a bunch more DP&SW fan content.

Conversion rate is:
1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds
1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)
1 Knut to 10p (roughly)
All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Daphne’s Birthday, Work and Play—Part One

Mountains. Mountains as far as the eye could see—snowy topped, jagged, desolate. Daphne Greengrass sat, cross-legged on a craggy ledge, overlooking a sheer cliff, and fought every instinct in her still human body, not to jump.

A bitingly fresh wind whirled Daphne’s hair around her face. She hooked several strands around her ear and relaxed as best she could against the cliff wall behind her. She rarely sat cross-legged—it wasn’t something she’d been brought up to do. Her mind seemed to know this very well. Even in her dream-scape, her muscles protested at the unusual position she was asking them to take.

The stone floor she was sitting on was awfully hard too …

Her vision blurred and a wave of dizziness hit her.

She was waking up.

Daphne opened her eyes, blearily, and sat up in bed. Her plushy snake uncoiled itself from her body and coiled itself up one of her four-poster pillars. The torches flickering on the wall had changed from dim green to bright orange. It was morning and the Slytherin girls dormitory was mostly empty. That was unusual. Usually, she was among the first up.

“They’re all upstairs preparing your surprise birthday wave-off,” called a nasally voice from the bathroom.

Daphne cursed under her breath. “Thank you so very much, Parkinson,” she said sarcastically. “I will do my best to act suitably surprised.”

She put Pansy out of her mind and smiled, because it was her birthday—her thirteenth birthday—which meant lots of things for a witch, but the one thing it meant above all for her was that Harry was taking her out adventuring. … Well, eventually, anyway.

Actually, he was going to take her out adventuring after they’d finished the important business of the day. Just her luck that her birthday was the only day they had to give the submarine sales pitch to MaCUSA.

But! After that, it would be just her and Harry, and it would be almost all a surprise. Only almost, because, at some point, she’d be doing her thirteenth birthday ritual. She knew that was going to happen. Choosing which ritual to perform had taken weeks. Thinking about it still caused her to blush.

Daphne swung her feet off the bed and slipped them into the pair of fluffy slippers.

She really hoped the business stuff wouldn’t last too long.

Ignoring Pansy, she showered, towelled herself down, wrapped said towel around herself, sat down in front of her bedside mirror, applied her cosmetic charms, then stood back up, and walked to the trunk beside her bed, retrieving something else she’d been looking forward to for a long time.

The something else was a long, frilled, scarf-like length of material in emerald green, soft and stiff at the same time. The silky material quivered in her hands, giving the impression of life trapped in fabric. Her mother had given it to her the night before she’d caught the Hogwarts Express back to Hogwarts.

Daphne walked back to the mirror, dropped the towel around her ankles, and smiled. Yes, she definitely now had breasts, no question. It was impossible to say that she didn’t. They’d been growing steadily for a couple years now, and, if her memory from her time under ageing potion served her correctly, were about half their final size.

Daphne brought the scarf up to her chest, let the smallest amount of magic flow into the material and gasped as it leapt from her fingers, flowed around her body, and moulded itself snugly, but not tightly, around her chest. It was an odd feeling, but not unpleasant, which was just as well. She’d be wearing it everyday now.

Still busily appreciating her new, grown-up look, Daphne caught Pansy staring at her in the mirror’s reflection. The Parkinson Heiress had not been having nearly as much luck as her in the breast department.

Daphne smirked and stepped into her new dress robes.

Pansy sniffed and stuck her nose up in the air. “So, you’ve got a bit of a head-start,” she said, sounding like she was putting a lot of care into sounding like she didn’t care. “It means nothing.”

Daphne smirked again. Then schooled her features and waved a vague hand. “Luckily, I don’t need to worry about such things, seeing as I already have a betrothed. I’m actually a little worried that they might grow too much. That would be simply awful.”

Pansy scowled.

“Don’t worry,” Daphne continued, admiring the way the dress whispered as it moved around her ankles. “I’m sure yours will come through in time for your birthday. When is it again? December?”

“November,” Pansy growled. “And I don’t need to worry. I will have my choice of suitors, you’ll see.”

Daphne didn’t wait for Pansy to finish getting dressed. She picked up the duffel-bag she’d already prepared the night before—full of specifically warm clothes—wrapped the cord of her handbag around her wrist, checked herself in the mirror one last time, and left the dormitory, climbing the stairs to the Slytherin common room, which would surely be full of people eager to show they cared about her thirteenth birthday—a show she naturally had to reciprocate. She was still the Greengrass Heiress, and as such, duty came before adventure, even if it was adventure she truly craved.

“Happy thirteenth!”

One voice from several dozen wizards and witches hit her all at once. The common room was packed. Green and silver paper streamers fell everywhere. Several of the decorative stone snakes wore party hats at jaunty angles. Presents poured across a table off to one side, carefully guarded by both Hermione and Marcus Flint.

“Wow,” Daphne said, walking into the centre of the room, dumping her bag, and looking around. “I didn’t expect all this.”

There were a couple of disbelieving snorts from around the room.

“Speech!” Someone shouted.

“Speech! Speech!” The cry picked up momentum.

“Wait just a minute,” Hermione shouted back. “Presents! She doesn’t have very long until Lord Slytherin picks her up.” She indicated a much smaller pile of packages on a nearby chair.

“Can it, Granger!”

“No,” a voice drawled. Draco Malfoy stepped out of his circle by the Dark’s court. “For once, the know-it-all is correct. Please, Heiress Greengrass.”

The room settled down somewhat. People started chatting among themselves.

Daphne gave Malfoy a reluctant nod and walked over to the table full of gifts.

Hermione leaned into her ear and whispered, “We’ve filtered out the important ones. They’re on the chair.”

“Thanks.”

Daphne picked up the first present and inspected it.

“Romulus Volf,” Hermione said, pointing out the name label. “I did not expect that.”

“Our lord has become a lot more public since Volf shouted those silly accusations last year. He’s probably hoping to mend fences.”

Daphne slowly started to work her way through the birthday gifts, calling out her thanks to whomever had sent them, if they were in the room, and having Tracey add those who weren’t to a ‘to be thanked later’ list.

Everything was going as expected, until it was Draco Malfoy’s turn. Naturally, if anything spectacle worthy was going to happen, it would be with him.

Daphne picked up the gift cautiously. It was among the last in the pile, with the heft and weight of a book. She unwrapped it. It was a family autobiography of Louis Malfoy—From Beauxbatons to Bordeaux. A dictaquilled copy in soft leather.

“I thought you might appreciate that,” Malfoy said with a slight smirk.

Daphne wasn’t sure she understood. What was ‘you might appreciate that’ supposed to mean? She had no particular interest in Malfoy’s family history and he should know that. This wasn’t the kind of thing people normally gave as birthday gifts. Declaration of intent gifts, certainly, but not birthday gifts, and this was not a declaration of intent gift. It wasn’t presented in the correct way, and besides, no one would be silly enough to try and give her such a gift. One might as well gift preventative birth control to an already pregnant witch.

Malfoy was standing slightly off to one side near his court.

All eyes in the common room were upon them.

“My father suggested certain arrangements could perhaps be made …” he said.

And then the knut dropped. What this was, was a birthday gift hiding a declaration of intent inside it. He was suggesting that maybe, one day, she and he would be family. But, it wasn’t an intent gift aimed at her—it was aimed at …

Daphne gave a lady-like snort. “If you think you’re ever getting your grubby little mitts on my sister then you’ve got another thing coming.”

“I don’t believe that is ultimately your decision, Heiress Greengrass.” And the word “Heiress” was clearly being said in huge quotation marks. “And the strength of the Gray can wane. Yes, now you’re not doing too badly, but you are still the weaker side, and the weak must ultimately bow before the strong.”

“Oh, wonderful. Then since my betrothed is stronger than you, you can bow before him.”

Malfoy’s slight smile vanished. “You need to be more careful, Greengrass. There are those who say,” and now he raised his voice so that it was obvious he was speaking to the whole room. “That the reason Lord Slytherin wears a mask is he is hiding something shameful. People are starting to suspect.”

“What are they starting to suspect, Malfoy?”

“Oh.” Malfoy waved a vague hand. “All sorts of things.”

“Name one thing.”

“I wouldn’t dream of talking about those kinds of things in public.”

“Oh, this is so much rubbish!” Hermione stomped over and stood beside Daphne. “You don’t have a clue what they are saying, do you? If you really knew anything you wouldn’t hesitate to shout it to the world.”

Draco glared at her. “No one asked your opinion you filthy little mudblood.”

The room stilled. A few people gasped. It was as if a single arrow had been loosed between two lined up ranks of battle tense soldiers, and those soldiers were now glancing around to see if anyone else looked like they were going to attack. Few people in the room cared much about the word itself, but, over the last year, a sort of understanding had arisen when it came to Hermione, especially after the reception she’d received on her thirteenth birthday. Ultimately, this wasn’t so much about blood purity as it was about pride and honour. Nearby, Ginny and Luna had their wands out, looking alert. The air was so tense it could have been cut with a diffindo.

The only person who didn’t seem to care was Malfoy … at least, until a voice from the Dark court sounded throughout the room. “Draco.”

Daphne recognised the voice immediately, and Malfoy’s reaction was priceless. He flinched.

Alexandra was sat in the middle of one of the Dark’s couches, taking up far more space than an eleven-year-old girl should.

The room’s attention quickly shifted to her.

“That wasn’t very nice Draco, don’t you think?”

“Black—” Draco started, voice already uncertain.

“From what I’ve seen, Miss Granger is a lovely girl.”

If she hadn’t been so tense, Daphne might have snorted. Alex and Hermione had been at each others throats in group combat training more so than anyone else in Harry’s group.

Malfoy’s face contorted. He glanced around the room, apparently gauging how much support he might get. The various little groups that made up the Dark looked uncertainly between him and Alexandra.

Malfoy finished his survey and narrowed his eyes. “You can’t seriously be suggesting that we should see her kind as our equals?”

“No, of course not,” Alex said, with what Daphne felt was slightly too much emphatic emphasis. “But that doesn’t mean you can’t be a bit nicer. Would you kick your house elf just because he’s your servant?”

“Yes.”

Alex’s eyes widened slightly. Clearly she hadn’t been expecting that answer. “You would?”

“Yes. It’s just a house elf.”

“But … but …” Alex seemed to be struggling with some terrible inner conflict. “But it’s your own house elf. That’s like cursing your own broom.”

Daphne heard several people snigger.

“An interesting way of looking at things,” said a new voice, far deeper than any student’s.

Many heads whirled around. Many lungs inhaled sharply. Malfoy and Alex, who were both right near the always empty Slytherin throne, spun a full 180 degrees to face the new voice.

Daphne smiled. Lord Slytherin was casually sitting on the Slytherin throne between the courts of the Dark and the Gray, under the effect of ageing potion and masked. He hadn’t been there a second ago. Daphne didn’t need legilimency to know that just about everyone in the room was wondering how he got there without anyone noticing, or just how long he’d been there.

Finally, it was time for her to be off.

Alex was the first person to move. “You!” she shouted, standing up quickly.

“I?” Slytherin said back.

“Duel me!”

Various members of the Dark gave her incredulous looks and started edging away. One fourth-year wizard actually dove over the back of his sofa.

Harry ignored them and slowly stood up. “Not today, Heiress Black. I have another important appointment.” He shifted his focus. “Happy birthday, Daphne.”

Daphne smiled brightly. “Thank you, my lord.”

Alex sat heavily back down in her seat and folded her arms.

Harry grabbed Daphne’s duffel-bag and led her out of the common room, greeting various students including Luna and Hermione as he passed. No one tried to stop them leaving.

Once they were outside, Daphne stepped out from behind her lord as they traversed the corridors of Hogwarts. “How much of that did you see?”

“All of it. It would appear our dear Lucius has set his son’s sights on Astoria.”

“I don’t understand why though,” Daphne said. “Father isn’t old, so he’s unlikely to get control of his Wizengamot seat for decades—maybe even a century. The same goes for the Greengrass businesses.”

“Jacob will most likely grant Astoria a dowry, considering she won’t get to fully manage the Greengrass estate for a long time.”

“But a dowry would still belong to Astoria.”

“In theory, yes. But I do still agree with you. It’s unlikely to be for financial reasons. I imagine it’s more likely a straight-up attempt to bring the Gray closer to the Dark rather than the Light.”

Daphne smirked. “Which is what we want.”

“Yes, but I doubt in the way they were imagining. Alex seems to be making good progress, doesn’t she?” Harry slowed his stride. “Oh? What do we have here?”

A figure was walking towards them from the great entrance hallway that led to the grounds. It was Lily Potter. It didn’t look like she’d been searching them out—rather that she’d been on the way somewhere else and just happened to run into them.

“Lady Potter,” Harry said as she neared.

Lily Potter stopped in front of them. “Lord Slytherin.” She turned to Daphne. “Happy thirteenth, Miss Greengrass.”

“Thank you.”

Lily Potter turned back to Harry. “I trust this excursion won’t take her out of classes come Monday?”

“It should not.”

“Very well.” Lily Potter looked like she wanted to say something else to the mysterious lord standing in front of her, but another quick glance at Daphne suggested it wasn’t something she was comfortable saying in front of other people. “Please excuse me. Good day to you both.”

Daphne Greengrass and Lord Slytherin continued to walk, leaving Lily Potter alone. Lily bit her lip before turning around and continuing on the path that led to the Slytherin Dungeons. Once there, she spoke the password to the Slytherin common room, entered, and looked around, ignoring the general commotion of a Saturday Morning. The prefects were efficiently taking down a lot of celebration decorations.

Unable to find who she was looking for, Lily walked over to the second year student she felt most comfortable with.

“Miss Davis?”

Tracey Davis turned to her from where she’d been deep in conversation with Hermione Granger.

Of course, Lily’s favourite student in Slytherin should have been Miss Granger, what with her being both muggleborn like her and easily top of her class, but Miss Granger always treated her rather coldly, something Lily never understood. Tracey Davis, by contrast, felt rather like her own Gryffindor students.

“You don’t happen to know where Harry is?” Lily asked.

“You just missed him, Professor,” Tracey replied.

“And you don’t know where he is?”

“No, Professor.”

“Oh,” Lily let out a slightly disappointed sigh. “I guess I’ll see him at breakfast then.”

“Most likely.”

“Well, thank you anyway.” She left.

Tracey and Hermione traded apprehensive glances. Harry wasn’t going to be in Hogwarts for the whole weekend. Their thoughts both trailed to the vials of Harry keyed polyjuice potion sitting in Hermione’s trunk.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On Gairsay Island, Daphne stepped out of the floo and into an empty living room, Harry stepping out a moment later behind her. The room was deeper than it was wide and ended in an open corridor going both left and right. A big set of double doors were set into the far corridor wall. On either side of the fireplace behind her, large windows let in a constant stream of bright sunlight. A thin layer of plaster dust on the floor suggested that the goblins had only just packed up their tools and that the house elves hadn’t yet had a chance to get their paws on the result.

Daphne recognised where they were immediately. This was the third floor living quarters of Slytherin Manor. Her future home.

“Like it?” Harry asked.

“Yes—very spacious, my lord,” Daphne said. “But it needs furniture. It feels empty without it. Especially if we’re going to use this as our base when we reveal you.”

It wasn’t only the living room that needed furniture. Daphne walked up and down the living quarter’s corridor, poking her head into each of the thirteen bedrooms in turn, each one an empty shell, ready to be filled full of stuff. She mentally claimed the one immediately to the right of the large central one with the office, which was obviously Harry’s. Luna could have the one to the left. Hermione, Ginny, and Alex could claim their own … later on. That was, if Harry succeeded in bringing them into the family too. Although, with how things went on Hermione’s birthday, she wouldn’t be surprised if that one, at least, was a fait accompli.

Harry was waiting for her down the stairs in the circle corridor that surrounded the balcony overlooking the ballroom. “Ready for your first birthday present?”

Daphne was more than ready. Harry led her down the corridor and into what she recognised as the library. A single bookshelf stood in the middle of the large room. There were several books on the shelves all wrapped up in various coloured packagings.

“Happy thirteenth birthday, Daphne.”

Daphne eyed the books before taking one off the shelf, hefting it in her hands. What kind of present would Harry get her? No, what kind of present would Lord Slytherin get her? They were slightly different questions after all.

“Why don’t you try and guess?” Harry said, letting an amusement into his voice that Daphne never heard him use as part of his Lord Slytherin persona in public.

Daphne gave a slight smirk. “Okay, I’m game.” She thought about it. “Something educational.”

“That much wasn’t hard to guess.”

“Something to do with what I’m currently learning.”

“Sort of …”

“Something to do with something that I’m not currently learning, but should be.”

“Again, sort of …”

“Something to do with something I’m trying to learn, but not doing so well at?”

“I wouldn’t say you’re doing badly at it …”

Daphne’s mind flicked through all her current projects—business, divination, leadership, politics, combat, animagus discovery … Eventually she settled on one. “Combat,” she declared. “Something I feel weak at and want to improve on.”

“Strategy,” Harry said, simply.

“Strategy!” Daphne snapped her fingers. “So close.” She frowned. “But, my lord, I’ve already read all the classic works on strategy.”

“Really?” Harry’s voice sounded playful now. “Name three books that influenced Voldemort’s strategies during his first rise.”

“Maintaining The Statute, by Samantha Goldstein—Blood is Thicker than Magic, by Dracula—and The Way of the Warlock by Robert Dimwiddy,”Daphne rattled off, with ease. “Of course, the Rise and Fall of the Dark Arts also points out that he drew heavily on the campaign of terror waged by Grindelwald, which he grew up in, for inspiration.”

“All true,” Harry said. “… to an extent,” he added. “Dracula’s treatise on how to win a blood feud and Grindelwald’s terror tactics do indeed mirror Voldemort’s tactics, but. …” He trailed off. “Well, firstly, where do you think Grindelwald got his terror tactics from?”

Daphne blinked. “He invented them, didn’t he? They were a combination of tactics on intimidation discussed in Blood is Thicker Than Magic and lessons learned from the resistance movement in the Germanic lands against the Second Magical British Empire.”

Harry shook his head. “Was it that resistance movement that eventually took Dimwiddy down?”

“Well, no, it was the Seventh Cursed Alliance.”

“So why do you think Grindelwald believed that using their tactics would help him achieve his goals?”

“Well, because. …” Daphne hesitated. “I don’t know.”

“It’s because of a muggle named Michael Collins, who, not long before Grindelwald, used very similar tactics to achieve independence for his country, Ireland, from the muggle British Empire.”

“Grindelwald took inspiration from a muggle?”

“Indeed. And he wasn’t the only one. Think about it. You’re Voldemort and you’ve seen Grindelwald fail, now, are you going to use his exact same tactics to fight your war?”

“No?”

“No.” Harry confirmed. “Oh, you take the basics from him, certainly, but you still need something else—something to make sure you don’t fail like he did. Voldemort spent over thirty years looking for every advantage he could get before he launched his own campaign against Magical Britain.”

Daphne looked down at the book in her hands. “And you’re saying that he got it from this?”

“Oh, no, not that one.” Harry plucked another book from the shelf and handed it to her. “This one.”

Daphne took the book and ripped off the wrapping paper. “On Guerilla warfare, by Mao Zedong. Who’s that?”

“A muggle lord who conquered China.”

“Really? Light or Dark?”

“By our definition he was something like a Light Lord, although most western muggles would choke if you suggested that to them. Muggles don’t use the words Light and Dark in quite the same way we do. Mao was extremely anti-hereditary power—about as anti-hereditary power as it’s possible to be. So much so that he abolished private property and declared everything,from the house you lived in to the food you ate, to be owned by the state.”

Daphne stared. “Wow. Not even Dimwiddy would have suggested that.”

“Like I said, the word ‘Light’ is not a perfect translation for what this particular muggle was.”

Daphne looked down at the cover of On Guerilla Warfare,a feeling of excitement welling up in her. She’d never even heard of these works before. And if she’d never heard of them, chances were people like Malfoy and John certainly hadn’t. She smiled. “And Voldemort used the tactics of a sort-of-but-not-really muggle Light Lord to fight a war for a muggle hating Dark? That is ironic.”

“You wanted to become a better strategist, Daphne. Because that’s how you feel you can best contribute in our group combat training.” Harry gestured to the long row of books on the shelf. “I give you twenty of the most influential muggle books on strategy ever written. Voldemort himself only really skimmed through most of them. He found Mao, became an instant convert, and focused in almost solely on him. But I know the others still hold immense value—even if I myself haven’t been able to assimilate all they have to teach.”

Daphne enthusiastically picked up the book she’d first selected and ripped off the paper to reveal The History of The Peloponnesian War, by Thucydides. She looked along the long line of books and smiled brightly. This present was so Harry.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lily Potter stared around the Great Hall and frowned.

Harry was most definitely not here.

She’d arrived early to make sure she caught her son before he dashed off to Merlin only knew where, but students were now packing up and heading off to whatever weekend actives they had, and Harry still hadn’t shown.

She didn’t want much, just to have him and John around her small Hogwarts apartment for a chat about school work, and perhaps try to encourage the two to be a bit more friendly towards each other, but it seemed what should be a trivial task wasn’t going to be quite so easy.

Lily thought deeply. Now, where would Harry be this early on a Saturday morning? The library? The duelling arena? The quidditch pitch? All possible, although maybe not so much the last one. Hopefully it would be one of the obvious places. Hogwarts was a maze. Finding anyone here was like looking for a needle in a haystack of hay-to-needle transfigured hay.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Slytherin Manor stood at the top of Gairsay island’s large rolling hill. On the south side of Gairsay Island, at the bottom of the hill, deep under Granger Cottage, in a hollowed out cavern dipping into the waters of the North Sea, the adult Grangers were just putting the finishing touches on their full-scale submarine model.

There had been changes.

A good number of the worktops, machines, and raw materials that previously littered the cavernous space had been shoved to the far wall, cramped up against each other with barely enough room to walk between them, all to make room for the model.

That model was made of polystyrene and balsa wood, and sat some fifteen-metres long—over one metre high at the front, two metres high at the back. Small wheels on the bottom allowed the model to be pulled apart at many points along its length, showing the inside to be hollow, and covered in tens of thousands of tiny runes, all printed onto printer paper and stuck on with thumbtacks.

Daniel Granger fondly patted the nose cone, which was hinged to allow entry through the front. This was his baby and he was damn proud of it. “Won’t fly in the air, of course,” he said to the two new arrivals. “Making room for the life support systems and all that other stuff seriously cut down the amount of rune room we had to play with.”

“It’s a broomstick,” whispered Jacob’s daughter in awe. “A broomstick so large you can crawl inside it.” The young teenager looked towards where Lord Slytherin was walking up and down along the model’s side, running a hand along its smooth surface.

“That’s right,” Emma said. She and Clare were sitting at a nearby table, drinking tea and cutting up a small birthday cake. “We spent ages on upgrading the trunk engine, but no matter how we worked it, we couldn’t get it to meet ICW ISS standards. Not to mention ministry export regulations. But then we thought, ‘Hey! Broomsticks already meet ICW ISS standards and ministry export regulations. And our miniature runes allow us to scale up a broomstick in a way no other broomstick maker can.’ Nimbus even practically gift wrapped the basic runic patterns for us and handed them to us on a silver platter. That bit alone could have taken years by ourselves.”

“We’re stealing Nimbus’s rune patterns?” Daphne asked.

Dan waggled a hand. “Stealing is a strong word. There’s no way for them to learn about it unless they break into our broomstick the way we did into theirs. Good luck on them finding a CAT scanner that can scan that.” He jerked his thumb towards the fifteen metre long monstrosity behind him.

At that moment, Lord Slytherin arrived back beside Dan after doing another circle of the model. “This all looks fine,” he said, “but we still do have a slight problem.”

“Which is?”

“I’ve read the documentation you owled me earlier, but I’m still far from an expert. If the boys from MaCUSA want detailed technical explanations, I’ll need back up.”

Dan looked uncertainly between his masked lord and his wife. “But, will they accept us as experts? If they know we’re not magical?”

“No, they won’t—and letting them know is not an option.” Slytherin reached into a fold in his robes. “… which is why …” He withdrew a pair of identical Slytherin masks. “… you’re going to be wearing these.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Clare watched from a distance as Dan and Emma enthusiastically slipped on their expensive wizarding robes and donned their brand new Slytherin Masks, chatting to each other at a mile a minute about merlins, flamels, runic patterns, muggle engineering, and how much of a fantasy novel they lived in.

The birthday girl sat nearby eating birthday cake with the air of a moviegoer waiting for the film to start.

Slytherin stepped up beside her. “Would you like to come too, Clare?”

Clare sighed. “Is that an order, my lord?”

“No, it is an honest offer. The wizarding world is more than just Diagon Alley and school. Jacob and Sunny are taking Dan and Emma to a quidditch match this afternoon. I can grant you leave for the day so long as you stay with the two of them and are back before mid-night.”

Clare thought about it. The trip between school and home had gotten a bit stale, even if it was more freedom than she’d ever had at the polyjuice brothel. She nodded. “Then, yes—I think I would like that.”

Slytherin handed her another green and black mask, which she quickly donned, not needing to worry about changing her clothes. All her clothes were robes. Slytherin then tapped the collar around her neck with his wand and she felt a slight change in its magic.

Wearing the mask felt odd. There was clearly something attached to her face, but it didn’t restrict her eyesight or breathing at all.

“I understand Dan and Emma have told you of my need for phoenix ash?” Slytherin asked. “How is that going?”

Clare nodded. “Yes—but there’s only so much they can buy before the supplier starts asking questions we don’t have the answers to. They’re popping along there once a week to buy as much as they’re allowed, but often, even that cleans him right out.”

“In that box?” Slytherin asked, pointing to a box on a nearby table.

“Yes.”

Slytherin stalked over to the box and glanced inside, then walked back. “That’s the result of two months of buying up all the phoenix ash in Britain?”

“Yes, my lord.”

Silence descended on them. On the other side of the workshop, Dan and Emma were busily packing up various papers and putting them into bags.

Finally, Slytherin spoke. “It’s not enough.”

“My lord?”

“It’s not going to be enough for what I need—not nearly enough.”

“Do you want us to keep buying it?”

“For the moment, yes.”

“As you wish.”

Silence descended again.

Then, “Clare?”

“Yes, my lord?”

“About the fact that we’re making use of Nimbus’ runic patterns in our submarine …” He trailed off.

Clare sighed. She’d been expecting this. Knowing the secret of the miniature runes was one thing, but knowing something like that? “Yes, my lord,” she said, slipping off the basic magic ring she wore. “I understand, my lord.”

“Thank you, Clare.” Slytherin pointed his wand in-between her eyes.

“Obliviate.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

MaCUSA Special Auror Jackson Collins fidgeted. He hated travel, even more than he hated working on weekends, but the boss lady hadn’t been too impressed by his ‘opinions’ of her judgement in regards to the Lovegoods.

“Congratulations, Collins,” she’d said. “You’re now our field expert on all things Slytherin, since you think you know so much.”

And as so here he was, deep under rainy old London, surrounded by goblins. Merlin, that was another thing he hated—goblins. Jackson glanced towards the door where two of the ugly bastards stood at attention, holding battle axes with heads larger than his torso, and watching their half-dozen strong delegation with beady little eyes. He shuddered.

“You don’t need to worry. They can’t attack us,” said a thin wizard sat next to him, speaking loudly enough to be heard over the general hum of conversation around them—certainly loudly enough for the goblins to hear him. He wore thin glasses and had a rather nasally voice. “It would break the treaty they have with the ICW.”

“Nah.” Jackson shook himself. “S’not that. Just had a bad run-in with one back in New York. Anyway, that’s my job to worry about. You focus on your numbers.”

The wizard frowned, but did nod slightly, leaning back over his papers, just before the doors opened and a procession of five wizards entered. Jackson’s hand twitched towards where he kept his wand under his sleeve. They all wore masks—fucking creepy. Well, all except the teenage girl. Somehow, that made the whole thing even more creepy.

The head of their delegation, Carol Heyworth, an attractive, no-nonsense brunette witch from procurement, stood up and greeted the one who identified himself as Lord Slytherin—the one who’s mere presence seemed to radiate danger. His voice made the hairs on the back of Jackson’s neck prickle.

Part of him wondered just how badly they really needed to solve the whole kelpie situation, before he reminded himself that if there was one thing he hated, even more so than working on weekends, travelling, or goblins, it was hopeless, week-long gillyweed operations in the freezing waters of the Great Lakes.

Then Slytherin started outlining his proposal for what turned out to be a classic European broomstick, but massively scaled up, quoting maximum dive times, manoeuvrability, magical capacity, and defensibility.

He talked crew numbers, production capacity, and serviceability.

About halfway through, Jackson decided, grudgingly, that the man at least knew how to talk a good game.

He then spoke of the way the nose cone would be able to open underwater without flooding the vessel, allowing aurors to summon kelpies straight from the water, and into the broomstick, without having to engage them in their home territory where they held the upper hand.

And at that point, Jackson was sold. If Slytherin could make it, then the Auror department needed one of these things. Ms. Heyworth seemed interested too. Apparently, the numbers guy next to him didn’t seem to share his opinion. He kept tapping on the desk with his pen, clearly impatient.

Some time later, a round of questions started and sure enough, numbers guy was first to jump in.

“This is very interesting, Mister Slytherin,” he said in that same nasally voice, “But I have a masters in European runes and I just don’t see how you could possibly fit everything you’d need in a closed artefact that large.”

“That is a Slytherin family secret,” Slytherin said, evenly.

“You just expect us to accept that, do you?”

“Yes.”

“But we are not subject to the Albion.”

Ms. Heyworth gave numbers guy an annoyed look.

“Alright then,” Slytherin said. “It is a trade secret, will you accept that?”

“Yes, he will accept that,” Ms. Heyworth said.

Numbers guy gave their leader an annoyed look of his own.

Two points to Wampus House, Jackson thought.

Of course, that didn’t stop Numbers Guy. He continued to occasionally pepper Slytherin with questions during the Q&A, some on point, some rather time wasting. Jackson was surprised the blonde teenage girl sat in the middle of Slytherin’s group had as much control as she did. Apparently, it was her birthday, but she was here to ‘observe and learn the family business’. If someone had asked him to sit in on a meeting like this when he’d been thirteen, he’d have been out of his mind with boredom. Hell, thanks to numbers guy, he was almost out of his mind with boredom now.

“I don’t see how you can possibly source so much broomstick grade wood,” numbers guy finally said towards the end of the presentation. “I have read a professionally compiled report on European broomstick export numbers, and it said that Britain’s broomstick makers couldn’t expand their overseas markets wider, in part because, and I quote, ‘finding appropriate magical trees is such a hit and miss operation.’ ”

“I can assure you,” Slytherin said in the same calm tone he always used, “that will not be an issue.”

“But, Mister Slytherin, I can assure you, the report did say—”

Jackson snapped. “Oh, will you pack it in, already!”

Numbers Guy reared back, eyes wide.

“Unless your report came from a prophecy, can we assume there are things it might not know about?”

Numbers Guy sat back down, looking offended, but didn’t speak up again.

When they were finally walking out of the meeting room, back into the Gringotts main hall, Jackson bent towards their leader’s ear. “Ms. Heyworth, I’m pretty sure the rest of the jerks I work with would really appreciate something like this man is selling.”

Ms. Heyworth smiled at him. “We’ll have to see what we can do. We still have several other options to investigate. Thank you for speaking up like you did back there, by the way. Grant just can’t bear the thought of anyone being smarter than him.”

“Sounds like he needs a wake-up call.”

“Yes. And please, call me Carol. It’s nice having someone on this team who’s more than just a massive head attached to a mouth.” Then she smiled at him again.

It was a very nice smile, Jackson thought. Perhaps travel could have its upsides too.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Merlin, that guy just didn’t know when to stop talking! Even the auror thought so.” Daphne was walking beside her Lord Slytherin on their way to quickly meet with Ragnok about dragons, wind, land, silt, and treasures associated therewith, before getting on the real birthday business.

“He was useful,” Harry said. “He focused their group’s distrust and combative tendencies away from us and towards one of their own.”

Daphne smiled. That was one of the things she’d noticed about Harry’s Lord Slytherin persona. He spoke little, and when he did, it tended to be in short statements of fact—quite different from when he didn’t wear the mask.

“Do you think they’ll sign a contract with us?” she asked.

“They might.”

Daphne smiled again.

They soon reached Ragnok’s office. The Grangers and Clare had already left to meet up with Daphne’s mother and father.

Ragnok welcomed them in by standing up from behind his desk and waving them into the seats before it. “Lord Slytherin, what can I do for you today?” he asked. “I hope you are not in any difficulties? We haven’t been receiving deposits from you with quite the regularity we’ve come to expect.”

“I have a puzzle that Gringotts’ might have the key to,” Harry replied, ignoring the latter comment.

“Tell me more.”

“Fate has spoken to me again.” Harry glanced at her. “—or rather, to us.”

Ragnok raised an incredibly bushy eyebrow. “Truly?”

“Yes. Daphne?”

Daphne quickly took over. “We believe the new prophecy is a hint or clue to some kind of hidden treasure. We’ve already looked in several places rather obvious places with no luck, but there is another obvious place—here in Gringotts.”

Ragnok pursed his lips. “Our vaults hold many treasures, young Heiress. Only the ones in your vaults are yours to do with as you please.”

“Of course, of course,” Daphne quickly replied. “But the expertise of Gringotts … You do undertake a rather large number of expeditions all over the world.”

Ragnok steepled his fingers and looked across the table at them both. He thought for a moment. Then he said, “You have this prophecy?”

“We do,” Daphne said.

Harry withdrew a mist filled sphere from the pocket of his robes, placed it on the table, and tapped it with his wand.

Luna’s unearthly voice, high and unnatural, filled the room. “Where the land meets the wind, find the sign of the dragon’s roar. There awaits you in the silt, ancient magics and gold and more.”

Ragnok cursed in goblin. He rubbed a gnarled hand over his face. Then he stood up and paced the room for several minutes. Finally, he turned to them both. “Please wait here,” he said. “I will return shortly.” And with that, he left, shutting the door behind him with a soft click.

Daphne and Harry looked at each other.

“I’m not sure,” Harry said.

Daphne shrugged.

Minutes went by. Daphne sighed and asked Harry for one of her birthday books, which he handed to her—On War, by Carl von Clausewitz. She started to read.

In war, it stated, force is the ultimate factor that decides victory. Civilised governments do not engage in war as an act of rational policy, but rather as an act of brutal violence. The ultimate goal is to disarm the enemy.

That would mean taking away their opponents wands, Daphne thought—if they used wands. Taking a wand didn’t work so well on someone who knew wandless magic. How could they restrain someone who could cast basic spells without a wand? Tie their hands with rope? But they might be able to cast a severing charm. Goblin steel then? That would be fine if they could get ahold of it—the stuff wasn’t exactly common.

Daphne’s thoughts were interrupted by the door clicking open again.

Ragnok poked his head back in and motioned to them. “Please, follow me.”

Finally. Daphne snapped the book shut and handed it back to Harry who pocketed it.

Ragnok led them out of his office and towards the main hall, but then, rather than turning in that direction, he led them, instead, in the other—downwards, down into the depths of Gringotts, not where the carts took wizarding vault owners, but back where the goblins had their hidden city—marble pillared and stone vaulted.

A kind of curious excitement started to fill Daphne. This was more like what she’d been hoping for. Seeing new and wonderful things—things most wizards never saw. She doubted Tracey or Blaise had ever been back here.

Down, down they went. Spiralled staircases quickly turned from normal sized to goblin sized. Ceilings started to lower. Smooth marble gave way to rough granite.

Eventually, they were led through a set of massive double doors, three times as tall as Harry stood as Lord Slytherin. Daphne gasped.

A huge room greeted them. It looked like they’d just walked down its entire height to get to the bottom of it, but its size wasn’t its most impressive feature. Every surface—the walls, the floors, the ceilings, the pillars, everything—was covered in intricately carved figures of what looked like solid gold. The whole room shone blindingly bright. Goblins filled the space, talking, sitting at desks, writing, pouring over parchments, pointing at things stuck high up on walls. No one paid their entrance any attention.

Ten-metre tall solid gold goblin statues stood interspersed throughout the hall, holding high weapons, or quills, or sometimes both. One gold goblin statue next to them wore a pinstripe suit and glasses, and held an abacus.

“Wow,” Daphne whispered.

Harry merely nodded.

“Have you seen our great hall before, Lord Slytherin?” Ragnok asked.

“I’m sorry to say, that I have—although not nearly as glorious as this.”

Ragnok growled and swore in goblin again.

“There’s just so much gold,” Daphne said, awed. “Each statue has got to be millions of galleons.”

Ragnok shrugged. “Hundreds of millions, actually. All totally worthless.” They walked deeper into the hall and eventually came to a stop behind a low partition wall. Ragnok knocked on the door. “This,” he announced, “is our expedition division.”

Daphne followed Harry into a much smaller area. They could still see the massive golden vaulted ceiling of the great hall, but the wall decorations were far more office like—charts and maps and random bits of paper all over the place.

All eyes turned to them as they entered before getting back to their work. One set of eyes, however, didn’t leave them. They belonged to a tall wizard with a long, red pony-tail, and what looked like a dragon’s tooth for an earring. His eyes were narrowed.

“Lord Slytherin—Heiress Greengrass.” A female goblin in a long flowing dress swept over to them. “May your enemies bleed and you get rich, etc, etc. I’ll take it from here, shall I?” She said this last bit to Ragnok who grinned.

“This delightful ball of energy is Secured-Collateral. I have taken the liberty of giving her your new prophecy details, but that is all. She will take good care of you.”

Then he left.

Secured-Collateral turned back to them. “The king has given me leave to show you our current ventures. Follow me, please.”

“Um …” Daphne threw another look at the wizard on the far side of the room, who’d been continuing to give them cold looks. “What about him?”

“Curse Breaker William Weasley is under contract and will not share anything if he values his job.”

“And if he decides his job is worth less than any information he might be given?” Lord Slytherin asked.

“Then we seize house assets.”

“And if his house has profitable dealings with my house?”

Secured-Collateral smirked. “You don’t want an oath breaker’s gold? Then it would be for you to sort out among yourselves.”

“Then I request you tell him nothing more than what you have already told him.”

“Done. Now, look here.” She pointed to a large map on the wall, on which were drawn dozens of circles, all coloured in with different shades of red. “This map shows our current operations.”

Daphne leaned closer. The biggest circle was over Egypt, but there were also large circles on Mexico, Japan, Shaanxi, Istanbul, The African Rift Valley, Greece, Italy, Peru, and Ghana.

“We can provide documentation for any of our areas of interest,” Secured-Collateral said. “but there will be a price.”

“What price?” Harry asked.

“Where the land meets the wind, find the sign of the dragon’s roar. There awaits you in the silt, ancient magics and gold and more.” Secured-Collateral pointed to a nearby table, on which was something hidden under a cloth. “You can keep the gold and the magic—it is the more we are after—a very specific kind of more.” She pulled back the cloth.

Daphne’s eyes widened.

In a glass box hovered what looked like the ghost of a huge gemstone as big a man’s fist—purple, misty, see-through.

“What is it?” Daphne asked.

“I can’t tell you,” Secured-Collateral said.

Harry walked up to it, crouched down, and started busily inspecting it from only a few inches away. “Is it valuable?” he asked.

Daphne’s mind sputtered in disbelief. Even Harry didn’t know what it was?

“I can’t tell you that either—sorry.”

“But, if we find one, you want it?”

“Yes.”

“And not anything else? Not the gold? Not the magic?”

“No.”

“And all of these expeditions, are to find these things? You must have built up quite a collection.”

“That’s also classified information.”

Harry looked into the ethereal jewel for a few moments. “Fine,” he eventually said, straightening up and stalking over to the map on the wall. “Sorry to spoil the surprise, Daphne.” He jabbed at a much smaller circle way up to the North, and turned back to Secured-Collateral. “For starters, we’ll take everything you might have on this one.”

Daphne strained to see. Harry’s hand was planted directly on Iceland. That’s where they were going adventuring tomorrow. She smiled widely. A place where the dragons roar. Of course they were.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Draco Malfoy sat alone in the Hogwarts library with his head in his hands. He’d begged off from his friends after lunch and retreated somewhere he hoped no one would find him. Things were not going well. He was losing control, he could feel it. Alexandra Black was slowly worming her way into the position that should rightfully be his. This morning, he’d held on to his status as top snake by the skin of his teeth, but how long would that last? Even being near her gave him feelings of dread.

He wondered if this was how his grandfather felt when the dark lord had swept in out of nowhere and took control of Slytherin House.

If only Virgo hadn’t gone to Gryffindor. She was supposed to be his trump card, but whenever he’d seen his sister these days, she was always around Merlin damned John Potter or the Bones Heiress. Even then, he wasn’t sure if Virgo would have been able to contain Black. The girl was just too powerful. It wasn’t fair!

Draco’s thoughts ran over the destruction of the Slytherin common room again for the thousandth time in the last few weeks. He shuddered.

How was he supposed to be able to compete with that?

He sat in silence.

An older couple stumbled upon him among the shelves, laughing and giggling, made quick apologies, and left.

Eventually, Draco let out a long, defeated breath.

He couldn’t compete with it—not directly. It wasn’t possible. He would just have to work with her—be the advisor behind her throne. At least Black would be a great counter to Harry and John Potter—a chance his generation of the Dark would desperately need. Better to gracefully bow out while he still had the chance, and help focus her efforts on reminding everyone why the Dark was not to be messed with.

“Mister Malfoy?” said an adult female voice.

Draco looked up. It was Professor Potter.

“Yes, Professor?”

“You haven’t seen Harry anywhere, have you? I need to speak with him.”

Draco sighed again. How the hell had this mudblood bitch shoved out two monsters like Harry and John? “No, Professor,” he said. “I haven’t seen him.”

“Oh. Well, if you do see him can you let him know I want a word in my office?”

“Yes, Professor.”

Professor Potter left, leaving Draco alone with his thoughts of what to do next.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Was agreeing to let them have the ghost gem thing a good idea?” Daphne asked Harry as they walked down Diagon Alley. “We don’t even know what they are.”

“If we don’t know what they are, then currently neither does he, which means we’re not at a disadvantage,” Harry said. “It is important when dealing with a prophecy to be as proactive as possible to ensure things turn out the way you wish them. If we just leave it, we might not stumble onto this treasure for years—maybe decades. We don’t want to wait that long.”

“I suppose not.” Daphne smiled. “So, what now, my lord?”

“Second birthday present.” They stopped outside Broomstix.

Daphne’s eyes lit up. “A new broom? Really?”

“Really. You can’t claim to be a spoiled princess if you don’t have the latest of everything.”

Daphne’s eyes widened. “Did you just tease me?”

“Yes.”

Daphne spluttered, but before she could say anything back, Harry had already swept into the shop. Just as well, as it would stop him from seeing her faint blush.

“So, why am I really getting a new broomstick?” Daphne asked once inside.

“You’ve chosen your thirteenth ritual?”

Now Daphne really did blush, and in full view of Harry. “Yes.”

“We’re getting a pair of cruisers to get us to the ritual site.” He lowered his voice. “That way we won’t have to bother with disillusionment.”

Now Daphne understood. Harry was taking her flying. She smiled.

“We’re also going to a quidditch match later on. Magpies vs Bats.”

Daphne’s smile widened. “Go Bats.”

Just then, the shop owner bustled up to them and started what sounded like a very well rehearsed sales patter.

Fifteen minutes later, both she and her Lord Slytherin were holding identical Nimbus Cloud Cruisers—with built-in notice-me-nots and advanced cushioning charms, things that quidditch broom sacrificed for greater speed and agility.

They then walked to the small broomstick runway at the end of the Alley, mounted up, and swooped up into the skies above London—and suddenly, Daphne felt at home—more at home than she’d felt in ages. Euphoria swept her as quickly as the wind swept her long blonde hair. She wanted to stretch her talons and cry out in happiness.

A sudden wave of dizziness caused Daphne’s broom to wobble, but she got it back under control and sailed off over the rooftops after her lord. She just had to remember that her arms were not wings.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Well, obviously killing is wrong,” Hermione said, “but if it’s needed, then it can’t be helped.”

Ginny was standing by the pensieve in the middle of the trunk Hermione used to teach the muggleborns, gazing into its swirling depths with a look of determination on her face.

Hermione was fishing in the memory cabinet while talking. “And Harry will be able to tell us when it’s needed,” she continued. “We’ve already done bad things—I mean, Harry’s new home was built with drug money—and conquering a country isn’t exactly pure, even if it is most definitely needed. That’s not even getting into all the stuff we did last year with the philosopher’s stone.”

Hermione found the vial she was looking for and walked over to stand beside Ginny. The younger girl stood almost half a head shorter than her. Hermione’s voice softened. “Having said that, this will not be pleasant, Ginny. Harry once showed me some memories from the war—when Daphne and I did something very stupid. It was horrible. The second worst I’ve ever felt.”

Ginny didn’t ask her what the first worse she’d ever felt was. Instead, she set her jaw and nodded. “I need to do this,” she said. “I need to get used to it.”

Hermione nodded back and poured the contents of the vial into the pensieve. “I’ll have a bucket ready.”

Ginny touched the silver liquid and was instantly sucked into its depths.

Hermione then settled herself down to wait, skimming through an advanced book on transfiguration and compartmentalising all the things she didn’t already know into her occlumency library. Years ago, when they’d first met, Harry had said she had the potential to be one of the greatest witches who ever lived, and she fully intended to live up to that faith. She would not let Harry down … not again.

Quite some time later, the pensive starting glowing, and Ginny burst out from it, like Athena emerging fully grown from the forehead of Zeus, and proceeded to throw up messily into the bucket Hermione had left for her.

Hermione waited until Ginny was done before lifting a second full vial with a questioning look.

“Yes,” Ginny said, flatly. “All the memories.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was a nice walk, Daphne decided, and the broomstick flight to the grasslands of Wiltshire had been wonderful. She and Harry had even glided over the wards of Malfoy Manor, hidden as it was only from muggle eyes.

They’d landed not too far away from their target destination and found a relaxing hiking trail that would lead them all the way to the ritual site.

It was a one and a half hour trek, and by the time they were nearing, late afternoon was definitely with them, but Daphne didn’t care. She was now thoroughly enjoying herself, and that wasn’t even taking into account the knowledge of where they’d be port-keying to later that evening.

Harry stopped her as they neared the ritual circle. “Mandrake leaf,” he said.

Daphne dutifully withdrew the leaf from her mouth and handed it over.

Minutes later she understood why he had asked before reaching the massive stone circle. A ministry official bustled up to them wearing long white robes with a black corded belt—it was an incredibly old fashioned look.

“Lord Slytherin. Heiress Greengrass,” the man said, looking nervous. “I’m Phillip Dai, from the Department of Family Affairs. I’m so glad you’re here. We don’t like to keep the muggles out for too long. Druids! I don’t know. Whichever idiot came up with the druid excuse needs to be fired, assuming he hasn’t already popped his clogs. Anyway, sorry about all this. Welcome to Stonehenge. Have you already chosen your ritual, Miss Heiress?”

He said all this as quickly as possible, as though trying to get everything he needed to say out before someone inevitably interrupted him.

Daphne blushed. “I have chosen.” She glanced at her lord’s mask, and, not for the first time, dearly wished she could see his expression. “I have chosen The Ritual of the Lady.”

Harry tilted his head in acknowledgement.

Daphne smiled shyly.

“Right, yes, okay then.” Mister Dai pointed to a crate sitting by one of the massive stone blocks. “You’ll find all the ritual reagents you need in those boxes. We’ll leave you alone to get on with it, okay?” He looked towards her lord, who nodded.

The two wizards left, leaving Daphne alone in the middle of stone henge. She quickly fished out what she’d need from the boxes, including a large amount of mistletoe and the frozen male genitalia of a horse. Then stripped down naked, placed a book detailing the ritual in the middle of the stone circle, positioned the ritual items in the prescribed pattern around her, shivered in the cold Autumn air, and, slowly, softly, began to chant.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Bodmin Moor Stadium sat on the Cornish moors like a hippo on a bed of moss—the only quidditch stadium in the country. Oh, all the officially recognised teams might have their own fields, where they practised and trained, and where the local wizards and witches could have a bit of a throw about, but in a country with a population of only just over twenty-thousand, there really wasn’t any need for more than one stadium.

It was large, over 150 metres long and over 55 metres wide, with eight rows of seats going all the way around the circumference, capable of seating nearly four thousand people, a whole one-fifth of the entire population. It hosted 78 games in the official quidditch season, between the months of May and August, and many friendly matches, or, in some cases, not so friendly matches during the off months.

Eight great towers rose over the stadium like candles on a birthday cake. These were the premium seats, where those who could afford it showed everyone else that they could afford it. Four of the towers held seats, just like the ones closer down to the ground—sixty-four seats in each tower. But the other four … they were the premium boxes—private spaces with only ten seats in each, complete with a dining area, a drinks cabinet, catered food, and a card table—purchased, or occasionally hired out, by the very rich or influential.

Wizards and witches were starting to flood into the stadium in preparation for the late-afternoon/early-evening game.

In one of the premium boxes, a stout, portly man wearing a bowler hat surveyed the thronging crowds. “Magnificent, isn’t it?” he said, fiddling with the trim of his robes. “Them all down there—and us—up here.” He preened before turning to the two people standing behind him, silently watching.

“I said, isn’t it magnificent?”

The woman dressed in pink robes started, apparently not realising he’d been expecting an answer. “Oh, yes, Minister, it’s wonderful,” she simpered. “Truly, you stand among the greats of wizard-kind.”

The minister beamed before turning to the wizard. “And what about you, Bentley? Don’t you think it’s magnificent?”

The man next to the woman bowed almost imperceptibly. “I must admit, Minister, that I have come to appreciate the little perks my position grants me.”

“Yes …” Minister Fudge looked the man up and down, uncertainly. Bentley was an older wizard with short white hair and the poise of a man who feels unquestionably secure in his position. He wore grey robes. Not the shabby grey of the unspeakables, or the embroidered grey that some young wizards now wore in imitation of Lord Slytherin, but the plain, charcoal grey of a man who considers himself a gentleman, despite not being born noble.

“Well, that makes two of us, doesn’t it?” Fudge laughed heartily, while Bentley merely gave a small smile.

Fudge turned back to the window. “Can’t wait to see the Magpies crush the Bats,” he muttered. “They need to be taken down a peg or two.” He brought his omnioculars up to his eyes and scanned the stadium. “Oh! Look!” He pointed excitedly to the another premium box on the far side of the stadium. “Lucius and Edgar are here! I must go and say hello. Donation season coming up, and all.” He quickly left, leaving the witch and wizard alone in the Minster’s box.

“Tea, Mister Bentley?” Dolores Umbridge asked.

“Yes, please.”

“Sugar?”

“One spoon.”

“Milk?”

“Just a splash.”

After several moments of clinking and stirring, Dolores placed a cup of tea down in front of Bentley, who’d sat down at the edge of the box to watch the players start their pre-game warm up while the announcer shouted out quidditch news and updates to the crowd.

“Excellent. Please take a seat.”

Umbridge quickly sat down next to him with a cup of her own.

“Tell me, Dolores,” Bentley said, taking a sip of the tea. “What do you think of Lord Slytherin?”

Umbridge hesitated. “He’s attractive?”

“I was not referring to the general tendency of witches to view a well-cut figure in a mask to be some kind of ultimate romantic fantasy.” Bentley’s voice had turned sharp.

Umbridge flushed. “No, Mister Bentley. I’m sorry. I don’t know what to think of him. I don’t really know anything about him, apart from that he’s a pureblood.” She paused. “Well, he’d better be a pureblood.” The last words were more spat than said.

Bentley smiled. “Tell me, is it true that Arthur Weasley is going to try and push his muggle protection act through the Wizengamot again?”

“It’s possible.”

“With Lord Slytherin’s help?”

“There have been whispers.”

Bentley put his cup down with a little clink of porcelain. “Dolores, we can not allow that to happen.”

Umbridge looked shocked. “But why? It would increase the power of the ministry. Isn’t that what you want?”

“Yes, but not if there is a greater prize at stake. Tell me, why isn’t the ministry already the dominant force in Magical Britain?”

“Because of the Wizengamot.”

“Exactly! A Wizengamot that for the last four years has been a limp fish. Oh, it’s been wonderful. We’ve had almost a free hand. Lord Slytherin is like a gift sent from Merlin.” He paused. “But only so long as he keeps holding the Wizengamot back! If he starts making laws of his own he’s going to be pushing into my territory, and that is unacceptable.”

Umbridge worried her lip. “But what do you want me to do? I’m the Minister’s undersecretary now. It’s my job to carry out his wishes within the ministry.”

“Yes, that’s true. But I am not totally without power over you, Dolores, as you well know.”

Umbridge flinched.

“So, you know your duty.”

Umbridge sighed. “Yes, Mister Bentley.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Lord Lucius Malfoy stood by the glass wall of the box that the Dark had collectively chipped in to buy some thirty years ago, casting a critical eye over the thronging crowd. There were just so many of them—so many people—so many wands.

“Oh, look,” said Lord Edgar Nott, standing beside him, holding his omnioculars up to his eyes. “Greengrass and Moke are here.”

Lucius strained his eyes towards the top box on the other side of the stadium, just able to make out figures of Lord and Lady Greengrass among the other nobles. He chuckled. “Still bitter?”

Edgar ignored him, choosing instead to continue fiddling with his omnioculars. Behind them, Narcissa and Lady Nott were chatting with a few minor lords of the Dark. “Hey,” Nott said, “Who are they with Greengrass?”

“Who?”

“Look for yourself.”

Lucius took the omnioculars and peered across the stadium. He scowled. “They,” he said, “are Slytherin’s pet muggles, and his pet whore.”

“The girl I could understand,” Nott muttered, “but the muggles?”

“Their daughter is not without her talents, I’m told.”

Nott snorted. “Such a waste.”

There was the sound of a door clicking open. They both turned away from the glass-wall, just in time to see the new figure look around the room, beaming with self-importance. Lucius put on his best sincere smile. “Minister.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

As the announcer finished recapping the results of last week’s match between Puddlemere and the Canons (the Canons lost massively) Jacob Greengrass scanned the skies around the pitch anxiously. Harry and Daphne were late. If they didn’t get a move on, the announcer was going to start without them.

On his right, Sunny was deep in conversation with Mrs. Granger and Clare. A nice girl, Clare—very respectful. Shame about what happened to her. She was looking a lot more cheerful now, at least.

On Jacob’s left, Daniel Granger was baring the brunt of Arthur Weasley’s muggle obsession with great aplomb while Weasley’s wife looked mildly embarrassed.

“Oh, oh! Could you explain to me the function of a rubber duck?”

“About the same as a dancing cake topper. Could you explain to me how promotion is decided within the Ministry of Magic?”

Which was odd, Jacob thought. He’d never seen Weasley up here in one of the top boxes before. They must have come into some extra gold.

Way below them, the long, thin line of wizards and witches that stretched all the way around the stadium started doing a Mexican wave.

“Excuse me, one moment, coming through.”

Oh, Merlin. Jacob pursed his lips. A small wiry wizard hoped over Dan’s legs and crouched down beside him. “Lord Greengrass,” he panted sounding out of breath. “I don’t suppose you’ve thought any more about—”

“No, Mister Hale,” Jacob cut him off. “The Gray will not be buying the last private box for the moment. I will let you know if and when we are.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Back in the Dark’s private box, Fudge preened. “I’m so glad I’m able to rely on your advice and support, Lucius, Edgar.”

“Of course, Minster,” Edgar said gruffly.

“If Madam Umbridge gives you any problems, just send her to us,” Lucius said, in that smooth tone he always used. “We’ll make sure she understands what her new position requires of her.”

There was a sudden roar from the crowd, by far the loudest so far. Fudge turned to see what had caused the ruckus and spluttered. “Lucius! Your omnioculars!” he cried, just as the announcer boomed.

“Wizards and Witches! Heiress Daphne Greengrass and Lord Slytherin!”

Fudge looked through the omnioculars and zoomed into where the wizard he’d been desperate to talk to was riding a broomstick above the quidditch pitch—the Greengrass heiress riding side saddle behind him, clearly enjoying herself.

“Three cheers for the birthday girl!” The announcer shouted.

Fudge was already out of the box and halfway down the stairs by the time the crowd got through its second cheer, feeling slightly miffed. He’d never got three cheers at the quidditch stadium. Not even when he’d just been elected minister—just a round of applause.

By the time he’d made his way onto the pitch, Lord Slytherin was shaking the last of the Magpie’s hands, while the team captain of the Bats bowed slightly for the girl.

“Lord Slytherin!” Fudge called heartily. “This is an unexpected pleasure! Welcome to Bodmin Stadium!” He beamed. “And you too Miss Greengrass.”

“Minister Fudge,” Slytherin nodded towards him.

“Please! Call me Cornelius.” He walked to stand with him. “Do you have seats? Oh, what am I saying, of course you do, but please—please allow me to treat you! A birthday gift for your future lady!”

He nodded towards the young Heiress who was now watching with a rather blank expression.

“Yes,” he continued. “The Minister’s box is the perfect way to watch a game!”

Despite some reluctance on their part, he eventually managed to lead the two nobles up to the Minister’s box.

“This is Mister Bentley, the Humble Hag of the Wardrobe,” he said, gesturing to the politely bowing wizard “—and this is Dolores Umbridge, my undersecretary.”

“Charmed.”

A few minutes later, Fudge was rubbing his hands together in glee, looking out across the pitch while the referee unclamped the bludgers. This was so perfect. He’d been wanting to get Slytherin alone for years. And now he was his captive audience for the next two or three hours at least.

“Um, Minister?” said a very uncertain voice behind him.

He turned around. Mister Bentley and Dolores were looking around the spacious room in confusion, Bentley half-way through pouring a drink.

Lord Slytherin and Heiress Greengrass had vanished.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On the roof of the Minster’s box, Daphne sat huddled up against Harry—and it was Harry now, rather than Lord Slytherin. They were both wrapped up in a blanket, which itself was wrapped in the invisibility cloak. Only their heads poked out the top of it, and they were disillusioned.

“Thank you, Harry,” Daphne said, softly. “I don’t think I could stand having to spend three hours listening to that twit prattle on.”

Harry chuckled. “One of the risks of going just a little over the top—you attract attention.”

Daphne smiled. “That was rather over the top. I was afraid for a moment you were going to have them play the wizarding anthem, too.”

“You enjoyed it.”

“Yes, I did.”

“AND THEY’RE OFF!” shouted the announcer. “WILLIAMS GRABS THE QUAFFLE, PASSES IT TO WALKER!”

The crowd roared its approval as the game started and the players sped off after their targets.

Daphne huddled closer.

“So,” Harry said, in a casual tone of voice. “The ritual of the lady?”

Daphne blushed. “Shut up.” She cast her gaze out across the pitch.

There were many rituals wizards and witches could perform on their thirteenth birthdays—almost all of them associated with either gender or sexuality. The ritual of the lady was one of the more traditional ones, granting the witch who performed it increased fertility and ease of childbirth. In exchange, her first six children would always be boys.

The ritual had fallen out of favour for the simple reason that, generally, only daughters and their immediate children could ever hold two sets of family magics at once. They were important in the creation of many unique magical artefacts.

But Daphne didn’t care so much about that. She’d chosen the ritual of the lady for other reasons. It was a promise. It spoke of another time, far off in the future, when the war Harry needed to fight would be over. When she and her lord would settle down and start a family of their own.

Out over the pitch, the Bat’s beaters had pinned the Magpies’s seeker, forcing him to drop the quaffle.

“WALKER CATCHES THE QUAFFLE, PASSES IT TO LAMBERT! LAMBERT SCORES!”

Daphne settled down to enjoy the game.

Over the next few hours the Bats outflew the Magpies handedly, eventually finishing the game when their seeker stopped bothering with the quaffle and focused exclusively on the snitch, quickly finding it and snatching it from behind one of the quaffle posts.

She and Harry quietly left soon after that, waving a quick good bye to Daphne’s parents, and flying, again, all the way back to London, arriving at King’s Cross with plenty of time to spare for their portkey to Iceland.

They arrived in Reykjavik feeling the sickening effects of portkey travel, and quickly checked themselves into the only magical hotel in the city. Daphne slowly fell asleep going over the day in her head, a small smile on her face, despite her stomach’s queasiness. It really had been one of her better birthdays.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A thousand kilometres to the South, in a magical and majestic Scottish castle, a shrill voice rang out through the Slytherin dungeons.

“WHERE—IS—HARRY!?”

—End of Chapter Forty-One—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: There are important changes coming to the Dodging Prison and Stealing Witches Audio Book project.

1. Book one is now complete!

2. Owing to having a rather large collection of awesome stuff going on, Soren will be stepping aside as narrator for the next book.

3. All future updates (including this one—chapter 12) will be posted to www.LeadVonE.com rather than to Soren’s Youtube channel (I’m working on other distribution means as well.)

4. All of Soren’s readings are also available on the website.

5. That’s it! Go have a listen, if you haven’t already.

Sticky Note: If you want to keep abreast of the release schedule, as well as any changes and the occasional piece of bonus content, you can head over to www.LeadVonE.com and sign up for the Gray Mailing List.

If you would like to discuss this chapter with other readers, I suggest you check out the fan-run discord server, the link for which can also be found both on my profile page and through my website.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Daphne’s Birthday, Work and Play—Part Two

“WHERE—IS—HARRY!?”

Slytherin students watched in bemusement as the irate muggleborn professor stormed up the stairs to the Slytherin common room from the boys’ dormitories.

“It’s well past curfew! Where—is—he? Mister Malfoy! Do you know?”

“No, Professor.”

“Nott?”

“I’m afraid not—ahaha.”

“Miss Parkinson?”

“Sorry, Professor.”

Down in the second year girl’s dormitory, Tracey Davis’ heart was making a spirited attempt to beat its way out of her chest.

“Just act like you normally would around Harry,” Hermione said, uncorking a tiny vial of polyjuice.

“But what about his clothes?” Tracey asked frantically.

“I’ve got a set of his robes here.” Hermione had stripped down to her underwear and was bringing the vial to her lips. “Look away!”

Tracey spun around just as Hermione’s skin began to bubble. “Oh, Merlin and Morgana—if Professor Potter finds Harry in our dormitory …”

“Yes, I know! Look outside, is there anyone there?”

Tracey poked her around the door into the corridor. “No, it’s clear. What are we going to tell her?”

“Get Ginny! She can disillusion!”

“Yes, but what are we going to tell her?”

“Tracey, I’ve got this! Just go!”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Lily Potter looked around the Slytherin common room for the dozenth time in the last five minutes. Where could Harry possibly be? She knew he was still in the castle. The headmaster had confirmed it.

When she finally got a hold of him, he was going to be in so much trouble.

Then, something on one of the sofas by the fireplace caught her eye. A slight ripple in the air—almost unnoticeable—a disillusionment charm.

Lily narrowed her eyes and pointed her wand at the space. “Finite incantatem!”

There was a much more pronounced shimmer as the disillusionment fell.

Lily stared.

Her son, Harry Potter, was buried deep under a blanket, fast asleep, and next to him slept Ginny Weasley. The two were snuggled into each other, Ginny’s head resting in the crook of Harry’s neck. Even as she watched, Ginny tried to nuzzle her way even deeper into him.

Lily’s heart melted. Despite the curt way Ginny usually acted around her, any mother would be hard pressed not to find the tableau in front of her utterly adorable.

She approached cautiously, feeling a good chunk of her anger and frustration draining out of her. She then poked around with her wand, stretching her extremely limited magic sensing abilities to the limit, eventually deciding that, yes, there was also a silencing charm around them, which would explain why they hadn’t heard her shouting only a moment ago.

Had Harry cast them? It wouldn’t surprise her. He was already at NEWT level, after all—such a little genius.

Lily dispelled the charm, crouched down beside them, and put a gentle hand on Harry’s shoulder, slowly shaking him. “Harry,” She said quietly.

Harry made a noise something like, “Mwushlumphmmm …”

“Harry,” she said, a little louder.

Harry’s eyes flickered open.

“You can’t sleep here, Harry.”

“Mum?” He looked mildly confused.

“If you and Ginny want to sleep you need to go to your dormitories.”

“Ginny?” Harry looked to his side, noticed Ginny, and became fully awake. “Mum, why are you here?”

“Harry, where have you been all day? I’ve been looking for you.”

“Training with Ginny.”

“Didn’t Ginny tell you I was looking for you?”

“Well, yeah, but I figured if it was important you’d find me.”

Lily let out an exasperated sigh.

Ginny was starting to wake up now. “Lady Lily?” she muttered.

“That’s professor while we’re in school, Miss Weasley.” She turned to Harry. “I’d like you to be at my apartment for dinner tomorrow tonight. Say six o’clock.”

Harry’s eyes widened. “I had plans tomorrow.”

Lily smiled. “I know you work hard, Harry, but I’m sure you can take out a few hours from training to have dinner with your family, yes?”

Harry considered this, then looked down sheepishly. “Yes, Mum.”

“And bring one of your friends—John’s bringing one of his—maybe Ginny here.”

“Yes, Mum.”

“And now, off to bed.”

Harry slowly got to his feet and shuffled his way to the stairs, holding an equally tired looking Ginny’s hand the whole way. They only stopped holding hands when Harry took the stairs heading into the boy’s dormitory and Ginny took the ones heading to the girls.

Lily nodded to herself, stood up, surveyed the Slytherin common, and left, leaving behind her a rather incredulous group of onlookers.

At the same time that lady lily was leaving, at the court of the Dark, Draco, Nott, Pansy, and Alexandra all traded looks.

“That,” said Pansy, “was the largest amount of dragonshit I’ve ever seen Harry Potter shovel anyone.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

The earth turned.

It was morning in Iceland, and the sun was just now deciding to show itself.

In one of the magical hotel rooms a few doors down from where Harry and Daphne were staying, a lithe middle aged witch, dressed only in rather racy underwear and slippers, was leaning over in front of a dressing-room table mirror, applying a thick layer of bright red lipstick. She had sharp features, blonde hair, rather long, painted fingernails, and the air of a woman who has done many things, and, in some cases, people, to get to where she is, and isn’t ashamed about it in the least.

She was not alone in the room. A man relaxed in the room’s lone double bed, equally unclothed and smoking a cigarette.

“Rita, Luv, why the rush? The tour won’t be setting out for an hour. They’re probably both still at breakfast.”

Rita Skeeter was now busily stepping into a set of fashionable magenta robes. A small vial of muddy, goopy potion stood on the dressing-room table. “Breakfast that I should be at,” she snapped. “Drat the editor, getting me the tip-off so late—drat portkey sickness. …” She glared at the man watching her straighten her robes with an appreciative eye. “… Drat you, Bozo.”

Bozo grinned. “I’m just interested to see what tasty little crumpet you snatched a hair from this time.”

Rita ignored this, produced a hair from a silver cigarette case, let it settle into the goop, and gulped down the vial of muddy potion. As she did, her hair changed from blonde to pepper grey, her nails shrank, and her face shifted, becoming older, more wrinkled. Her robes auto-adjusted themselves to fit someone a little shorter with a stoop.

Bozo rolled his eyes and let out a disappointed sigh. “You couldn’t have just gone with a notice-me-not, could you, Luv?”

“Don’t be stupid.” Rita’s voice now sounded old and creaky. “Slytherin’s over-inflated reputation may be little more than smoke and mirrors, but I’m not taking the chance that the man could spot one of my notice-me-nots from a mile away.”

Rita then snatched up her handbag, hobbled to the door, opened it, hobbled through, and shut it behind her.

Bozo puffed out another long stream of smoke. “Well, Luv, you’re the first fashionable granny I’ve ever seen who doesn’t use a beauty potion.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

The wizarding enclave in Reykjavik was not, in anyway, a large affair, which was understandable. Iceland did not have a large population. At just two hundred wizards strong, they were so small, they could barely afford to field a national quidditch team. Some years they couldn’t even manage that. They didn’t have a ministry, per se. Maintaining the statue of secrecy was everyone’s responsibility.

What they didhave was an ICW representative whose job it was to keep himself to himself when everything was going well and go cap in hand to the various other members when they weren’t—such as during an incident two-hundred years previously, when a beautiful breeding pair of Swedish Short Snouts had somehow found their way to Iceland from Scandinavia, quickly enchanting the locals, despite their power and ferocity.

It was all fun and games, until a muggle got eaten, and the Icelandic wizards realised they didn’t know nearly enough about dragons to keep them.

As was his duty, Iceland’s ICW representative travelled to Italy and politely asked the Kingdom of Sweden to come pick the dragons up. The Swedish representative refused, instead telling them to just slaughter the two beasts and have done with it. Not taking this for an acceptable answer, he then went to the Ukrainian representative and asked if they would like two free Swedish Short Snouts. The Ukrainian Minister of Magic sent word that they had no use for more dragons and to deal with it themselves. Finally, he’d petitioned the Emperor of the Magical Roman Empire, who’d told him to, “Get stuffed, and stop wasting my time you massive oaf.”

Ticked off no end, Iceland’s wizards did not butcher the dragons. They instead herded them into mountains, hired experts from Magical Britain to plug the gaps in their expertise, and set up a dragon reserve of their own. Twenty years later, Sweden was furious, Ukraine was jealous, and The Emperor of the Magical Roman Empire became the largest consumer in Europe of Iceland’s newest chief export—inexpensive Short Snout products.

Many of those products were proudly displayed in the windows of the dozen-ish shops that Harry (Lord Slytherin) and Daphne walked by on their way to the wizarding Iceland guided tour. Meat, blood, bone, horn (both ground and whole), individual scales, heartstrings, claws, even in one shop, a whole dragon’s head, mounted on the wall with a plaque beneath it saying, ‘Slain by [Your name here].’

The largest shop by far though, sold dragon hide armour—incredibly expensive stuff. A full set of shimmering blue duelling robes, including trousers, undershirt, boots, gloves, and the robe itself, would set the prospective duellist or auror department back a little over 160 galleons—nearly eight-thousand pounds—and an auror generally needed to replace their gear at least once a year.

They stopped by to admire a particularly fine set in the shop and ask some questions, before Daphne turned over the price tag, and whistled under her breath. “Wow—did my duelling robes cost that much?”

“Like I said,” said Lord Slytherin. “Spoiled pureblood princess.”

“Oh, shut up,” Daphne retorted, cheeks reddening. “But I suppose this explains why none of the other girls’ duelling robes are dragon hide.”

They continued walking at a relaxed pace until they reached the conclave’s main square, where someone had rolled out a half dozen carpets and tied them all together with rope. A small group of other wizards and witches were already there, dressed in what could only be described as ‘tourist’ dress. Several wore omnioculars around their necks and one woman was bundled up against the cold so tightly that she was practically round.

“All aboard!” shouted a huge man who looked like he might be distantly related to the Hogwarts gamekeeper. He waved Harry and Daphne onto the second carpet “Lord Slytherin—Miss Heiress.”

They didn’t have long to wait before the carpets all slowly rose off from the floor, causing Daphne to let out a little squeal and cling to Harry, and they were off, flying over the many houses of Iceland’s capital, and out over the desolate whiteness.

“I thought you loved flying,” Slytherin said, sitting cross-legged on the carpet the two had all to themselves.

“I love it when I’m the one doing the flying,” Daphne replied, still clutching her Lord’s arm tightly as the chill wind whipped through their hair. “Just sitting on a floating rug feels wrong.” She smiled. “Still better than sitting in the castle all day though.”

They passed over a small set of mountains.

“And if you look on your right,” came the voice of the tour-guide on the first carpet in the train, “you’ll see Katla, known for its violent eruptions, and known to the locals as the grand-father of dragons.”

Their fellow tourists all went Ooooo and a couple took magical photos with massive cameras that exhumed great puffs of green and purple smoke.

“My lord,” Daphne started, in a meaningful tone of voice.

Harry nodded and quickly cast a privacy charm.

“What do you think?” she said, once the charm had gone up. “Could that be the sign of the dragon’s roar from Luna’s prophecy?”

“It’s not impossible, although if it is then we’ve got quite a task ahead of us—that’s a big mountain.”

After that, Daphne and Harry continued to chat with each other under privacy charm, simply enjoying the scenery, the calm, and each other’s company. Three carpets behind them, an old woman watched the pair with sharp blue eyes.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Rita Skeeter wasn’t paying attention to the majestic scenery around her. Her gaze was instead fixed on the wizard and witch three carpets in front of her.

They’d put up some kind of muffling charm so that not even her sharp hearing could catch what they were saying to each other, but that didn’t matter. Quite apart from being an acceptable lay, Bozo had his other uses too. One of these was the ability to read lips as though reading a book. Slytherin, of course, wore a mask that covered his entire face, but the girl didn’t.

Despite being a backward dump hardly worthy of being an independent magical country, at least in Rita’s mind, Iceland did at least have a public pensieve. She mused that it was probably the only pensieve in the country, while her mind already started to write possible headlines and pen damning story threads.

“Lord Slytherin vacations alone with his betrothed. … Heiress Greengrass emerged from their shared hotel room that morning practically glowing. … The young Heiress spent the whole tour pressed up to her future lord’s side …”

Rita frowned. Was that too subtle? People were such colossal idiots. They generally had to be beaten over the head before they got what they were being told. What if she kept the story thread but changed the headline?

“PROPRIETARY CONCERNS OVER LORD SLYTHERIN’S SECRET VACATION WITH HEIRESS GREENGRASS.”

’I think it’s shocking,’ some random idiot she’d grab in Diagon Alley would say.

‘Just goes to show, you can’t trust someone who doesn’t show their face,’ or possibly, ‘They ought to do something about it!’

The problem was that no one knew anything about Lord Slytherin. If she started trying to tarnish his image without exposing who he really was, all she’d do was add another layer of respectful fear to the man’s already ridiculous image. When a powerful man gets away with something, it just confirms to everyone how powerful they are.

It was nearing mid-day by the time the tour finished, gently bringing them to stop back at the square they’d started at.

Rita hobbled after the girl and Lord Slytherin as quickly as she could back to the hotel, only turning from them when she reached her own room, just four doors down from theirs. She grabbed Bozo and together they rushed, or in Bozo’s case, sauntered, down to the public pensieve shop.

“S’no good, Luv,” Bozo said, shaking his head while they kneeled in front of the Greengrass Heiress of Rita’s memory. “That charm scrambles their lips too. All I can make out is that she really, really likes ice cream.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“That old witch moved fast, didn’t she?” Daphne called up through the entrance to Harry’s trunk after changing into something rather more suitable for adventuring in. She still got a secret thrill every time she wore boys clothes. It just felt so taboo. Tracey’s reaction reminded her of that every time she did it in her oldest friend’s presence.

“Probably a spy,” Harry said, helping her out of the trunk. “We’ll make sure to lose her before we head off anywhere important.”

It turned out that wasn’t necessary. The bent over woman wasn’t anywhere in sight as the two made their way out of the capital and towards where the goblins had set up their expedition base of operations—a ring of warded wizard tents a little way off the muggle road.

“I’m still amazed Father is letting us do this trip unchaperoned,” Daphne said as they neared the tents. “Now that I’m in-between.”

Harry coughed. “Actually, Daphne, we are chaperoned.”

“What?!”

“One of your house elves, Milly, has been following us since we left Hogwarts. Not always easily, I might add. I had to drop her a trail to follow when we were on the broomsticks.”

Daphne huffed. “I should have known.”

They didn’t have any more opportunity to talk before they were greeted at the outer-ring.

“Good to see you again, Lord Slytherin—Miss Heiress.” Secured-Collateral gave them a wicked goblin grin. “A lot colder than London, out here, and a lot more desolate, but you can’t be wanting for dragons. We’ve got them in spades.”

“You came here for us?” Daphne asked.

Secured-Collateral laughed. “Someone with a prophecy poking around the old treasure hunting grounds—where else is there to be? We’ve already done a sweep of some of the areas that match what your looking for, but there’s a lot of wind here—and where the land meets it is just about everywhere.”

“Your sweep was comprehensive?” Harry asked from under his Lord Slytherin mask. They followed the perky goblin into one of the expanded tents.

“Very.” Secured-Collateral pointed towards a map stuck to a cloth wall. “I myself don’t see what else you’ll be finding, but who knows how fate works, hmm? Maybe you’ve got some special talents we don’t know about.”

Daphne’s face did not go blank. Only amateur’s faces went blank when presented with such an obvious probe for information. “We’ll take a look around and see if there’s anything you might have missed,” she said. “I know it’s unlikely, but you never know.”

Secured-Collateral nodded. “You got it. Ask one of the goblins in the next room for the maps—and I hope you’ve got warming charms on your brooms. You’re going to need them.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Daphne didn’t need a warming charm. She soared through the air as if she was born to be there, which, for a small part of her, was true. So much better than a carpet.

Her future lord, by contrast, did need a warming charm. In fact, not only did he need a warming charm, he needed several extra layers of robes too. A Slytherin Green scarf was wrapped around his neck.

Daphne couldn’t help think the whole thing was rather cute—not a sentiment she could ever remember thinking about Lord Slytherin.

“Not all of us can be Golden Eagles, my lady,” Harry said, Daphne holding formation with him as they cruised towards the most likely target on the map they’d been given.

Daphne giggled. “I can’t wait to be in the animagus hunt. A thousand feet up in the air—no one will get even close to me.”

“I think that might be counted as bad sportsmanship.”

“Too bad. What about falconry? Isn’t it expected for a lady to be on her husband’s arm?”

Harry chuckled. “Witty.”

“Thank you.”

They continued to soar towards their target for a little while longer, Harry’s scarf whipping around in the high wind. They reached their destination and hovered over the warded wreckage of a Viking longship—a Viking longship with a roaring dragon’s head at the front.

Harry shivered, even through all his thick clothes and magic.

“Is your animagus form cold-blooded?” Daphne asked. “I would have thought they were warm-blooded.”

She could practically hear the smirk form under Harry’s mask.

“Neither. I am, in fact, half-blooded.”

She matched his smirk with one of her own. “Witty.”

“Thank you.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“What shall we do with this, Mistress?”

Convertible-Security looked up from her work. Two of her boys were holding what looked like a rather frightened old woman at pike point.

“Caught her poking around the camp perimeter,” one of the two elaborated.

“Please,” said the woman desperately, “I’m just a tourist. I didn’t know this was a goblin camp.”

Convertible-Security shrugged. “Put her in chains for an hour. If she’s clean of polyjuice, release her. Otherwise, bring her back to me and we’ll see what’s what.”

“Yes, Mistress.” The two goblins saluted.

The old woman whimpered as she was dragged away.

Convertible-Security went back to her work, which at the moment included a rather promising report by the team down in Ciro. There weren’t many things that the goblin clans worked together on, but this was most definitely one of them.

It was a full ten minutes before the word came through that the old witch, hindered by neither goblin wards nor goblin steel, had escaped.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Rita Skeeter shivered as she ducked back into her hotel room. This was absolutely not the kind of weather to use her animagus form in.

“Back already, Luv? Miss me that much?”

“Shut up, Bozo. I need another polyjuice. The little shits caught me.”

“On the dresser.”

Rita snatched up the vial of polyjuice, produced another hair from her silver cigarette case, let it fall into the potion, drank the potion, and changed.

Bozo whistled. “I like this one much better.”

Rita straightened her robes. They now hugged her body like a silk wrapped around an hourglass. “I’m sure,” she said, tartly. Her voice now sounded like honey dribbling into the listener’s ear. She made for the door. “And make yourself useful while I’m out. Ask around the place or something. I don’t pay you to just lie around the place.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Daphne had found an appropriate rock to sit on. She focused her magic into her fingers, pointed her index finger at the floor, and said, “Profero oculus Kilrogg.”

She felt her world shift. She opened her eyes, and then she opened her eye.

The longboat was beached far up a rocky slope. Someone had obviously dragged it all the way up here and left it, but not before surrounding it with ancient rune stones designed to conceal it from all but the most determined.

The goblins had been determined.

A set of much newer ward-stones now mirrored the old ones, encircling them in a power all their own.

Daphne manoeuvred her magic eyeball up and down the old hull, looking for the tell-tell sign that someone, a long time ago, had placed a fidelius charm. It was, after all, by far the most obvious way she and Harry might find an ancient treasure where no one else had.

“There’s a lot of ground to cover other than just the boat,” Harry’s voice said. “The beach has got to be a hundred meters away.”

Daphne nodded. “If it’s here, I’ll find it.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“I think we should all go.”

Those were the first words out of Hermione’s mouth when she, Tracey, Ginny, Alexandra, and Luna all met in Hermione’s trunk at lunchtime to discuss that evening’s dinner with Lady Potter.

“If we all go,” Hermione continued, before anyone else could get a word in, “there’s far less chance of Lady Potter or John Potter discovering that one of us is Harry.”

“I can’t be there,” Alex said. “Why would I be there?”

“Obviously I didn’t mean you.”

“You said we should all go.”

“Yes, but—”

“Hermione—Alex.” Luna’s dreamy voice cut across the two. She was fixing a large white flower in her hair. “Let’s not fight. We all just want to help Harry.”

Alex and Hermione looked abashed.

“Hermione has a good point,” Luna continued. “The more of us that go, the more we can distract Lady Potter from any unusual behaviour.” The white flower snapped a fly from the air and gulped. “We must all do our best to act as normal as possible. I imagine Alex has stuff to do with the Dark.”

“What?” It took Alex a few moments to catch up. “Oh, yes, I do, lots. At the same time, in fact.”

“I still have trouble believing she’s a spy,” Tracey muttered.

Luna nodded. “Then we just need to decide who is going to be Harry.”

“Ooo! Can it be me?” Ginny grinned. “I’ve always wanted to try it.” She put on a serious face and a tried to drop her voice as low as she could. “I’m afraid I must ask you not to torture muggles, mister pureblood supremacist. It is most undignified.”

Hermione scoffed. “Harry doesn’t talk like that.”

“Lord Slytherin does.”

“Well, you’re not going to be Lord Slytherin.”

“Nope!” Ginny grinned again. “I’m going to be Harry.”

Hermione let out an exasperated sigh. “I should be Harry.”

“Why?”

“I’ve done it before!”

“No, you’ve been Lord Slytherin. And that was only for, like, thirty seconds.”

“But Harry would want—”

“Ginny—Hermione.” Luna’s dreamy voice cut in, again.

They both looked at her.

“I think Ginny should be Harry tonight.”

“Why?” Hermione asked, sounding miffed. “Lady Potter is expecting her to be there.”

“Ginny is devious,” Luna said. “This mission will need a devious mind. She has many of the same skills that Harry possesses, like wandless magic and swatting. Her friendship with Harry is also less well known than yours is. It might be better it stays that way. And if she is spotted as a fake, she is best able of all of us to leave without being caught. We could tell Lady Potter that Ginny isn’t feeling well.”

Hermione grumbled and folded her arms.

Ginny beamed.

“Besides,” Luna continued. “There is another role that we’ll need you for—and you’re perfect for it.”

“What?”

“Distracting Lady Potter, of course. Who better to distract a professor than the best student in the year?”

Hermione perked up. “When you put it like that …”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Rita Skeeter was pissed off. She’d been flying all over the place trying to catch a hint of where Slytherin and the girl were, but they just weren’t to be found.

Eventually, she arrived back at the hotel room, shivering with cold and sniffing badly.

Bozo was sitting up in bed with his shirt off. His hair was messed up, and the room smelt of sex. There was a piece of paper on the desk on which someone had written a floo address. It was also amazingly warm. That just pissed her off even more. “I thought you were going to go find something useful,” she snapped.

Bozo didn’t bat an eyelid. “Yeah, Luv—I did. There’s a rumour Slytherin’s here for the dragons. Perhaps he snuck off to see one up close.”

“You want me to go sneaking around the dragon’s nests?!”

“I’m just telling you what I heard. One of the sales girls at the dragon armour shop told me they’d been in there—asking some very interesting questions, apparently.”

Rita huffed, scrunched up the paper with the floo address on it, and threw it at Bozo’s forehead, before stomping out of the room and slamming the door shut behind her.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

The lake next to the Volcano was crystal clear and as still as a mirror. A single rock thrown into it would cause perfect ripples to spread out in ever-expanding circles until the ripples broke into bobs, and, slowly, settled back down again. The surrounding scenery could put the viewer in mind of some alien planet, all rocks, and rocks, and, well, more rocks.

Daphne sat back on her rock, as the eye of kilrogg zipped back towards her. She released her grasp on the divination magic, and the eyeball faded from the world.

“Nothing?” Harry said.

Daphne shook her head. “No—I don’t think it’s here either. The longboat felt like a better bet, to be honest. Besides, there’s no wind.” She picked up a pebble and chucked it into the water. It went ‘Ploop.’ “I was really hoping we’d find it by now.” Daphne sighed. “And now?”

“Afternoon Tea.”

Daphne brightened up. “Where?”

“Right here.”

Ten minutes later they were both enjoying a picnic of buttered scones and jam that Harry had been hiding in his shrunk-trunk. A small pot of tea boiled under an emerald green flame. The afternoon sun was halfway down in the sky. They sat opposite each other on the same blanket they’d been wrapped up in the previous evening.

Daphne allowed herself to just enjoy the peace and quiet for a while.

Eventually, she put her plate down, dabbed at the side of her mouth with a napkin, and asked, “Where are we going to look next?”

Lord Slytherin put down his teacup with a little clink. “I think it’s time we got a bit closer to the source of the prophecy’s main identifier.”

“You mean dragons?” Daphne couldn’t help a little bit of excitement creep into her voice.

Her lord tilted his head. “I mean dragons.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“I’m not sure about this, Black.”

Draco was nervous. This seemed to be his default state of being around the Black Heiress, but this was pushing even those boundaries, and if he wasn’t careful Pansy or Theo would be sure to notice something was up.

“Look,” Black said, clearly impatient, “Do you want to always be in your father’s shadow, or do you want to forge your own path?”

“I am the Malfoy Heir,” he said, “I serve the house of Malfoy until it is time for me to become its lord.”

“And you can serve your house better by taking initiative!” Black snapped. “Now grab the rope and stop being a pussy.”

Draco winced but did tentatively take hold of the rope that was dangling from a hole in the castle ceiling.

“A lady shouldn’t use words like that,” he muttered, as the rope went taut and started lifting him up into the air.

“I’m sorry, did you say something?” Alex was already in the secret passageway above.

“No,” Draco quickly replied, “Nothing.”

The passageway in the ceiling was dusty, dirty, and cramped. They crawled forward on their hands and knees at about the same speed as a flobber worm after a particularly large dinner.

“My robes are getting filthy,” Draco complained.

“Shut up.”

“Please don’t tell me you’ve been doing this all year.”

“Shut up.”

“Not even the self-cleaning charms are going to get this out.”

Black glared back at him. “Don’t you do dirty stuff all the time? Like the animagus hunt?”

“That’s different.”

“How?”

“You’re supposed to get dirty then.”

“And I’m telling you that you’re supposed to get dirty here, Malfoy. Now shut up and keep up.”

They crawled on through what felt like miles of cramped tunnel, Draco silently cursing the first year girl in front of him all the way, until eventually they dropped down into another, far more roomy passageway, one in which someone had placed what looked like miniature runestones in a circle around a bare patch of wall.

“Keep close to me,” Black said.

Draco nodded.

Black tapped the wall with her wand, and the wall swung back and out.

They stepped through the gap in the wall and found themselves in …

“The library?” Draco said, nonplussed. “You took me through all that, just to go to the library?”

“Not just the library, Malfoy.” Black gestured towards a sign at the end of one of the shelves which read, ‘Necromancy and Demonology.’

Draco’s eyes widened, “We’re in—!”

“Shhh!”

Draco crouched down and lowered his voice. “We’re in the restricted section?” he hissed. “Do you have any idea how much trouble we could get into by being here?”

“Yes, which is why you’re going to keep quiet and follow me.”

They walked through the shelves until Black found what she’d obviously been looking for. She picked out a book, flipped through with a practised thumb, and started reading. Eventually, she looked up at him. “Well?” she asked. “Aren’t you going to look for something?”

Draco hesitated. He really shouldn’t be here. He really shouldn’t be doing this. Everything about this was wrong and dangerous on so many levels.

But …

His eyes flickered to a book titled ‘Unraveling the Dark Arts, Volume II.’

But, if he was going to be here anyway …

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Daphne and Harry stood at the entrance to a massive valley. They’d felt the ward magics all around them as they entered. A team of wizards had turned up shortly after that to find the intruders, but they’d simply hidden under the invisibility cloak until they’d given up and left.

And now they stood facing the valley.

Daphne’s mouth was dry.

Dragons were everywhere.

Large adults rested on the tops of mountains, watching the goings on down below with apparent disinterest. Younger ones played further down, blowing fire on each other, and butting their crystal blue heads together. Massive nests made of rock could just be made out atop the many crags and gullies. Off to one side, a somewhat small female nuzzled a much larger male.

There were dragons everywhere, and there were the signs of dragons everywhere.

The rocks were scarred with frightening claw marks, and the ground was blackened, almost glassy and scattered with countless reminders of where they were, from fragments of bone to teeth, claws, and ash.

As if to emphasise the point, one of the larger dragons chose that moment to let out a bellowing roar.

Daphne felt a chill go down her spine.

“You’re safe with me, Daph.”

Daphne smiled and stepped closer to Harry. “Yes, my lord. I know.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Damn Slytherin!

Why did Bozo have to be right?

Rita Skeeter ducked behind a massive boulder in the valley of dragons, heart pounding, breath heaving. She’d barely avoided being caught by the dragon preservation wizards by hiding out in her beetle form, and had nearly frozen to death because of it.

She rubbed her freezing skin and desperately tried to get some warming charms to penetrate her shivering body.

What the hell was he doing here?

Why the hell was he here?

Why the hell was she here?

Having almost literally frozen, Rita then figuratively froze as a large, dragon-shaped shadow briefly eclipsed her, before the weak sun found her again.

She had half a mind to just give up and fly back, but she couldn’t do that now. Not now. Not when Slytherin was clearly up to something. He’d never expect anyone to be following him here. If he’d ever let anything slip, it would surely be now.

Rita steeled herself, cast one last warming charm, and changed.

The beautiful jewelled beetle flittered across the desolate dragon landscape, towards its unsuspecting target.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Daphne snapped her real eyes open in triumph.

“I’ve found it,” she whispered.

Harry was by her in an instant. “Truly?”

“Yes,” Daphne’s voice was hushed, excited. “There’s a fidelius charm at the end of the valley. It’s not large but it clearly hides a cave.”

Harry winced. “I wish you hadn’t said that. We really need Hermione for this.” He gestured vaguely, and, as it happened, in completely the wrong direction. “Quickly. Guide me.”

Daphne nodded, grabbed his hand, and led him up the valley, taking care to keep a good distance from the many reptilian eyes that tracked their movement.

“It’s here,” Daphne whispered.

“What is?”

Daphne cursed, and pulled Harry inside.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

In her little beetle mind, Rita cursed.

They’d disappeared. Where had they gone? They’d been there, clear as day, and then suddenly, they weren’t. And it was far too cold to stay as a beetle.

She shifted back into her human form, and hid behind a convenient rock. No way was she staying out in the open with so many animal eyes around.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Daphne quickly found the rune stones which anchored the fidelius charm to the cave. Since they didn’t have Hermione to temporarily wipe Harry’s memory, and let him install a new set behind the old ones, Daphne knocked the stones over instead, with a thirty-foot pole, from the other side of the cave.

Harry blinked, looked around and firmed his jaw. “Right. Good work, Daph. I’ll take it from here.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Rita stared. There was a cave on the other side of the valley. That hadn’t been there before. Where the hell had that come from?

Is that were Slytherin and Greengrass had gone? Should she make a break for it? But she was so cold. If she ran for it, and a dragon attacked, she was as good as dead. If she changed into her beetle, she could make it across the distance to the cave, but would she be able to stay as a beetle for how long it would take for Slytherin to cough up his secrets?

Probably not.

She grimaced and cast another warming charm. Once her fingers felt like they weren’t about to drop off, then she’d change, and go.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Daphne sat staring at Harry, sat cross-legged and eyes closed in the middle of the cave.

She wasn’t sure how long it had been, but it had been a while, that much was certain. Harry then opened his eyes, grinned, tapped his wand on the new primary rune stone in front of him, and said, “Fidelius Occultum.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Warmth! Finally!

Rita poked her head over the boulder.

Now she could finally make a break for …

For what?

A feeling of fuzziness crept into her brain. She tried to think, but every time she tried, the thoughts flowed out as though her brain was a sponge and someone was giving it a jolly good squeeze.

Rita blinked. She cursed. Something had happened again. She wasn’t sure what, but it had.

Damn it! All this way and she’d missed them, again!

“DAMN IT!”

The words rang out across the valley, bouncing back and forth like a siren’s call to hungry sailors.

Rita froze in horror as soon as the words left her mouth, all thoughts of Slytherin forgotten. In the distance, something roared.

She was just about to change on instinct and fly away when, once again, a shadow eclipsed her.

Dread filling her, Rita slowly turned around, and looked into the eyes of a winged predator 100 times heavier than her, fully capable of swallowing her in one single gulp. A puff of flame instantly told her that to change meant instant death.

The dragon inspected her critically.

“P-Please.”

The dragon lunged, Rita screamed, something popped into being in front of her, and the glorious squeezing of an apparition enveloped her entire body—an apparition somehow capable of going straight through apparition wards.

She fell on the ground in a heap, and, miraculously, not bitten clean in half. She breathed in great gulps of wonderful, wonderful air.

“What’s all this then?” said a horribly familiar female voice.

Rita slowly looked up. Goblins.

A house elf stepped up beside her. “Milly is being watching this nasty witch trying to snoop on the young mistress, oh yes. Milly is being considering letting her being dragon food, but Lord Greengrass is preferring to use his enemies rather than killing them.”

Rita groaned. Out of the frying pan and into the fire.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

In the Icelandic cave guarded by dragons, Daphne and Harry looked down at the small chest they’d dug up.

Daphne wiped wet sand off her hands and frowned. “Is that all?”

The all in question was a small chest half full of golden galleons and half full of old books. A substantial fortune to the man on the street, but not much in the grand scheme of things.

Harry pulled one of the books free. “It seems so. Maybe there’s something of value in these.”

“There’s only got to be, what? Maybe four thousand galleons?”

“Could be.”

“That’s not going to be much help.”

“It’ll keep us afloat for another half a year.”

Daphne sagged. “I was hoping for rather much more than that. It doesn’t seem much considering what Luna had to go through for it.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

The Hogwarts library was vast, containing much of the accumulated knowledge of a thousand years of scholarly activity. For the adventurous soul, there are many treasures to be discovered, if said soul could avoid being caught. In the previous school year, Harry Potter had gone so far as to install a fidelius charm to make his own rummaging that much easier.

He’d taken it down at the start of this year when he discovered the limitations on the number of fidelius charms a single caster could maintain.

But that didn’t mean that hiding in the forbidden section was no longer possible—far from it. The Hogwarts Library was vast, as has already been mentioned, and just like the rest of the school, bent space in strange and sometimes very convenient ways.

Among the shelves of the forbidden section, Draco Malfoy cautiously navigated through an archway made of books and into yet another area he’d not encountered on his last lap of this section.

He’d spent the last few hours scanning the spines of hundreds of tomes, pulling out books at random, and skimming their contents—mostly boring, sometimes gory, occasionally fascinating—all the while unable to keep his heart from pounding in his chest at the thought of what would happen if he were caught.

He poked his head around the next corner and gazed down the main corridor of what turned out to be the necromancy section. Alexandra Black was sitting cross-legged on the floor, nose deep in a book, seemingly unaware of her dangerous surroundings. Another pile of books sat beside her.

This girl was the source of all his headaches and fears, but, at the same time, Draco couldn’t help feeling something strange—something he so rarely felt. Being here, where he shouldn’t be, without his parent’s permission or knowledge, was, there were no other words to use, thrilling.

He edged his way up the corridor, ears constantly alert for the sound of approaching adult footsteps, or just any footsteps at all.

He reached the first year girl and glanced down at the pile of books.

They reeked of dark magic—exactly the kind of books he’d been strenuously avoiding since they arrived. You never knew what you might find. Perhaps it would scream the moment someone picked it up, or curse you to only speak in tongues, or instantly turn your kidneys into soup. There were many dark curses that could kill you before you could get to a trained healer.

Did Black not know?

Without looking up, the girl then put down her current book and reached for the next one on the pile. Draco was just about to shout a warning when black chains sprang from nowhere, wrapped around the book, ripped it open, and dragged it in front of Black’s face, all while the book struggled and writhed like a condemned man being held down by four or five stronger men.

Black turned to the front page, frowned, and looked up. “Oh, it’s you.”

Draco clenched his fists. “Do you have any idea how dangerous that was?” he hissed. “It could have killed you.”

“No.” Alex pointed to a book on the far shelf. “That book would kill you. This one is merely charmed to fight back.”

“You couldn’t know that.”

“Yes, I can.”

“How?”

It should not be possible to look down your nose at someone who is sitting cross-legged beside you, while you are still standing, but Alexandra Black managed it. “It’s just so obvious,” she said. “Magic whispers to me.”

Draco hesitated. The way Black had said that last sentence screamed Dark Lady at upper sonorous levels. Eventually, he said, “But still—necromancy, Black? Don’t you think that’s a bit much? We’re not grownups yet.”

“Why shouldn’t we?” Black shot back. “We have occlumency, which makes our minds older, but our parents would have us use it only to make sure we don’t embarrass ourselves. We are capable of so much more.”

“Maybe your father, does, Black. Mine trusts me with dark magic.”

Black snorted.

“It’s true!” Draco bit out.

“Show me then.”

Draco slipped his wand out of his robes, pointed it down the corridor and whispered, “Serpensortia.” A large black snake shot out of his wand and fell at the end of the corridor. A small cloud of dust rose where it landed. It looked around and hissed.

Alex nodded.

Draco looked at her triumphant. “You see?”

“I see talent that is being wasted.”

“What?!”

“You cast that easily, without even thinking about it, and yet that was your ‘most impressive’ piece of dark magic? Give me a break.”

“Well, what would you do?”

The black chains holding the still struggling book slammed said book shut. “I would find something more ambitious to attempt. We are Slytherins after all.”

“Ambitious like what?”

Black waved a vague hand at the rows upon rows of books. “I don’t care. Pick something.”

Draco’s eyes scanned the books. He reached towards a book, and a chain grabbed his wrist.

“Not that one!” Black said, sharply. “Unless you want to go through life speaking only Russian.”

Draco shook the chain off and glared. “What about this one?” he asked, pointing at the next book down.

“Sure. That one’s okay.”

Draco opened the book and his stomach turned. The artist had been quite graphic with their illustrations. Necromancy, apparently, covered a huge range of topics, but by far the most basic was … “This,” he said. “We could do this on a spider or something.”

He handed the book to Black.

Black read the page he’d selected and gave him a funny look. “The inferi ritual?”

Draco mistook Alex’s look of bemusement for worry. “What? Scared, Black? You’re not backing out now, are you?”

Black smirked. “Not at all. I was just surprised. Meet me at the Black Lake at six.”

“What? Tonight?”

Black rolled her eyes and turned back to her books. “Yes, Draco, Tonight.”

They didn’t stay in the restricted section much longer after that. Draco spent the time memorising the details for the inferi ritual, which seemed to be shockingly simple, if terrifying in its results. Just before he slipped the book back in its place, his fingers traced the symbol they’d need to create for the ritual. A memory flashed through his mind—a memory of a giant undead tree tearing itself out of the ground to crush anyone that got in its way. That tree had been created with the same symbol—the symbol of the deathly hallows.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

As Draco left, a large grin formed on Alexandra’s face. That had been so much fun. The look on Malfoy’s face when she’d given him the, ‘you are wasting your talent,’ line, and when he’d actually picked up the inferi ritual it had been all she could do to keep a straight face. She’d been this close to bursting out laughing.

Alex made her way out of the restricted section, with its crazy geometry and cursed books, and then doubled back to the normal library, or as normal as a magical library could get. She found herself a quiet nook, dashed off a quick note for Luna, stuffed it into an official-looking envelope, and, checking that no one was watching, pulled another library book out of her bag. It wasn’t a book from the restricted section, but that didn’t matter. Getting caught with this book would be, in its own special way, much, much worse.

“Come now, Malcom, look at everything he has—money, fame, friends—don’t you want that too?” The Black Witch of the North smiled seductively and beckoned Malcom closer. “The Boy Who Lived is nothing compared to what you could be.”

Alex smirked and curled up in the armchair.

Malcom frowned and walked forward. “He shouldn’t have done what he did. But that doesn’t mean I trust you. I remember what you did before.”

The Black Witch of the North walked over to the mirror on the wall, covered with a large black drape. “The fate of the world, Malcom. I know we’ve had our differences in the past, but we must put that past us. The Boy Who Lived is too blind to see what is really there. You are not!” And she pulled off the drape to reveal—

“Miss Heiress?”

Alex’s heart leapt into her throat. She snapped the book shut, and just had the presence of mind to look annoyed rather than guilty. Hestia and Flora Carrow walked around the corner and stopped when they saw her.

“Yes?”

“Please, Miss Heiress,” probably Flora said nervously, “It’s nearly dinner.”

“Is it?” Alex blinked. She and Draco must have been longer than she’d thought.

“And since you said we weren’t to be at dinner without you, we had no choice but to come and find you,” probably Hestia continued. She paused. “Are you sure you don’t want us to call you The Dark Heiress?”

Alex hopped off the chair and slipped the Lockhart book back into her bag, careful not to show its cover to the twins. “No—Miss Heiress is fine.” Alex slung the bag over her shoulder. “Let’s go.”

They left the library, each twin falling into step beside her. The Carrow twin’s reaction to the common room incident had been perhaps the most extreme of all her classmates. Alex had entered their shared dorm room after lights out, taken in the looks of fear on the two girl’s faces, and barked, “Go to bed.” She’d gotten two squeaks of acknowledgement in return, and two pledges the next morning to be at her beck and call for anything she might ever need while they were at Hogwarts, “anything at all, Miss Heiress, just please don’t hurt us.”

“You need to send an owl, Miss Heiress?” probably Flora asked, pointing to the envelope Alex still carried. Alex had instructed them to wear different coloured hair ornaments to tell them apart.

“No,” Alex said. “This is for Heiress Lovegood.”

“Lovegood?” Hestia wrinkled her nose. “She’s loopy. What business could you have with her?”

Alex felt a stab of anger, but held it down. “That is a Black family matter,” she drawled. “I am still the heiress of a Light family, regardless of my personal feelings.”

“It must be terrible, Miss Heiress.”

Alex nodded. “Quite terrible.”

They arrived at the great hall and took their places at the Slytherin table, but not before Alex made a great show of giving Luna the letter. After all, if you didn’t want anyone to think you were in secret communication with someone, the second best way to do that was to not keep the communication secret.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“Where have you been?” Pansy asked Draco as he sat down at Dinner.

“Nowhere,” Draco replied, perhaps a tad too quickly. “Have you done our astronomy homework yet?”

“Of course,” Pansy replied. “Have you done our astronomy homework yet?”

“I’m doing it tomorrow.”

“So, you weren’t doing homework, then. C’mon, Draco—you can tell me. You’re running off alone all the time now. We used to do everything together. Remember when we were little and climbed into your father’s greenhouse?”

Draco couldn’t help a small smile, before quickly erasing it. “Yes, I remember. But I still haven’t been doing anything important.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

In a trunk in the Slytherin second year’s girl’s dormitory, four young witches were in full on ‘getting ready to go out’ mode. The fact that ‘out’ in this case merely meant elsewhere in the castle was of no consequence to the proceedings.

The two muddy potions on a side table, however, were.

Hermione and Tracey looked on as Ginny and Luna picked up the potions and downed them in two quick gulps. Suddenly, their skin began to bubble. Ginny’s hair got shorter, while Luna’s changed from dirty blonde to fiery red.

Moments later, where Ginny had been standing was a perfect copy of Harry, and where Luna had been standing was a perfect copy of Ginny.

“Okay,” Tracey said, “I understand that Ginny can act Potter better than Luna, but isn’t this needlessly complex?”

“Lady Potter is expecting Ginny to be there,” Ginny said, adjusting the boy’s robes that now tailored her frame perfectly. “Wow, this feels so weird. I totally get why boys sit with their legs spread now.”

“Even so …”

“And Luna needs to leave before dinner is over,” Luna said. “Harry can’t do that without getting into trouble with Lady Potter.”

Tracey smirked. “Well, Tracey is just glad she doesn’t have to drink that muck. What was that letter that Alex gave you at dinner?”

“The letter is why Luna needs to leave early,” Luna said.

“Oh.”

“Can we please stop talking in third person now?” Hermione was busy fixing her earrings in place. “It’s rather irritating.”

“Ginny thinks its fun,” Ginny said, grinning impishly.

“Harry doesn’t talk like that.”

Ginny shrugged, stood a bit straighter, and adopted a face of mild good humour, laced with a touch of steel. She tilted her head. “Thank you, Hermione. You are, of course, correct. Please pass me my bag.”

“What?”

“My bag, Hermione, if you please.”

“Can’t you get it yourself? It’s right there.”

“Hermione,” Tracey said cautiously. “That’s Potter you’re talking to.”

“Not until we’re in public. And anyway, Harry wouldn’t ask me to pass him his bag when it’s just us. He’d summon it himself.”

“Yes, but if he did, you would get it for him.”

“Harry needs me for things more important than passing his bag.”

“Yes, but if he did—”

“—Then it would just be for show.” Hermione turned to Ginny. “You’d better not abuse this. Harry would not approve.”

Ginny smiled. “I trust Ginny to do what’s needed on a mission. And I know I can rely on you to do exactly what I say, when I say it, Hermione.”

Hermione huffed. “I do what Harry says because Harry knows what’s best—you’re not actually Harry—just remember that.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Stew was bubbling in a small cauldron over a light blue fire. The smell rose into the air full of the promise of rich, meaty flavour, fighting for nasal dominance with the smell of freshly baked bread coming from a small magical oven. The aroma of fresh flowers dotted around the apartment in jars and vases barely stood a chance.

Lily Potter checked the stew once more and smiled.

And all without a single house elf, she thought to herself. James wouldn’t understand, although he’d pretend to understand, but James wasn’t here. Being the lady of an ancient and noble house was hard work. There was so much parchment floating around—something that her new teaching duties only made worse—or would have, if she didn’t have a teaching assistant. Sometimes it was nice to just spend an afternoon doing something different—preferable something involving actual magic. Again, thank Merlin for that teaching assistant.

Being the lady of an ancient and noble house was hard work, but it was not without its perks.

Lily Potter brought a spoonful of the stew to her lips and sipped. Not quite ready, yet.

A loud knock came from the living room. Lily left the kitchen, crossed the space, and opened the door. It was Harry.

“Hi, Mum.” Harry smiled winningly at her.

And Harry had brought not only Ginny, but Miss Davis and Miss Granger as well. “Good evening, young man. I wasn’t expecting this many.”

“You said I was to bring Ginny,” Harry said quickly. “And it wouldn’t be right if I didn’t bring Hermione.”

“And Miss Davis?”

Tracey gave her a nervous smile.

“She’s also my friend,” Harry said brightly. “And she’s ever so clever. If it wasn’t for Hermione, and Daphne, and well, me, I’m sure she’d be top of the year.” Harry paused. “Well, John too, I guess,” he finished rather less enthusiastically.

Lily put a hand on her hip. “Well, I can’t really say no can I?” She turned to the girls and her voice switched from parental to reassuring. “Of course you’re all welcome, girls. Come into the kitchen and I’ll show you some useful charms. I’m sure you’d like that.”

Lily switched the wizarding wireless on as she passed it on the way to the kitchen. “There you are, Harry. I know how much you enjoy listening to the news.”

Harry thanked her and sat down on the couch next to the wireless to listen by himself. Behind her, the girls all filed into the kitchen and started to ooo and ahh over the stew.

Lily frowned. She hadn’t known her second born son (by about five minutes) at all while growing up. They’d only been reunited during the summer, but after a whole month of getting to know him, she thought she knew him fairly well, and she couldn’t help shake the feeling that something wasn’t quite right.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Ginny sat on the sofa, listening to the wizarding wireless how she imagined Harry would—like a secret mastermind planning world domination.

*Wibble-wobble* The Union of African Ministries has stated that there is no connection between this week’s spate of disappearances and a similar string several months ago. Nevertheless, a Uagadou representative has gone on record as stating that the school is upping security measures and that parents should be alert when transporting their children. One of the missing persons is a sixteen-year-old Uagadou student, last seen five days ago on a day trip to a local village. All future day trips have been suspended until further notice. * Wibble-wobble*

*Wibble-wobble* The ICW voted last night to recognise the Full Moon Ministry as a legitimate wizarding government and provisional member of the ICW after thirty years of civil war between Full Moon Rebels and Transylvania. The last-minute peace deal between the two warring factions was hammered out in the chamber, and spearheaded by Supreme Mugwump Albus Dumbledore. Critics have blasted the deal as condemning hundreds of innocents to a fate worse than death, while supporters have praised the tough stance the deal takes on Full Moon activities outside of their new borders. *Wibble-wobble*

*Wibble-wobble* And in local news, Cork’s petition to the ministry for funding to build an extension to the community’s enclave has been turned down on budgetary grounds. Of all the mixed wizarding enclaves in Britain, Cork currently has the largest ratio living outside its walls, with only one enclaved wizard to every four living among the general muggle populous. By comparison, London, which has a magical population nearly three times as large, has a ratio of just one to one. A spokesman for the ministry said that it was regrettable, but until Cork could afford to galleon match the project, there was nothing they could do. The mayor of Cork has expressed his dismay, calling the ministry’s decision, ‘short-sighted and dangerous.’ *Wibble-wobble*

*Wibble-wobble* And now it’s time for the wind report. Light breezes across the country make for perfect flying condi—

Ginny leaned over and fiddled with the knob.

“—Mason passes the quaffle to Halbert! Oh! That was a close call!”

Ginny leaned back and grinned. Masterminding was a hard job, after all, and everyone knew Harry liked quidditch too.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Back in the kitchen, four wands pointed at the walls, four voices said, “Plates!” and a dozen plates flew from the shelves, spun around the room, and settled onto the kitchen counter, evenly spaced out, and without so much as a crack between them.

Lily smiled at her students. Two of them had got it right on their very first go, and Tracey had managed it on her second attempt. If only all her other students were as good as this group was. “Well done, girls,” she said. “Ginny, I’m especially impressed with you.” And she was. She’d heard from Flitwick about her and Luna Lovegood’s impressive progress in his class, but seeing it was something else. And her attitude had practically done a 180 since the start of school. Spending time with Harry was obviously doing her good.

Ginny smiled dreamily. “Thank you, Lady Potter.”

Tracey looked at her wand. “But, when are we going to need household charms? I mean, really?”

Lily fixed her with a knowing look. “You say that now, but there may well come a time when you’ll be glad you learned them.”

“I know what you mean,” Miss Granger enthused. This girl also seemed to be making a special effort to get along with her, counter to her usually frosty demeanour. “I couldn’t stand always being reliant on a servant to do everything for me. It would drive me mad.”

“I think,” Ginny said, “that lady Potter was more referring to the adage that the way to a boy’s heart is through his stomach.”

“Perhaps.” Lily gave Ginny a sideways look. “Do you have a boy you’re interested in, Ginny?”

“Harry of course.”

Hermione rolled her eyes.

Lily just smiled and softly shook her head. “Why don’t you go and see if Harry is ready for dinner?”

“Okay.”

When the stew was finally ready to be served, Lily re-entered the living room to find Ginny smiling brightly in Harry’s lap—something that Harry, while clearly trying to play it cool, nevertheless looked more than a little uncomfortable with. Lily frowned. Something still seemed off.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Ginny was doing her best not to panic. Luna had just come in from the kitchen, plopped herself down in her lap, and then snuggled up against her as though she were, well, Harry. Which would be fine, sort of, if Luna really were Ginny, and she really was Harry—and Luna was betrothed to Lord Slytherin, who was also Harry, so it was okay, but most people didn’t know that, so it also wasn’t. But more to the point, her body, that is to say, Harry’s body, whose form she, Ginny, was currently borrowing, was reacting to Luna, or rather to her, Ginny. She was reacting to herself—or was that Harry’s form was reacting to her? Or was Harry form reacting to Luna? Arghhhh!

She played it as dignified as she could while Lady Potter had the other girls set the table, which felt really weird to be excluded from, and they almost had everything set up just so, when a knock came from the door.

“Ah, that’ll be your brother.”

Ginny tensed, which was probably a good thing, as it was the only thing stopping her from swearing when John walked in accompanied by Susan Bones, and none other than the diary—AKA Virgo Malfoy.

John froze as soon as his eyes landed on her and it took Ginny a moment to realise what the situation looked like.

Oh, it was just too perfect. She couldn’t not do it.

Ginny looked John right in the eye, smirked, wrapped her hands around Luna’s waist, pulled her in close to her, and mouthed, “Mine.”

The look on John’s face was worth a million galleons.

The first course was amazing after that—or as amazing as dinner can be with a murderer, a betrayer, an abandoner, and last but not the least, your best friend who, up until that point, you’d thought of in purely platonic terms, and who had then spent over half an hour sitting in your very unusually male lap.

It was rather a surprise when Luna suddenly got up and announced she was going to the bathroom.

“But Ginny,” Lady Potter called after her, “We have a—“

The front door closed shut.

“—bathroom in the apartment,” Lily finished with a confused look on her face.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Rita Skeeter stormed into her hotel room and slammed the door behind her. “Pack your things. We’re going.”

“Already?” Bozo made no move to start packing even as Rita started throwing clothes into her magically expanded bag.

“Yes! How many hours have I been gone?”

“Gotta be close to five or six.”

“Damn Goblins!”

Bozo raised an eyebrow. “Goblins?”

“Bloody House Elf nearly caught me while I was transformed. Didn’t—but that’s a small mercy. Dumped me with the little rat-bags, who handed me over to the dragon preserve after Merlin knows how long. I tried to tell them Slytherin was there too, but they weren’t having it.”

She grabbed a file from the desk and chucked it at Bozo. “Here. He’s yours if you want.”

Bozo caught the file, chuckled, and leafed through the rather thin document. “Don’t mind if I do, Luv. Don’t mind if I do.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Ginny was sweating. Ever since Luna had left, the line of discussion had turned from the innocuous and was leaning more towards the interrogatory—of Harry specifically.

Even more worrying, she’d realised, with horror, was that the diary seemed to be interested, especially, in her, Ginny. It kept asking questions about her. How Harry knew her, where they’d met, what they liked about each other—questions that she could easily answer, but the focus was disturbing.

Lady Lily’s questions were more circumspect, but still had a certain weight and thrust to them that suggested she thought there might be something wrong.

John just glared at her.

The only person not in their group who wasn’t focused on her was Susan, who was happily chatting with Tracey about potions homework.

Thankfully, she did need to answer a call of nature. That would give her time to breath.

“Excuse me, I think I’m going to also go to the bathroom,” Ginny said, pushing her chair back and standing up.

“It’s the second door on the right,” Lily said, quickly.

“Got it!” Ginny called back. It was just after she’d locked the bathroom door, and turned to the toilet, when she realised what she was about to do, and remembered to blush.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“Does Harry always focus so hard on his studies?” Lily asked Hermione.

“Oh, yes, he’s a very hard worker, he’s taught me so much, but then, many of my classmates do. Like in herbology there’s this plant we’re working on, and Professor Sprout says that the plant makes an excellent anticoagulant, but Neville Longbottom, he’s a Gryffindor, says that it’s only the stems, leaves, and roots that have that effect and you can get a more potent extract if you first remove the—“

“You aren’t worried that he might be overdoing it, do you?”

“What?”

“You aren’t worried that Harry might be overdoing it?”

“Oh no. Harry’s always careful to take regular breaks and stand up and walk around and stuff like that. He makes me do that all the time. I read in a book one time that a wizard’s body can hold much more magic if it’s fit and healthy, and so ever since then, I’ve been doing jogging and swimming and stuff like that and it helps me out a lot. I don’t understand why more wizards don’t do it. I know that the quidditch teams and duelling teams do, but they’re just a few and I know that we have great healing spells to counter diabetes and liver disease and so on, but that doesn’t mean we shouldn’t—”

“Can you think of any reason why Harry might be acting differently?”

“Differently? Harry? No. Not at all. Why? Do you think Harry’s acting differently?”

Lily looked at Hermione for a moment before sighing and standing up. “Never mind—it was just a thought. If you’ll excuse me, Miss Granger. I’m going to make a cup of tea.”

On the other side of the table, Virgo Malfoy watched the conversation with a thoughtful expression.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Ginny was just closing the bathroom door behind her, and trying not to look like she’d just done something unbelievably dirty. When a hand grabbed her shoulder, she recognised who it was in time to avoid stunning them, mores the pity.

“What the hell do you think you’re doing?” John Potter hissed from less than a foot away. “Ginny isn’t yours!”

Ginny smirked again. “Yes, she is.”

“I’ll tell her you said that.”

“Go ahead.”

“Ginny hates possessiveness.”

“Ginny hates lots of things,” Ginny said. “Your dumb arse just happens to top the list.”

“Ginny has no reason to …” John trailed off.

Ginny raised her eyebrows.

John then stayed silent for so long that Ginny started to feel uncomfortable.

Finally, he spoke. “You told her.” Three words—simple, and, once spoken, obviously true. His face turned at once from understanding to furious. He leaned closer and hissed, “You bloody told her! You fucking hypocrite! You said not to tell anyone! What did you tell her? You lied to her didn’t you?! I would have saved her! I would have—”

And that was as far as he got before Ginny kneed John in the groin.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

“Also, I think Lady Potter is getting suspicious,” Hermione said in a low voice.

John Potter had arrived back in the living room a few minutes after Ginny looking beyond murderous and was currently being talked down from whatever rash action he was considering by Susan.

“Jeez,” Tracey replied, looking around the room. “What tipped you off?”

“Well—“ Hermione began.

“That was a rhetorical question,” Tracey interrupted before Hermione could get started. She shook her head. “Don’t worry,” she said. “I’ll take care of this. Trust me.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Ahhh. Lily took a sip of warm tea. Perfect. She frowned. Now, what about Harry?

“Lady Potter?”

Lily looked around and smiled warmly at her favourite student. “Yes, Miss Davis?”

“I mean no disrespect, but if you wanted to know about why Harry might be acting strangely, Hermione is probably the worse person to ask.”

Lily’s ears picked up. “Oh?”

“Yes.”

“Why’s that?” She took another sip of tea.

“You didn’t hear what happened on Hermione’s birthday?”

“No? What happened at Hermione’s birthday?”

“Well …”

BOOOM!

The shockwave of a massive explosion from a long way away shook the room, causing the windows to rattle in their frames.

Lily firmly put down her cup and snatched her wand. “Stay here!” She ran into the living room. “All of you!” she barked, before running for the door and slamming it behind her.

Tracey, Hermione, Ginny (disguised as Harry), John, Susan, and Virgo all looked around at each other.

“Wizard’s Chess?” Susan suggested, hopefully.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

[Some time earlier]

Draco Malfoy looked around furtively as he left the dungeons and passed into the maze of corridors that made up the rest of the castle. He was feeling that feeling again—an almost overwhelming rush, fuelled by the knowledge that what he was doing was not only against the rules, and also certainly the law, but more importantly, that his parents had not given him the go ahead, and he hadn’t even asked.

Draco heard approaching female voices and ducked behind the large statue of a manticore, then cursed himself for it.

“Oh, Professor Sprout likes me a lot,” said one of the girls. “I just don’t necessarily like her that much—I just smile a lot in class to get the good grades.”

“No,” said the second girl. “No, Tim hates charms. I mean he absolutely despises it. He said, right, he said he’d give it up if he could in an instant.”

“Oh Merlin, imagine Tim in Arithmancy.”

“Or Runes.”

“Wait—how about this—next charms class—”

The two voices faded away as they turned the corner. Draco stepped out from behind the statue, and mentally shook himself. He hadn’t done anything wrong yet.

The only other person he met on his march to the grounds was a random fifth-year Ravenclaw, whom he gave a curt nod, and then he was out—out in the chilly October evening air, heavy with light mist and dark with blocked sunlight. He pulled his robes tighter around him.

“Draco?”

He jumped and spun around. It was Pansy. She was standing in the doorway behind him and looked determined. “You followed me?” he asked.

Pansy nodded. “You’re sneaking out again, aren’t you? Without me.”

Draco sighed. “Look, I can’t bring you with me. I can’t explain why, but I can’t.”

“Is it Malfoy House business?”

Draco didn’t hesitate. “Yes,” he said.

“And if I sent an owl to you father asking for confirmation?”

Now Draco hesitated.

Pansy smirked. “I knew it!” She stepped up beside him.

Draco growled. “No, Pansy—I mean—it’s not that it’s family business, it’s just …” he trailed off before finding his words again, “it’s just that there are things that you don’t share with everyone. I’m sure you understand.”

“I do.”

“Then go back.”

“No, I’d rather go with you.”

Draco cursed. A brief debated warred in his head over whether to call the whole thing off. Eventually he decided to probe deeper. “What I was planning to do tonight might be considered legally … questionable.”

Pansy frowned. “All the more reason for me to go with you then. You’ve been distancing yourself too much from the rest of us. We don’t like it.”

Draco groaned, translating that last statement as, ‘I don’t like it.’ He knew Theo couldn’t give a damn, and Crabb and Goyle likewise. “Fine, you can follow for now, but you might have to go back anyway.”

“Why?”

Draco didn’t reply, instead choosing to let the reason why became apparent on its own. Pansy’s eyes widened as she caught sight of Alexandra Black waiting for them by the Black Lake.

“I know I didn’t say you couldn’t bring anyone,” Black said, without preamble, eyeing Pansy up and down. “But I assumed it was assumed.”

“She wouldn’t be denied,” Draco drawled. “I guarantee she will keep her silence.” He shot Pansy a sideways look.

Pansy hastily nodded. “Lips are sealed.”

Despite Pansy’s assurance, it actually took many more minutes of discussion, negotiation, and promise making before the Black Heiress seemed satisfied. The three of them then moved from the edge of the lake, and into the forbidden forest, Pansy holding tightly onto Draco’s hand.

Draco didn’t blame her. The forbidden forest was the great bogeyman of the students. “Don’t upset the teachers,” the older ones would say, “Or they’ll send you for detention into the forbidden forest.”

Pansy’s hand-grip became almost vice-like when Black produced a large slab of cow meat from a shrunk-trunk, deposited it in a clearing, and directed them all to hide in the trunk.

“I thought we were using a spider?” Draco hissed once they were all safely inside the trunk.

“We are,” Alex whispered back.

There was movement outside the trunk—a skittering, clicking sound, which made the hairs on the back of Draco’s neck rise. He wanted to say, “What kind of spider do you want to attract with bait that large?” But didn’t. Every instinct was telling him to shut the hell up. Beside him, Pansy, still clueless as to what they were actually doing, whimpered.

When they eventually emerged from the trunk, Draco just stared. It was an acromantula as large as a horse—possibly larger—drugged or dead, he wasn’t sure. Dear Merlin. Yes, he’d said they should practice on a spider, but he’d meant a normal one! Like normal people used!

“Black,” he said, managing not to let his voice tremble, as Alexandra started clearing away piles of dead leaves from the ground in a matter of fact kind of way. “I’m not sure this is a good idea. The book said, ‘power equal to the power to be chained.’ ”

“Trust me, it’ll be fine,” Alex said, sounding unconcerned.

Pansy was now clinging to his arm. He whispered into her ear what they were doing, to which her eyes widened, if possible, even further, but she didn’t run or object.

Black finished clearing the space and handed Draco and Pansy a paintbrush each and a bucket full of chicken blood between them. “I only brought two brushes, so it’s up to you.”

It took quite a while, but between them, he and Pansy succeeded in painting the dread symbol of the deathly hallows around the massive spider while Alex tied it up with heavy, heavy looking chains. A horrible feeling of déjà vu was steeling over Draco, but it was firmly pushed from his mind when Alex brought out a number of items from her trunk, including what looked like a highly polished, white stake, but which, apparently, was a dementor bone.

“I thought dementor bone was a type of plant!” Draco half-shouted.

“I don’t know why you’d think that,” Black said with a shrug. “Can you think why he’d think that, Pansy?”

“No,” Pansy weakly replied. “But, is that really a dementor bone? I thought dementors were unkillable.”

“They are.”

“So how?”

“I don’t know.”

The ritual, when they actually came to perform it, was the most terrifying thing Draco had yet done, and he was certain it was for Pansy too. It had first required them to strip naked. That alone was pretty scary. They then chanted the words of the ritual and focused their magic into the dementor bone foci.

Then, terror. The beast lurched, even while chained down, struggling against the metal bonds, which to Draco suddenly looked far too thin and flimsy.

They poured all the magic they could into the ritual. Pansy was shaking. Draco was sweating. He’d already used all the ready magic he had. He was now running directly from his core, and still the newly raised monster wouldn’t submit. He looked towards Black, who was similarly struggling, and then, Draco thought he saw something, but it might just have been his imagination. A faint shimmer in the air behind Black—a faint shimmering hand on Black’s shoulder. But then Black’s magic surged like a dam had broken and the shimmer settled into the air as though it had never been there.

Draco felt the pressure lessen. He felt the ritual strengthen. He felt the beast give one final cry of defiance, before the laws of magic exerted themselves and claimed its slavery, even from within the throes of death.

He collapsed to his knees and panted.

It was over.

He looked up. The beast stood stock still in the middle of the ritual circle, ready to take their commands. He could feel his and Pansy’s faint link to the monster, even if it was Black who was ultimately in control. He started to laugh. They’d done it.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Not far away, hidden in the trees and bushes, the three students, now celebrating, clearing up, and making plans for what to do with their new spider inferi, were being watched by a half dozen heads, these ones quite a bit smaller than the one they’d just raised, and several dozen times again that many actual eyes.

*Click* “Monsters!” *Clack* “Unnatural!” *Click* “Insult!” said one.

*Clack* “Danger!” *Click* “Powerful!” *Clack* “Magic!” said another.

*Click* “Father!” *Clack* “Speaks!” argued the first, clearly agitated. The acromantula then sensed something behind it—something not visible to any one of its several dozen eyes, but nevertheless, very much there.

And then, it died.

Several very hectic moments later, all the others died too. All except one, which sped away from the scene through the trees, and was soon lost to sight.

Luna Lovegood shimmered into view and bit her lip, looking at the space where the retreating spider had fled. “Oh, poo.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Alex, Draco, and Pansy had decided to send their new inferi away to lurk among the forest trees. They didn’t want to release it, and they certainly couldn’t keep it close by. Even if it could theoretically fit inside Alex’s expanded trunk, it certainly wouldn’t fit through the lid.

They cleaned up the symbol of the deathly hallows, packed up the dementor bone, and scattered the leaves back around the clearing.

Something heavy was weighing on Draco’s mind. “Black,” he started, “What would you say if I asked if it was possible to raise an inferi tree?”

“I’d say it sounds like an interesting project. Did you have a tree in mind?”

The two stared at each other with equally blank expressions.

Pansy looked between the two before putting a hand to her mouth. “You think Alex was the one who—!“ she cut herself off.

It would explain a lot, Draco thought to himself. It would explain why she seemed so familiar with that they were doing. It would explain why she just happened to have a dementor bone with her at Hogwarts. It would explain why an eleven year old girl didn’t seem at all fazed at the prospect of subduing a class XXXXX beast the size of a horse. She was a necromancer! Their champion. No wonder he’d lost.

Black shrugged. “I don’t have a clue what you’re talking about,” she said, and Draco knew pushing now was useless.

Just then, a small paper bird flapped its way out of the trees.

They all watched it as it landed in Black’s hands and unfolded itself for her to read.

Everything changed. Black’s expression went from unconcerned to serious. Her movements went from casual to sharp. “Spiders! Run!”

Pansy gasped.

Draco took a step backwards. “Can’t you take them?”

Black scrunched the paper up, shoved it into the pocket of her robes. “Too many!”

“How many?” Pansy asked.

Black reached for her trunk. “Hundreds!” she barked. “Move!”

Draco didn’t need telling twice. He grabbed Pansy’s hand and together they ran, trying not to trip over tree roots as they dashed through the thick forest. Black soon caught them up and powered through to lead their retreat. She seemed to move through the trees as though born to it, never missing a foot step as she blazed their trail, but never letting either him or Pansy fall behind either.

Draco wasn’t sure how long they ran, but it felt like hours. It felt like hours. It was probably only a few minutes.

A massive explosion sounded behind them. And then another. And another. It was as though the whole forest was under attack from one of the horrible muggle weapons his father had told him horror stories about. And then spiders. Spiders everywhere. Draco refused to let go of Pansy as one of the massive ones snatched them both up and into the trees. Black screamed her defiance, getting a couple of them with her magic chains, but soon, even she was overcome, trussed up, and hauled away from the safety of the school, and deep, deep into the forest.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Lily Potter arrived at Hagrid’s hut just in time to find the game keeper loading his massive crossbow. Severus, and Minerva had somehow got there ahead of her.

“Tha’ ain’t good,” Hagrid said as another massive explosion rocked the forest. “Not good at all.”

“What is it?” Lily asked.

“We do not yet know,” Severus said, smoothly.

“We need the headmaster!” Minerva almost shouted, “Where is he?!”

In the end, Filius, Filtch, Sprout, and Septima all arrived before Lockhart, looking like he’d just stepped out of a magazine shooting for Witch Weekly. “Hello, all!” he called out cheerfully. “What’s all this hullabaloo?”

“Headmaster!” Minerva said, “We need a student headcount!”

“Ah,” Lockhart scratched his nose. “Is that really necessary? I mean, surely this will resolve—”

“Headmaster!”

“Oh, alright, alright—one moment.” Lily then watched, almost in pain, as Lockhart, someone who she used to idolise, but who had since clearly demonstrated his skills lay more in the literary than the practical, slowly and clumsily reached into the wards and counted the students’ presences, the way a toddler might arrange coloured blocks.

“Everyone’s in the castle,” he eventually declared, “except for Mister Malfoy, Miss Parkinson, Miss Black, and Miss Lovegood. “They’re still somewhere on the grounds, but it’s rather complicated to tell exactly how far away they are, or—”

Lily looked towards the forest and cursed.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

The ride through the forest was one the most uncomfortable things Pansy had ever been through, and by far the scariest. Eventually, they were unceremoniously dumped in the middle of a clearing, so full of spider webs it resembled snow.

Clinking and clacking filled the air. “Aragog! Aragog!”

“Stall!” Black mouthed in silence. “I’ve got a plan!”

Pansy and Draco both nodded and as one, the three students locked down their occlumency and stood up, blank-faced and dignified. Behind the facade though, Pansy still felt the almost overpowering urge to throw up, cry, and wet herself, possibly all at once.

An absolutely massive acromantula emerged from the trees, as large as a small dragon, milky eyed and hairy legged.

“These are the monsters?” it said.

“Yes!” came a skittery cry.

“Kill them.”

“Wait!” Pansy shouted. “We’re not monsters!”

“They tell me you carry the mark of the great terror,” the huge spider said. “Your clothes bear its mark.”

“Slytherin?”

Angry clicking noises filled the clearing.

“Do not speak the name!” Aragog spat, and a spider really knows how to spit. “Keepers of the great terror! The house that banished me!”

“That wasn’t Slytherin,” Black said carefully, as though this conversation wasn’t her main focus. “That was Tom Riddle.”

“He was of the Slytherin family. You are of the Slytherin family. Therefore, you are of Riddle’s family.”

Pansy felt a slight pull on her mind.

“Slytherin is a school house, not a family!” Draco shouted. “And we don’t even know what this great terror is! How can we be keeping it?”

“We do not speak of it!” Aragog started to turn away. “You are meat—fit only to nourish my brood.”

“Wait! My father leads the Dark!”

“My father is head auror!”

“My father is very influential in the construction and packing industries!”

Draco and Black both looked at Pansy.

Pansy grimaced. “Well, he is!”

Aragog made a definite clicking sound. “It matters not. Fresh meat is fresh meat. Goodbye, keepers of the terror.”

An explosion, much closer this time, rocked the clearing, sending spiders flying, and something burst out of the trees. Acromantula inferi. Pansy shrieked as Draco grabbed her arm and hauled her onto its back, helped by Black’s magic chains. The spiders gathered themselves quickly, but not quickly enough to stop their flight from the clearing, all eight inferi legs skittering along the forest floor at top speed.

A wave of spiders gave chase. Draco and Pansy did the best they could with their wands but only Black was having any real effect. The wave of angry, skittering legs closed in. One set made a leap for Pansy. She screamed, but before the spider landed, an arrow slammed into it, piecing it right through the thorax. It slid off the side of their ride and was gone from sight before it hit the ground.

A horn sounded.

More shadows moved among the trees—different shadows—four-legged, cantering shadows.

And the sky was filled with arrows.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Lily Potter pushed her way through the bushes and stared at the trail of dead acromantula, ranging in size from cat sized to goat. A piebald centaur stood next to them, holding its bow in its hands. “Greetings school teacher,” it said. “I am glad you have come.”

Severus stepped out behind her. “They don’t look blown apart.” He looked up at the centaur. “Why are you glad we have come?”

“The treaty has not been broken for forty years. Yet tonight it was broken. Such is the way of fate.”

“What did they do,” Lily asked gesturing to the dead spiders.

“Three students from the school were eating by the lake. They were grabbed and taken away. We saw it all.”

“—And you didn’t help?!” Severus glared. “Where are they?”

“Heading north-east at speed. Much of the herd is in pursuit. They’ll pass the wards soon.”

“I thought you weren’t helping,” Lily asked.

“A common human thought.”

Severus whirled around, cloak billowing. “We’ll head to the front gate and apparate around the edge.”

Lily nodded and the two hurried off, leaving a silently watching centaur, standing in a sea of dead spiders.

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Alex was exhausted. The effort of directing such a powerful inferi, combined with the constant use of her magic chains had long since drained her. She was starting to feel the effects of magical exhaustion.

Pansy and Draco were still holding on for dear life, occasionally adding a hex of their own, but most of their contribution came in the form of screams and yells on the line of “Look out!” and “Tree!” and the ever popular, “AAAIIIIIII!”

There hadn’t been any time to navigate. Simply getting away was the priority. Alex smacked away a dog sized acromantula and fell back onto their ride’s back. “Don’t you have anything stronger, Malfoy?” She shouted.

“My father didn’t let me learn anything stronger!”

“Wonderful! ARGH!”

Dark shadows had given way to sunset oranges. Their inferi acromantula had burst out of the forest and skidded to a halt to stop itself plunging into water, jerking the three Slytherins off it’s back and onto a shoreline. Pansy fell first, slamming onto the ground and crying out in pain. Then, Alex and Draco joined her, coming to within an inch of braining themselves on a massive ward-stone that marked the forest’s borders. Water lay in front of them. Forest lay behind them. They were trapped.

A rush of many legs shot out of the forest, and made an immediate grab for Pansy. Massive front legs wrapped around her waist and yanked her off the ground.

“Draco!” Pansy screamed.

Draco staggered. “Black! Do Something!”

“Tired,” Alex muttered. “No magic.”

“Draco! Help!” Pansy was almost back at the forest’s edge now, even while two more spiders closed in on Malfoy and Alex.

“Pansy!” Malfoy screamed, raised his wand at the nearest spider and put his hand on the ward-stone to steady himself.

Alexandra saw what was going to happen almost before it did, and had just enough time to shout, “Don’t!” before Malfoy bellowed, “Serpensortia!”

It was like watching a magical lightning strike. Power so dense it was practically visible thrummed down Malfoy’s arm from the stone, pulsed straight through his body, and into his wand, which exploded.

A massive snake, as large as a boa constrictor, burst from nowhere and landed in-between him, the spiders, and Pansy. It was black, tall, and crested—one might go so far as to say, ‘crowned.’

Alex reacted first. “Shut your eyes! Pansy! Draco!” She slammed her own eyes shut and proceeded to listen as a dozen spider voices screamed in terror, and, in many cases, death. She had no idea if the others had listened to her, or what else was going on, all she knew was that if she opened her eyes, she was sure to die.

The fight didn’t last long. The sounds of slaughter soon died down, replaced by the gentle lapping of ocean waves, and a far scarier noise—a slithery noise. Alex trembled, functionally blind and helpless, convinced that at any moment she was going to feel fangs puncture skin, and that would be the end of her.

“Obscuro!” Bellowed two voices—one male, one female—voices she knew. “Bombarda! Reducio! Expluso! Sectumsempra! ”

She kept her eyes shut tightly.

Something screamed in pain.

And then silence.

“You can all open your eyes now,” said the woman.

Alex did so.

The young basilisk was dead on the ground. Their inferi acromantula was in several extremely mushy bits . Many other dead acromantula lay along the shoreline, scattered among the rocks or up against the cliff face to their side, but they didn’t look like they’d been cursed, rather they had simply died.

“Explain yourselves,” Snape said.

“Severus!” Lady Potter shot him a disapproving look. “They need rest.”

Draco groaned on the ground. Pansy was shaking, but still alive.

“They can rest, after they tell us anything we might need to know.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Explaining turned out to be quite easy. The two professors already believed they’d been simply chatting and eating by the lake when they’d been taken by the spiders, so it was no large matter to re-tell what had happened after that, carefully leaving out the part with the inferi acromantula. The way they spun their tale, one acromantula from the nest had simply decided to go rogue.

Lily gave the remains of their evening project a sad look. “We didn’t know.”

Snape jerked his head. “Mister Malfoy is in mild need of healer attention and Miss Parkinson is visibly distressed. We will take you back to the castle and return for you, Miss Black.” Her head of house glared at her. “Do not move from here.”

Lady Potter took Pansy gently by the arm and Professor Snape took Malfoy, and together the two disappeared with a loud crack.

Alex didn’t try to get up, instead simply allowing the waves to crash behind her and her body to slowly embed itself in the silt. To think they’d run all the way from Hogwarts to the coast. That had to be, what? Twenty miles? Fifty? A long way anyway.

She looked around. The ward-stone marking the boundary of the forbidden forest was set against a natural cliff face that rose up from the shore. Even from here she could feel the thrum of it’s magic.

She crawled closer to inspect it. Runes covered the base, and the pillar—incredibly complex patterns that would take any professional days to decipher. Except … She looked closer. Deep within the rune patterns was another shape, one you might overlook if you didn’t know what to look for, but Alex did know what to look for. Harry had shown her what to look for, after all, all over Hogwarts—the tiny scratched sign of a snake.

“Alex!”

Alex jerked up. A centaur trotted out of the forest, carrying Luna on its back. She jumped down and embraced her. “I was so worried! Where are the others? Are they okay?”

“They’re fine,” she replied quickly. “But there’s more important things.” She told Luna about Snape and Lady Potter, and that they’d be back soon. She then decided to point out the snake on the wardstone.

“Do you think Potter already knows this one?”

Luna looked at it, then around the shoreline, at the dozen or so dead acromantula, then back at the ward-stone. She laughed. “That was Draco’s work was it?” she pointed at the dead spiders.

“Yeah, kinda. He did the summon that killed them.”

“How did he summon it? Was it a whisper?”

“No it was definitely loud.”

“A shout?”

“More like a bellow. They had Pansy and we were about to die.”

“Mmmm.” Luna put a thoughtful finger to her lips. “Where the wind meets the land find the sign of the dragon’s roar, there awaits you in the silt, ancient magics, and gold, and more.”

—DP & SW: NRiCD—

Events passed swiftly after they all got back to the castle. Luna managed to persuade the teachers that she’d merely been visiting the thestral herd. Draco found his way to the hospital wing, and Alex joined him soon after it was discovered she was suffering from acute magical exhaustion.

Hagrid could be heard crying himself to sleep as the sun set. Aragog had been one of the casualties of the fight with the centaurs. Lady Greengrass, standing in for Harry, had been summoned to an emergency meeting of the Wizengamot early next morning, which passed a new act right there in the chamber forbidding Draco Malfoy from practicing ‘his’ new version of the Serpensortia, regardless of how impossible it was for him to recreate the circumstances that led to its use.

The ministry sent agents from the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures into the forest, who emerged several hours later with an agreement to oversee a new set of negotiations between the acromantula and the centaurs, with special provisions for the breaking of the old treaty by the acromantulas. The monster spiders, apparently, were not at all happy.

When Harry and Daphne finally arrived back at the castle it was to find the girls with many updates to give on the situation with John, and Virgo, and Draco, and everything. It was Luna and Alex’s report, however, that most interested Harry.

$Open$

A stone creaked, opening a path in a cliff-face that, by all rights, could not exist. Harry held his wand up high, the better to illuminate the dark passageway beyond.

He stepped down into the corridor, dusty and dank, senses alert for hidden traps or curses. There weren’t any. The passage way soon opened up into a small room. He held up his wand and the light glittered off of something sitting on a table in the middle of the room.

Cautiously, Harry edged forward to inspect the object. No, he thought, that couldn’t be right. But it was. He knew it was from Voldemort’s many memories. The object was a Mesoamerican relic of some kind, solid gold, highly ornamental, wonderful craftsmanship, and clearly very, very old—far older than colonisation of the new world. But here it was in Scotland—in a secret parseltongue only cave that hadn’t been disturbed for centuries. What was it doing here? How much was it worth? If it was of muggle origin rather than magical …

Harry licked his lips.

Muggle gold artefacts tended to be very, very valuable.

He held up his wand again and looked around the room proper.

Books. More books. Just like the Icelandic cave. He picked one at random and read the title. Or he tried to read the title.

“Sea—Important person—Diary,” he said, out loud and rather slowly. He flipped it open. Mesoamerican pictograms filled the pages. A dead language. Useless. He flipped some more. Suddenly, the writing changed from pictograms to Old Norse, but it wasn’t any kind of old norse that Harry had seen. It was all scrambled up and made absolutely no sense. “Code,” Harry said, put it aside, and proceeded to flip through more of the books.

As he did, his excitement and anticipation grew. The vast majority of the books were written with the same pictograms as the first, and were clearly magical in origin, even if the gold statue on the table felt distinctly muggle. Any secrets they held might well be unique, but only if he could read them.

He flipped through all the books, looking for anything that might help, but it wasn’t until he returned to the first book he’d picked up that he struck pay dirt. In his haste to check the other books, he hadn’t realised that the book was actually divided into three parts, and that the third part was written in Latin—a language that he certainly could read.

The very first paragraph read—This sea log is to be written in three parts so that both the war-leader and captain may read, as well as the people of the court of feathered serpent.

Harry closed his eyes in rapture. He now possessed a rosetta stone for an ancient American civilisation and a ton of unknown magic books to go with it. Forget a chest containing a handful of galleons and some random tomes. This was truly worthy of a gift from Fate.

And he had just the witch to crack it.

Way off on the other side of the forbidden forest, in the Hogwarts library, in a fortress of books surrounding her the way a pyromaniac might surround themselves with candles, Hermione Granger sneezed.

—End of Chapter Forty-Three—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: The chaps on discord set up a Dodging Prison and Stealing Witches TV Tropes page, which should be easily found through a little google foo. If you’ve never visited TV Tropes before, it is a wiki-style website that documents narrative tools (tropes) used in popular media, including fanfiction. A fair warning though—the site is highly addictive and can easily drain hours, days, or weeks of your life. You have been warned.

Sticky Note: If you want to keep abreast of the release schedule, as well as any changes and the occasional piece of bonus content, you can head over to [www * leadvone * com] and sign up for the Gray Mailing List.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Hermione’s Quest—Part 1

Fate raised a warning finger at Harry. “Remember not to let house rivalries detract you from strategic necessity. There are Gryffindors it would do you well to bring to your side.

“… Granger.”

—Chapter One

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

[19th September 1992]

“Happy Birthday, Hermione!”

“Thank you.”

“Congratulations on your thirteenth, Vassal Granger.”

“Tim, that’s not really a title that you give her.”

“Sorry.”

The Great hall was packed. It was lunchtime and people had been approaching Hermione all day.

“So, er, Miss Granger, will you accept this as my declaration of intent?”

Hermione took the package from the older Ravenclaw boy and examined it critically. She opened the box and looked inside. It was full of Ferrero Rocher.

“That’s okay, isn’t it?” the boy asked nervously. “My grandmother is a muggleborn, and she said you might feel more comfortable with this sort of thing than something more traditional.”

Hermione smiled. “Yes, thank you very much, mister … ?”

“Oh! Fairbanks, Timothy Fairbanks.”

“Then yes, Mister Fairbanks, I accept your gift.”

Timothy bowed and hustled off.

Hermione turned back around in her seat and added Fairbanks’ gift to the pile. Intention gifts with extremely muggle origins had been a running theme so far.

On Hermione’s right, serving herself a portion of green peas and mashed potato, Daphne smiled. “That’s fourteen so far.”

Hermione’s smile faulted. “Yes.”

“That’s more than many girls get all day.”

“I know.”

“It makes sense though. Many families who wouldn’t bother going after the daughter of a noble house seem to be more comfortable encouraging their sons to go after you. Even if their muggle gifts are borderline insulting.”

“I’m okay with them.”

Daphne gave her friend a sideways glance. “And yet, you do not seem to be bursting with joy.”

Hermione hesitated.

Daphne smirked. “Maybe you are waiting for one gift in particular?”

Hermione said nothing. Instead, she stared at the tangerine bowl and remembered an exchange she’d overheard over a week ago.

Harry had been talking on the sofa in his trunk while she, Hermione, had been reading a book in a corner. She’d been mostly ignoring Harry’s conversation with his guest until he said something that reached straight through her occlumency shields and activated the part of her mind labelled, ‘utter dread.’

“Tracey, I can’t marry everyone.”

Tracey was sitting opposite Harry with her hands on her knees. She had her head down and was staring at the floor.

“There are lots of wizards out there,” Harry continued. “And what I have committed myself to, is already … pushing the bounds of social respectability.”

Tracey didn’t look up.

“Besides, Lord Davis made my involvement in your courting conditional on my not being one of the suitors. If we work together, we can easily stall him long enough for one of our classmates to grow up enough to actually make an impression on him.”

Tracey mumbled something under her breath.

“You know, I definitely miss the snarky Tracey. This meek version is just the type the old men like.”

Tracey finally raised her head and glared. “I said, ‘Fine!’ Potter.”

Her expression softened. “And thank you, my lord.”

Tucked away in her reading corner, Hermione’s heart had been beating at a mile a minute throughout the exchange. It took most of the rest of the day to calm down.

Daphne neatly loaded the back of her fork with mushy peas and mash, elegantly brought it to her mouth, chewed, and swallowed. She put her fork down. “Hermione, you aren’t seriously worried, are you? Harry all but said he was going to get you an intent gift last year.”

Hermione was worried. When she’d been younger, she and Harry had once both taken ageing potion and secretly attended a noble and pureblood party, and ‘Charlotte Timberland’ had experienced adult feelings for the first time. Now they were back with a vengeance—had been for some time, in fact—and the only thing worse than having her thoughts constantly filled with Harry were the thoughts suggesting this was all a big mistake and that he’d never intended them to be close in that way, or else that he’d changed his mind, maybe because she wasn’t good enough, hadn’t proved herself enough, that she, in fact, wasn’t Harry’s most trusted. After all, he was already ‘pushing the bounds of social respectability.’

Hermione took a deep, shuddery breath and used her occlumency to centre herself.

“Miss Granger?”

Hermione turned around.

“Happy thirteenth. Would you accept this as my family’s intent gift?”

She inspected the gift. It was an ostrich-egg-sized Terry’s Chocolate Orange.

Classes that day were pure torture. Harry didn’t act any different to how he usually did and Hermione just couldn’t focus on her work. It was a small mercy that they’d only had History of Magic that afternoon. By the time classes were finally out, she’d added another two muggle-inspired intent gifts to her pile and one actually magical one.

“Let’s display all the muggle chocolate on our table in the common room,” Tracey suggested with a grin. “It’ll drive Malfoy nuts.”

Hermione then spent a whole hour watching the common room door, at first with nervousness, but then, as the minutes dragged on, with a slowly sinking feeling.

“Miss Granger?”

It was all Hermione could do not to yelp. This time, when she turned, it was to find Harry standing on her other side.

“Y-yes, Mister Potter?”

“A word, if you please.”

Hermione cleared her throat. “Yes, of course.”

Harry turned and walked back to his dormitory.

Feeling like her body was made of lead, Hermione stood up on unsteady feet and pointedly ignored Daphne’s smirking face.

She soon found herself in Harry’s trunk, sitting opposite him on the sofa, with her hands on her knees.

“We’ve got a lot to talk about, Hermione,” Harry said. “Well, I hope we do. I’m not one for beating about the bush when there’s a massive elephant in the room, so here goes. Would you accept a declaration of intent gift from me?”

It was as if a dragon-sized weight had been lifted from Hermione’s shoulders. She’d read the expression ‘her heart soared’ many times in her life, mostly in the many romance novels she’d read as part of her initial training in wizarding culture, but she’d never properly appreciated just what the phrase meant—until now. “Yes, Harry,” she said. “I would like that a lot.”

Harry smiled. “Then it will be so. We’ve both come a long way since we first met.”

“Yes. You were the best maths tutor I ever had.”

“I was the only maths tutor you ever had.”

Hermione giggled. “So, what’s the lots we have to talk about?” Now that her mind had broken through the barrier it had been slamming against all day, if not all year, it was free to speed ahead off into the distance. “Is it about courting? Or priority? Since Daphne is Lady Slytherin and Luna is a consort, what would I be? A consort too? A Potter? I can’t also be a Slytherin, I know that—talking to snakes and flying would be wonderful though—maybe then I’d be better on a broom. Oh! How are we going to talk to Mum and Dad about this? Or your parents? Would Lord Potter need to sign a contract if I was going to be a Potter? But you’re a lord, too. Or doesn’t it work like that? Maybe—”

“—Hermione.”

Hermione stopped.

Harry was smiling at her.

She blushed. “Sorry.”

“That’s okay. Remember that we are still very young. And unlike other wizards our age, we have the added advantage that no one can sign a contract for you without my approval first—a rock-solid safety net—although I’m sure that Luna would point out that a rock-solid safety net is actually a pretty poor design choice.”

Hermione smiled.

“And to answer a few of your questions, Lord Potter would need to sign if you were going to be a Potter, but, assuming our courting goes well, I imagine you’d be a Granger.”

“So you would be my consort then.”

“Technically, yes. Consortships are most common among noble houses, but many houses have family magics that they don’t want released to the general populace—purebloods especially.”

“But why not a Potter? Unless … Oh, hang on.” Hermione bit her lip as her mind quickly made links that she’d just not been in a position to make before. “Slytherin Manor has twelve bedrooms apart from yours.”

“It does.”

“Twelve?!” Hermione squeaked. “That’s the ‘bounds of social respectability?’ ”

“Someone’s been eavesdropping on private conversations,” Harry said with a grin. “But no—not twelve—five actually.”

Hermione let out a relieved breath. Five she could handle. Twelve would have been ridiculous. Not that Harry couldn’t handle twelve girls—he obviously could—he was Harry—but she wasn’t. A thought struck her. “Wait a minute. If not Tracey, then who? Ginny?” Her thoughts went to their combat training, and to the raven-haired girl she’d been arguing with all year. “Oh, please not Black.”

“You don’t believe the Lady Black would be a worthwhile addition?”

Hermione huffed. “No, you are right, of course, but she can be really immature.”

“This from the girl who wrote her evil headmaster a letter in neon-pink ink with dancing unicorns and smiley faces.”

Hermione blushed.

“But enough about that,” Harry said with a smirk. “I think it’s time I fulfilled my promise and gave you your gifts—both of them.”

“Oooo, yes.”

Harry’s birthday gift turned out to be a rather nice leather bound book on advanced healing techniques. She carefully placed it on the bookshelf in her trunk after profusely thanking Harry and was about to climb out when Harry stopped her. Apparently her other gift, the declaration of intent gift, the important gift, would require the pensive. Hermione bit her lip. What could it be? Some amazing piece of arcane magic? A hidden secret stolen from the Dark Lord’s head?

Harry stood by the runed bowl holding several glass vials in his right hand, filled with silvery memories. His left hand held an envelope. “I was thinking about getting you another small library like I did when we first met,” he said, fingers absentmindedly flicking the envelope round and round. “But then I thought, no, I wanted to give you something that actually meant something, to me. But then I thought, well, I don’t really have much that means a lot to me—not really. I had to really dig deep to find something worthwhile.” He stopped flicking the envelope. “I’m dredging up painful memories here. But well, we’re friends, aren’t we?”

“Harry, you are my best friend,” Hermione said with zero hesitation.

Harry smiled softly. “Then, will you accept this as my declaration of intent gift?” He handed her the envelope.

Hermione deftly opened it with her wand and was surprised to find that the only thing the envelope contained was a simple chocolate frog card.

MERLIN

Famously the greatest wizard who ever lived. Merlin is reputed to have been born in the early 400’s, although no one knows for sure. Among the greatest of his achievements was the construction of the Albion Family Magics, the building of the Libra Arcanum, which later became the Hall of Prophecies, and the defeat of Dark Lady Morgana. Despite his many crowning glories, his intimate relationship with the Dark Lady remains his most well known and most controversial.

“Harry? Yes, I accept it—happily—but I don’t understand it.”

Harry took one of the glass vials, uncorked it, poured it into the pensieve, and gestured her forward.

Hermione stepped forward, took a deep breath, dipped her finger in Harry’s memory, and was sucked in and forward, down, down, down.

Hermione landed.

A whistle blew. A floor jerked under her. Wizards and Witches waved from behind a window to her left, and the Hogwarts Express slowly started chugging out of Platform Nine and Three Quarters.

Hermione got her balance and tucked a stray hair behind her ear.

Okay, she thought, this probably wasn’t the Dark Lord’s memory—that must make it one of Harry’s. Was this from their timeline, or … her heart skipped a beat … was it from the last one?

The door to her right was half open. That would be as good a place as any to start. She stepped through the door and her breath caught.

A small boy sat alone on the seat. Obviously Harry, but that wasn’t what stole her breath. Everything about her friend suggested he was nervous, poor, and uncared for. His hair was dirty. His clothes were both muggle and threadbare. The trunk by his feet looked like a good kick would put a hole right through it. Hermione had by now spent years learning how to read people and this Harry looked like he was expecting the world to spit on him and then charge him for the privilege—The way he sat all hunched up on his seat, reading a potion-stained second-hand book—the way his eyes flickered around as though waiting for a wonderful dream to end.

Then, something happened to the memory, like the passing of time far faster than normal. The door opened and closed several times and a half dozen young witches and wizards streamed in and out, some taking longer to talk to Harry, some just poking their head in before leaving.

The memory slowed down again.

The door behind her creaked open and a bossy voice said, “Is there any room here, I say, is that a book you’re reading?”

Hermione winced. She recognised that voice. How could she not? She turned. This at least, wasn’t a surprise. She’d seen the other Hermione before when Harry showed her what her manners in the last timeline had been like—or rather, what they hadn’t been like.

Last timeline Hermione still had her huge buck teeth and her hair was so bushy one might expect to find baby birds nesting in it, but by far the greatest difference was her expression. It was an expression which screamed, “I am superior to you all, because I know all the things,” at a hundred-thousand merlins.

Harry nervously held the book up as though for inspection.

“Oh, yes, I’ve read that one,” Hermione said, rather dismissively. This however, didn’t stop her from sitting on the seat opposite the young boy. “Have you also read our potions book?”

Harry nodded.

“I’m really looking forward to lessons,” Hermione continued, “I’ve heard transfiguration is supposed to be the hardest, so naturally that’s what I’ve been reading the most.”

The rather one-sided conversation continued for five minutes before the subject of Harry’s brother was raised.

“I’ve read all about him of course, I’m surprised you’re not sitting with him.”

And it was only a little later that the trolly arrived and Last-timeline Hermione, looking rather guilty, bought an arm-full of different wizarding sweets of all types. This included several chocolate frogs, which This-timeline Hermione proceeded to watch the way a carnival-goer might watch the one cup out of three that the small, white ball had just been placed under. And just like the carnival-goer, Hermione’s mind was racing ahead, trying to solve the puzzle before the solution was presented. It wasn’t exactly hard.

She held the Merlin card tightly in her hand while Harry unwrapped his chocolate frog to find a Merlin card of his own.

She shook her head as Last-timeline Hermione complained that having to buy chocolate to learn about wizarding history was stupid.

And she nodded as Harry, the younger version of her Harry, gave the card to her other self, before asking timidly if they were friends.

Last-timeline Hermione hesitated before leaving the compartment. Someone was missing a toad, apparently, and she’d volunteered to help look. The look on her face betrayed her nervousness over Harry’s question. “Of course, we’re friends,” she eventually said in a matter-of-fact way. And despite the terseness in her words, This-timeline Hermione could easily hear both the promise and the hope in her other self’s words.

The door slid shut.

And Hermione was raised up—up and out—exiting the pensieve with a single, well-practiced, elegant step. Out of the memory, and back into the real world.

Harry was watching her.

“I had no idea,” she whispered. “I thought I just ignored you. I had no idea we were actually friends.”

Harry suddenly looked extremely awkward.

“What?”

Harry looked at the other vials in his hand.

“There’s more?” Hermione asked.

“I wasn’t actually sure if I was going to show you these. I’m still not sure if I should. It feels a bit much.”

“Is it about me? If it’s about me, then I want to know.”

Harry regarded her intently. For a moment she was scared he was going to say no. Eventually though, he slowly nodded, and gestured her towards the pensieve.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“What do you think?” one older Slytherin asked his friend.

“I think it’s disgusting.”

The two boys were glaring at the court of the Gray, with its massive pile of muggle sweets and chocolates on the low table, taunting them with its heretical untouchability. They were Gray themselves, but the Gray’s ambiguous political stance meant that there were, in fact, many dark leaning purebloods among their ranks—many who regarded the shameless display of such muggle artefacts as ‘not the way we do things.’

They were shocked out of their idle grumbling when the girl to whom the presents had been gifted burst out from the stairs to the dormitories, marched across the common room with barely concealed tears in her eyes, angrily slashed her wand at the pile and cried, “Incendio Tria!”

A powerful blue fireball billowed out of her wand and engulfed the table, quickly incinerating everything it held.

The common room watched with wide eyes.

They couldn’t know that the girl had just watched her other self quickly turn away from her best friend as a result of peer pressure from her Gryffindor classmates.

They couldn’t know that simple ignoring, soon turned into nasty jabs and insults, growing slowly worse over time, and that two years after that she’d torn up the chocolate frog card he’d once given her, right in front of his face, while calling him a murderer.

All they saw was the thirteen-year-old girl torching a pile of muggle gifts in anger and fury with tears still pouring down her cheeks.

‘Pureblood in all but blood’ was the phrase some of them used later on.

They certainly didn’t see Hermione rushing back to Harry’s trunk and proceeding to have an emotional breakdown on her best and oldest friend’s shoulder, crying and sobbing, while swearing that she would never ever do that to him, ever, ever, ever.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

[The present]

After the incident in the forest with the acromantula, the only thing the school wanted to talk about for a whole week was Draco Malfoy and his supposed basilisk summoning ability. It didn’t matter that casting the spell had damn near killed him. It didn’t matter that the only reason he’d been able to cast it in the first place was because he’d unwittingly turned himself into the magical equivalent of a lightning rod, channelling raw power through his body, straight from the Hogwarts wards themselves. It didn’t even matter that doing so had destroyed his wand, an event of near traumatic levels for most wizards, forcing Draco to drop classes until Lord and Lady Malfoy turned up to get him a new one.

No, none of it mattered. Whispers followed the young heir everywhere. People who usually nodded to him with slight disdain, now nodded politely. Those who used to nod politely, now did so with a touch of fear.

One might suspect this would result in an increased willingness on the boy’s part to bully and harass his classmates with all sorts of strange spells and hexes, but oddly, it hadn’t happened, something that Hogwarts’ resident healer, Madam Pomfrey, in particular was grateful for.

She was less grateful for this.

“A leave of absence?” Madam Pomfrey looked up from the letter she’d been handed, the better to stare at her most promising student. The letter was signed, both with her parent’s signatures, and that of Lord Slytherin.

“It shouldn’t be for long,” Hermione said. “My family has some business I need to take care of, which will take up a lot of my time. You did say I was well ahead of my studies.”

Madam Pomfrey grunted disapproval. In truth, the young Slytherin wasn’t just ahead on her healing training, she was miles ahead. If she’d continued as she had been, she could have conceivably finished healer training before she left Hogwarts—an unheard of achievement. Unlikely now, apparently.

“Very well, Miss Granger,” she said, reluctantly. “I do hope this won’t be for too long though.”

“No, Madam Pomfrey.”

“And I expect you to keep your skills and knowledge at their current level of sharpness. If you come back here having backtracked I will be most unhappy.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The gathering was the usual Wizarding crowd from the upper echelons of the nobility. Tracey recognised some of them, and those that she didn’t she was sure she’d know by name—their last names, at least. There were a few young men, but they mostly kept their attention on the young women. That is to say, they kept it on the women who were older than she was, but still young enough to be called so.

“I don’t think I really like the look of anyone here,” Tracey whispered to her escort.

Harry, disguised as Lord Slytherin, shrugged. “Don’t worry about it. We’re just going through the motions. I wouldn’t expect you to suddenly declare your undying love to someone twenty years your senior over a plate of club sandwiches.”

This particular gathering wasn’t in the ballroom of some great manor, as was often the case, but instead in the Lovegood’s garden. Small tables had been set up and all manner of finger food provided for the guests. Some of the lords had parked themselves at the barbecue, where Lord Lovegood was happily burning sausages, while a similar gathering of ladies, led by Lady Lovegood, had taken up residence in the orchard gazebo. The rest of the guests had scattered themselves around the garden, standing and chatting, while a wizarding troupe played orchestral versions of popular Weird Sister’s songs.

“I’m surprised you managed to ‘get out’,” Tracey said, putting the emphasis on the getting out part. “Considering what happened last time.”

“I think you all handled what happened the other week admirably,” Slytherin said. “And now they have experience, I’m sure the others will be able to handle—” his voice dipped lower “—My mother, even better if she comes looking for me again.”

Tracey smirked. The image of Lady Potter in green and silver robes, wearing a mask, and introducing herself as ‘Mummy Slytherin,’ was just too amusing.

“Look there,” Harry said. “By the conservatory door.”

Tracey looked. An older man of average height with a slightly portly build was chatting amiably with a lady who looked like someone had pushed dead rat under her nose. “Is that Lord Thynn?” She asked.

Harry nodded.

“Are you going to introduce me to him?”

Harry snorted. “No, I think not.”

“Why not? He looks amiable enough to not care if I turn him down. Is it because he’s Light?”

“Not at all. You remember before when I was talking about the ‘bounds of social respectability’?”

Tracey’s eyes widened slightly. “But he isn’t even married?”

“No, he isn’t. He does, however, have a—how can I put this lightly?—he has a harem.”

Tracey looked at Harry with narrowed eyes. “You have a harem.”

“Oh, no, no, no,” Harry tutted. “I’m not talking about merely being contracted to more than one witch, no, I mean a real harem. As in, he has a large group of unmarried women who live with him in his manor and are reliant on him for their well being—over twenty of them.”

“How does that work?”

“From what I understand, they’re mostly muggles.”

Tracey’s eyes widened again. “I thought he was Light.”

“He is. He loves muggles. Literally.”

“Wooooow.”

“Don’t mention anything though. It’s a slightly less than open secret.”

Tracey nodded at about the same time as Harry gave her arm a firm squeeze. “Look sharp, Tracey. We have company.”

“—Lord Slytherin,” a voice said.

Tracey turned to see an older man she didn’t recognise with short white hair, charcoal grey robes, and a comfortable smile approaching them.

“Tracey, this is Mister Bentley. Mister Bentley, this is Heiress Tracey Davis.”

“A very pretty young lady,” the older man said.

“Thank you, Sir,” Tracey said as she came back up from her automatic curtsey.

Lord Slytherin nodded to the man. “Mister Bentley is our Humble Hag. He runs the ministry while Minister Fudge is out shaking hands and kissing babies.”

“He runs …” Tracey noticed the corners of Mister Bentley’s lips tug upwards at Harry’s comment. “I’m so sorry, I should have recognised you.”

Mister Bentley shook his head. “A civil servant isn’t supposed to be famous.” He looked to Lord Slytherin. “And that was hardly fair, my lord. Minister Fudge does a sterling job. I’m sure you’d have come to the same conclusion if you’d stuck around at the quidditch match to listen to several hours of his unrivalled charisma.”

“I do apologise. I was afraid that Daphne wouldn’t have been able to handle the overwhelming excitement.”

“I believe the minister wanted to talk about noble funding.”

“I suspect he’s not the only one.”

Tracey was watching the exchange in fascination.

“I?” Mister Bentley asked. “I am but the humble hag. It is not my business to involve myself in the matters of department heads.”

“Department heads of the wardrobe?”

“Yes.”

“Humble hag of the wardrobe?”

Mister Bentley looked around innocently before looking back. “If we lived in a world in which the humble hag of the wardrobe did have a say in how the departments that he oversees got the majority of their funding, then if an individual turned up out of the blue who looked to be rich enough to fund the entirety of a minor department or quango all by himself, I suppose that humble hag might be interested to hear what interests this individual has that might affect his eventual decision.”

Harry was silent for a few moments before he finally said, “I like bird watching.”

Mister Bentley smiled. “I’m glad we had this discussion, Lord Slytherin. And you too, Heiress Davis. If you’ll both excuse me?” He bowed and left.

“I like bird watching?” Tracey asked, incredulously. “Was that code for something?”

“Not really.”

“Is Mister Bentley married?”

“No. His wife died fifteen years ago.”

Tracey smirked. “Then you should be thankful you’re not a witch with an open contract, because I think he enjoyed that.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was morning in the great hall. Halloween had come and gone with barely a hiccup, minus Headmaster Lockhart standing up and declaring that that night would be ‘trick or treat,’ and since there were only four doors in the castle that students dared trick or treat at, a small inter-house war inevitably broke out when certain students decided they’d much rather just eat the treats they’d been given and not hand them out at their common room entrances.

There certainly weren’t any petrified cats, threatening messages on walls, or puddles of water on floors—something that frustrated John Potter no end. The timeline was diverting horribly—had diverted horribly already, in fact, and there was nothing he seemed to be able to do to stop it. He was flying blind now, and would have to make the best of a bad situation.

“You look like you woke up on the wrong side of the bed,” Virgo commented from his left side—a very pretty girl—one of those major diversions.

On his right side, Lavender snorted. “He’s under too much stress. Aren’t you, John? Quidditch, Duelling, Homework, and looking after you!” she said this last part to Virgo with a little more heat than John thought was necessary.

Virgo looked ready to retort back, but John cut over them both. “Girls,” he said, “it’s fine. There’s nothing wrong and I am not under too much stress. And Virgo needs looking after. I can’t tell you why, but she does.”

Virgo nodded at him and went back to work on her breakfast while Lavender pouted.

Just then, the post arrived, dozens of owls streaming down into the great hall to drop off their many packages and letters. John collected the many letters to the-boy-who-lived and stacked them in a neat pile beside him. Virgo took the first letter off the pile, slit it open with her wand, and read. “Another donation,” she eventually muttered. “House Potter is doing quite well out of you, aren’t they?”

John gave her a nonchalant shrug.

Surprised noises around the hall made him look up again. The post owls were not nearly finished with their deliveries, but all the rest of them were focused on one table, and one girl, in particular. Hermione looked ecstatic. Like a child with a new toy. Or rather, like Hermione with a new book, a proud beacon of joyful energy, which is exactly what this was—only more so. Dozens of owls kept arriving, one after the other, all of them carrying very obviously book shaped packages. Some of the books weren’t even wrapped up and looked extremely muggle. He spied one of the titles and leaned closer to Virgo. “What does ‘cypher’ mean?”

“To write in code,” Virgo said, simply, in the middle of reading another of his letters.

“What would a Slyth—” John stopped himself. He still couldn’t bring himself to think of Hermione as a Slytherin, and seeing her so obviously proud to be sitting across the hall still made him furious if he thought about it for too long. “What would a witch need a muggle book on that for?”

“Presumably because she has a message that she wishes to send without it being read and doesn’t trust magic to do the job for some reason, or she has a coded message she wants to read—not unusual for Slytherins.” Virgo looked up. “That’s what my father said, anyway.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The basic gnome, as many know, is a magical creature shaped vaguely like a potato—semi-sentient and highly destructive to magical gardens up and down the country. Muggles didn’t see them, like many magical creatures, not because they couldn’t, but because their minds simply slid over them the same way they did outside the Leaky Cauldron or when faced with the Knight Bus.

Not being noticed when you are at the bottom of the food chain is a useful ability to have. It’s just a shame that the power of a notice-me-not is relative to the power of the observer doing the noticing.

Somewhere deep in a pristine flower-bed, a gnome, unfortunate enough to decide to explore this particular garden, let out a terrified squeak and bolted for the ward line. It got all of twenty paces before a bright red light hit it square on the back and sent it tumbling into a dry-stone wall.

A man bent down, picked up the creature, and dangled it by a foot.

“Good shot, Mister Bentley.” An old witch hobbled up to the on the other side of the dry stone wall and gestured at the gnome with her cane. “That little blighter’s been giving me the run around for days.”

Mister Bentley gave her a polite smile. He and Mrs. Bun had been neighbours for nearly thirty years now. “Surely not,” he said. “I can’t imagine anything that could slip past your exacting gaze.”

“Eyes, not as good as they once were.”

“And yet, your garden is looking as perfect as ever.”

“Oh, you charmer.”

An owl holding a letter chose that exact moment to alight on the wall between them.

Mister Bentley let out a theatrical sigh. “Duty calls, it seems.” He read the letter as Mrs. Bun hobbled off. It was a request for a private meeting from one of his better placed little helpers. He produced an eagle feather quill from the recesses of his robes, penned a quick reply, tied the note onto the owl’s leg, and, as an afterthought, tossed the still stunned gnome to the bird of prey, which snatched it in its talons and leapt into the air.

Mister Bentley then turned his attention back to his garden. The leaves needed to be gathered, the flowerbeds weeded, the bow-truckles fed, and the lawn trimmed. Not that anyone taking a casual glance would say that it was anything other than immaculate, but that was the point, wasn’t it? Work you can take pride in required constant effort over many, many years. He produced his wand, and quietly got to work.

He was pruning his dwarf whomping willow when the wards alerted him that his little helper had arrived.

Calmly, but efficiently, he summoned tea from the house, along with various papers and boxes, sat down at the little patio table, and considered how best to steer his masters the way they needed to go.

Lord Slytherin would be an important key, of that he was sure. He hadn’t been entirely sure about the man when they’d first met at the quidditch match, but his subsequent chat had alleviated some of his concerns. Bird watching, indeed. That probably meant the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures. Nothing too worrying. The man was like him—a gentleman—dignified, poised, and cultured. It such a shame their political alignments currently put them at odds. He’d have made an amazing under-secretary.

And speaking of under-secretaries …

“Ah, Dolores, please have a seat.”

Dolores Umbridge, wearing salmon pink robes, sat down opposite him, looking nervous. “Mister Bentley.”

He served them both tea and then immediately got down to business. “I understand Lord Malfoy summoned you to Malfoy Manor last week. What was that about?”

“He was telling me about my new responsibilities. He said that the Minister is nominated by, and serves the Wizengamot, and as such, my loyalty must first be to them—no matter what my loyalties might have been in the past.”

“And what did you say to this?”

“I agreed.”

“Well done.” Bentley took a sip of tea. “Did he say anything else?”

“He asked me to pass him any important wardrobe papers.”

Bentley thought about this for a moment, put his tea down, reached for the stack of files on the table, flipped through them, extracted several, and passed them over. “Here you go. He should find those ones rather amusing. Now, what of Mister Weasley’s muggle protection act? Any progress on getting it scrapped?”

Madam Umbridge fiddled with the hem of her robes. “Um, I’m not actually sure …”

Bentley paused with his teacup halfway back to his lips. “Not sure about what?”

“Well, how exactly do I do that? I don’t know anyone with dirt on Weasley. Not that they’re willing to give away, anyway. The man seems friends with everyone.”

Bentley sighed and put his cup down with a clink. “Okay, let’s go through this logically, shall we? Firstly, who is Arthur Weasley’s boss?”

“He doesn’t have one? The Misuse of Muggle Artefacts Office is a quango.”

“True, then let me ask another question, who appoints Mister Weasley?”

“Regent Bones—in her capacity as chief warlock on the magical court—but she’d never sack him.”

“Does Regent Bones have a boss?”

“Not on the court—it’s an appointment for life.”

“But as Head of the Department of Law Enforcement?”

“Minister Fudge.”

“And does Minister Fudge have the power to fire Madam Bones?”

“No, only the Wizengamot can appoint department heads.”

“—And the Light have had a stranglehold on the appointment of the Head of Department of Magical Law Enforcement for over forty years.” Bentley nodded. “So, that avenue is closed. Now tell me, what else does a quango need to do its job apart from leadership?”

“Laws.”

“Who makes these laws?”

“The Wizengamot. But I thought the whole point of this was to stop the Wizengamot.”

“Indeed it is, so that avenue is also closed. What else does a quango need?”

“Gold.”

“Where do they get that gold?”

“Patrons. And the Ministry Vault. “

“Yes. Now, the Ministry Vault is interesting, but as much as we would like it to be otherwise, only a lesser percentage of our funding actually comes from there. Let’s talk about patrons. Who is the primary benefactor of the Misuse of Muggle Artefacts Office?”

“I don’t know.”

“Well, luckily for you, I do know.” Bentley handed Dolores a single piece of parchment.

Dolores read it. “Lord Thynn?” Her nose wrinkled in disgust. “Blood traitor. But I still wouldn’t know where to begin putting pressure on him.”

“What you may not know is that Lord Thynn keeps a rather large collection of muggle women at his manor.”

“Muggles?” Dolores spat. “That’s disgusting. How is he allowed to do that? Doesn’t that violate the statue of secrecy?”

“He uses the muggle guide laws. Officially, they are all his ‘girlfriends.’ Of course, if they want to stop being his girlfriends, they are free to do so, but then they also get their memories wiped. I suspect a wizarding lord can provide many incentives to not want their knowledge of magic wiped.”

“So how to get him on our side?”

Bentley gave the pink-dressed witch an annoyed look. “I have provided you by far all the clues you need. If you can’t work out the rest, perhaps I am putting my faith in the wrong place.”

Dolores grimaced and went quiet. For a whole five minutes the two sat, Bentley quietly enjoying his small private paradise—green, fresh, and tranquil, far away from the bustle and noise of the city and the ministry.

Eventually, Dolores cleared her throat and started to voice a plan, tentatively at first, but as she continued to speak, with growing confidence and certainty. By the time she finished and looked to him for approval, she had a self-satisfied smirk on her face.

Bentley smiled. He knew she’d get there in the end.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the privacy of her trunk, Hermione ripped the paper off the last of the books she’d received from her parents and placed it next to the others in a line so that the edges matched up just so. She cast a critical gaze at the collection and then rearranged them to sit in alphabetical order. Then she arranged them again, but this time by subject. Finally, she arranged the books alphabetically within each subject.

There.

Hermione nodded.

Harry had entrusted her with an important task and she was not going to fail him. The thought was unthinkable—although, she had just thought it, so …

Hermione vigorously shook her head, causing her long mane of hair to whip around her face.

No. This was important. Harry needed her to live up to the expectations he had for her. To be ‘the greatest witch who ever lived.’ And the first thing she had to do was crack the code on these ancient Norse writings. It wasn’t enough to simply be able to read ancient Norse, no these writings had been encrypted.

Her first thought to ask her parents hadn’t helped. The tri-language book had a powerful muggle repelling charm built into magically activated invisible ink. Her second thought to check the Hogwarts library hadn’t helped either. Madam Pince hadn’t even known what ‘cypher’ meant—although the librarian’s generally unhelpful attitude never helped matters. So, her third thought—the one she was currently pursuing—had been to get her parents to raid the mathematics section of the local bookshop and send her every muggle book on encryption and codes they could.

Hermione then picked up the only new magical book she’d acquired—Complex Occlumency for the Arithmancy Mind—opened it to the first exercise, read, took a deep breath, closed her eyes, and tried to let the numbers start to dance across her mind.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In another trunk not far away, Harry peered over Alexandra Black’s shoulder while the first year girl poured over a rather useful book.

“We need two-dozen adult beech trees,” Harry said. “Bowtruckled—highly saturated in local magic—straight, if possible.”

“Two-dozen …” Alexandra flipped through the pages of the Dendromancer’s Doomsday Book. “Okay. What about this one?”

“Longbottom Manor? I doubt Regent Longbottom would be willing to sell. And no way are we crashing those wards for this.”

“Ah. Then how about this one?”

“Mmm … Tickledead Wood—not sure where that is.”

“My lord.” Daphne unfolded a large map on the desk.

“Ah, thank you.” Harry inspected the map. “Yes, that looks possible. Please add it to the list. Next?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the ministry of magic, the position of humble hag is given to they who sit directly below politicians in the chain of command. All of those politicians together make up the wardrobe, and the humble hag of the wardrobe sits directly below the minister himself. The job of the humble hags is to ‘arrange matters’ on behalf of their masters—a minister or department head, and see to it that the broomstick of government keeps flying, or occasionally, if needed, sweeping.

No one is one-hundred percent sure why they are called humble hags, but it is generally considered to be an attempt to ensure they don’t get too big for their boots.

“Mister Bentley?”

Arthur Weasley entered the office of the current humble hag of the wardrobe with not a small amount of trepidation. Even though the humble hag didn’t even hold nominal authority over his operation, that didn’t mean he wasn’t powerful and capable of making his life difficult.

“Ah, Arthur.” Mister Bentley smiled a warm smile. “Please come in. Take a seat. I just wanted us to have a little chat.”

“I know what you’re going to say,” Arthur began in a determined tone of voice, even as he sat in the armchair opposite Mister Bentley’s own. “And the answer is no. I’m not going to back down. Our laws have to adapt. Many of our people are related to muggles. They don’t like our current laws. And if we don’t change, we could be in serious trouble as muggles continue to develop new artefacts, which we are not equipped to deal with.”

“New artefacts?”

“All sorts of things. But I’m not going to be cowed. Not now I’ve finally got the Gray’s co-operation.”

Mister Bentley held up a hand. “Arthur—please—you have me all wrong. This is not a dressing down. I agree with you.”

Mister Weasley blinked. “You do?”

“Of course. In fact, it is exactly that drive to push fairness into our laws for which I wished your council.” Mister Bentley opened a file on the low table between them and pushed a small file across the table. “You see, there was a rather unfortunate case several months ago—a young London muggleborn wizard abusing the muggle guide laws—never made the papers—it was felt best to hush it up, but, well, you can see why it would be a good idea for it not to happen again.”

Arthur Weasley’s eyes widened as he read the document. “Four girlfriends?” he asked incredulously. “How did he arrange that? I thought there were limit recommendations—especially for muggleborns.”

“There are. I believe the young man had the bright idea of doing each of his guide interviews in a different enclave. The local offices aren’t obliged to check the central records, you know.”

Arthur Weasley continued to read. “Confundus charms, memory charms, love potions, low-level dark magic. Oh my, yes, I can see the problem.” He put down the parchment. “What happened to this wizard?”

“Currently doing community service after a two-week stay in Azkaban.”

“But why a new law? Couldn’t this be solved by better co-ordinating local and central government operations? Parchment protean charms, maybe?”

“In theory, yes, but the Minister is being awfully cautious at the moment. The last thing he wants is to be accused of setting up a divination government.”

“I see.”

Mister Bentley smiled warmly again. “So you understand why I need your help.”

“Certainly.” Arthur nodded to himself. This clearly needed to be sorted out. An extra paragraph or two shouldn’t be too hard to add into the proposed act, and he couldn’t imagine anyone would possibly object.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was the dead of night. The moon was crescent. The sky was cloudy.

Just outside a small forest, somewhere in the South-East, a man in a rented HGV, wearing jeans, a button-up shirt, and a green and black mask, drove up to a gate, and stopped his vehicle. The way he executed that stop, with many jerks and creaks, suggested someone altogether unfamiliar with the task. Eventually, he succeeded in putting it in park, hopped out, and opened the gate.

“Oi!”

The man turned around at the noise.

“What are you doin’ here this time of night?” Another man was shouting over the lorry’s rumble while walking up to the masked lorry driver. “This here is managed woodland.”

There was a movement, a blur of something in the air, and the second man’s eyes crossed. “Oh, right,” he muttered. “Surprise inspection. Of course.”

Minutes later, Lord Slytherin approached a single tree that looked not unlike the hundreds of others he’d just passed and ran a hand up the trunk. Perfect.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was late afternoon and the Wizengamot was in session. The subject at hand was the second reading of the Muggle Protection Act. Interest in law-making had picked up recently since the passing of the emergency ‘Draco Malfoy’ Act, but the room was still far from packed.

Up in visitor’s gallery, Dolores Umbridge watched the proceeding with the air of someone watching what used to be their favourite TV show, but which had since let them down again and again. So many lords, so many sullied lines. They had made so much progress, but now they were backsliding. Gone were the golden times after Light Lord Dimwiddy—a time when noble families wouldn’t even consider marrying half-bloods. Now it barely caused a raised eyebrow. And that didn’t take into account those outrageous lords who allowed their heirs to marry muggleborns, like Davis and Potter. Granted, Davis couldn’t have known his firstborn son would die before giving an heir, leaving his second son in line, but that wasn’t the point—and the new Lord Potter had no excuse.

What Magical Britain really needed, Dolores thought, was a law compelling Noble Houses to only marry blood that was pure. That would put them back on the right track.

Out in the chamber, the reading went on, and eventually, the critically important paragraph was read out.

There.

Dolores stood up, adjusted the bun of her hair, and left.

The journey between the Wizengamot chambers and the Ministry of Magic wasn’t a short one. Dolores had to journey through many long corridors and up several flights of stairs, before finally arriving at the lift that would take her back up to the minister’s offices. Eventually, she stepped out of the lift and made for the files behind her desk, ignoring all the various other under, assistant, and deputy secretaries who bustled around the place in their joint quest to make Wizarding Britain as complicated as possible.

She reached for one of the files, flipped through until she found what she wanted, and withdrew several parchments. She then made her way back towards the door. Someone tried to stop her as she left, but she told them she was on business for Mister Bentley, and that was that.

She made her way down to the public ministry floos, threw a pinch of floo powder from a bag on the mantlepiece, gritted her teeth at what she was about to do, stepped into the fire, and said, “Thynn Manor.”

Dolores swirled through the floo, considering the meeting she was about to have with the reprobate lord of the Light. At least he’d never gone so far as to sire an heir with one of his whores.

The rushing stopped and she stepped out into a waiting room, clearly sealed off from the rest of the large house.

“Can I’s be helping you?” A house elf had popped beside her.

Disgusting creatures. Dolores made a face. “Get me your master at once!”

“Who is you being?”

“Never you mind—your master is expecting me.”

The elf popped away.

She had to wait several minutes before the doors to the manor finally opened and when they did, it was not Lord Thynn who greeted her.

“Are you Madam Umbridge?” asked what was very obviously a muggle. No proper witch would be seen dead wearing shorts that short.

“I am,” Dolores replied. “Your master is expecting me. Take me to him at once.”

“Lord Thynn is not my master. But please, follow me.”

Dolores bristled at the muggle’s tone, but bit down her retort for the moment. She was then led through the large house, fighting down her urge to react with disgust at all the obviously muggle additions that had been made. Eventually she asked, “and how did you come to the lord’s attention?”

“That is a private matter between me and Lord Thynn.”

Dolores frowned. “Where are the others?”

“I assume you mean the other girls? They are in the women’s wing. This is the public part of the house.”

“At least he has the decency to keep you hidden.”

The muggle turned and smiled dryly at her. They had reached a large double door. “Lord Thynn will see you now.” She opened the door, and Dolores stepped through.

“Ah, Madam Umbridge. The minister’s new undersecretary, yes?” Lord Thynn was standing by one of the large windows. “To what do I owe this pleasure?”

“My lord. There have been developments in the Wizengamot that I was told you might appreciate being made aware of.”

“Oh, yes? And why are you telling me this? The minister having a holiday, is he?”

“No, my lord. The humble hag sent me.”

“Old Bentley, hmm? Very well, what is this development?”

Dolores handed Lord Thynn the parchment she’d been carrying. “One of the new acts includes rather stricter regulation for those who act as guides to muggles in our world.”

Lord Thynn’s eyes widened while reading the paper.

“You see why Mister Bentley thought this might concern you, my lord. With this act, your current ‘arrangements,’ discrete though they are, would become highly unlawful, which could in time become a problem for you.”

Lord Thynn grunted. “Okay, you’ve got my attention. Clearly you want my help to stop this. But I am only one vote. The Gray holds the swing power.”

“Oh, that’s not necessarily true. You see, this act is being pushed by one of your beneficiaries.”

Lord Thynn gave her a shocked look. “Who?”

Dolores cleared her throat. “Arthur Weasley.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was a weekend morning, and in the first year Gryffindor dormitory, the soul part of what would become the greatest dark wizard who ever lived was busy with important tasks.

So, what do we think? Virgo held up a set of dress robes to herself in the mirror.

I think it looks good, Julia thought back. It’s cute. John will like it.

A flash of annoyance shot through Virgo, but it was soon under control. Yes, John liking it was actually important, if not for the reasons Julia had in mind. As much progress as had been made since Halloween, there still hadn’t been a good opportunity to get him to give up his portkey. But at least there hadn’t been any more attacks.

Virgo idly held up a second set of dress robes. And these?

The lace is nice. I’m not sure about the hood though.

All dress robes come with hoods.

Yes, but this one would make us look like we’re delivering cakes to our granny.

I murdered my granny. I erased her from this world.

Well, she wasn’t a very nice person.

Virgo held up a third set of dress robes. What about these?

Oh, now that’s nice! And it goes with our shoes.

So, this one?

Yes. Definitely.

Virgo quickly got dressed. The dressing up would only be until afternoon, but it was important to always look your best. That had been an early lesson learned in Slytherin House the hard way. And on this matter, both Virgo and Julia were in total agreement. Later on, they’d have duelling practice with Susan, something that John still hadn’t joined in on, but he was apparently getting private lessons with Professor Flitwick—the privileged, powerful bastard that he was.

“Malfoy?” One of the other girls poked her head through the door. “John’s asking if you’re going to be much longer.”

Virgo smirked. “Tell him that waiting for a lady is something he’ll just have to get used to.”

The girl grudgingly nodded and disappeared.

Virgo and Julia then sat down and read for a respectable amount of time, just so no one would think they’d been ‘summoned’ by the boy who somehow defeated Virgo’s other self, before gracefully descending the stairs.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In one of the private booths at Le Petite Magik, Lord James Potter was having lunch with a rather despondent Misuse of Muggle Artefact’s Office Head.

“I just don’t understand it,” Arthur said, staring at the wonderfully cooked and expensive food in front of him. “Lord Thynn’s always been highly supportive of both my career and my efforts in the department. For him to suddenly floo call me and demand I scrap the new act under threat of pulling out his patronage … It makes no sense.”

James swirled his wine before taking a sip. “I assume this was after the last reading?”

“Yes.”

“Maybe something to do with any changes or additions that were made. Anything major?”

Arthur went over all the little changes, compromises, and additions that had been made before the latest version had been read out at the Wizengamot.

James sighed. “Tell me, have you ever met Thynn’s secretary, and ‘female friend,’ Becky?”

“Rather comely muggle woman? Yes, I have.” Arthur frowned. “What? You think she’s the reason Lord Thynn’s against it? But the new laws wouldn’t stop him from being Becky’s guide. It’s only supposed to stop the major abuses.”

James looked awkward. “Becky isn’t the only one. Not by a long way.”

Arthur’s eyes widened. Then he looked away and stared at nothing for several moments. Finally he clenched his hand into a fist and slammed it down on the table, causing all the plates and cutlery to jump. “Damnit!”

“Quite so.”

“I can’t backtrack, can I?”

“If you want to maintain your reputation, no.”

“Well, I can’t drop the whole act. Not now. You’ve got to help me, James. “

“With funding? The house of Potter is spread rather thin at the moment.”

“The only other people I could even think to go to on such short notice would be Sirius or Amelia … or Slytherin, I guess.”

James gave Arthur a sharp look before composing himself and taking another sip of wine. “I’m not saying it’s impossible …”

Arthur seemed to have an idea. He reached into the folds of his robes. “On that note, Lily sent this to Molly a while ago. Have you seen it?”

James took the photograph being offered him. It was a picture of his son, Harry, and Arthur’s youngest, Ginny, snuggled up together, asleep, in the Slytherin common room. He chuckled. “Cute. Don’t think I’ve ever seen Harry looking that unguarded” He handed the photo back. “Wait …” he paused. “You’re not suggesting what I think you are, are you?”

“It would bring the houses of Weasley and Potter closer.”

James wrinkled his nose. “I don’t want you to take this the wrong way, Arthur, but your Ginny, well, are you sure you can control her?”

Arthur frowned. “What do you mean?”

“Lily and I are having to be very cautious with Harry right now. He’s far too close to Lord Slytherin for our likings. He listens to us, yes, but I can’t help the feeling he does it more because he’s been told to, rather than because he sees us as legitimate parental authorities. A betrothal contract is one of the few powerful sticks we have if things go really bad. Do you feel you could influence Ginny to reign Harry in if needed?”

Arthur hesitated for just a tad too long before hastily saying, “Oh, yes, I’m sure I could. Ginny and I have always been close.”

James shrugged noncommittally. “I’ll think about it. In the meantime, maybe we can arrange a patronage pool for your operation. Better that then you having to have to go crawling to Slytherin.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“So, what do you think I should do, my lord?”

Lord Slytherin looked at Arthur Weasley over the small table shrubbery between them. They were in the same muggle restaurant they’d both gone to the last time they’d lunched together. There had been quite a few lunches and dinners together since then.

Slytherin took a drink from his orange juice. “Tricky,” he said. “I certainly agree that the work you do is important and needs more than just base ministry vault funding, but maybe you are going about this the wrong way.”

“What do you mean?”

“Lord Thynn seems to have been a good patron for you in the past—the two of you see eye-to-eye on many matters. It would be a shame for you to lose him.”

“I can’t scrap those paragraphs from the act without losing the respect of so many of my peers.”

“That’s the risk you run by basing your reputation on principles.”

Arthur grimaced.

Slytherin dabbed at his mouth with a napkin before continuing. “Arthur, If you’ve backed yourself into a corner, then find another way out of it. Find another reason to get rid of those paragraphs. One that is acceptable to your peers.”

“What other reason?”

Slytherin shrugged. “I don’t know. That’s your job.”

“Right,” Arthur muttered. He glanced up. “Incidentally, given what you told me about Harry and Ginny needing to be close, what would you say to a betrothal between the two?”

“I’d say it’s not up to me, but in principle it would be a good idea.”

“You think Harry would be happy with that?”

“Quite likely. And, based on what I know, I suspect Ginny wouldn’t be totally against the idea, either. It’s Lord Potter I’m not so certain about.”

“He seemed to be quite concerned about Ginny’s ability to ‘reign in’ or ‘control’ Harry when I spoke with him about it.”

“Interesting … I can’t help but wonder what his game is.”

“You’re not the only one.”

“You know Lord Potter quite well, don’t you?”

Arthur gave Lord Slytherin a dry look. “I wasn’t actually talking about him. Our little conversations”—he gestured around the muggle restaurant—“are reasonably well known. I seem to have become something of an unofficial ministry expert on Lord Slytherin, despite still knowing very little about you or what you officially stand for.”

Lord Slytherin said nothing.

“You’re going to have to make a stand on something eventually,” Arthur continued. “I’m not saying this because I’m fishing, you understand, I’m merely saying that at some point, you will need to be ready to say what it is you actually believe in.”

Several hours later, and a thousand kilometres away, found Harry Potter deep in the basement of the almost completed Slytherin Manor. He sat in front of a large blackboard. On his right, his house-elf, Plato, was busy drip feeding draught of living death into the obscurus he’d kidnapped, and was now experimenting on, to find a way to remove a soul-bound parasite from an eleven-year-old girl he’d previously sent another eleven-year-old girl after to murder. Behind them, Voldemort’s horcruxes sat in their silk-lined boxes, waiting to be used when he had the opportunity. Upstairs, goblins were putting the final touches on a mansion that cost several million pounds, paid for with drug money, while at the bottom of the hill, a family of muggles that he’d vassaled to himself were busy developing advanced magical armaments, which he was planning to sell to the highest bidder.

His animagus form would make people freak out when they learned of it.

Luna’s probably would too, if her constant insinuations were anything to go by.

Alex was having a massive identity crisis about her form.

Daphne’s and Ginny’s were the only somewhat normal ones of the lot, although still very impressive.

Hermione’s would cause a sensation.

But to get those forms, he was going to have acquire enough phoenix ash to make the ritual work, and that would require accessing a store large enough for his needs—and there was only one store large enough—and it was highly unlikely the individuals in charge of it were just going to hand the ash over, or even sell it to him. That meant stealing what he needed. Again. Just like with the stone, and the cloak, and even, some would rightly argue, the girls.

And on the blackboard in front of him, in big chalk letters, were written the words, “WHAT SHOULD I BELIEVE IN?” And he continued to stare.

—End of Chapter Forty-Four—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: This chapter was drafted, and made available early, for beta readers on the leadvone discord server. The first draft part of the next chapter has already been made available the same way. https://www.discord.me/leadvone

Sticky Note: If you want to keep abreast of the release schedule, as well as any changes and the occasional piece of bonus content, you can head over to https://www.leadvone.com and sign up for the Gray Mailing List.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Hermione’s Quest—Part 2

In 1740, the third-to-last member of the Ancient and Noble house of Pithy, the then Lord Pithy, peacefully passed away as the result of being gored by an enraged tebo while hunting in deepest Africa.

The mantle of Lord then passed to his brother, the second-to-last member of the ancient line, who immediately got twenty of his best mates together, went out for a dignified mourning drink, got rip-roaring drunk, and, while trying to impress a lady of easy virtue, splinched himself into the bottom of an abandoned mine, and was only found when the rain washed out his drowned, and very dead, head several days later.

The last member of the now rather endangered house—the previous lord’s sister—quickly took it upon herself not to rest until she had secured the house’s future. Given that her marriage contract did not allow for any children by her maiden family, and as there was no Lord Pithy to grant her request for a divorce, she plotted to do this by freeing herself of her current shackles in the only other way that would work.

It was just a shame her trusted maid put the basilisk venom in the wrong goblet.

Thus the Ancient and Noble house of Pithy came to an end, and with its passing, all the accumulated family magics were released to the world. Often this would change nothing, since even extinct, one still needs to know how to cast the family magic in order to make use of it, but in this case, the same maid who mixed up the poison, also had access to her mistresses’ secret diary, which contained many of the magics of the now dead house.

Not really knowing the value of what she had, the maid sold the diary to a friend for five galleons. The friend then took it to a dealer she knew in Knockturn Alley, who paid her fifty galleons. Finally, the book was purchased by a well-to-do muggleborn who, drunk on the ideals of the muggle enlightenment, then did something almost unheard of in the wizarding world, up to that moment.

He published it.

Five-hundred years of accumulated magic in the subject of occlumency—particularly in regards to the field of arithmancy—were unleashed upon the wizarding world, and the arithmancy revolution began.

Deep within the Hogwarts library, deep within the library of her own mind, Hermione Granger was treading the path of countless arithmancers since that day over 250 years ago. Of course, all of those others tended to be in their twenties before even attempting the mind magics she was now.

Across the blackness of her consciousness, lines formed shapes, broke apart, whirled around, and formed new shapes, in a never-ending kaleidoscope of potentiality. The potential was in cracking the code on the ancient Nordic writings. She’d been at it for weeks now, and was starting to get frustrated—both with her lack of progress, and with her now chronic magical exhaustion. Using her powers continually at this level was far beyond what she’d ever asked her brain to handle before.

But she would succeed. She had to. Harry was relying on her.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In his own little slice of Magical Britain, Mister Bentley tended to the lawn he’d been meticulously cultivating since even before he’d become Magical Britain’s top civil servant. That was a good analogue for Magical Britain itself, he thought, carefully uprooting an errant weed-bud with a skilful jab of his wand—a well-maintained lawn. Like a lawn, Magical Britain had a history. Poisons, carelessly added, took decades to seep away, everything should be neatly trimmed, and, occasionally, you needed to add something truly foul smelling to get the best long-term results—no matter how much Mrs. Bun might voice her mild disapproval over the garden wall they shared, bless her. In fact, now that he came to think about it, Mrs. Bun was a perfect example of an outstanding blade of grass on the lawn that was Magical Britain.

Mister Bentley surveyed his handiwork for the hour and nodded his head in approval. If only all parts of his lawn were so well behaved.

He made his way back up to the garden table, summoned his latest office reading, quietly sipped from a cup of ever-warm tea—two sugars with milk—and considered matters.

Weasley had just played a well-thought out move by anonymously leaking to the Prophet several negative stories from countries with rather draconian muggle-guide-laws, along with an independent report detailing how Norwegian wizards successfully police their muggle-guide-laws, before suggesting to his various backers that, ‘We really need more research before rushing into things.’ The Muggle Protection Act had been momentarily stalled, but now it would only be a matter of time before it picked up steam again.

He needed another angle—one with a little more staying power. Weasley would be cautious if he involved himself again so quickly and directly, so an oblique approach, maybe.

He sipped his tea.

Of course, it didn’t need to be stalled all that long—just until the Wizengamot broke for the winter, which wasn’t all that far away. That would give him a good long chunk of time to play with.

Yes, Mister Bentley thought. Maybe it was time for him to have a chat with his natural enemy.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On the outskirts of the forbidden forest, two almost invisible figures darted through the trees—barely a shimmer in the air—dodging and weaving, duelling spells flying between them at the speed of a muggle squash game. Leaves on the ground, golden and crinkly, rustled as they passed. Both were tired, but neither particularly cared.

Then, as if deciding to kick things up a notch, one of the figures abandoned the constraints of gravity altogether, flying up into the bare forest canopy while unleashing a torrent of brightly coloured spells behind it.

The other figure didn’t even hesitate. A blast of wind swept the leaves around its feet high up into the air, saturating the airspace with a thousand dancing spots of golden brown. There was a slight moment of reality confusion, and where before there had been a shimmer, now, there was just a leaf.

Up in the air, a female voice screamed. The screaming figure, still shimmering, dropped like a stone until there was another moment of confusion, another leaf replaced the shimmer, and the scream started again, this time higher up, but still descending rapidly.

Sometimes magic changed the laws of physics, and sometimes, it didn’t.

The shimmering figure who could actually fly had by now stopped firing off spells, choosing instead to watch its flailing opponent continually falling through the air at terminal velocity, but just about managing to never actually hit the ground.

“Help!”

And with that single yelp, the flying figure moved. Several spells were fired off in quick succession, the figure darted forward, and moments later, Harry Potter shimmered back into view on the ground, carrying a panting Ginny Weasley in his arms.

“Thanks,” Ginny gasped.

“No worries. Can I suggest you don’t try that trick again without me being there, though?”

“Yeah, yeah, sure.” Ginny spent the next moments paying off her body’s oxygen debts before she found her senses. She was still in Harry’s arms. She gave him an impish smirk. “My lord can let me down now.”

After she found her feet again, the two sat down to review her progress. She and Luna were still miles ahead of the others, although Alex was starting to catch up a little. Hermione and Daphne spent far too much of their time on other matters to keep pace. The only real combat training they got was during group sessions. Ginny could tell, however, that something was on Harry’s mind.

“Is it something you can talk to me about?” she asked.

Harry ran a hand through his hair. “I’ve just been thinking about how we position ourselves when we eventually go public. What policies do we support? What sides do we take and for what?”

Ginny gave Harry a confused look. “Who says we need to take anyone’s sides? Isn’t that what it means to be Gray?”

Harry waggled a hand. “Yes and no. When I first formed the Gray I did so with the idea of rebuilding Slytherin House—of using Slytherin House as a kind of focal point to build a political power capable of steering Magical Britain. That’s what sold many of the other lords. And our political actions so far, few as they have been, have all been reasonably neutral. But it is as I said to Lord Greengrass way back then … ‘the status quo is not sexy.’ If we want to extend the Gray beyond just a small group of lords, we’ll need a cause that more than just a few-dozen lords can appreciate.

“Sounds complicated,” Ginny said with a grin. “Politics is definitely more the others’ thing than mine. I’ll just stick to fighting.”

Harry nodded and looked up into the sky. “On a totally unrelated note, Lord Slytherin was having lunch with your father a few weeks back. Some things came up that we need to talk about. And possibly make a plan for, if you’re up for it.”

“Sure, I’m up for anything.”

Harry gave Ginny what could only be described as, ‘a look’. “I suggest you withhold judgement on that until I’ve told you what the discussion was about.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Hey, Justin, Sophie, check this out.” In the Founders Club room, Kevin Entwhistle flashed his friends his latest transfiguration essay with a grin. At the top, in handwriting that every student in the school could easily identify as McGonagall’s, was scrawled a large O.

Sophie Roper beamed and clapped. “Well done, Kevin! I knew you could do it.”

Justin slapped him on the back. “Yes, good job. All the work’s paying off.”

“I’ll say,” Kevin replied.

In another part of the classroom, the first year muggleborns were deep in focus, gazing deeply into each other’s eyes while practising their occlumency. The brunette twins, Violet and Marigold Chesterfield were partnered together, naturally, while Kevin’s little sister, Annabel, was partnered with the excitable Colin Creevey. This left Alan Gage, the plain looking one, as the odd one out, currently partnering with a charitable Dean Thomas.

Marigold blinked, looked away, and giggled. “You’re getting good at this, Violet.”

“Thank you, Marigold,” Violet replied. “You are pretty good yourself.”

And up at the front of the classroom, at the normally empty teacher’s desk, sat their leader, Hermione Granger, eyes tightly closed, with a look of such ferocious concentration on her face that it made many in the room slightly uncomfortable.

“Is she still giving you the cold shoulder, Justin?” Sophie asked.

“No, not really. I’m not even sure she realised she was doing it. Or maybe I was just imagining things.”

“She’s amazing,” Kevin said. “But she does need to relax a bit more.”

“She’s taught us so much,” Sophie said. “And pretty soon we’ll be starting on wandless magic. That’s, like, Lord Slytherin level magic.”

Justin frowned. “I just wish I could get my Mum and Dad to see it that way.”

Sophie smiled. “Don’t worry about it. I’m sure if anything happens, we can talk to Hermione, and she’ll ask Lord Slytherin to help us. And when we’re seventeen we won’t even need their permission. We could become Vassals like Hermione all by ourselves if we wanted.”

The two boys nodded.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“And to what do I owe the honour of a visit from the minister’s own humble hag?” Lucius Malfoy looked across at the man sitting opposite him. Bentley had been the gears in the ministry machine since before he’d even taken up his lordship. He suspected the only reason the man had never made it onto Voldemort’s death-list in the last war was because the Dark Lord thought he might be useful after his conquest.

“My lord,” Bentley started, “normally, of course, I wouldn’t involve myself in Wizengamot matters—”

“—as well you shouldn’t,” Malfoy said with a raised eyebrow.

“—But in this case,” Bentley continued, “I feel it might be appropriate to do so.”

“Why?”

“One of my many responsibilities is to co-ordinate the different departments, including the DMLE and the Department of Mysteries. When events transpire that might undermine the stability of Magical Britain, I have a duty.”

In the privacy of his head, Lucius rolled his eyes. Ah, the old ‘my duty extends past my jurisdiction’ justification—classic. He made a hand gesture to indicate Bentley should continue.

“There have been discussions at the highest level, about the possibility of giving parents of muggleborns the franchise.”

“What?!” Lucius’ eyes widened.

“As you know, being granted the vote would make them full citizens of Magical Britain with all the rights that come with it, including the right to legal representation, access to St. Mungo’s, vaults at Gringotts …”

Lucius’ eyes bugged to almost comic levels as Bentley continued to read out the list of potential rights that could be granted to muggleborn parents—to muggles.

“… And of course, all obliviation magics would have to be approved by the DMLE rather than being handled by the obliviator squad as is current practice. Hence my concerns about stability.”

Lucius finally found his voice. “That would be unthinkable! Who’s talking about this?”

“Oh, it’s all very early stuff at the moment. A quiet word from one lord of the Light to another.”

“The Gray would never allow it.”

“Well, that is a point of view, certainly, but you may recall that Lord Slytherin did grant vassalage to what is now the House of Granger. They already enjoy many of these privileges.”

Lucius sat back in his chair and took it all in. Muggles having the vote would be horrific. Even if the Wizengamot put up the candidates for minister, just the fact that muggles could vote would cause the more malleable candidates to shift their political stance. Muggleborns made up a quarter of the population. If, for the sake of simplicity, they assumed each muggleborn had two parents, that would add a new voting block as large as an extra third! And leaving aside the political ramifications, just the idea of thousands of muggles traipsing up and down Diagon Alley on a daily basis, at Bodmin Stadium, and the other enclaves, infecting them with their non-magical ways … of actual wizards having to wait in line at St. Mungo’s because a muggle had a piffling little problem … urgh.

If there was even a small chance that Slytherin was secretly pro-muggle—even if that didn’t seem his style—well, it had to be addressed.

“Okay,” he eventually said, “so what’s your plan?” Obviously Bentley did have one. He wasn’t a man who didn’t.

Bentley smiled. “The Gray is nothing if not pragmatic. If the Dark were to come up with their own Muggle Protection Act, one that offered the Gray things the Light wouldn’t be willing to compromise on …”

Lucius frowned. “No one is quite sure what Slytherin actually wants. Apart from the restoration of his house.” He thought back to the vote he’d stopped from passing at the Hogwarts’ directors meeting. “Along with a few other things …”

“The both of you are on the Hogwarts’ board of directors,” Bentley continued, almost perfectly echoing Lucius’ own thoughts. “I imagine that would be a good place to start in talking with him.”

Lucius nodded. Yes, it would be. And now that he knew he wasn’t dealing with Lord Voldemort, thanks to his ‘daughter’, it would make it all the easier.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The forest was lush and tropical. A thousand birds hooted, chirped, and sang all around her. The buzz of a billion insects accompanied them. To a girl who’d never left the borders of rainy old England, the heat and humidity were oppressive. But this girl was not Ginny Weasley. Between the trees, Alexandra Black crept, constantly feeling her magic for the tiniest hint of an attack. She pushed aside a bush and found what she was looking for. Her eyes lit up. A massive forest clearing, and in the middle, a huge Mesoamerican pyramid. And inside was the target Lord Slytherin had set for her.

The entrance proved no difficulty.

Neither did the many magical trip-lines and pressure sensors.

Then she got careless and tripped one.

She was already halfway down the narrow, horribly round-shaped passage when she heard the rumbling up ahead.

“SHIT!”

Running in robes was not easy, and not for the first time, she wished she’d accepted Slytherin’s offer to transfigure her something more like what Daphne sometimes wore. She was only saved a rather horrible restart by jumping into a pit across a wide chasm. She landed heavily and scrambled to her feet. That was when she saw the skeletons.

Through her many breathy pants, Alexandra smirked. “Now this—is more—my thing!”

The first skeleton lunged for her, but black chains burst from her wand and held it fast. Moments later, those same chains held all four of the undead in front of her. She then triumphantly pointed her wand downwards and shouted, “Canker Disserpo!”

Nothing happened.

Alexandra frowned.

Suddenly the pit was filled with light, she felt a little yank behind her navel, and the next thing she knew, she’d landed on her backside in front of Slytherin, currently disguised as Harry, who looked down at her with his emerald green eyes. “And where did you learn that spell?” he asked. He didn’t sound angry, but there was a definite seriousness to his tone.

“The restricted section,” Alex replied, getting to her feet and rubbing where she’d landed on the hard stone floor. “Why didn’t it work?”

“This is a dream. I make the rules here. And one of those rules is no constructs that could risk the integrity of the dream itself. Canker Disserpo is a blight, Alex. It creeps and infects. I would not wish to see if it could break free.”

Alexandra fingered the pendant around her neck that Ginny had mysteriously given to her after the confrontation where she’d learned Slytherin’s true identity. “But it would have worked, right?” she asked. “The skeletons would have been forced to obey me.”

Harry nodded. “Yes, it would have, if you got it right.”

The night continued from there. Alex fought her way through the various traps of the pyramid and after only two more attempts found the centre all by herself without having to be remote-apparated into it.

“Now what?” she asked, sitting again in front of Slytherin.

“A question. If you could change anything about Magical Britain, what would it be?”

Alexandra didn’t even have to think. “Ladies should be able to sit on their own Wizengamot seats. It’s so unfair—we can’t even be our own proxies.”

“Ah, yes,” Harry said. “I should have guessed that would be your reply. Anything more actionable? I’m in the middle of drafting the outline for the book we’re going to use when I go public. I’d appreciate input.”

Alex’s eyes lit up. “Better laws to protect family legacies. What my father is doing to the House of Black shouldn’t be allowed.”

“So, a noble position?”

Alex hesitated. “No, I mean, it doesn’t have to be noble, right? Everyone can have a house, can’t they?”

“Technically, yes. Except unmarried muggleborn witches, and underage muggleborn wizards, although it does require jumping through a lot of hoops and only the future head of house can do it. Most never do. They generally only bother when they’re starting a business.”

“But they could do it,” Alex pushed, “so my point is still valid. Strengthening family legacy laws benefits everyone.”

“But it benefits people with strong legacies more,” Harry said with a smile. “People like you.”

Alex folded her arms. “So you’re saying I’m wrong?”

“I’m saying it’s a very traditionalist Dark view.”

“A wrong traditionalist Dark view?”

Harry smiled. “Alright, it is a little wrong, yes—from a pure fairness point of view.” He put up a finger to stall Alex’s objections. “But that doesn’t mean it isn’t still an option.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Letting this slide through is not an option!” Lord Nott slammed down the parchment he’d just read onto the table between himself and Lord Malfoy. “Muggles as citizens!? Are they mad!? What are the options? If only we still had him we could solve this with one single well placed killing curse.”

Lucius sighed. “We’ll need to strip most of the more ridiculous paragraphs from the current act before adding our own back in. We’ll need a basic framework before we talk to our friends.”

“Fine,” Nott said. “What do we keep? This stuff about giving Weasley authority to make classifications of new muggle rubbish seems pretty inoffensive. What even is a microchip? Do you know?”

Lucius shook his head. “No, I don’t, and I don’t particularly want to. What about this one removing currency exchange restrictions for mudbloods in cases of extreme distress?”

“Dangerous. Remember the Carnegie affair. And how is that even anything to do with muggle protection?” Nott asked.

“Nothing. I suspect they’re just using the act as an opportunity to shove through everything they’ve been wanting to pass for the past four years.”

“Despicable. But it is what we’d have done.”

“Quite.”

“So what are we going to give Lord Slytherin? What does he want?”

Lucius handed over a piece of parchment. “Apart from what’s public, which you obviously know, this is my only clue.”

“Minutes of the Hogwarts director’s meeting? What’s this about?”

“One of the motions put forth was to give Slytherin guardianship of the school’s mudbloods.”

“Five in each year … Thirty-five total. Why not happily hand them over? They’re just mudbloods. Maybe he could even be persuaded to ditch the whole act.”

“I doubt it. They aren’t valuable enough by themselves, even if he wanted to create some kind of Slug-club style old boys club, which is the only plausible reason I can think of for why he would want their guardianships. And his rapport with Arthur Weasley is supposed to be rather strong for some reason that baffles me.”

“That’s a fat lot of good. Then what do we do?”

“We’ll probably need to talk to Lord Slytherin directly. Or perhaps, if we can’t arrange that, indirectly.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“I can’t believe you!” Daphne hissed. She was sitting on Hermione’s bed in the Slytherin girl’s dormitory with her back to the headboard and her knees drawn up to her chest. The curtains were closed and they’d already applied several layers of privacy charms. It was easy to tell it was Hermione’s bed, because even neat and tidy as it was, there were still books piled everywhere—Daphne had needed to wedge herself into a space to actually find a headboard to lean back against. Laying open by her side was one of the muggle strategy books Harry had bought her for her birthday.

Sitting cross-legged at the foot of the bed, trying to look innocent, was Hermione. Looking innocent was now something she was naturally good at, even while also looking tired, which, right now, she did. Despite the meticulous care she usually took of her hair, a certain bushiness was creeping back.

“A unicorn!” Daphne continued. “A unicorn animagus! My favourite animal in the whole world! You—You—!” She opened her mouth again, but couldn’t seem to find the words.

“Daphne …” Hermione began.

“I’m not jealous, you understand,” Daphne said. “Being able to ride a unicorn would be just as good as being one. But then you—! Humph!” She folded her arms and pouted.

“It’s not my fault,” Hermione said. Like Daphne, she also had a book, this one laying in her lap. “You didn’t get to choose to be a golden eagle. You could have been any kind of eagle. Any kind of bird.”

“I’m happy with what I have. I’ve always wanted to be good at flying. And having a unicorn animagus on our side will be incredibly useful. The symbolism alone is powerful. Unicorn hair, hoof powder, never mind freely given unicorn blood.”

“There, you see.” Hermione smiled encouragingly. “It’s not that bad.”

“But … But … But a Shetland unicorn?!” Daphne threw up her hands in the air. “I can’t ride you if you’re a Shetland unicorn! You’re too small! It’s that Morgana damned hair of yours! That’s what caused this!”

“Well, I’m sorry,” Hermione grouched. “We can’t all have naturally-perfect, silky-smooth hair right out of bed every morning. I imagine you’d have got a unicorn with a cashmere coat, if it’d been you.” Suddenly, she yawned—a long and drawn out yawn, not the kind politely made in company to indicate that the yawner is just a little tired, but the jaw-achingly full yawn of the truly whacked.

“I’ll give you your bed back,” Daphne said, moving to the edge. “You don’t want to push yourself too hard. Harry wouldn’t like it if you hurt yourself.”

“Harry needs me,” Hermione said, crawling up to where Daphne had been before. “He’s relying on me. I can’t fail him.”

“Did you hear about the valuation he got for the old muggle gold he found in that second cave?” Daphne asked. “£350,000—seven thousand galleons.”

“That sounds nice,” Hermione said. Her head landed on her pillow, in-between an encyclopaedia of runes and a muggle book titled, ‘cracking substitution cyphers with frequency analysis.’ “Will that keep the goblins happy?”

“For the moment.”

“Good. Harry’s got lots of important things to do. He shouldn’t have to be distracted by something like mere gold.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was raining. The afternoon sun didn’t stand even a chance of piercing the uniform dark-grey sky, spread across the Scottish wilds like a dementor’s cloak. It was at times like these that John Potter really regretted being such an outdoorsy type. Technically, the roof of the duelling arena was supposed to close in bad weather, but for whatever reason, the light drizzle, which pattered around him while he shouted encouragement, didn’t count.

“C’mon, Susan! Don’t let her box you in!”

In their little corner of the arena, Susan Bones valiantly tried to fight off the advances of a hyper-focused Virgo Malfoy. John could clearly see it wasn’t easy going. Despite Virgo being a year younger than Susan, and muggle raised, she was clearly talented, powerful, and determined.

“Expelliarmus!” Virgo shouted, taking advantage of a gap in her opponent’s defences, and cleanly ripping the wand from her grasp. It flew across the space between them, allowing her to deftly pluck it from the air.

Susan cursed.

John clapped and flashed the younger girl a charming smile. “Well done, Virgo!”

“Thank you.”

“And you, Susan,” John began, as the three of them made their way towards each other, “you were doing well, but you allowed Virgo to control the pace of the duel right from the start. Your footing was sloppy when she pushed you, so I want you to go through those drills again while I go against Virgo.”

Susan took her wand from Virgo’s unresisting hand, grinned at him—“Yes, Professor Potter,”—and walked away.

John smirked after her before turning back to his other student—the girl who’d have never come to Hogwarts if he hadn’t come back in time—the girl who probably wouldn’t have even learned she was a witch if it hadn’t been for him—Also, he thought, somewhat guiltily, the girl who wouldn’t have been indoctrinated in Malfoy slime and then left to rot by that same slime when she turned out not to be the perfect Slytherin daughter, if he hadn’t been tasked by Fate and Death to save the world.

“Do you need a moment to rest?” he asked.

“No, I am perfectly ready to defeat you.”

John chuckled. “Oh, I see, just like the last three times, mmm?”

Virgo said nothing, but instead got into position for their bout.

Still chuckling, John did the same. They began and he immediately put her on the back foot with an elemental wind. It howled through the arena, kicking up leaves and twigs everywhere, and causing all the other Hufflepuffs—busily duelling on the other side of the arena—to cry out in surprise. Things from there went pretty much as they did the last three times. Virgo tried to counter his magics with surprisingly intricate spells and animations, but they were all ultimately useless. She eventually stood exhausted in the middle of the arena, her wand by his feet, looking incredibly frustrated.

“Don’t worry about it,” John said, soothingly. “You’ll get better.”

Virgo shot him a look of anger before schooling her features (or softening them? It was hard to tell.) “I don’t need your sweet words, Potter. You beat me every time with raw power. You shield every spell I send at you and your elemental magics deal with everything else I have. Lord Malfoy made me watch memories of your duelling tournament from last year. You beat seventh years as though they were your age. Seventh years! One after another! Almost no rests! Do you have any idea how insane that is?! You, John Potter, are a monster—you, and your brother.”

John had been preening under the girl’s fierce words, until the mention of Harry, whereupon his face darkened for just the fraction of a second before he got control of himself back.

“If you continue training under Flitwick, I will never be able to reliably beat you,” Virgo finished. “I simply won’t be able to skill up fast enough to out-match the difference we have in power.”

“Virgo, you shouldn’t be measuring yourself against me. You can already beat Susan. That’s an amazing accomplishment.” He smiled encouragingly at her. “You score top in all your classes. You’re an amazing witch. And very pretty too.”

That didn’t get quite the reaction he was hoping for. Every other girl he’d given that line to in the past had at least blushed. Virgo just crossed her arms, sniffed, and marched off to duel one of the Hufflepuff first-years.

Susan sidled back up to him and giggled. “You like her, don’t you?”

John jerked around. “No, I don’t. She’s a …” He started to say Malfoy but he stopped himself in time. Susan didn’t like it when he said things like that, and besides, was Virgo really a Malfoy? When it came right down to it? Sure, she’d have Malfoy family magics, but she’d been raised by muggles. She knew about things that no pure-blood princess would know about—or even him for that matter.

Susan easily picked up on his hesitation. “She’s a nice girl—very smart—a bit reserved, but that’s not surprising given what she’s been through. You should open up to her a bit more.”

“I still don’t know if I can trust her.”

“You trust me, don’t you?”

“Yes, of course.”

“Well then,” Susan said, as if that was a good enough argument. “Besides, if you wait too long to trust her, it might be too late.”

“What do you mean?”

Susan sighed. “John, she’s a daughter of the House of Malfoy whose Lord is unhappy with her. I’m actually rather surprised. If I were her, I’d be a lot more worried about my prospects than she seems to be.”

“Prospects?”

“Contracts.”

“Oh.” A lumos went off in John’s head. “Oh!” His face darkened again. “Oh … You think Lord Malfoy would contract her to some death eater or someone?”

“Or someone,” Susan said, meaningfully. “I was thinking more along the lines of Lord Slytherin.”

John choked when some saliva almost went down the wrong pipe. He got his breath back again before replying. “Why?” he coughed hard again. “Why would he do that?”

“Auntie says the Wizengamot is fighting hard about these new muggle protection laws. The Dark desperately wants the Gray on its side rather than the Light’s. Contracts have traditionally been a way to cement new alliances.”

“Slytherin already has Greengrass and Lovegood.”

“Auntie once told me that Wizards who want more than one wife often aren’t satisfied with just two.” She gave John a knowing look. “Remind you of anyone?”

“I am nothing like Lord Slytherin!”

“Of course not. You’re just a charming, handsome, powerful wizard who doesn’t wear a mask.” Susan blushed when she finished.

John gaped at her for a second before bursting out laughing. “And how, Heiress Bones, do you know that Slytherin doesn’t look like a hexed monkey under his mask?”

Susan continued to blush. “Fair point.”

“But I’m glad you think so highly of me. And is it just me or do I notice that you’re growing too?” He leered at his friend’s chest, which had definitely expanded in the last few months.

“Oh, shut up,” Susan said playfully, covering herself with her arms and giggling again.

A loud shout distracted them. They turned.

Virgo was sitting on her backside on the ground with her wand half-way between her and her opponent, looking absolutely furious with herself.

“I did it!” Her opponent, Marigold Chesterfield, cheered, jumping up in the air, arms held up high, while her twin, Violet, looked on impassively.

“I tripped,” Virgo snarled.

“Still did it!” Marigold laughed.

“Again!”

John watched the now livid Virgo duel several more times against the first-year Hufflepuff girl, ruthlessly stomping her into the ground like a boot stomping an ant. Not that Marigold seemed to care much, continuing to smile even as her wand was ripped from her hand again and again. It was amazing how fierce Virgo got when she duelled. It actually reminded him of someone. A certain red-headed someone—a certain red-headed someone sitting prettily in Harry’s lap, innocently oblivious to the evil words mouthed behind her.

Way up in the highest stands, a certain red-headed someone was lying on her stomach under the invisibility cloak, peering through a pair of omnioculars at Virgo’s duelling exploits, and carefully making notes.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Daphne was sitting on Hermione’s bed again. The curtains were drawn, and, like always, all the privacy charms the girls knew were active. “—And Ginny thinks there’s nothing to worry about right now, but she’s keeping an eye on the situation anyway,” Daphne continued. She was in the middle of sorting out stuff that Harry needed to know, stuff he probably didn’t need to know, but would like to know, stuff he actually didn’t need to know, and stuff that he really needed to know, like, right now. “Alex got into a fight with a couple of third years, which wasn’t so great, but she handled it. It wasn’t the same display she demonstrated in the common room, but that could be attributed to her just not bothering with ‘small fry’. In any case, Harry will certainly want to know about that. But then, Alex will probably just tell him herself during dreamy time.” She put a thinking finger to her chin. “But I’m not sure when their next session will be, so best if I just include that in the report as well.”

Hermione was sat up by the headboard, sitting cross-legged in her sleepwear with a look of vacancy across her features. She occasionally nodded to show that, at least some part of her was engaged in the conversation.

“I should probably also ask if he has any information from his spies in the ministry about the situation in the forbidden forest now that Mosag is running the Acromantula show. There hasn’t been anything on that in the Daily Prophet for over a week.”

Daphne paused, mid-monologue.

Hermione was shaking.

Daphne leaned in closer. It wasn’t easy to spot, but on closer examination it became clear her close friend was trembling like a leaf. “Hermione? Are you okay?”

Hermione’s eyes instantly re-focused. “Of course I’m okay.” Her voice was strained.

“You don’t sound or look okay.”

“No, I’m fine. I’m just tired.”

Daphne frowned. Hermione had been working herself to the bone recently. Everyone knew it, although obviously most didn’t know what she was up to. Not even Daphne really knew what she was up to, other than she was trying to learn to read the logs from the Hogwarts sea-cave. Hermione always did have a stubborn streak. “Then you won’t mind if I take a peek, just to check everything’s alright?”

Hermione huffed and crossed her arms. “Of course it’s okay! Because I’m fine!”

Daphne withdrew her wand, pointed it at Hermione’s forehead, gathered her own mental faculties, and whispered, “Legilimens.” The spell floated between them like the faintest wisp of smoke. It brushed against Hermione’s occlumency shields and she felt her friend open up to let her in, a massive archway in her shield’s walls.

Daphne’s consciousness was halfway through when she felt the creaking. Alarmed, she just managed to extricate herself before a point right above the archway buckled, and the entire thing collapsed like a house of cards.

“I can’t,” Hermione whispered

Daphne’s consciousness snapped back behind her eyes.

Hermione’s breathing had changed. It was now ragged, panting in short, sharp gasps.”I can’t.”

“Hermione.”

“I—Daphne—I—It’s not working—I can’t.” Her eyes were wide and darting. “I’ve tried. But it’s not working! I can’t!”

She was having a panic attack. “Hermione!” Despite it being something she’d never normally do, Daphne climbed over the bed and quickly wrapped her arms around her.

“I can’t!”

“It’s okay. Take deep breaths—calm, deep breaths—come on. You need to work with me here.”

It took almost half an hour for Hermione to calm down, and now that she was actually looking for them, Daphne couldn’t begin to understand how she hadn’t spotted the signs of acute magical exhaustion before—magical exhaustion so bad it had caused even Hermione’s basic occlumency to come tumbling down, leaving her open to all the accumulated stress piling on her all at once.

“It’s the code,” Hermione sniffed out. “I figured it was a substitution cipher, because I once read a book that mentioned them, and there’s this muggle technique called frequency analysis, which has never been used with arithmancy occlumency, and I really wanted to learn it, but there isn’t much data available for Ancient Norse so I figured I could just make up for the difference by brute forcing it, and I didn’t want to disappoint Harry, but once I started I didn’t want to waste all that effort when I might solve it at any moment, and the arithmancy books warn against using more magic than you can handle, but I’ve been using occlumency for so long, and I’ve always been able to restrain myself, but it’s already taken a long time, and Harry needs this done, and, oh, I’m so stupid!”

“Hermione,” Daphne said soothingly, still hugging her. “You are not stupid. It’s okay. But you have to rest. Your body needs to recover.”

“But what am I going to do!? I have to solve this! If my occlumency isn’t enough, then I’ll need a computer, but you can’t have electronics in Hogwarts—except maybe the ritual room—but we’d need to fidelius it, and where would we get a power source? And would the fidelius itself interfere with the electronics?” She was still shaking in her arms.

Daphne sighed. It was clear Hermione wasn’t going to try to sleep until she had at least a passable solution to her problem. She wasn’t quite sure what ‘brute forcing it’ meant, but it sounded vaguely like attrition warfare, which was rarely a great idea, so, Hermione needed a different tactic. A flanking manoeuvre, as it were.

Unfortunately, she, Daphne, didn’t know anything about muggle code-breaking, so, even if it was useless, she’d start with what she did know about. “Have you tried all the magical methods, yet?”

There was a moment of silence before Hermione said, “I told you, I’ve been using occlumency.”

“No, I mean you’re applying a muggle method of turning a bunch of rubbish into something meaningful. Have you tried all the magical decoding spells, yet?”

There was silence

“I’m so stupid,” Hermione whispered.

“Hermione?”

“I haven’t used any of them!”

Of course, Daphne mused, sometimes it turns out that you’ve been using flanking manoeuvres so much you forget that direct assaults still exist.

“I just assumed!” Hermione angrily continued. “I knew about a muggle way to do it, and like a stupid ignorant muggleborn didn’t even consider that there was already a magical way to do it. Oh, Merlin, I’m still like that other me!” She started moving out of Daphne’s embrace.

“Where are you going?”

“The library. There’s still some time before curfew. I’ll—”

Daphne grabbed her wrist. “Hermione, you need to rest!”

“I—” Hermione started again, before what was clearly a dizzy wave hit her, and she fell forward onto the other half of the bed. Daphne checked. Hermione was out like a light.

Sighing deeply, Daphne put her to bed, before getting dressed again, and heading out to tell her lord about what had happened.

When Hermione woke up, it was to find Harry at her bedside, with an understanding face and a calm word. They spoke about what happened, and Hermione promised to be more careful in future. Harry even knew where she should start to look for the code-breaking charms. Of course he knew best, Hermione thought, snuggling herself back under the sheets when Harry left after giving her orders to rest for the rest of the weekend. Harry always knew best.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It was a Wednesday. It was also late afternoon. This fact annoyed Lord Lucius Malfoy who generally went out riding with Nott at around this time, while their wives took tea up at the house. The fact that the weather outside the castle window showed it to be probably the last good weather of the year, didn’t help matters.

On the opposite side of the headmaster’s desk, Gilderoy Lockhart was looking unusually nervous. “Are you sure he’s coming?”

“I assure you,” Malfoy said smoothly, “Slytherin is not nearly so unreachable as you might assume.”

Lockhart started muttering something about how he’d never gotten an answer from Slytherin on anything, no matter how many owls he’d sent him, before Malfoy tuned him out.

Lucius himself was only half sure of Slytherin’s eventual arrival. After thinking about how to set up this meeting, he’d hit upon the rather obvious idea of having Draco hand deliver a letter to Heiress Greengrass. The headmaster’s presence—as well as the official purpose for this meeting—was, unfortunately, necessary. Slytherin rarely answered requests for meetings, but there was something about Hogwarts that consistently drew the man out of his hiding hole. He’d just have to signal to the man what he wanted through the time-honoured practice of double meanings.

“But I guess, in the end, the call of a famous celebrity like me was just too much for him to stay away!” Lockhart flashed a grin at no one in particular before collapsing back in his chair, his face quickly shifting from confident to tired. He stared at the mess of papers in front of him. “How do you handle all of this, my lord?” he asked.

“I don’t,” Malfoy said.

At that moment, the door to the headmaster’s office opened without bell or knock, and the visage of Lord Slytherin stepped through. Lockhart’s expression instantly shifted from tired to alert. The three exchanged greetings, (“Order of Merlin, Third Class!”), and sat down.

“What’s this about that couldn’t have been owled?” Slytherin asked.

First double-meaning, Malfoy thought, and said, “There are some things, Slytherin, that are best not written down.”

“Is that because they might leak, or because they shouldn’t be discussed at all?”

“Neither, but there are some things that should just be talked about face-to-face, one on one, as it were.”

“Indeed!” Lockhart said, smiling widely. “And we’ve been given a golden opportunity to market Hogwarts, and, dare I say it, those at the top—” He gave them both a roguish wink “—to the entire Wizarding World!”

“Go on,” Slytherin said.

“Are you familiar with the Tri-Wizard tournament, Lord Slytherin?” Lucius asked.

“Massive tournament between the three most important European wizarding schools—rather dangerous—discontinued when all nine champions, mostly from noble families, were all killed at once when one of them decided that the best way to deal with a hydra, was to keep chopping the heads off.”

“An apt summation,” Lucius drawled. “And as you can probably guess, Ludo Bagman has been chatting with Barty Crouch about the idea of bringing the tournament back. I understand they’ve already reached out to their opposite numbers who are in favour of the idea.”

“I don’t see any reason to object,” Slytherin said.

“It would require you to take a more active role, in discussions,” Malfoy continued. “Especially when there are matters of great urgency and import to discuss. You’ve been rather distant in the day to day matters of the steering of Magical Britain, but if that’s changing then we, and especially I, would appreciate your thoughts, Slytherin.”

Slytherin’s mask regarded him for a moment.

Then Lucius felt it—a slight brushing against his occlumency barriers. He gasped and swatted it away. That hadn’t been what he’d meant!

“Capital suggestion, my lord,” Lockhart said, jovially. “What say you, Lord Slytherin? I know there are some things I wouldn’t mind talking to you about either.”

Lucius spent the next few minutes of discussion sweating profusely as legilimency probe after legilimency probe brushed over his defences, never violent, never pushy, but nevertheless, gently persistent.

Eventually Slytherin cleared his throat. “I feel that if Lord Malfoy here, really wants to introduce more stringent entry criteria for the competitors, then he will need to be ready to compromise on certain other issues.”

Damn. This really was the only way he was going to get to talk with Slytherin, wasn’t it? He took a deep mental breath and readied himself.

The next time Slytherin’s legilimency probe brushed over his shields, just as Lockhart started explaining how a chimera should actually be dealt with, he didn’t swat it away, but allowed it to settle on the surface like snowflakes on a brick wall. More magic flowed through the connection, and eventually, after another minute chatting, Lucius’ world split, and his view went dark.

And then there was light.

He was now standing in the foyer of Malfoy Manor, the home he’d grown up in—the home he’d been seat of ever since his father died—and the home that he’d based his own personal mindscape on.

He cautiously opened the front door and peeked outside.

Total Darkness—save for a small rectangle of light in a far-off wall that looked miles away.

A thin bridge of marble stretched off towards that rectangle of light, and on either side of that bridge, an endless drop into complete blackness, staggering the mind with its vast unknown, like a silent ocean at midnight.

A figure was floating across the bridge towards him. It was, of course, Slytherin.

Lucius schooled his features as the enigma lord approached.

Slytherin stopped just before his front door. He would go no further—of that, Lucius was sure.

“You have my attention,” Slytherin said. “But I advise you to be quick—lest we attract attention.”

Lucius nodded. “We are not happy with the muggle protection act.”

“Who?”

“The Dark.”

“I’m sure you’re not.”

“Is there anything that would persuade you to outright drop it?”

“Your daughter?”

A chill went down Lucius’ back. “Not Virgo.”

“Then I can’t think of anything.”

“You’re interested in muggleborns aren’t you? You vassaled one, Merlin knows why. Have you heard what those idiots in the Light are suggesting? Total citizenship for muggle parents of muggleborns.”

“Perhaps I’m in favour.”

Lucius tilted his head, as though to concede the point. “Perhaps you are. Or perhaps taking away one of the tools you use to collect your precious muggleborns is not in your, interest? What’s the value of being vassaled to you, if they already have all those rights anyway?”

Lord Slytherin said nothing.

“But I’m sure that if it was put up,” Lucius continued, “you’d be forced to accept it, if you want to maintain your pro-muggleborn position.”

“I don’t have a pro-muggleborn position.”

Lucius shook his head. “No, you’re right. You don’t have any position. How long will you be able to play that game? Allying with the Light means constantly strengthening the ministry and taking away the powers that allow us to steer our world—kicking out the pillars that hold us up, while we’re still standing on them.”

“Then what are you proposing?” Slytherin asked.

“That you let us make some proposals of our own. Obviously this will take time and play into certain people’s agendas, but if I’m thinking correctly, you don’t actually much care about this legislation anyway.”

“Laws do need to evolve to adapt to new circumstances.”

Lucius sneered. “Something you’ve been helping with no end.” There was a gust of mental wind and Lucius quickly reminded himself of the raw magical powers likely ready to come crashing down on his shields should he get too cocky. He centred himself, cleared his throat, and continued. “I suggest, for example, that family law should extend over magical guardianships of muggleborns—a way to help bring muggleborns into our culture, perhaps?”

Slytherin said nothing again.

Lucius counted that as a win. He smiled. “May I be frank?”

Slytherin inclined his head.

“I believe you are an isolationist, like me. You don’t want muggleness in the Wizarding World any more than I do, but you believe you can use it—a foolish belief, in my opinion—a dangerous belief—but at the core, you are an isolationist. We should be working together.”

“Just as you worked together with me during the last board meeting?”

Lucius wanted to scowl, but hid it just in time. “We both know why I withdrew that support. You are—not—theDark Lord.”

“I never said I was.”

“No, you just let me look a fool all by myself.” He paused. “But that doesn’t mean we can’t work together now. We’ll write up a new proposal for the act, just taking out the more outrageous paragraphs and adding in ones that would—” he made a vague gesture with his hand, “—help you along a bit. The Dark and the Gray can understand one-another better, I think.”

Slytherin slightly inclined his head. “This may be true.” And with that, Lord Slytherin turned and started floating back over the bridge between minds, over an endless pit of darkness.

“And that’s how you should properly deal with a Chimera!” Lockhart finished, beaming.

He was back in the headmaster’s office.

On the way out from the meeting, Lockhart tried to trap Slytherin into a private meeting of his own, but Slytherin responded simply by handing the man a small envelope and telling him he’d talk with him then.

Lucius recognised that envelope. He’d received one himself not too long ago, and although his Winter Festival schedule was normally completely full, he had decided that attending the first Slytherin Gala Night at the newly constructed Slytherin Manor was probably a good idea.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Known Knowledge Unknown?” Professor Vector looked at the girl in front of her with surprise. “It’s not good manners to snoop around in other people’s secrets, young lady.”

“Please, professor,” Hermione said, “this isn’t for that—this is for historical research.”

“Historical research?”

Hermione nodded.

“Hmmm … Well, in that case, I suppose you can borrow it.” She took a tome off her shelf and handed it to the beaming girl. “But don’t let me hear of you using it for nefarious purposes.”

“No. I promise you won’t. Thank you, Professor!” Hermione left the arithmancy classroom, carefully closed the door behind her, and almost ran down to her favourite library spot. Success! The library’s only copy was checked out, but she’d tracked it down, and now she had it.

Twenty minutes later, Hermione was vibrating with excitement. It was highly likely that the code in the book wasn’t a code at all, but merely a password protected document, protected not by mathematics, but by simple magic. That meant she could analyse it with her magic sensing skills, which she and Daphne were now learning along with the other girls in their regular group combat training sessions.

“Afternoon.”

Hermione’s eyes lit up. “Harry!”

“It’s a good thing you can exclaim like that and still keep it a whisper,” Harry joked. “Any progress?”

“Yes! I’ve found the book you suggested.”

“Nice. And you’re feeling better?”

Hermione blushed. “Yes. Much better thank you. I’m sorry.”

“No more apologising. You’ve said sorry enough.”

“Right, I’m sorry.”

Harry raised an eyebrow.

“I mean, yes. I’ll stop doing that.” Hermione looked around the reasonably empty library. “So, are you just here to read, or?”

“I wanted to bounce some ideas off you actually.”

Hermione’s eyes lit up again. “Of course!”

Harry proceeded to tell her about his talk with Lucius Malfoy, about the muggleborn situation, and about Malfoy’s assertion that he was an isolationist.

“Well, basically everyone in the Wizarding World is isolationist, really,” Hermione eventually said. “The ISS makes everyone an isolationist by law. But yes, I do see that there are different levels. I suppose you are kinda isolationist in a way …” She thought for a few moments. “But it makes perfect sense for you to be,” she continued. “If everyone had the stuff Mum and Dad do, there wouldn’t be any advantage in having it.”

“It would certainly be more convenient to keep things like that, yes,” Harry said, “But I’ve been thinking about it, and … I don’t know. There’s a serious problem with maintaining the statute. It didn’t fall in the last timeline, but it was under serious strain. Part of me wonders if it might be better to simply move all the wizards in the world to a new place and create an independent nation for them.”

Hermione listened with rapt attention.

“Then if the statute ever did fall, there wouldn’t be a witch-hunt situation, because the wizards would all be out of the country. The muggle ICW has systems in place for integrating new countries. If it started early enough, we could even take all the magical buildings with us. But there’s only really one place this would work, and that’s Antarctica. Muggles have never colonised it because of how inhospitable it is.”

“—But we have warming charms!” Hermione jumped in, excitedly. “Large-scale ones using wards! They could melt the ice and expose ground for growing crops and stuff! Antarctica’s huge! It could easily hold all the magicals in the world, and all the magical creatures, and more! Harry, this could really work!”

Harry made a non-committal gesture. “It could. Although I suspect it’s politically impossible. But even if we thought it was a good idea, we certainly wouldn’t announce it like that, which still leaves the problem of how I should best position the Gray.”

Hermione hesitated. “I’m not really sure about that. I mean, that’s up to you. You know best.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In Le Petit Magik, Sirius Black put down his wine goblet. “And now, for some reason, the Gray are delaying the third reading of the Muggle Protection Act and it might not even see a vote until the next session. I suspect the Dark are getting to them.”

On the other side of the table, Sirius’ best friend, Lord James Potter, looked thoughtful. He was sitting in exactly the same spot as when he’d had lunch with Arthur. It was his favourite spot. “The Dark do seem likely,” he said, taking a bite of his mostly-eaten beef wellington. “This does put our plans backwards a lot. Arthur’s a good man, but he can occasionally put his foot right in it.”

“I think you don’t give him enough credit. Lord Slytherin is notoriously difficult to pin down, and putting together that partnership couldn’t have been easy.”

“Still haven’t met him?”

“Slytherin? No.”

“What about this Slytherin Gala thing coming up? Going?”

Sirius grimaced. “I don’t think I really have a choice.”

“Oh, why?”

“Alex would throw a fit if we didn’t.”

“I thought Alex swung with Lucius’ son these days.” James’ expression briefly resembled someone entering a dirty bathroom.

“Harry promises me he’s got the situation under control.”

“You’re relying on Harry to reign in Alex? I’m not sure how to feel about that.”

“You and me both, Prongs. But what choice do I have? Harry is the only one Alex listens to even a bit these days.”

“What are you going to do if she stays with her current ‘friends’?”

Sirius looked incredibly uncomfortable. “I don’t know. What can I do?”

“Set her up with someone more suitable?”

Sirius glared at his friend. “I refuse. Not after what happened to Jezebel.”

James looked contrite. “Sorry. I didn’t mean to bring up bad memories.”

“Forgiven.” Sirius put down his fork and knife and waved down a waiter for the bill. “What about the Muggle Protection Act?”

“Tricky.” James finished his wine and put the now empty glass down on the table. “Maybe I’ll have a word with Bentley. He always seems to know what’s going on.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Harry and Daphne were walking around the great lake. This was de rigueur for young wizards and witches who found themselves betrothed, for one reason or another, but most other wizards and witches generally didn’t discuss matters of high-level legislative policy that might actually soon become the law of the land.

Eventually, however, their discussions turned to matters closer to hand.

“Daphne, do you think I’m pushing Hermione too hard?”

Daphne shook her head. She’d recently switched over to wearing her winter robes—long, burnt orange, and cashmere, trimmed with puffskein fur. Such things weren’t technically necessary with warming charms, but no one ever accused fashion of being too logical. The grass underfoot crinkled beneath her booted heels.

“Hermione pushes herself,” Daphne said. “You merely don’t stop her.”

“No, that’s not what I mean. Hermione is a genius, but lately I’ve noticed her thinking has become … Argh, I’m trying to find the right words. It’s very ‘inside the box?’ ” Harry snapped his fingers. “No! It’s inside my box. That’s what I mean—inside my box. I’ll bring her a problem and she’ll think about it only in terms of the parameters I already gave her. Or, if I suggest an idea, her next idea will always be a riff off of it. The only times I get pure Hermione thoughts are when I give her nothing and let her think 100% by herself. And that can be okay, but …”

“… But you’d prefer if she were a bit more open in her thinking, and you’re worried that your constant pushing to better herself is causing her to align her thoughts too closely with yours?”

“Yes, but I’m mostly worried I might have pushed things too far on her birthday. I didn’t have to show her any of that stuff from the last timeline. I could have just let her live out the whole rest of her life not knowing.”

Daphne sighed. “Harry, do you remember what Ginny said when you asked her how she was feeling under that hate potion keyed to you? She said she felt, ‘Horrible,’ and that she could, ‘See everything clear as day. Your manipulativeness, your calculation, and the way you don’t care about anyone that you don’t consider to be yours.’ But she also said that she liked that stuff. Hermione is the same way. She likes the bad parts of you too. They are what keep us all safe.”

Daphne turned around to face Harry. “Did you need to show Hermione that stuff on her birthday? That depends. One thing I’ve always most respected about you, Harry, is your honesty. You don’t keep secrets from us, unless there’s a very good reason, and even then, it’s usually just because you’re waiting for a good time rather than because you intend to keep us in the dark forever. Showing Hermione the truth was completely in alignment with the part of you that makes you, you.”

Daphne took Harry’s hands in hers. “But on the other hand, no, it wasn’t needed. We’re not children anymore, Harry. You don’t need to keep hammering the nail into the wood when it’s already lodged in right up to the head. We’re not going to abandon you. Hermione least of all.”

Harry took a deep, shuddery breath. “Thank you, Daphne. You are right, of course. I need to change my mindset. It’s just very difficult sometimes …” He trailed off.

Daphne slowly hugged him. “I know. If you want, let me keep an eye on the rest of the girls. You just keep working on keeping us safe, being a good friend, and a good betrothed.”

Harry hugged her back. “Yes, I think that’s a good idea. Thanks, Daph.” They held the hug for several more moments before Harry broke away. “On that note, I now need to go meet up with Hermione to make sure she’s not overdoing the occlumency again.”

Daphne smiled. “Okay. I’m going to meet up with Tracey and talk to some of the older students who want something. Good luck.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The Founders Club meeting room, was once again in use.

More muggleborns from upper years had been turning up lately, although they’d all been told that they couldn’t stick around for the occlumency training until they’d signed the same deal as the second years had. Some had signed. Some hadn’t. Those that had were going through the basic exercises with each other, guided by Justin and Sophie.

Hermione, meanwhile, sat at the teacher’s desk and glared at the old book in front of her—the book Harry had given her, and whose magical code she needed to crack before she could even think about translating the old Mesoamerican scripts contained within. She placed her hand on the cover again, sunk into her occlumency, extended her magic sensing, and thought, once more, ‘how do I open you?’

And once more, the thought came back, ‘you speak my secret, oh flower of magic.’

That was all she had to go on. It could have been much worse. The requirement to decode the book might have been the crying of a newborn prince on the last light of Halloween. It might have been the blood of a virgin, born under a blue moon by star-crossed lovers, one of whom had once won the Grand National. It might have been just about anything. That didn’t make her current problem of a practically endless combination of possibilities any less problematic. Harry was unlikely to be pleased if she hurt herself again.

At that moment, the classroom door opened.

A couple of heads turned towards it, until they saw it was Harry, at which point they turned back to whatever it was they were doing. Hermione smiled brightly at him as he quickly made his way over and cast a few basic privacy charms—the kind it was at least plausible for him to know. “Harry! How was your walk with Daphne?”

“Relaxing. How’s your brain holding up?”

“Fine. I haven’t been putting as much of my magic into calculation as I was, and I’m taking regular breaks whenever I start to feel tired.”

“Do you mind if I take a look?”

“Of course not.”

Hermione felt Harry’s legilimency probe brush over her mind. A shiver shot down her back as she opened herself to him and let him in. A few moments later he pulled out.

“Good. You seem to have fully recovered.”

Hermione beamed.

They spent a little while after that discussing Hermione’s progress in her various projects, including the Founders Club. Harry watched the students practice while she filled him in.

“I want to start them on wandless magic soon, but I’m not sure which spells should come first. The stunning spell? Like we did?”

“Have them start on the summoning spell.”

“Oh! Right, that makes sense.”

They watched Colin Creevey and Annabel Entwhistle gasp as they both disconnected from each other, and then broke out in furious blushes.

“Anything else, my lord?” Hermione asked.

“There is one thing actually, yes. I’ve decided it’s time for you to undergo a series of special mental exercises designed to further improve your mental abilities.”

Hermione perked up. “That’s wonderful.”

“You remember the discussion we had about colonising Antarctica?”

“Oh, yes!”

“I want you to come up with a list of reasons why my idea is a terrible one—practical, strategic, ethical, symbolic, magical, etc. Then come up with a better one by yourself. No help from others.”

Hermione’s face slowly shifted from enthusiasm to confusion. “I … I …” Then it shifted to determination. “But Harry, your idea clearly is the best.”

Harry shrugged. “Nevertheless, this is all part of the exercise. I know you won’t let me down.”

Hermione hesitated before her face firmed. “I won’t, Harry.”

Harry’s face softened. “But make sure you don’t hurt yourself again, right?”

“Right.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“So, what do you think about the progress being made on the Muggle Protection Act?” James asked. He was sitting in a plush leather armchair, sipping on a glass of brandy.

Opposite him, Mister Bentley smiled. “Well, obviously it is a good idea. And we at the ministry welcome your efforts to make our jobs easier. As for progress … I understand the Dark will be meeting sometime next week to hammer out their own amendments and alteration to the act.”

“How do you know that?” James shot back, surprise evident on his face.

“I know,” Bentley said calmly. “Now whatever alterations they make are obviously going to be unacceptable, but the Gray may not see things that way.”

“So, what would you suggest?”

Bentley smiled again. “Don’t you worry about a thing, Lord Potter. I suggest you leave it all to me.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Lord Lucius Malfoy, this court finds you guilty of behaviour likely to cause a class C breach of the International Statute of Secrecy. Normally, this would result in your doing a small amount of time in Azkaban, however, owing to your esteemed position in our society, and the many positive contributions you have rendered to the magical community in general, we are instead sentencing you to community service, the exact details of which shall be decided by the committee assigned to your case.” Madam Marchbanks banged her gavel. “Do you have anything you wish to add?”

Standing in front of the small group of judges, wearing his finest wizarding robes, holding his silver snakes head cane, and standing proud and tall, Lord Malfoy slowly nodded. “I live to serve, your honours. This will be no different.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Not far into the forbidden forest (just far enough for it to not be forbidden), Harry was watching Luna feed the thestrals with strips of raw meat while explaining to her the relocate-everyone-to-Antarctica concept.

“It’s a nice idea, Harry,” Luna said, gently patting one of the thestrals on the back while it and another ripped a chunk of flesh in two. “I love snow. It’s pretty.”

Harry smiled. “But?”

“But it could take decades. We might not have that much time.”

“Mmmmm. …” Harry tapped his chin. “So what would you suggest?”

“Do you care about everyone?”

Harry thought about that. “No, not really,” he said. “Just those that matter to me.”

“Who matters to you?”

“You do—you and Daphne, Hermione, and Ginny—even Alex—your parents too—Tracey and some of the lords of the Gray and their families … Clare, as well, a bit.”

Luna nodded. “That’s a good place to start. I suggest not trying to build a place for everyone. That will take far too long, and most won’t go along with it anyway. I suggest just focus on making our home, Gairsay Island, as protected as possible—a little oasis in a sea of chaos—capable of surviving anything anyone throws at it—a fortress—a home.”

Harry smiled. “Wise words. Thank you, Luna.”

“I live to serve you, my lord.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Hermione was almost ripping her carefully straightened hair out in frustration. She just couldn’t see how she was supposed to move on from where she was. The password could be anything, and—

“You’re getting stressed again,” Daphne said lightly from the other side of Hermione’s trunk. She was a few pages into yet another of her muggle strategy books.

“I know!” Hermione groaned. “But I’m not sure what to do next. I’ve tried everything in the magical books on code-breaking. Is there some other kind of brain-dead obvious way of magically cracking a password that I, being just a stupid muggleborn, still don’t know about?”

Daphne pursed her lips. “None that Iknow of. Why don’t you ask Harry for help?”

“I can’t do that! Harry is relying on me to solve this. I’m sure he could solve it if he had the time, but he doesn’t. That’s why he needs me.”

“What about your other project? How’s that going?”

Hermione hesitated. She’d spent half an hour the previous night thinking of ways that Harry’s idea was a bad one, but every time she came up with a reason, there was always another idea she came up with for how that problem could be solved.

Rising sea levels caused by melting ice? Simply grow the glaciers around the settlement instead of sending it out into the ocean. Concentrating magicals together making them more vulnerable to muggle long-range weaponry? Develop physical shield wards capable of stopping even a nuclear warhead. There must be a lot possible with so much magic concentrated in such a small space, instead of spread out across the entire planet.

Hermione shook her head and focused back on the problem in front of her. Then her eyes fell on the title of the strategy book Daphne was reading.

The Intelligence and Counter-intelligence of World War II—Enigma

Enigma! Hermione launched herself from her chair—“Give me that!”—and snatched the book from Daphne’s hands.

“Hey! That’s a Slytherin Library Book!”

“Article 1-G of the Granger-Slytherin Vassalage Contract—MAAN House Slytherin will grant House Granger unfiltered access to the Slytherin Library.”

“Yes, but not while I’m still reading it!”

Hermione ignored her, along with her subsequent muttered comments about making Hermione’s next hour of required service, under article 2-C of the same contract, shovelling dragon dung in the Hogwarts greenhouses. Instead, she flipped through the book’s table of contents, quickly zeroing in on the relevant sections. Hermione sighed. Of course, she thought. Just how dumb was she? Just because a muggle method didn’t work before didn’t mean there was no muggle method that might prove useful now.

—End of Chapter Forty-five—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: The Hermione story line continues! This chapter was drafted, and made available early, on the leadvone discord server. The first draft part of the next chapter has already been made available the same way (along with a lot of reader discussion). www.discord.me/LeadVonE

A/N: The discord channel now has over six-hundred members and a load of people have made a whole lot of fan-content—fiction and art based off of Dodging Prison and Stealing Witches. Up until recently these have been hosted on the DP&SW wiki, but we now have a more permanent solution on the leadvone website. Check it out by heading over the website, and using the drop-down menu titled ‘fan content.’

Sticky Note: If you want to keep abreast of the release schedule, as well as any changes and the occasional piece of bonus content, you can head over to www.leadvone.com and sign up for the Gray Mailing List.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Hermione’s Quest—Part Three

The dining room of Malfoy Manor was alive with the buzz of conversation and the soft clinking of glasses and cutlery. Every seat of the long hardwood table was filled, and every plate was almost clean. Every so often, a house elf wearing a clean pillowcase would pop in, gather up the finished dinner and pop back out.

Lord Malfoy sat at the head of the table, in the seat in which he had once sat, and surveyed the lords of the Dark. There were around twenty of them—not all thirty-eight the Dark could call on in the Wizengamot, but plenty for their purposes here tonight. Nott and Parkinson were on his right, and Yaxley and Burke on his left. Further down, Wiggs and Travers were talking animatedly with Charmer and Ballyrun. Lord Genesis—a rather on-the-nose name for Magical Britain’s only Vampire Lord—drank from his glass of pure red liquid, whilst listening politely to Lord Zazo, whose family had been cursed several centuries back to always speak with a lisp.

Then there were Lords Flagley and Selwyn who both lived in Upper Flagley and were as inseparable as brothers. Upper Flagley wasn’t a large wizarding community, at only just over one hundred wands, but it did produce the indisputably best wizarding cheese in the whole country.

And on the other side of the table sat Lord Struttsworth and Lord Knock—the first owning several brothels around the country, including the one in Knockturn Alley, and the latter owning and running the auction house, among various other enterprises.

Lords Womp and Vablatsky were a herbologist and a seer, respectively.

The Noble House of Threesickle traditionally always married Selkies from a colony off the coast of Holyhead and had a slight blue tint to their skin—even Lord Threesickle himself, who also wore a long cloak of seal fur, and everyone knew whose fur it was.

Finally, there were Lords Puddlemere and Rosier. Lord Puddlemere owned quite a few of the commercial and residential buildings in the Puddlemere enclave, while Lord Rosier … At that moment, Malfoy caught Rosier’s faintly glowing yellow eyes and had to suppress a shudder, instead turning it quickly into a nod.

Rosier seemed to take that as an indication that business was about to start, because he broke off his discussion with Puddlemere and turned to watch him. One by one, the other lords of the Dark also fell into silence and turned towards him, each face looking expectant—convenient, since he did, in-fact, want to get things underway.

Lucius let the silence drag on for a moment before he began. “As you know, I have called us all here tonight because of the Muggle Protection Act.”

“Outrageous, it is!” Selwyn burst out.

“Yes, Selwyn, thank you—if I could be allowed to get through this without interruption? Now as I was saying, the Muggle Protection Act was due to be voted on last week. You may have noticed this didn’t happen. That is because I met with Lord Slytherin and persuaded him that we—that is to say, the Dark—might be able to add something of value to the proceedings.”

This caused surprised mutterings down the table.

“You met Slytherin?” Vablatsky asked. “What’s he like?”

“You mean, you don’t know?” Puddlemere said, incredulous.

“My sight cannot see him.”

“Gentlemen.” Lucius put his hands up. “Focus, please. Yes, I met him. It was not easy setting up a private meeting, but I succeeded. We talked and we acknowledged that there were many points that the Gray and the Dark could agree on, and that if we came up with an alternative Muggle Protection Act that they might well support it instead of the Light’s version.”

Silence. Many of the eyes around the table regarded him with incredulity.

Then the Vampire Lord, Genesis, started to chuckle. “You mean to say that you, the protectors of blood purity and wizarding culture, are going to sell out to this newcomer’s power plays and push a muggle progressive act in the name of lessening the damage the Light would cause by themselves?”

Lucius gritted his teeth. “Yes, that is exactly what I am saying.”

“But why should we have to put up with this?!” Selwyn interrupted again. “We didn’t put up with this when he was around.”

“He was a Dark Lord, Selwyn.”

“Well, you are sitting in his chair.”

“This is my house. This chair is my chair—a chair my grandfather graciously gave up to our lord whenever he wished to make use of this room. I am a lord of the Dark, like you. I am not a Dark Lord. Do any of you wish to claim the mantle of Dark Lord?” He glared around the table. There were roughly equal concentrations of amused, neutral, and angry faces. No one, however, spoke, not even Rosier or Genesis. “Well then,” he continued, “until our lord has returned to us, we will continue to fight within the system as lords of the Wizengamot ought.”

“What about his phylactery?” Selwyn asked, apparently unwilling to let this go. “Has any progress been made finding it?”

“None yet,” Lucius said, smoothly. “Now, I have written up a list of all the points in the current act along with notes of what are obviously the biggest problems with it.” Parchments appeared in front of all the lords around the table.

“What is this?!” snapped Struttsworth, pointing at one of the lines with a long, bony finger. “You want to allow muggleborns to keep muggle artefacts they owned as children?!”

“I want nothing of the sort,” Malfoy snapped back. “But we have to make concessions on something.”

“The Dark Lord would not approve.”

“I’m sure he wouldn’t. But I’m sure he’d approve far less of, for example, giving muggles the right to stand as witnesses in trials against wizards. Or making it law that whenever wizards wish to permanently relocate to the wizarding world, pensieve copies of all their muggle relatives’ memories be kept on file in case they ‘change their mind’ later, Struttsworth.”

Struttsworth glared sharply at him.

“Have I made my point?” Lucius asked.

“Crystal,” Struttsworth bit back.

“Good.”

It took hours upon hours of bickering, arguing, and back and forth before they had anything even remotely like a consensus. Even then, it would need much more work before they were ready to show it to the leaders of the Gray. After the lords of the Dark all filed out of the Malfoy dining room, heading towards the floo, and home, a side door opened, and Lady Narcissa stepped through. Her normally immaculate robes were slightly dusty.

“Well?” Lucius asked.

“I get the feeling the only reason Rosier didn’t jump to take your chair when you asked is because the Dark Lord is not fully gone.”

“Genesis?”

“He won’t step up. He’s had three hundred years to take a leadership position beyond his own kind, and he never has.”

“Yaxley? Charmer?”

“Yaxley would not take such a risk by himself. He is a follower, not a leader. Charmer does not lack in skill, but he has too many ties to the Gray and the Light. All the best candidates to take on the mantle of Dark Lord are in Azkaban, and they’d never take a title that they believe he-who-must-not-be-named still holds the right to.”

“So, barring his actual return, we really are relying on Virgo.”

“Or possibly our niece.”

Lucius nodded. “Or possibly our niece.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

—Captain’s log 01 AD 1042—

With the blessings of the wind of magic, my crew and I are leaving the Court of the Feathered Serpent as the sun rises on the ocean, with much celebration and merrymaking, to travel back to our homeland, laden with as many golden objects from the lands beyond the isle as a king of old might have children.

This venture has been more successful than I could have ever believed and I will see it through. Grandfather was right to put his faith in me. The people we met were most accommodating and I will long miss the warmth and generosity they, and especially the women, showed me and my crew. The city was truly a magical place, full of the most intricate of enchantments—like the great hall of Hogwarts, but in every house, and every public place. Even the majesty of Constantinople does not compete.

I am not entirely bereft of company, however. As well as gold, the feathered lord granted us Akna to accompany us and to act as a navigator to guide us through the dangerous magics that almost sunk us on our way here. She is quite delightful and her youth and energy brightens the spirit of everyone on board. I count myself lucky we travel not on a longship poor of magic where there would be no space available to enjoy her charms.

—Captain’s log 05 AD 1042—

Land sighted. Our journey through the magic of the sea that protects the feathered lord is complete, thank magic, for our food is not infinite and our skins need refilling.

Akna is quite happy to see land again. She tells me that while she oft travelled the sea as a little girl, this is the first time she has ever been away from home for more than a night. I find myself immensely pleased that it is only I she can confide these little secrets to.

As soon as we land we will try to find the tribe we traded with on our way here.

—Captain’s log 06 AD 1042—

Our landing did not go well. While we did at first succeed in re-filling our skins with water from a river, we could not find the people we had previously traded with. Instead we were met with men armed with spears and arrows and when we tried to communicate our desire to trade, they laughed. I guess they felt they had the advantage because they outnumbered us four to one, but they only had one magic user, and he did not possess a wand.

Indeed, as I have oft noted on this journey, while men and women back home regard a wizard’s wand as a symbol of power to be feared and respected, here it might as well just be a stick of wood. This is unfortunate since if they truly knew the power we wield they surely wouldn’t be so foolish as to attack us.

Attack us they did, however, and we were forced to react in kind.

By the end, all but a few of their people lay dead at our feet and the few who escaped would surely either never return, or else bring numbers so vast that not even our powers could save us.

We were not entirely without casualties though. Muir was impaled with a spear and Owen could not weave his healing magics quickly enough to stop him passing over to the other side. We burned his body on the beach before setting off again. Akna cried. Although they could not speak with each other, Muir was a gentle man and his death hits her hard.

—Captain’s log 07 AD 1042—

The mood onboard is grim. Muir was particularly gifted with weather magics and his loss leaves us open to the whim of every ragged rain cloud and gust of wind. Akna still hasn’t found herself again and her mood spreads throughout the men like dragon-pox. We see many people along the coast—they stare at us out of bushes and watch us before disappearing again, but we dare not land while the memory of our recent battle is fresh.

I find myself hoping Akna feels better soon. Things are better when she is happy, but I also know I cannot allow myself the luxury of such weak and feminine feelings. My crew is relying on me to see us home and it will be by the skill of seamanship and the power of our magics that will deliver us safely. Not hopeful feelings or happy thoughts.

—Captain’s log 09 AD 1042—

Finally. As the morning sun rose, we saw a welcome sight on the shore. The tribe we previously traded with stood on beach waving and shouting at us with great fanfare and cheer.

I was cautious, and we all approached fully ready to pull back if it looked like they would turn aggressive, but we had no reason to fear. Luckily, one of their number had some limited knowledge of a language that Akna also knew, and so we were able to learn that the men that had attacked us, and whom we had then slaughtered, were long enemies of these people—that these people had been forced off those lands, and that we were now ‘forever friends’ of them.

I don’t know about ‘forever friends’ but we much appreciated the good cheer that followed. The chief even offered to marry off his daughter to me. Akna advised that I refuse and I couldn’t help but laugh. The fierce look in her eyes after many days of sadness warmed my heart more than any warming charm could.

—Captain’s log 12 AD 1042—

After several days with the people here we are ready to move on. Our food supplies are refilled again and with more than just fish. We have a long way to go, but I’m happy to be moving on again. One person who does not seem unhappy to see us leave is these people’s wizard. I rather think he didn’t appreciate the competition.

—Captain’s log 89 AD 1042—

The seas have become much colder now, much more like the waters around home. The shoreline is thick with trees as large around the base as three grown men standing with arms stretched. This is good. It won’t be long until we strike out into open ocean, and from there it’s on to Greenland, then Iceland, and then to the shores of home.

—Captain’s log 94 AD 1042—

Oh magic, I pride myself on my bravery and unwillingness to back down in the face of fear, but I don’t think I’ve ever been more scared in my life. Akna, bless her. Thank the feathered lord for gifting us with her. We were rowing through the small ice islands that speckle this sea like little gems when we all felt it—a creeping feeling of fear and dread. Now, I’ve heard the tales and learned the sagas—I am not some ignorant peasant who knows not the difference between a demon and a ghost. But when a faceless figure in tattered black robes started to descend on our boat, causing the very water around our craft to freeze and our oars to stick fast, I felt a primal terror grip my soul like I’ve never felt, and I was not the only one.

That was, until Akna screamed something I did not understand in a language I did not know, and a magnificent glowing white serpent coiled out from around her outstretched hand and launched itself at the monster, which screamed in rage or fear, I could not tell which, and retreated from our boat, leaving us free to break the ice around us and keep on rowing.

I don’t think I will look at that girl quite the same way again. Although her heart is too fair to kill a man in combat, she is still truly a warrior.

—Captain’s log 95 AD 1042—

We have arrived in Greenland to much everyone’s relief. We did not see any more of the robed monster that approached us in the frigid seas around us, and I for one hope to never see such a foul being again. I have commanded the men to keep the gold we carry hidden from the eyes of the locals and their rare wizard that make this land their home, for I do not believe the wands we proudly display would stay the hand of these folk in the face of such vast wealth and treasure.

Akna stands fascinated by the ways of the settlement we are staying within, having seen little of these traditions and customs while on the boat.

I find myself looking forward to life back at Hogwarts, to the great hall, and to the cooking of Lady Hufflepuff’s servants.

—Captain’s log 96 AD 1042—

This sunrise we left the shores of Greenland after ensuring our food and water supplies sufficiently full. It is another hard row to Iceland, but I have friends there. The water is calm. And I don’t foresee any problems from here out.

—Captain’s log 97 AD 1042—

Oh, praise Merlin and Woden. Such joy. Akna has confided in me this morning that she is with child. I could not be more happy. The sun is bright and the seas are tranquil. It is as though the skies sing their praises to me.

—Captain’s log 98 AD 1042—

I have begun proper instruction for Akna in Danish, Latin, and Welsh, as well as the proper role of a lady within the Albion. Her time on board has prepared her well, and her quick mind and focused spirit serves her too. I am not sure what will be Grandfather’s reaction to Akna’s condition, but I am determined to see that she takes the honourable path rather than be cast out as a low woman. That would not do at all. We expect to reach Iceland before sundown, Fate willing.

—Captain’s log 101 AD 1042—

We leave Iceland in high spirits. The men were well pleased to be back on dry land again, and to taste the meat of reindeer again, rather than the flesh of fish. We have only four more days to the Sheep Islands and then another three to the shores of Caledonia.

—Captain’s log 102 AD 1042—

Thor’s mighty hammer has stuck the seas and plunged us into battle with the waves. I cannot write long. I am needed.

—Captain’s log 106 AD 1042—

Finally, the storm has cleared. We are far off course, but with luck we would be several days to the south, and not far out into the great ocean.

[MANY MISSING ENTRIES]

—Captain’s log ? AD 1042—

I write these words perched atop a rock on the coast of what I pray to be Caledonia. My ship is lost. All my crew is lost. It was a dragon. As long and again as the boat, black as midnight and evil as Morgana. How was I to know we had strayed into the Hebrides? Into the cursed islands.

Everything we brought back with us from the world beyond the great ocean, everything save this one cup that I foolishly snatched before the beast descended, and which almost resulted in my joining my men through the veil, everything lost. The only other treasure I was able to save was Akna. She sits by my side, crying. If Muir’s death hit her hard, it was nothing to this. I suspect the only reason we were spared was because the dragon, being of the nature of snake, heard something of itself in myself and Akna when we called out to it.

The others were all eaten.

I can still hear the crunch of bone when I close my eyes.

I do not know how long we held our own in the water, but there is no doubt that without both our magics we would surely have been lost too.

—Captain’s log 121 AD 1042—

This will be my last entry. Grandfather has ordered that all records of this sorry expedition be sealed away behind wards that only those of the Noble House of Slytherin may access. My only consolation is that he has accepted Akna to be my bride. Her magics fascinate him. But I fear that had she not been a speaker, he would not have done so, even with his great-grandchild growing in her womb. When the time comes, I’m sure she will make a formidable Lady Slytherin.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Deep inside Hermione’s magical trunk, the young witch in question replaced the captain’s log back where it belonged, next to a dozen or so other books taken from the Slytherin hidey-hole by the sea.

Cracking the code had been relatively easy once she’d applied psychology to the problem. The only way the Allies had managed to crack the German enigma code during World War Two had been because of human error, like choosing very easy-to-guess passcodes. The magical password to the captain’s diary had turned out to be the 22nd of April 1011—no doubt some date of significance to the long-dead Heir of Slytherin.

After that, it had just been a matter of analysing the three languages in the diary for patterns and teasing out grammar and syntax from the language of the Court of the Feathered Serpent, a language that Hermione had found few parallels to in known native Mesoamerican languages, and which she had decided to call Featherlish—at least, until someone thought of something better.

She’d been helped in no small part by a biography of Jean-François Champollion, the man who’d translated the original Rosetta Stone, as well as her own basic arithmancy occlumency.

The week following her successful translation had been spent delving deep into the Featherlish books left behind, most of which turned out to be written by Akna Slytherin over the course of her life. They contained everything she could remember about the magic she’d learned back in her homeland. Fascinated, Hermione could see the basic versions of some of the spells that Hogwarts now taught their students—not many by any stretch, but certainly a few. But spells weren’t the only things about her homeland that Akna wrote.

Hermione read the story of the founding of the Court of the Feathered Serpent—about the wizards of Central and South America, who’d decided to close themselves off from the non-magical world, a whole 1,500 years before the ISS was enacted. She read of the raising of a whole island far out to sea off the coast of Cuba, the magical protections their god-king rulers had gifted the island, and the great city they built there—a monument to the wonders of magic, where farms floated in the sky and honey flowed in streams next to water as clear as crystal.

She read of their culture—their religion, sports, food, and politics, occasionally picking up just a hint of melancholy from the gradually maturing woman—melancholy for a world she’d left behind years before and to which she’d never return.

Hermione had read all this and more for a week solid, hardly ever coming out of her trunk, even taking her meals in there, only making appearances for classes, turning up with slightly fuzzy hair, and leaving again the moment the bell rang.

She’d also read of the methods this society used to maintain their total isolation, methods she’d never considered when she’d so assuredly told Harry that his idea for an independent magical nation was unquestionably a good idea. The Feathered Court didn’t have memory charms, so they had no way to fix problems among the non-magical population, if needed. This resulted in a policy of taking muggleborn children from their homes by force the moment magic was detected by their seers. Sometimes the parents would even be murdered, and in those circumstances where the child was too old to be integrated into magical society without extreme resentment on the part of the child, the child too, was killed. Better that, the logic went, than accept disruptive elements into their carefully balanced order.

Hermione sat down in her reading chair and put her hands under her chin.

Obviously, they, that is to say, modern wizard-kind, had memory charms, so if they were going to totally isolate themselves, they wouldn’t need to resort to murder, but was it right to just steal muggleborn babies from their parents? It didn’t feel right.

But Harry would have obviously already thought of that, because he was Harry, so he must believe it was okay. And if Harry thought it was okay, then it must be okay. After all, it’s not like the biological parents would know about it, and the child could be memory-charmed until adulthood, or even longer, if they wished.

But how would she, Hermione, have felt if she’d never grown up knowing her mum and dad? She didn’t like that idea. Not at all.

But on the other hand, Harry had told her to find problems with his idea. Maybe this was what he meant?

Whatever the case, it definitely needed more thought.

At that moment, the trunk lid opened, Hermione looked up, and Harry’s legs appeared, followed shortly by the rest of him. “Long time no see,” he commented with a smile.

“Hi, Harry.” Hermione pushed aside her thoughts for the moment and focused on the here and now. She had something to show him. What was it?

“Oh, yes!” she jumped out of her chair, just as Harry reached the bottom of the stairs. “I cracked it!”

“I thought you cracked it ages ago?”

“Yes—no—yes, but no. Look, I maybe figured out where the boat filled with gold is! And I figured out how much gold it contains!”

Harry perked up. “Oh?”

“Yes! Using the navigational readings and ocean current maps, I think it might have settled around the Anton Dohrn Seamount. That’s around two hundred kilometres off where you have your cave vault—five hundred from Gairsay Island. If it didn’t, it’ll have slammed against the Rockall Plateau. As for the gold, there’s a passage in the diary where captain Slytherin says they have as many gold objects as a king of old might have children! A bit of a strange unit of measurement, but I guess people weren’t as exact back then. Well, I went to the history section and did a survey of old kings, but the only two I could find who had unusually large numbers of children were Ramessees II with 162, and Qin Shi Huang who had fifty—so I took an average of the two, and by that calculation, the captain means they have around 106 gold objects, which might have a market value of around 600,000 galleons—around £30,000,000.”

Harry whistled. “Very well done, Hermione.”

“Thank you, Harry.” Hermione was beaming.

“Six hundred thousand galleons,” Harry muttered. “Five hundred kilometres, you say?”

“About that.”

Harry was silent in thought for a moment. “Then I think I should talk to your mum and dad,” he eventually said. “Maybe the prototype they’ve been working on for MaCUSA is ready for a real-world test run …”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“The tripping hex,” whispered Professor Severus Snape, “is a basic tool in the wizard’s arsenal. Used correctly, it can cause an opponent to lose situational awareness for the precious second required to land a decisive blow. Used incorrectly, it is a frivolous waste of time, giving your opponent a free strike at your body, during which you will most certainly die.”

At the front of the classroom sat Virgo Malfoy, watching the man whom Lord Malfoy had assured him was a triple agent for his other self, confident in his ability to look attentive, while actually being bored out of his skull.

“This hex is best used in conjunction with—”

A shield breaker, thought Julia in a sing-song voice.

“—a shield breaker … for maximum results. Unless your opponent has no need for shield charms, in which case—”

You will most certainly diiiieeeeee.

“—You will most certainly die.”

You are also bored, Virgo thought.

Soooo bored, Julia thought back. Can’t we do something more interesting?

Like?

I don’t know. Something new!

Something new, hmm?Virgo cast his gaze around the classroom falling briefly on Alexandra Black of the Dark, bookended on either side by twin daughters of the House of Carrow, before finally landing on the enigmatic Ginevra Weasley, sat next to Luna Lovegood, the whore. If learning magic is not enough, he thought,how about drama? You witches are supposed to love that.

Okay?

Virgo smirked. Prepare yourself, little girl.

Hey! You’re also a little—

And the world went dark.

They talk about a foggy mind, but this was quite literally so.

And then the fog cleared, leaving Virgo standing in the middle of the Slytherin common room, his body a ghostly outline in a much more opaque memory—his original body. Julia appeared by his side a moment later, almost two heads shorter than him.

Virgo smirked down at her. “You were saying?”

“This isn’t real.” Julia pouted up at him. “You lost that body sixty years ago. You can be an almost teenage girl or an old man, but not both. Choose.”

“I have already chosen, little girl. I chose to be an immortal Dark Lord.”

Julia huffed. “Where are we anyway? Why are there snakes everywhere?”

“This is the Slytherin common room, as seen just over sixty years ago.”

“Really?” Julia’s eyes widened.

“Yes. Now, watch, and learn.”

Julia looked around the room. Everywhere, Slytherin students sat in armchairs, or stood around in small groups, whispering. Everything was tense, like before a race on sports day.

This is no race, Virgo thought.

“Well, what is it?” Julia asked out loud.

“A coup.”

A large door opened and an older student stepped through. The room hushed as he entered. He took a few steps into the room, looked around, and called out, “Where is he?!”

Silence.

“WHERE IS HE?! If that little shit doesn’t show himself, I am going to—”

The older student didn’t get through another few words before many gasps from around the room stilled him. In the middle of the room, where before there had been only empty space, now stood the cloaked figure of Tom—the Tom Riddle of the memory, several years younger than the Tom Julia was used to seeing in Virgo’s memories. Maybe a fourth year?

“Third year, actually,” Virgo said, out-loud.

“You learned to turn yourself invisible in third year? I thought the syllabus didn’t teach that spell until the end of seventh year?”

Virgo’s lip curled upwards. “Well remembered, but if you wish to achieve true power you must always be a step ahead of those who keep a step ahead. Remember that.”

Meanwhile, in the middle of the common room, Memory Tom Riddle had finished casually taking off his cloak and hanging it on a coatrack that had just appeared out of thin air, wooden snakes coiling up the central shaft just as the stone snakes of the room coiled around the pillars.

“See how angry he’s getting?” Virgo said to Julia, who could indeed see that the student by the door was watching the whole display while getting redder and redder in the face. “That’s a good thing. Angry people make mistakes.”

“Isn’t it dangerous making people angry?”

“It can be, when you are significantly less powerful than them, but when you are closer to equals in power, it helps cloud their judgement.”

“ARE YOU FUCKING DONE?!” The older student shouted.

“Mmm?” Memory Tom looked around, “Oh, yes.” He smiled. “What can I help you with?”

“The end spot at the Slytherin table in the great hall is mine! How dare you disrespect me, the Heir of the Noble House of Lestrange, by sitting there.”

“Then you know how you can satisfy your honour,” Memory Tom said.

“What’s going on?” Julia whispered, even though she knew whispering was needless.

“Goading him into a duel,” Virgo said. “He knows he’d be at a disadvantage, and so …”

“Fine!” The Lestrange Heir spat. “But I’m calling in a proxy!”

“Agreed,” Memory Tom said.

Julia could see victory in Memory Tom’s eyes.

“My proxy will be Malfoy!” Lestrange said.

Off to one side, another older boy with shoulder-length blond hair shuffled awkwardly. “Sorry, Rulfarion, I can’t stand in as proxy here. Nothing personal, but I have my reasons.”

Lestrange was caught flat footed for only a moment before he whirled around again, “Knock! Then you—”

“Sorry, mate. I got a letter the other day from my older brother. My hands are tied.”

Lestrange’s face paled. He whirled around again. “Hawking!”

Hawking shook his head.

“Womp! Lupin! Walker! Tempest!” One by one the three wizards and one witch shook their heads. Lestrange turned finally, desperately, to a pretty witch sitting in the middle of the room by the fireplace. “Catherine?”

The girl looked down at her shoes. “I’m sorry Rulf. It’s for the best.”

Lestrange looked broken. Then moments later, that depression turned into a raging fury. He barely held himself together while duelling wards were put up, and lasted only a few rounds into the fight before Memory Tom had him pinned up against a wall, brought down by a well-timed tripping hex.

“Serpensortia!”

All the room, including Julia, let of a shriek as a huge black snake slammed down mere inches from where Lestrange was desperately struggling.

And then, Memory Tom spoke to it. “Coil around him, but do not bite until I say,” he said.

Julia’s eyes widened again. “It’s a magic snake?”

“No,” Virgo replied. “This is a memory, so you are hearing what I remember. It is a magical language called parseltongue, passed down through the Slytherin line for centuries—passed down through the Noble House of Gaunt, until it passed to me.”

The snake had wrapped itself around Lestrange, who was now staring at Tom as though seeing a grim, totally drained of anger, leaving only fear.

“The heir,” he gasped out, while the coils tightened, “of Slytherin.”

“Yes,” Memory Tom drawled. “That’s right.”

“But that’s impossible. The line’s been dead for centuries.”

“I am no mere mudblood, like you all thought,” Tom said, pride peeking through his carefully constructed mask of disdain. “My mother is a Gaunt.”

“That still—makes no—sense,” Lestrange choked.

“Magic works in strange ways. Clearly I have been singled out by Fate for greatness.”

Memory Tom dropped Lestrange from his magic grasp, allowing him to collapse to the floor, while still bound by a hundred kilos of fanged, coiled muscle.

Slowly the room faded back into the cloudy blackness of the mind.

Now, what have you learned? Virgo thought.

That parseltongue is creepy as hell. Do you think I could do it?

An interesting question. We shall have to try it sometime. What else?

That the tripping hex is actually quite useful when your opponent is really angry.

Indeed.

Oh, yes, and that I still hate you.

Virgo mentally smirked. Of course you do, little girl. Of course you do.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

On the other side of the classroom, Ginny sat, watching Virgo Malfoy staring off into space. She really wished Harry would hurry up figuring out how to get the girl out of the diary’s body so they could kill it. Or was that the other way around? So that they could get the diary out of thegirl’s body so they could kill it? That would actually make it even easier.

Not that she was going to let up on her training. She had to learn how to kill and she had to do it fast.

Some time later, as they were making their way out of the defence lesson, the two caught each other’s eyes and Ginny was sure for a moment that she saw a flash of something in the diary’s eyes. Recognition? Knowing? Suspicion? Fear?

Whatever it was, it was just more reason to buckle down and become what she needed to be.

That night found Ginny Weasley alone and invisible in Hagrid’s chicken coup, flashing knife in hand, bloody up to the arms, dead chickens everywhere, and the next morning when the half-giant wandered into the hall, it was to find him complaining that something had been at his chickens again, and that he needed a budget for a better coup.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“600,000 galleons?” asked Alexandra Black, looking between Harry Slytherin and Daphne Greengrass. Greengrass had surreptitiously pulled her aside between classes for a quick chat inside Harry’s trunk. “600,000 galleons is a lot, right?”

“Alex, can I assume your father hasn’t gone over the Black finances with you?” Harry asked, sitting in the armchair opposite hers.

“Him? Not likely. Magic forbid any daughter of his might want to do something worthwhile with her life. I can’t believe I have the same animagus form as him! I’m nothing like him!”

Daphne rolled her eyes. “You should be happy with your form. A grim can be immensely useful—especially for a necromancer.”

“I know that, but still—I’m nothing like him!”

Harry had a whole bunch of parchments in front of him on the low desk between them. He put one of the parchments down and regarded her thoughtfully. “You know, Alex. Lord Black is still your lord—not to mention your father. Having a cordial relationship with him might be a good thing.”

“But he’s unbearable! He treats me like a child—like a muggle child. Do you know what he said to me before I came to Hogwarts? When I asked why I wasn’t going to the same lessons as John, and Susan, and all the others? He said, ‘you don’t need to worry about politics, you should enjoy your childhood.’ As though being left out was helping in any way.”

“Lord Black did have his family’s politics forced on him in a way he didn’t appreciate.”

“But now he’s doing the same to me! Just in the opposite way!”

“Yes, ironic, certainly. And your reaction is just as ironic, since you’re basically doing to him what he did to his own father.”

Alex felt a short, sharp punch in the gut. She stared at the floor before shaking her thoughts away. “That doesn’t change anything. Even if what we’re doing is kinda similar, I’m not going to try and reach out to him. That’s his job! He’s the grown-up. And anyway,”—Alex’s voice took on a bitter tone—“he’s always too busy with work.”

There was silence for a moment before Alex crossed her arms. “I don’t need him. I’m fine by myself. And if I need help … well, I can ask you, can’t I?”

Harry nodded slightly. “I still think you’d do well to explore ways to become closer to Lord Black, but yes, of course. We are friends.”

Alex nodded. “Then what’s this about sunken gold?”

“Hermione thinks she knows where we can find about 600,000 galleons worth of muggle treasure,” Daphne said.

“And you asked if that’s a lot,” Harry continued, “to which, I would say, yes—yes it is a lot. We could buy six Slytherin Manors with that much gold—easily. The GDP of the whole of Magical Britain, by contrast, is about 4.4 million galleons.”

“What’s GDP?” Alex asked.

“Oh, dear Merlin.” Daphne made vaguely frustrated hand gestures. “Actually, I think Alex is right, Harry. Lord Black does have a lot to answer for. GDP is a measure of value created by an economy.”

“So us having liquid assets worth thirteen percent of the value created by the entire country?” Harry said. “Yeah, it’s a big deal.”

Alex’s eyes widened, almost comically large. “You’re saying you could buy thirteen percent of the whole country?”

“No, that’s not what he’s … Argh!” Daphne rubbed her temples. “I can’t believe your father.”

“I know!” Alex said hotly. “I get it! I don’t have all the education an heiress is supposed to have!”

“What it means, loosely,” Harry calmly said, “is that we could buy thirteen percent of all the products and services Magical Britain creates in a year—that includes food, broomsticks, rents, haircuts, and quidditch matches, along with any value the government creates and a few other things added or subtracted for various reasons. That’s not the same thing as the value of all the stuff in the country. That would be a lot more than 4.4 million galleons.”

“But it’s still a lot of money,” Alex said.

“Yes, it is still a lot of money,” Daphne replied. “But look at all these!” She waved a stack of parchments. “Do you know how many people come to us asking for investment? Dozens! And not just heads of houses or individuals, either—even whole cities—asking for ridiculous amounts! Have you seen this one, Harry?” She passed over a parchment. “Cork wants us to help them build an entire new expansion for their enclave.”

“Oh, yes, I remember this,” Harry said. “The ministry was willing to go fifty/fifty with them, but only if they came up with their own funding. One thousand new houses? Plus streets, shops, and magical warding? Do they think I have a philosopher’s stone or something?”

“I wouldn’t be surprised if some people did think that,” Daphne muttered. “And you have to admit, if circumstances had turned out a bit differently, they might have been right.”

“Gringotts has a philosopher’s stone, doesn’t it?” Alex asked. “Why can’t the ministry just order them to make more gold? Then everyone could have as much as they needed.”

“Leaving aside the basic wrongness of that statement, no, they couldn’t,” Harry said, picking up another parchment and quickly scanning it. “The ministry doesn’t control Gringotts. Gringotts is under treaty with the ICW after the fall of the last Magical British Empire. They are, effectively a country within a country, propped up only by the threat of violence from the entire magical world. New money doesn’t come from Gringotts.” Harry paused. “Well, the actual gold does,” he corrected himself. “But the money supply only increases when muggleborns and half-bloods exchange muggle money into galleons. That’s why our currency controls are so tight.”

Harry exchanged a meaningful look with Greengrass, which Alex had to assume meant something, but she wasn’t sure what.

She pouted. “How long is it going to take me to learn all this?”

“To be fair, a lot of this isn’t exactly in the standard noble house curriculum,” Harry said, glancing towards Greengrass. “Something you should probably keep more in mind, Daph.”

Daphne looked slightly abashed.

“Maybe two or three years?” Harry continued, turning back towards Alex. “Daphne, Hermione, and Luna learned a lot quicker, but they also had a lot more free time, whereas you have stuff to do.”

“What about Ginny?”

“Ginny has decided to invest every moment of her free time into combat and infiltration training. She is determined to never be caught out again.” Harry picked up another parchment and raised an eyebrow. “Why are Witch-co looking for investment for a new warehouse?”

“Because they’ve never had one before.”

Harry looked surprised. “Really?”

“Yes. But it’s not the kind of thing we’d be interested in. I know we might soon have more gold then we know what to do with, but we should still be careful about what we invest in.”

Harry rubbed his chin while reading the parchment. Then he smirked, rolled it up, and slipped it into the pockets of his robes.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The prospect of finally solving their financial problems had Daphne, Hermione, and Ginny bubbling with a kind of excited energy none of them had felt in quite a while. Alexandra, being newer to the team, didn’t have that same tension built up inside her from years of vague financial uncertainty, and so was content in burrowing her way deeper into the Dark, while Luna was still Luna—calm, collected, and prone to pointing out truths that many people would suggest be left unsaid, such as when all five of them had been relaxing in Hermione’s trunk one evening, and she’d pointed out that Harry would soon be getting erections.

“He’s probably never had one before,” she said, in her dreamy voice. “Azkaban can’t be good for penises.”

“Do you think looking at us will make him like that?” Ginny asked, slightly wide-eyed.

“Probably not you and me.”

“What? Why not!? Are you saying I’m not sexy?”

“Ginny,” Daphne said in a business-like tone. “Any boy our age would find you sexy, even if they wouldn’t have a clue what to do about it, but Harry is not like any boy our age. Don’t forget he’s much more mature than they are.”

The conversation abruptly ended when Alexandra butted in and insisted that since Lord Slytherin didn’t yet care for any of them as witches, they should stop with the useless chatter and get back to working on what he did care about them for.

“I still can’t quite believe how powerful he is,” Alex muttered later on that week after their group took an especially severe beating from Harry in group combat training.

“You’re all getting better,” Harry said, throwing Daphne back her wand. “But you’re still not using Luna’s power reserves to the fullest. And Ginny, your swapping is getting better, but you’re still not good enough to use it reliably in air to air combat.”

Ginny pouted. “You still haven’t told us what your animagus form is. It’s not a Phoenix or anything ridiculously good at flying is it?”

Harry smirked. “No, and no more clues. Taking me down during the ritual will be an excellent exercise for you all.” He glanced at Luna who was smiling. “Well, me or Luna, I guess. Whichever turns out to be the bigger surprise.”

Of course, many people around the school knew something big was going on with the young Slytherin clique, even if they had no clue what. There were just too many clues.

“It’s so not fair that you get to leave on the weekends,” Kevin Entwhistle said to Hermione during a Founders Club meeting. “Why do you get to leave? It’s not like you have family business, like Greengrass.”

“I do have family business,” Hermione defended herself. “I may not be from a noble house, but I am vassaled to one, remember?”

“But what is it?”

“I told you, I can’t say. It’s private.”

Eventually though, after a week of curious looks and sideways glances, Saturday came, and a familiar figure in a green and black mask arrived at the Hogwarts front gates to take Daphne, Hermione, and Luna away for the weekend. Not widely known, of course, was the fact that this figure arrived at the front gates via the front door.

“Lord Slytherin,” professor McGonagall said in a professional, yet disapproving tone of voice. “We will need our girls back before classes start on Monday, but I hope that won’t mean they arrive on the castle grounds with only five minutes to spare—like last time.”

Harry then produced brooms for all four of them and they flew the short distance to Hogsmeade, Daphne soaring above them all, while the other three playfully zipped around each other in the crisp morning air like robed and cloaked black dragonflies.

“Are we not using your house here?” Hermione asked as they landed in the village centre.

“It’s not mine any more,” Harry replied. “Handed it back over to Lord Woodcroft. Not worth it now we have Slytherin Manor.”

They all stepped into the floo at the Three Broomsticks, and arrived in the entranceway of Slytherin Manor not long after. From there it was a short walk down the hill to the Granger cottage.

The door was opened by Clare who didn’t look surprised to see them. She led them into the small kitchen and poured pumpkin juice for the girls and orange juice for Lord Slytherin.

“How’s schoolwork?” Harry asked, while Daphne, Luna, and Hermione busied themselves with going over the plan for the next forty-eight hours.

“Frustratingly slow, my lord,” Clare said. “Even with the optional Sunday school classes. But better than being a prostitute, and much better than being in Azkaban. We got a visit from a dementor this week, so that everyone knows what happens to bad little boys and girls.” She shuddered. “We all went to another quidditch match the week before. They really do like their carrots and sticks, don’t they?”

Harry nodded. “Oh, yes.”

“Being near that dementor was the worst thing I’ve ever experienced,” Clare continued, “It was like my first time from back then all over again, except focused and amplified and oh so much worse. Is there a way to fight them?”

“Dementors?” Harry asked. “Yes, there is. It is not easy at all. But yes, it can be done.”

“What is it? I don’t ever want to be near one of those things again.”

Lord Slytherin put down his glass. “It is called the patronus charm. A spell that can only be conjured by an intense positive emotion—hope, happiness, love—dementors feed off all these, but the charm turns them into something so powerful, they burn—like a rabbit turning around and head-butting the fox.”

“Can you cast it?”

“Yes, I can,” he replied, although there was obvious reluctance in his voice.

“Could you show me?”

On the other side of the kitchen, Luna was shushing the other two into silence.

Harry shrugged and pointed his wand into the middle of the room. “Expecto Patronum.”

Pure white mist poured out of his wand. It swirled about where he pointed and quickly took on a form.

Daphne and Hermione gasped.

Luna looked on with mild sadness in her eyes.

Bathed in brilliant white light, a bony figure in a tattered, glowing robe floated several inches off the floor, tall enough to brush the ceiling with its cowled head.

“My lord?” Clare whispered.

Slytherin made a slashing motion with his wand and the dementor patronus vanished. “It is nothing,” he said firmly. Then his voice took on a far more cheerful tone. “Come now. We have a lot to get done today, but I’ll be sure you get the books you need to practice the charm on your own time. You deserve that at least.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The garden was a sea of tranquillity, bathed in weak sunlight and frost. And yet, in the middle of the lawn, the grass of which crunched underfoot, sat a man wearing thin, light robes, sipping on a thin, china cup of tea. Another cup sat opposite him, endlessly steaming away, a small jam biscuit sitting patiently in the saucer. The chair by the cup was empty. He didn’t shiver. He sat as though enjoying a cool summer morning.

Mister Bentley took another sip of tea, enjoying the peace of his sanctuary—the stillness, the order, even the memory of Mrs. Bun leaning over the wall, cheerfully gossiping over whatever small thing the dear had found to find important. On a small stool by his side sat a small pile of nondescript parchments, and a small thin box.

“Mister Bentley.”

He smiled, but did not turn around. “Ah, Dolores. Do please take a seat.”

Dolores Umbridge walked around the small table, sat down, and carefully took her own cup of tea. For a moment, neither spoke.

“Tell me,” Bentley eventually said, breaking the silence, “what is it that makes the difference between a Dark or Light Lord and a lord of the Wizengamot?”

Dolores looked taken aback by the question, before answering, “Power?”

“Yes, but many lords of the Wizengamot are very powerful. No, power alone is not what makes a Lord of Lords.”

“Then what?”

“Some would say is the willingness to act outside the system to achieve their ends, and what makes them different from a common criminal is that they are supported by a large chunk of the legislature. That’s what he-who-must-not-be-named was. It’s what Light Lord Dimwiddy was, and, even though he would never admit it, it’s what Dumbledore is too.”

Dolores’ eyes narrowed. “You think Dumbledore is breaking the law?”

“I don’t think so, I know so. But that is irrelevant to this discussion. Now tell me what you think about Lord Slytherin.”

“Didn’t I already do that?”

“Not in the context of this conversation.”

Dolores looked off into the distance before tentatively answering. “People do think he’s a Gray Lord. Does that mean he also breaks the law?”

“Probably,” Bentley said, although he didn’t give off the impression of being all that concerned about it.

If the November trees had any birds left, this would be the moment they’d tweet into the silence.

“Mister Bentley, I don’t mean to seem disrespectful, but why are we talking about this? Has something gone wrong? Do I need to handle something? You only ever call me to you when there’s some dirty work to be done.”

Bentley frowned. “A blunt way of putting it. You still need to work on your discretion.”

“Sorry, Mister Bentley.”

“And in regards to your question. No, everything is going splendidly. The current Wizengamot session is almost over and they won’t open again until Spring. The Solstice is a mere formality. It is unlikely the Dark and Gray will come to any agreement before then, but I will be seeing to things this morning just to make sure.”

“Then what?”

Mister Bentley looked wistfully around the frosty garden. “Next summer, I have decided to take my retirement early.”

Dolores gasped. “But, you can’t! Without you, the ministry won’t be able to survive! We’ll be overrun by mudbloods and blood-traitors!”

“You exaggerate, my dear.”

“No. Who’s going to be the Wardrobe’s next Humble Hag?”

“That will be up to the judiciary, but I will recommend the current Humble Hag of the Department of Magical Games and Sports, Bertha Jorkins.”

“Her?!”Dolores looked horrified. “She can’t handle it! She’s soft!”

“She is the best choice available.”

“Are you honestly saying she’s better than Crouch? Or Wilkes?”

“None of the current Humble Hags are a good choice, which is the real reason we are having this discussion. Now I’m going to ask you again, what is the difference between a Lord of Lords, and a lord of the Wizengamot, and why do I believe Lord Slytherin not to be a real Gray Lord—charming though he may be?”

Dolores bit her lip. Her brow furrowed in concentration. “The Dark Lord wasn’t a lord of the Wizengamot?” she hesitated. “Neither is Dumbledore, nor was Dimwiddy. But Lord Slytherin is a Wizengamot lord. Is that it?”

Mister Bentley reached to his side and picked up the thin box. He placed it on the table in front of them.

Dolores eyed it cautiously.

He opened it to reveal an elegant black quill.

Dolores’ eyes widened. “Is that what I think it is?”

“If you think it’s a blood quill, then you’re right.”

“Why do you have a blood quill?” she asked in a whisper.

“Because sometimes agreements have to be made that are stronger than a strictly legal contract of ink can bind. I have used this quill for nearly six decades.” He pushed the box towards Dolores. “You may not be a Humble Hag, but I suspect I can rely on you to do what is in the country’s best interests.”

Dolores was speechless as she took the quill and rolled it in her fingers. She then smiled a sickly smile. “I understand, Mister Bentley. I fully understand.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Hermione stared with wide eyes as she made her way through the doorway and into the cavernous space under her parent’s new home. She hadn’t been here in nearly three months, and wow, had Mum and Dad been busy. It sat on small metal rails, pointing into the black waters of the cave, long, wooden, and polished, it looked like many of the broomsticks she’d seen for sale in the windows of shops in Diagon Alley or the Puddlemere Enclave, except large enough to crawl inside. The nose cone was open with a tiny set of stairs leading up to it, while the bristles all looked like each one could have been a family sized broomstick with room to spare in its own right.

That her Mum and Dad had made it … amazing.

“Wow,” Daphne whispered.

“I know,” Hermione whispered back.

“Girls!” Dan Granger hopped down from where he’d been engaged in some activity near the bristles and strode over. “My lord.” He nodded to Slytherin. “No problems getting here I hope?”

“None, Dad,” Hermione said.

“And this must be Xenophilius’s daughter,” Dan said. “Luna, wasn’t it?”

“Yes, I am Luna,” said Luna. She pointed at the broomstick. “And that is a big broomstick.”

“Yes,” Dan beamed. “We’ve been working on it straight for nigh on three weeks now. Just took it out for its first paddle last night.”

“Does she have a name?” Luna asked.

“Not yet,” Dan patted the shaft, “But we’re sure it’s going to start with SBS—as in, Slytherin Broom Stick. Maybe a place name, like Hogwarts? That’s traditional with ships.”

“You could call it the SBS Big Broomstick,” Luna suggested.

Dan blinked. “But what about when we build a second one?”

“Then you could call that one the SBS Bigger Broomstick.”

“Slytherin Broomstick Big Broomstick,” is really dumb, Hermione cut in. “What about SBS Harry?”

“Boats are supposed to have feminine names,” Luna pouted.

“How is ‘Big Broomstick,’ ” a feminine name?

“It isn’t,” Daphne said. “But many boats don’t have feminine names, like the Bismarck, or the Victory.”

“So, Big Broomstick!”

“No!”

Emma chose that moment to cut across the argument. “What do you think, my lord?”

Hermione watched Harry turn and regard the broomstick, before turning back. “It was lovingly created by two geniuses, and will now explore the world for buried treasure and hidden knowledge. While today we search only for the sunken ship of Slytherin, who knows what the future will bring. Maybe Atlantis? Maybe the Court of the Feathered Serpent? While we may sell many other broomsticks, this one will always be with us. I propose we call her the SBS Hermione.”

Hermione gasped, feeling suddenly incredibly small. She glanced around and saw everyone was looking at her with warm smiles.

“A wonderful idea,” Emma said. “From what our lord has told us, none of this would have been possible without your work, dear.”

“Yes,” Dan added, “We’re both very proud of you.”

“Mum, Dad …”

What followed quickly devolved into a round of family hugs and sobs all around. It took several minutes to get everyone straight again and back on task.

“Everyone in!” Luna sang, crawling into the newly christened broomstick. “Oooofffff, it’s cramped in here.”

“Is there going to be room for all of us?” Daphne asked with her face inches from Luna’s bum.

“There will be!” Dan called out from somewhere behind them. Just crawl into your positions!”

“Dad? You’re not coming too?” Hermione asked.

“Only one engineer needed, pumpkin. Your mother is smaller.”

“Wow, Hermione!” Daphne called. “You’ll like these! They’ve added cushioning runes on the steering broomsticks!”

“Oh, Thank Merlin!”

“Wait, is our lord at the front or the back?”

“He’s at the back!” Emma called down the stick, “Luna is in front!”

“I hope the ones for MaCUSA aren’t going to be this cramped?”

“No!”

“Good!”

Eventually, after a whole lot of shuffling about, everyone got to where they needed to be.

“Everyone got their emergency portkeys?” Slytherin called out.

There was a chorus of yeses.

“Then let’s shove off!”

Everyone cheered as the nose cone was lowered and the transparency runes activated, letting them all see out of the front of the stick.

A jolt of nerves shot through Hermione from where she sat in her wooden bucket seat. This was an adventure. An adventure with Harry. Another one. And she was along for the ride.

From somewhere outside came the noise of a chain being released from a catch, the whole stick lurched, and then, with a loud, girly squeal, which she realised came exclusively from her, rapidly slid into the inky blackness of the North Sea.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The records office of the ministry of magic had been modelled on the hall of prophecies, but while the hall of prophecies merely had to contend with reasonably inert balls of glass, the records office dealt on a daily basis with parchment and shelves that had had so many illicit divination charms layered on them over the years by well-meaning clerks trying to speed things up, that finding anything was actually more difficult than having no index system at all—unless, of course, you really knew what you were doing.

Mister Bentley walked into the hall and made his way immediately to one of the weekend clerks who had a green stripe above their nameplate, a sure sign that they were one of these rarefied individuals. When he approached her, she was happily chatting with a couple of her colleagues, (a brunette and a red-head) but that quickly changed when he approached.

“Mister Bentley?” The woman asked nervously.

Bentley glanced at her nameplate. “Mrs. Cox.” He smiled. “I need the records from the judiciary’s office related to breaches of the International Statute of Secrecy in the last year.”

Mrs. Cox started writing down notes. “Any record in particular you’re looking for?”

“I believe there have been two prisoner relocation hearings regarding the same witch during that time? I’m not sure of her name.”

Mrs. Cox finished writing and gave Mister Bentley another nervous smile. “I’ll probably have them ready for you in a few hours.”

Mister Bentley nodded in understanding and walked away.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Whew,” Chelsea Cox said, wiping her brow. “Not every day you get a request straight from the Humble Hag of the Wardrobe.”

Her friend, Isabelle, smiled. “You going to get on with that then?”

“Yeah, I suppose I should.”

“I can help you, if you want. I think I saw some of these ones the other week. They can’t have moved that much since.”

“Really?! Thanks, Isa, you’re a life saver.”

“Don’t mention it.”

They eventually found the file skulking around with a collection of budget requests from the sixteenth century. Chelsea Cox slipped the papers out of their file and read them. “Clare Cooper.” Her eyes widened. “Currently serving a ten-year sentence on the grounds of Slytherin Manor for breaking the ISS. I wonder what Mister Bentley wants with her? Hey, look, she has your hair.”

She looked around.

“Isabelle?”

And then a red light hit her and she knew no more.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Isabelle lowered her wand and smirked. She picked up the file and flipped through the contents. “Sorry, girl, but Mister Bentley being interested in a person like this is exactly the kind of thing that Lord Malfoy wants me to keep my eyes out for.”

And then a red light hit her and she knew no more.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Yeah,” said the third colleague stepping out from between two filing cabinets and snatching up the file. “Me too.” Five minutes later found her throwing a pinch of floo powder into a private Wizengamot floo on the other side of the ministry. “The Rookery!” And then … “Lord Lovegood!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The moment the SBS Hermione slid into the water time seemed to stand still. From a moment of shrieking adrenaline and exhilaration quickly came the deathly quiet of the deeps. Unlike the practically duck-taped submarine van, there were no engine noises, no rush of water, and no creaking of aluminium panels bending and popping as the water pressure tried (but failed) to turn their craft into a crushed can.

Instead, the magical wood around them felt as safe as a mother’s womb, and the transparent nose cone gave them a perfect view as they navigated their way through the short underwater cave, leading out into the open waters of the North Sea.

Hermione’s brain didn’t stay in wonderment alone for long though. Soon it was back to fretting about the journey ahead, how long it would take, whether they would even find Captain Slytherin’s sunken long boat at all, and whether she was really worthy of all this praise that was being heaped on her. After all, Harry himself had said she had a long way to go before becoming the greatest witch the world had ever seen.

There was a nagging feeling in the back of her mind that her rigorously trained brain had a serious flaw and that she was trying to debug a program from inside the program.

“I suggest everyone get themselves comfy,” Harry as Lord Slytherin said from where he sat with Luna, riding the SBS Hermione’s twin broomstick steering system. “It’s going to be a long trip.”

“Can we play I spy?” Luna asked.

“Sure, so long as Daphne isn’t allowed to play.”

“Hey!”

“What? You’ve got an eye that can see through walls.”

“So? I won’t use it!”

At the front of the broomstick, Emma giggled.

“Mum?”

“Sorry, dear” Emma waved it away. “It’s just nice to see you all having fun, even when things are serious. I don’t think I’ve ever heard you crack that kind of joke, my lord.”

“I guess being around young people makes me feel younger too.”

That caused Hermione, Daphne, and even Luna to snort.

The rest of the evening continued without incident. The maps Hermione had plotted out ahead of time proved more than sufficient to lead them where they needed to go, and the SBS Hermione’s many new magical navigation charms and runes did the rest, including a magically charmed muggle style periscope to see above water. After all, it wasn’t as though they could use Daphne’s divination magic to help guide the broomsticks they’d eventually sell to MaCUSA.

It took eight hours to travel the five hundred kilometres to the seamount, and by the time Daphne had been scanning the ocean for another eight hours they were well and truly knackered.

“We’ve made good progress,” Daphne yawned. “Even if we haven’t found anything yet. How are we going to sleep?”

“The normal way, I imagine,” Harry said. “Let’s anchor ourselves to something. Then everyone get your heads down as best you can. I’ll take the first watch.”

They rotated shifts throughout the night—first Emma, then Hermione, then Luna, and then back to Harry again. Daphne was the only one exempt since she’d be expected to spend hours on end using rather draining divination magic to scan the other half of the seamount come morning.

Eventually it was morning, and Emma got to experience first-hand the wonders of teeth-brushing, hair styling, and make-up charms.

“Raise the periscope,” Harry ordered.

The periscope was raised and Hermione peered through to check nothing weird was going on. She blinked. “Um … my lord?”

“Yes, Hermione?”

“Macavity and Hedwig are staring down our periscope. They seem to be rather agitated.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Cuckoo! Cuckoo! Cuckoo!”

Mister Bentley woke up in bed to the sound of his magical alarm clock. It was Sunday. This made no difference to him. Just the start of another day, and of yet another opportunity to guide Magical Britain with wisdom and foresight.

He swung his feet off the king-sized oak bed, glanced back at the empty space on the other side of the bed, and made his way to the en-suite bathroom. He relieved himself, then brushed his teeth, combed his hair, and washed his face. Still in his dressing gown and slippers, he shuffled to the front door, opened it, walked down the garden path, breathing in the fresh-air of his little haven, and picked up the morning milk and ever-warm toast by the front gate.

The delivery of the morning milk was a muggle idea—not something he usually approved of, but so convenient he couldn’t bring himself to care. And it wasn’t as though he had the power to stop a legal partnership between two noble houses, in any case.

He walked back up the garden path, cheerfully waved to Mrs. Bun over the garden wall, who was hanging up laundry for drying charms, sat down at his kitchen table, and had the milk pour itself into a glass, while his knife magically spread jam on the toast.

After indulging in a naughty third slice, he stood in front of a full-length mirror, while charming on his charcoal-grey work robes. He carefully inspected himself and couldn’t help approving of what he saw. The consummate gentleman. Professional, sophisticated, and perfectly adept at manoeuvring the pieces on the chess board to where they needed to be.

He picked up a copy of file he’d requested from the hall of records the previous day.

Clare Cooper—twenty-two—muggle-born—currently serving a ten-year sentence for a medium-level breach of the International Statute of Secrecy—although because of the Wizengamot’s debtors laws, was currently serving that sentence, not in Azkaban, but on the grounds of Slytherin Manor.

He tucked the file under his arm, walked to the fireplace, threw a pinch into the flames, called out, “Ministry,” and was instantly swept away.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Deep under the water of the Atlantic Sea, the nose cone of the SBS Hermione had been opened, creating a bobbing and ebbing vertical wall of water that Harry had crawled through before vanishing upwards.

Hermione waited anxiously for news from inside the broom-sub, along-side Daphne, Luna, and Emma Granger.

“I’m sure it’ll be fine,” her Mum said. “Lord Slytherin is a very busy man.”

“It does raise a good point though,” Daphne said from just behind them. “Can you add post-wards to the sub? Is there enough space?”

“I’m not sure, I’ll have to talk with Dan when we get back. There are some spaces left, it just depends on how large the rune matrix for a post-ward is.”

It was very cramped inside the prototype sub, but Emma still managed to give Hermione a warm hug. “How’s your magic? You were working so hard yesterday.”

“It’s fine, Mum. I practice a lot.”

Emma Granger smiled at her daughter. “You do that. Lord Slytherin told us a bit about the occlumency you’ve been learning. I hear my little genius is turning her brain into something like a computer.”

“It’s a little bit like that, yes.”

“And your healing studies?”

“I’ll start on them again very soon. I think Healer Pomfrey thought I’d be away for far longer than I actually will be.”

“I’m so proud of you.”

Hermione felt her cheeks go red. “Thanks, Mum,” she whispered.

In the back of the sub, Daphne and Luna gave her warm little smiles of their own.

Then the wall of water rippled, and Lord Slytherin’s head stuck itself through. “Both Hedwig and Macavity have letters for me from Luna’s father. I’ve got to go. Something rather important has turned up. Emma, you’re in charge until I get back, but please defer to the girls’ judgements in matters of magic that aren’t runes.”

“As you wish, my lord. Do you know how long you’ll be gone?”

“Perhaps all day. But don’t worry. Everything will be fine. You all have portkeys if everything goes to hell. Plato!”

After a few moments, Plato, the rather disorientated house-elf, popped into the sub in-front of Harry’s masked head. “Master?”

“I have to leave. Please stay here with Emma and the girls, and if there is any mortal danger that their portkeys can’t get them out of, see to it that they all get to safety as quickly as possible.”

Plato bowed deeply. “Understood, Master.”

Still being hugged by Emma, Hermione nodded to herself. That had been a well-formed and quickly put-together contingency plan. Just like Harry. Although there was still the matter of the homework he’d given her to tear apart his idea for Antarctic colonisation. She still hadn’t done it.

“See you all soon,” Harry said, before disappearing back through the wall of water.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The ministry was quiet. Relatively quiet, anyway. It was a Sunday, after all. Most wizards and witches would be at home with their families, or else screaming their heads off at a quidditch match at Bodmin Stadium, or out shopping in Diagon Alley, or enjoying one of the many other leisure activities the wizarding world provided their citizens.

Bread and circuses.

Mister Bentley walked through security with nothing but a congenial nod to the guards, and made his way to the minister’s office. Here at least, there was noticeable activity. “Florence, my dear, is the minister in?”

“Yes, Mister Bentley. He’s just listening to the duelling league updates on the wireless.”

“Excellent, could you let him know that I need a word?”

“Certainly, Mister Bentley. About anything in particular?”

“Just a few updates on matters of situational importance.”

Bread and circuses, Mister Bentley thought, watching the receptionist vanish through the door to the minister’s personal office. Magical Britain was not in anyway large, and given how tempting it might be for a wizard to risk the statute by using their powers in the muggle world, there needed to be plenty to satisfy them in the real world. The Department of Magical Games and Sports covered a lot more than just games and sport, and might as well be re-named the Second Department of Magical Law Enforcement.

He was soon ushered into the minster’s personal office to find Fudge avidly concentrating, sitting on one of the chairs by the wireless.

“Goldstein falls back on the defensive,” the commentator almost whispered, while in the background, grunts and whooshes painted over a background of silence. “Stun, stun, trip, shield, Delacour moves in.”

Dolores Umbridge, standing dutifully behind the minister, caught Bentley’s eye and offered him an apologetic look.

“Goldstein tries for an elemental,” the commentator’s voice started to rise. “Doesn’t get it off—Trips!—Goes for a swat! Misses! And that’s it for Goldstein!” The sounds of a small crowd politely clapping filled the room. “An amazing finish to an outstanding series. If that spell swat had connected at the end it just might have been able to turn things around for the American, but in the heat of the moment, he just didn’t have what it took.” An older sounding voice came on. “That was yesterday’s stage five finals of the All Wizard’s Duelling Tournament. Join us next—”

Minister Fudge clicked the wireless off and looked up, annoyed. “In fifteen years of duelling, Goldstein has never tried spell swatting in a tournament before. It’s not his style.”

“Maybe he just wanted to try something new?” Bentley politely suggested.

“No, it’s not because of that.” Fudge got up and paced over to his desk. “Anyway, what did we need to talk about? Please not that stupid Cork business again.” He sat down in his plush leather chair. “Or the new ICW obliviator regulations? “

“No, it’s neither of them.” Bentley slid over to the other side of the desk while Dolores took out a hardback book and started taking notes. “It’s a new matter that has recently come to my attention—an ongoing abuse of our penal system, one that cannot realistically be allowed to continue.”

“Why come to me about this, Bentley? This is a matter for the DMLE, isn’t it?”

“Not really. Fixing the abuse in question would normally require legislation through the Wizengamot, but given the current state of things, that’s unlikely to happen for quite some time. But an executive order from the minister would allow us to put a plug on current cases.”

“What are these abuses?”

“Are you familiar with our debtor laws?”

Fudge scratched the back of his head. “Ah, somewhat. Creditors have certain privileges over debtors who can’t repay their debts, correct?”

“Broadly, Minister, yes. One of those privileges is to request that debtors sentenced to prison serve their prison term in the employment of the creditor. But recently, some citizens have been using these laws simply as a means to protect friends and family from being sent to Azkaban.”

Fudge’s expression became concerned. “What families?”

“None of the convicts in question are either noble or pureblood,” Bentley said, as smoothly as silk on a maiden’s cheek.

The corner of Madam Umbridge’s lip curled upwards.

“Oh,” said Minister Fudge. “Good, then.” His expression became firm. “Can’t have that then. Flagrant abuses of the laws created by our own noble Wizengamot, right under our noses.”

“No, Minister.”

Fudge signed the parchment Bentley had placed in front of him. “See to it that it’s stamped out.”

Bentley took the parchment and turned to go. “Yes, Minister.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“And they built a magical city hidden from the rest of the world over a thousand years before the ICW enacted the International Statute of Secrecy. They were so far ahead of their times, unlike the rest of the American civilisations who, in terms of administrative sophistication, were about on par with the Assyrians. Is it any wonder they decided to isolate themselves?”

The SBS Hermione had been trawling through the waters surrounding the Anton Dohrn Seamount for the past few hours, a tiny moving bubble of silence and calm. And inside, while Daphne peered into a divination mirror, jumping her sight from spot to spot, looking for any sign of a wreck matching the description of what they were looking for, the actual Hermione was in full-on lecture mode to her remaining captive audience of two.

“It is a little surprising,” Emma said. “You’d think someone with power would want to rule others without. I understand why the ISS was created, but this Court of the Feathered Serpent clearly had nothing to fear from their non-magical people.”

“I don’t know,” Hermione said. “Akna didn’t write anything about that in her journals—at least, nothing that I’ve found yet.”

“How far through them are you?” Luna asked.

“About three-quarters.”

“Maybe we’ll find something else in the boat too,” Emma suggested. “Maybe magic preserved the parchment all that time. I wouldn’t mind reading some of these books myself. Hermione, could you teach me the language?”

Hermione frowned. “I’ve got a lot to do, Mum.”

Emma smiled. “Of course, of course.”

“And anyway,” Hermione’s voice became barely louder than a whisper. “I doubt you’d want to read some of it. You might find it upsetting.”

“Why?”

“Just the way they treated muggles back then. It wasn’t always very nice.”

“Dear, your Mum and Dad have read what feels like half the history books in Flourish and Blotts. We know all about how wizards have treated muggles.”

“It’s just …” Hermione hesitated. “It’s just that the Court of the Feathered Serpent did many really horrible things. Like killing muggle parents of muggleborns, or just stealing them away. They didn’t have memory charms, so they just killed them.” Hermione’s voice was becoming strained.

“Oh, sweetie.” Emma hugged her.

“But suppose the magical world had to isolate itself further now,” Hermione ploughed on. “I’m not saying it will or anything,” she quickly added. “But suppose it had to. What then?”

“Well, the wizarding world does have memory charms now, so, no need for killing anyone.”

“But, but, the idea of someone arriving in the night and doing that to you and Dad—”

“—Isn’t going to happen. Ever.”

Hermione fell silent. The only sound to be heard was the faint underwater sounds of the broom-sub. Luna was politely busying herself with a book. Daphne had her eyes closed and was obviously elsewhere.

“Hermione,” Emma eventually said. “When Lord Slytherin approached your father and I, we had a choice—either join you one hundred percent on this adventure, or pretend nothing had changed, and try to live with the fact that our daughter had basically moved to another country, and that we’d rarely ever see her again. Obviously we chose to join you. How could we choose anything else? If the wizarding world had to isolate itself further, I think that’s what they should do. Let the parents choose. Then they could have the option to fully immigrate, if they wished.”

“And if they chose not too?”

“That’s when the memory charms would come in.”

Hermione hugged her mother tighter. “How could anyone choose to do that?”

Emma sighed. “Being a mother or father does not automatically make one a saint, dear. There are many people out there who would give up their children to avoid a radical life change. Especially if they were given the option of just forgetting. No one is perfect.”

“Harry is.”

Hermione hadn’t actually meant to say those words. They just sort of, slipped out. But they were out now.

Emma smiled. “I know it may seem that way, but no, not even Harry is perfect, dear.”

Hermione frowned. “He is. He always knows what’s best. He knows everything. Tell me one time he was wrong.”

Emma frowned in turn. “Dear …”

“No. You don’t know all the facts! Harry always knows what’s best.”

“Hermione.”

Mother and daughter turned. Luna was looking at them with her dreamy expression. “Did Harry ever tell you about when he first tried to befriend Alex?”

“No?”

“He made a complete pig’s ear of it. That was a time he was wrong.”

“But …”

“And there was the thing with the you-know-what at the end of last year.”

“That wasn’t his fault!”

A clearing of the throat from behind them caused Hermione and Emma to turn again. “People can be amazing and still not be perfect,” said Daphne, who’d now opened her eyes. “If we were to take our lord as an example. He’s done many questionable things over the years.”

“But it was all needed,” Hermione said, desperately.

“Was it? What about Clare?”

“He saved Clare! She was being used as a prostitute!”

“And how much did it cost to save her? A thousand galleons? What about the three other girls? Where are they now?”

“But … but buying all their debt would just fuel the market and cause more muggleborns to be snatched! And anyway, we don’t have unlimited funds, you know that.”

“Why don’t we have the money to free those other three girls?”

Hermione hesitated, letting Daphne get in her answer before she could formulate one of her own. “We don’t have the money, because our lord decided it would be a better idea to spend it on a mansion—a seventy thousand galleon mansion.”

“But we need Slytherin Manor,” Hermione argued. It’s our base of operations to ensure our survival.”

“But did we absolutely have to spend so much on it?”

“I …”

“We didn’t, Hermione. Slytherin Manor is now the largest magical manor in the whole country. We could probably have done very well with just the third or even fourth largest.”

“But, we still couldn’t have bought the other girls’ debts. The black market for muggleborns—”

“And who leads the Gray? The political faction capable of green-lighting any legislation if at least one of the other factions is in full agreement on it? Wouldn’t the Light be rather on-board with the idea of stamping out that particular market?”

“Daphne, why are you saying all this!? What would our lord say if he heard you!?”

“He’d say, Hermione, ‘Excellent analysis, Daphne. I’m glad you’re not letting your loyalty to me cloud your judgement!’ ”

Hermione flinched. It was like a kick to the gut. Nothing more or less. And Daphne looked genuinely annoyed. Again, no one said anything for several long seconds, and Hermione eventually realised that her Mum was gently stroking her hair, and that she was still holding her tightly.

Another sound slowly started to fill the broom-sub—the sound of Luna humming.

Daphne let out a long breath. “Anyway, to get back on task, I think I might have found something.”

The atmosphere in the enclosed space noticeably changed, and suddenly, Hermione’s mum was all business. “How far?” she asked.

“I’m not sure—maybe a few hours—I can lead the way.”

“Right, let’s do that. Luna, how are you feeling?”

“Right as rain, Mrs. Granger.”

“Okay.” She leaned back to look Hermione in the eyes. “And you, sweetie?”

Hermione took a deep breath to centre herself. “I’m fine, Mum.” And it was true. She could feel her magic swirling around inside her, agitated, restless. They’d been steering the SBS Hermione for a long time now, in multiple shifts, and theoretically, most adult wizards should be puffed out by now. But not her. She’d been wielding her magic constantly, in some way or other, for years now. As she clambered over Emma Granger to the regular-sized broomsticks towards the back of the broom-sub that steered the craft, her thoughts drifted back to Daphne’s words, and then, as they so often did, to Harry.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The elevator around Dolores Umbridge rattled and shook as it made its way down to the DMLE. The doors slid open and she marched out, a woman on a mission, a mission that only she could execute. She marched straight up to the first assistant secretary she saw, and smiled. “Excuse me, I need to see the chief Auror.”

The man gave her a bored look. “And you are?”

Dolores’ smile vanished. “I am Dolores Umbridge—the Minister’s undersecretary—here on official business.”

The man’s look turned from bored to attentive. “One moment, Madam Umbridge.”

And just like that, Dolores’ smile returned.

It didn’t last long though. Dolores was forced to wait three minutes and thirty-two seconds in the waiting room before she was finally showed in to the Chief Auror’s office. The nerve! What if she’d needed to inform him that there’d been a break-out from Azkaban? Or that someone was trying to assassinate the minister?”

“What is it?” Lord Sirius Black asked, the moment she’d stepped in.

“My lord,” Dolores began.

“—I’m not your lord here, Madam Umbridge. I am Chief Auror.”

Dolores bit back a scowl, hiding it instead under the sweet smile she’d endlessly practised in the mirror. “Of course, Chief Auror. I am here to deliver this.” She threw the parchment the minister had signed across the table.

Lord Black picked it up and read. He frowned. “How many people does this affect?”

“Three. Their names and addresses are on the other side.”

Lord Black turned over the parchment and read. He put the parchment aside. “Fine. We’ll take care of this from here. Good day, Madam Umbridge.”

“Chief Auror,” Dolores said, not moving an inch back towards the door. “if I may, there are certain details about the execution of this order that need very careful handling.”

Lord Black glared at her. “Such as?”

“The prisoner, Clare Cooper, in addition to the usual security wizards, will also need a fully armed auror pair to pick her up. That is why I brought this to you. You must have noticed her address? Granger cottage is on the grounds of Slytherin Manor. You might find it … difficult to extract her from there, so she will need to be intercepted as she floos from school. And due to Slytherin’s influence, the minister insists on an immediate transfer to Azkaban while we investigate the abuses.”

“Yes, thank you, Madam Umbridge,” Lord Black indicated the door.

“We want to make sure Lord Slytherin doesn’t try anything unwise during the transfer.”

“Yes, Thank you.”

“And can I also remind you that the prisoner is to be strip searched and any artefacts she holds are to be confiscated for investigation?”

“Madam Umbridge, I am fully aware of all the regulations that pertain to my job, and many of them require my immediate attention, so please leave.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“There!” Daphne’s excited voice cried out in the magical wooden craft.

“We can’t see what you do!” Hermione said in exasperation.

“A bit to the left. More left. Forward. We’re just coming up to it.”

“Would we be able to see it if we opened the nose?” Emma asked.

“Definitely.”

“Luna?” Emma said. “Will you do the honours?”

“Yes, Mrs. Granger.” There was a faint hum, and the SBS Hermione’s nose cone opened up, letting the waters of the Atlantic splash against the magical barrier preventing the insides from flooding. In a few moments, the barrier became as transparent as a window.

“Wow,” Hermione said.

“That is a sunken longship,” Luna added.

“Not all of us have a ‘see in the dark’ spell,” Emma said, pointedly. “Can you aim the light out there, please?”

They did so, and Emma was finally able to see what the others could. “Looks promising,” she said.

Hermione nodded. It really did look promising. It wasn’t massive, maybe twenty meters long, but she knew there would be many ancient spells interwoven into the woodwork, making the insides larger than the outsides. It was filled with earth and silt, and buried at an angle, causing the back to stick up more than the front. Every surface that wasn’t buried was covered in coral.

“Bring us in closer,” Emma called out.

Hermione leaned forward on her broomstick.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Mister Bentley glanced up from the parchment work he’d been busy with, and up at the clock, quietly ticking over his desk.

Sunday classes at the lesser schools would be out soon. Once this Clare Cooper was under the ministry’s care again, he would learn if that gave him any leverage over Lord Slytherin. The man might very well not even care, but it was at least worth a shot.

This whole business with the Muggle Protection Act was a gentlemanly battle of wits, and Slytherin was a wonderful opponent. Much of the country saw him as a mysterious and dangerous figure. He was, in fact, restrained, polite, and sophisticated, just like him.

Dolores may be frightened that Slytherin would oppose the transfer with force, but Bentley knew better. If he cared at all, Slytherin would come to him, and offer him something in exchange, which is exactly what he wanted.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Hermione edged the broom-sub ever forward in the water, towards the sunken wreckage.

“How close should we get?” Daphne asked.

“We should be careful getting too close,” Luna said. “There might still be—”

A shudder went through the SBS Hermione causing everyone to still and look around.

Then Hermione felt it, an all-mighty pull on her magic, as though she’d just opened the world’s largest chocolate frog. She cried out and almost lost her balance on the broomstick, but just about held on.

“Hermione!” Her Mum was at her side in a rather scrabbly instant. “Are you okay?”

“I’m—Fine.” She gasped out.

Behind her, Luna had her teeth gritted, and was visibly straining.

And from the front of the sub, looking out of the open nose cone, she could just about hear Daphne mutter, “Magical Merlin.”

“What?!” Hermione put all her willpower into turning the sub to let her see too. And then she saw it.

Triggered by the approach of such a powerfully magical artefact as the SBS Hermione, the downed longship was coming back to life.

“Slower!” Emma shouted. “Don’t force it!”

“It’s fine! We’ve got it!”

All along the old longship, dirt and muck was being forcibly expelled from the insides by ancient cleaning charms, flying out into the water, and creating a murky, watery fog.

And then it was over.

Hermione panted.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Bentley glanced at the clock again. Any moment now the aurors would be redirecting Clare Cooper as she flooed back to Slytherin Manor from the Shoe.

He stood up, made his way out of his office, and spotted one of the serving ladies making the afternoon rounds. What was her name? Florence? No, Fiona! He walked over. “Excuse me, Fiona, I don’t suppose you have any of those wonderful egg and cress sandwiches, do you?”

“Yes, Minster Bentley.”

“Break time, Humble Hag?” asked a voice like a bassist in a cave.

Bentley didn’t need Fiona’s squeak or the wide eyes of the other wizards and witches in the room to know who was standing behind him.

He turned.

“Lord Slytherin, what a surprise.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“You have one hour,” Emma said, portioning out gillyweed to Hermione, Luna, and Daphne, who were all wearing bathing suits and warming charms.

“But what if things go wrong here?” Hermione asked. “You don’t have magic.”

“Plato will be making sure nothing goes wrong, young miss,” said a disembodied voice, causing her to jump slightly.

Luna giggled.

“Forgot he was there,” Hermione muttered.

“Ready, girls?” Daphne said.

They all nodded, started chewing, and when it started becoming difficult to breathe, dived out of the SBS Hermione, straight through the shimmering wall of water, and out into the North Atlantic.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“I hope I am not intruding?” Slytherin said.

“No, not at all,” Bentley replied. He had to admit, he hadn’t anticipated the meeting with Lord Slytherin to start out like this, but needs must. The man was obviously in a hurry.

“Good, because I have a problem that I need your help with.”

Mister Bentley smiled. “Of course you do. Why don’t we go to my office and discuss this in—”

“—My office, Humble Hag.”

“I was not aware you had an office in the ministry.”

“I have borrowed one of the ones for Lords of the Wizengamot.”

Mister Bentley shrugged. “Very well, then. Lead the way.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

If she hadn’t been a unicorn animagus, she’d for sure have been something aquatic, Hermione thought as she effortlessly swam towards the shipwreck, now clean of all the silt and muck, although, strangely, the magic had done nothing for all the coral covering every surface.

Daphne and Luna swam beside her, and only needed the tail to be mistaken for a pair of mermaids. They glided to the deck and then pulled themselves to the door leading to the tiny room at the back, which in normal circumstances would barely be called a shed.

‘After you,’ Daphne mimed to Luna, who gave a happy thumbs up and slipped inside. Hermione followed after the other two girls, looking around with bubbling excitement at being this close to something so obviously old, and which they were now exploring because of the work she’d done.

The passageways of the ship were as detailed as the records she’d read in Captain Slytherin’s notes and the expansion charms at work here were definitely on an order of magnitude more impressive than the ones used in their trunks, or even the more special ones provided by the noble house of Hawking.

What could Harry do if he had access to that kind of magic? Great things, surely.

She glided through the next corridor, pulled herself through the next door, and swam straight into Daphne, who was selfishly blocking the entrance. ‘Hey!’ Hermione angrily tapped on her future lady’s shoulder, only to slowly stop when she finally caught a glimpse of what was filling the room.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“So, what do we have to discuss?” Bentley asked once they were in Slytherin’s temporary office. He couldn’t help admiring the man’s taste. They were both sitting in plush leather armchairs, upholstered in emerald green, and crafted from whomping willow, while the walls had been altered from the usual ministry plastered decor to a warm panelling of alternating teak and poplar. “Is this by any chance about Clare Cooper?”

Lord Slytherin was tapping his fingers on his knee. “I don’t understand how you can justify this,” he said. “This is clearly not an abuse of the system. If anything, it is the system that is in the wrong. It is the system that allowed Clare to be taken from her family, to be forced to have sex with strangers against her will, and then to be made a criminal for something she did not understand.”

“Lord Slytherin, if the ministry uncovers evidence of abuse of the system, we have to investigate it, I’m sure you see that. What happened in Miss Coopers past is irrelevant. And I’m sure it’s unfortunate, but if someone doesn’t understand that what they’re doing wrong, that is even more reason for them to be held under the ministry’s watch.”

Slytherin continued to tap his knee with his fingers. Tap, tap, tap, tap—tap, tap, tap, tap.

“Besides,” Bentley continued, “the order has already gone out now. They should be picking her up around about now.”

“Truly?” Slytherin seemed to think for a few moments before leaning forward in his chair. “What is it you want, Mister Bentley?”

Mister Bentley smiled. He looked away and scratched the back of his head. “The Light’s muggle protection act … I don’t think you really care all that much about it, do you? Not really.”

Tap, tap, tap, tap—tap, tap, tap, tap.

“So, that’s it, is it?” Slytherin asked and Bentley was surprised to hear a note of bitterness in his voice. “Nothing but a cynical power play. Throwing an innocent person with a prison guarded by happiness sucking demons because it’s convenient.”

Mister Bentley sighed. “Honestly, I thought you’d be different from this. Look, it brings me no pleasure in saying this, but, in our world, it is very much the case that the strong take what they will, and the weak suffer what they must.”

Tap, tap, tap, tap—tap, tap … tap. “Is that so? You’re going to love this, then.”

Bentley hesitated. The bitterness in Slytherin’s voice had gone. Totally erased as if it had never been there, replaced instead by a cheerfully casual lilt.

“What do you mean?”

“Oh, it’s nothing.” Lord Slytherin put his hands on his knees and easily pushed himself up. “Just a little project I’m working on. That’s the other reason I wanted to talk to you. I need some advice.”

“Advice?”

Lord Slytherin walked over to one of the redecorated walls and tapped on it with his wand. Just like the wall in Diagon Alley, the wood panels started sliding up and over each other, quickly forming an arch into a second room, hidden from him at first, and now that the arch was there, obviously also a part of this one.

“Come! Come!” Slytherin pulled him up from his chair and hurried him towards a table in the middle of the second room, covered by a white sheet. “Tell me what you think.” And with that, he pulled back the sheet.

Bentley stared in horror.

“I think the model makers did quite a good job on your house, didn’t they?” Slytherin said.

“But, but..” Mister Bentley tried to find words to fully express what he was seeing. “Mrs. Bun … She wouldn’t. She couldn’t!”

“Couldn’t decide that she’s getting a bit on in life and that she’d prefer to move to a smaller place nearer her children? She is a dear, isn’t she? Has she made you any of her blueberry pie recently? I suspect not, given how busy you always are with work—out at the crack of dawn every day, apparently.”

The whole of Mrs. Bun’s formally beautiful garden had been totally cobblestoned over. The model house in the middle was much the same, but the garden!

“Witch-co have been looking for a place to put a warehouse for ages,” Slytherin cheerfully continued. “It just so happens that your neighbourhood is in the perfect central position—and a few expansion charms will make it ideal, and all totally legal. Of course, having a magical warehouse next door does come with some downsides, people in and out all day, noise, mess, not to mention it becomes a beacon for magical pests of all kinds, but on the plus side, you’ll always be the first to get your milk in the morning.”

Bentley continued to stare in horror.

Slytherin’s voice then lost all hint of amusement. “I am perfectly happy to play political games with you until the world ends, Humble Hag, but if you fuck with mine, I will fuck with yours.”

Bentley looked into the green and black mask and saw no mercy. He really had misjudged, hadn’t he? His voice became desperate. “But arresting Clare Cooper is an executive order from the minister! I can’t rescind it.”

“Then I suggest you get working on changing the minister’s mind, Humble Hag. And quickly. I have this option until you retire. I’m sure I don’t need to explain myself further.”

Mister Bentley fled the room with just one goal in mind. Save his haven.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

One, two, three, four …

The counting had begun almost as soon as Hermione had floated into the room, and hadn’t stopped since.

Twenty-five, twenty-six, twenty-seven …

Solid gold objects of every form and function littered the underwater space like the living-room of a hydrophilic hoarder.

151, 152, 153 …

Despite Daphne’s attempts to stop her, Luna had already adorned herself with all manner of golden objects, including necklaces, bangles, rings, and even an actual crown, and was now sitting in a massive golden chair playing the part of aloof queen surveying her kingdom, her long, blonde hair floating in the water, the rest of her, weighed down with enough treasure to buy a house … or three.

289, 290, 291 …

It just went on and on. Hermione could scarcely believe how much they had here. And it was they, wasn’t it? After all, this really was Slytherin’s treasure, which meant it rightfully belonged to Harry. And what Harry could do with all this …

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It took another whole ten hours to get back to Slytherin Manor.

Emma firmly told them to leave everything where it was, and just bring back their notes and memories. After all, these artefacts had value in the muggle world as much for their historical value as their gold content.

Hermione, Daphne, and Luna catalogued as much of the treasure as they could before leaving with a few basic rune stones in place to conceal the longship from passing magicals and muggles alike and Harry would come by later to put a fidelius in.

When they finally all burst into the kitchen from the basement, it was to find Harry, disguised as Lord Slytherin, personally tutoring a recovering Clare.

Shooting out of the floo ten minutes early to find two intimidating men with huge shields and wands pointed at her had not been a happy experience. The Aurors had not stripped her, which had been a small blessing, but their boat had still been halfway to Azkaban when the order had arrived by owl that the aurors were to turn back and deliver Miss Cooper, unharmed, and with the ministry’s apologies, to Gairsay Island.

“We even got Bentley to disband that custom’s point on the mainland,” Lord Slytherin said, while Clare took another sip of fire-whisky. “Now, what did you find?”

Stunned by what had been going on while they’d been underwater, it took Hermione a moment to process what he’d asked, but as soon as she remembered about the gold, it all came back.

“There’s just so much of it!” Daphne said.

“I can’t imagine what ‘king of old’ the captain was talking about,” Hermione huffed. “Genghis Khan wasn’t for another three-hundred years!”

“And we now have the money for a menagerie too,” Luna said.

Daphne looked surprised. “You didn’t say you wanted a menagerie before.”

“Well, we didn’t have the gold for it before.”

“We don’t have the gold for it now.”

“No, but we will soon.”

The conversation went on long into the night, and long past everyone’s bedtime, especially the girls’, and, technically, Harry’s too—not that that was ever an issue.

At one point though, Hermione stepped outside for a breath of bracing Orkney air, and found herself alone with her lord. “My lord?”

“Yes?”

“Are we alone?”

“Yes.”

“Is your ageing potion going to wear off soon?”

“In about five minutes.”

“Can we talk then?”

“We can.”

They waited five minutes. Then, Lord Slytherin’s clothes started to shrink, along with the rest of him. Harry reached up and took off his mask. “What’s up, Hermione?”

“Harry. I … I spoke with my Mum about the whole colonisation thing, and she suggested that muggle parents should be allowed to choose if they emigrate to the wizarding world or not.”

“You appreciate the problems that would cause, don’t you? Having a class of people unable to use magic in a world of magic users.”

“Yes, but it would be a problem created by doing the right thing. There are always going to be problems. So choosing to have that kind of problem is better.”

Harry smiled. “What if I told you I thought you were wrong?”

Hermione bit her lip. “Then I’d argue with you.”

“Why?”

“Because you may soon be one of the richest wizards in the magical world, not immediately, but soon. I trust you to always protect me, Harry, but I want you to protect others too. I want you to be the hero to others that you are to me.”

Harry sighed. “You know that won’t always be possible, right?”

“I know. We’re struggling against people who would see you, me, and all our friends dead or in servitude, and against a world that doesn’t care, but that doesn’t mean we can’t take opportunities to do good when they pop up.”

Silence descended on the pair for a moment. The only sound was the chatter from the cottage behind them and the whistling of the wind through the trees.

Eventually Harry said, “Hermione?”

“Yes, Harry?”

“Don’t ever let yourself doubt that I need you more than you could possibly imagine.”

Hermione beamed.

—End of Chapter Forty-Six—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: This chapter was drafted, and made available early, on the LeadVonE discord server. The next chapter is quite a bit shorter than this one, but is already finished and available to read in its entirety in the same way (it’s more of a bonus chapter—like Daphne Goes Down to the Village). Details can be found through my profile page.

Sticky Note: If you want to keep abreast of the release schedule, as well as any changes and the occasional piece of bonus content, you can head over to [www * leadvone * com] and sign up for the Gray Mailing List.

If you enjoy my writing and would like to see more of it, please consider checking out my original projects, which you can also get access to through my website.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Interlude — There’s No Business like Hogwarts Business

The Gryffindor common room was warmth and grandeur realised in stone and magic. Orange flames burned on every wall, a roaring fire filled the hearth at all times of the day, and all throughout the space, large comfy sofas were filled with the weight and chatter of several dozen student witches and wizards.

Sitting around the central fireplace, the boy who lived held brooding court with his collection of sycophants, hangers-on, yes-men, underlings, pawns, fan-girls, occasional actual friend, and Virgo Malfoy.

On the other side of the room, Fred Weasley was sat and silently studying the scene, resting, with his chin in his hands, while he considered things.

He and his brother were in what could only be described as an interesting situation. Younger sons of a Light, pureblood, ancient but common house, they had somehow managed to insert themselves as business partners to the mysterious and powerful Lord Slytherin, even if they’d never actually met the man. They’d accepted a patronage agreement with the other Potter son on a whim, and that had somehow snowballed into a contract with Devlin Whitehorn whose family made the Nimbus broomstick line, providing an income stream that, while not quite setting them up for life, was very impressive for a couple of fifteen-year-olds. He doubted any of their more noble classmates were doing five-digit business deals on the side while juggling their education.

Most of their attention now was on general problem solving for some mystery project for The Settlers, Lord Slytherin’s other garden shed inventors. Fred wasn’t sure exactly what the project was, but suspected it was something to do with living underwater. George, by contrast, thought Slytherin wanted to enter the flying market with a broomstick of his own.

Of course, while all this was very cool, it didn’t stop the fact that neither of them was looking forward to the sparks that might fly when Mum learned of what they were up to, and even more so that Dad had been helping them too. The fact that so much money was involved was unlikely to make it any better. But they would not let that stop them. They were their own wizards—capable of so much more than slotting into the ministry machine—to climb and politic their way up a ladder created by someone else. Much better to craft your own ladder with you already on top, even if it didn’t reach quite as high.

“Just let us know if you need any more, right?” George said, standing a few feet away and shaking the hand of an upperclassman.

“Sure thing,” the upperclassman happily replied before turning and walking away, his other hand clutching a small box, full of Chocolate Frogs and Fizzing Whizzbees.

George landed beside him, pockets jingling. “Over a galleon so far this week. We’ll have to make another trip down to Honeydukes before too long.”

Fred nodded absently, eyes still planted on the boy who lived’s little group of followers, plus Virgo Malfoy. Something about that girl just creeped him out, although he couldn’t put his finger exactly on what.

“We should make a trip tomorrow,” George said.

“Mmmm … ?”

“I said, we should make a trip to Honeydukes tomorrow. We’re running low on supplies and it’s even a Hogsmeade weekend, so we won’t need to sneak around the village. You okay, Fred? You seem a bit out of it.”

“Just thinking about things.”

“Oh, what things?”

“Should we even bother selling more sweets and drinks to our housemates? It’s not much money compared to the other stuff we do.”

“It was your idea.”

“Yeah, I know, but I was just thinking that maybe we should focus a bit more.”

“It doesn’t take that much time.”

“Couldn’t we use that time better though?” He turned towards George who was looking thoughtful.

“Maybe,” his twin conceded. “But what is it we actually get out of selling stuff to our classmates?”

“Money?”

“Yes, but we also get a mindset. The Weasley Twins are business people. They do business. If we need something, we go to them. Sure it’s not all that valuable now, but in the future …”

“… When many of them are heads of houses,” Fred continued, “it will be valuable. I see your point.”

“Exactly!”

Fred hummed for a few moments, thinking deeply. “But if that’s the case, why only the Gryffindors?”

There was a moment of silence between the two twins, during which a trio of witches a few sofas over shrieked in laughter over some private joke.

“Good point,” George slowly replied. “But how would we do that? It works now because everyone knows where to find us. The other houses can’t come into the Gryffindor Common Room.”

“We set up somewhere else in the castle?” Fred asked. “Somewhere teachers aren’t likely to stumble on.”

“But all those places are hard to get to. You have to know exactly what to do. We can’t risk handing out parchments.”

“No, I agree. Word of mouth only.”

“So how?”

“Mmmmm …” Fred put his chin back in his hands and stared off into the middle distance. “I’m sure we’ll figure something out.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the Headmaster’s office, Headmaster Gilderoy Lockhart sliced the seal of yet another parchment, and started reading. His hair wasn’t quite as coiffed as normal and a few grey hairs had started to poke through. Who’d have known that running a school would be so much work! He’d expected there would be more leisurely walks in the grounds and fewer merlin-damned meetings—meetings with parents, meetings with staff, occasional meetings with students, with the ministry, the board, and even other schools, now that plans for the tri-wizard tournament were being drawn up.

He rubbed his eyes, sighed, and continued reading about the modified rules Karkaroff was demanding they integrate into the tournament. Then a ghost slipped through his door. Gilderoy’s sigh immediately turned into a wide grin, his eyes brightened, and his whole posture shifted into one of jovial confidence so quickly one might believe the world had just glitched.

“Sir Nick!” Gilderoy beamed. “Good old Nick, my friend! What can I do for you?”

Sir Nicholas de Mimsy-Porpington’s face stayed impassive. “You know last week was Hogsmeade weekend? I thought you should be aware, Headmaster, that I have just come across two students in one of the corridors selling wares they obviously bought from the village.”

Gilderoy’s huge grin didn’t fade. “Yes?”

“Yes, headmaster. Their set up looked rather … well planned.”

“Not selling anything dangerous were they?”

“No, headmaster, but the rules say—”

“—Well then, I don’t think we need to worry about this do we? A small bit of entrepreneurialism is to be expected! Encouraged, even! Yes, that’s it exactly, don’t worry about it, hear me?”

Sir Nicholas didn’t look at all happy, but bowed deeply. “As you command, Headmaster.”

The ghost then left and Gilderoy collapsed back into his chair. Honestly! He didn’t have time to deal with every small little thing. Children selling sweets? He had more important things to deal with.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“You’re doing so well, Sophie, I’m very proud of you.”

Sophie beamed as Hermione read over her latest essay—the one that Professor Snape had given an O. When she’d first come to Hogwarts, her grades had been terrible, and being a Ravenclaw with bad grades was like being an easily tired house elf and her position in the social hierarchy as a muggleborn girl of modest means had been very clear to everyone, even if a few of them had been kind about it.

But now—now she was outperforming them all. Now, she was the top of her class, the best-scoring Ravenclaw in her year. Her classmates eyed her with grudging respect, and many of the younger ones even came to her asking for help—so many, in fact, that she’d had to start turning some of them away. She was nowhere near Hermione, of course, but miracles could only go so far.

“Keep it up,” Hermione finished handing the essay back to her. “We’ll be starting wandless magic soon and you’ll need to be as far ahead as you can be to keep up.”

“Yes,” Sophie said, practically glowing from the praise. “Thank you.”

The Founders Club meeting continued on like it usually did, but with the added buzz among their year about their soon to begin wandless magic lessons.

Eventually they all started to file out and she found herself falling in with Justin and Kevin.

“So unfair that we didn’t get to go to Hogsmeade with the others,” Kevin said. “I’d have liked that. I never get to try all the sweets at Diagon Alley.”

Justin looked both ways before lowering his voice. “If it’s just sweets you want, I might know how to help you there.”

“How?” Sophie asked. “You bought some more?”

“No, but, well … follow me, they should be around now. This is actually really cool.” His eyes now had a playful glint to them.

“Who?” Kevin asked, “What’s really cool?” But Justin was already leading them to the grand staircase. “Okay,” he said, when they were obviously alone. “You just have to remember this, right?” and he proceeded to recite a poem.

Go to the fifth floor,

Towards the hospital rooms,

Duck under the tapestry,

Find the armour that looms,

Turn three times while humming,

What tune is up to you,

Then walk back the way you came,

To find us, our service, and brews,

And many more things too.

“Go to the fifth floor?” Sophie asked.

“Service and brews?” Kevin echoed.

“Yes,” Justin said, still smiling. “Go on, see if you can find the place.”

It took them several minutes of wandering to eventually identify which tapestry the poem was talking about—several of the ones they first tried had solid walls behind them—but they eventually located it and the armour that looked like it had been made for the groundskeeper. Sophie chose to hum Rule Britannia while Kevin hummed the opening song of Postman Pat, and Justin, the opening bars of Flight of the Valkyries.

They then made their way back up the passageway, wondering over the fact that, somehow, the paintings and decorations had changed. They turned a corner into another wide corridor and saw, sitting to one side of the passageway, facing the opposite wall, an open trunk—an open trunk that an older student with flaming red hair was busy climbing out of.

“Welcome,” The boy said, hopping down and spreading his arms wide. “You have quested through many perilous perils to find us, but now you have. Fred Weasley, at your service. And you, Mister Finch-Fletchley, I didn’t think we’d see you again so quickly, but I’m happy we are.”

After the introductions were made, Fred Weasley started showing off all the stuff he had for sale. While the boys chatted, Sophie stole over to the trunk and inspected the sign that had been hung over it.

Sweets, Drinks, and Potions.

Need a pick me up for a late night of studying?

Running low on Blood Pops?

No worries! We can help. See our list of prices below.

Special requests considered on a case by case basis.

Opening hours between six and eight Monday to Friday.

Then a list of prices and services.

Sophie ran her finger down the list, fascinated.

“But if you want to push the boat out, can I suggest these little wonders?” Fred said to Kevin, while Justin was enjoying a Chocolate Cauldron he’d just bought.

“Not sure if I have the money for that,” Kevin said, looking longingly at the contents of a tray.

“Not to worry. We have many unique flavours to suit every taste and pocket.”

Sophie looked up and down the corridor, otherwise empty save for the portrait of a sleeping old wizard surrounded by arcane-looking instruments. Truth be told, she was rather sick of being the poor muggleborn of Ravenclaw. She couldn’t do anything about the muggleborn, but the poor bit …

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Classes were just ending. Fred Weasley packed his satchel, gave George a nod, which they both understood, and made his way alone towards the secret hallway where they now did all their research in their trunk while occasionally taking orders for all sorts of things from an ever-growing portion of the student body. Even he was amazed at how well their little project was going. Hufflepuffs, Ravenclaws, even Slytherins were now regular visitors. The cloak and dagger nature of it all appeared particularly attractive to the students. They hadn’t needed to pick up and run from a teacher even once yet. No one had tattled. Not even the few prefects who’d learned the poem’s secret.

They’d picked the spot specifically because it was tough to get to, almost no-one ever came here, and several secret passageways surrounded it in just the right way for them to put up some basic wards, the most important being a muggle repelling ward. It wasn’t a perfect defence against Filch, but it certainly helped.

Fred hummed a popular Celestina Warbeck song while turning around three times, walked back down the corridor, turned the corner, and stopped dead. The girl who’d been with the second year boys from a few days ago was sitting at a small table a few paces away from their trunk, stacked high with books. She was looking at him nervously, a book open in her hands, having obviously heard him approaching.

“Now, what’s all this then?” he asked, sauntering over. “I didn’t think this was that great a spot to study.”

The girl—Sophie Roper, wasn’t it?—pointed at a small card at the front of her desk, which read—

Tutoring Sessions

2 sickles an hour

Any subject

“I just thought there wasn’t any law against me doing what you were doing,” she said quickly. “And you weren’t offering tutoring so it’s not like I’m competing with you or anything.”

Fred turned to loom over the smaller girl. “Yes, but you see, little Ravenclaw, we have certain contingencies in place if a teacher finds us, and we put a lot of work into making sure this place was hidden, and that people would know how to find us.”

“So?” the girl said. “It’s not like you own this bit of corridor.”

“No, but you being here too makes things difficult for us.”

“So you’re saying I can’t be here?”

Fred frowned. They hadn’t planned for this.

Footsteps approached, but he knew it was just George.

“Fred? What’s going on?”

Fred quickly explained the situation to his twin while the girl glared nervously up at them.

They went into a huddle a little way away from the new table and cast a basic privacy ward.

“So, what do we do?” Fred asked. “Tell her to go away?”

“She might go to a teacher,” George replied.

“Yeah, she might, but she won’t. Unless she wants the whole school to hate her.”

“We can’t bet on that.”

“I think we could.”

“Yes, but I’ve got a better idea. Why not let her stay here, but charge her rent?”

“How much?”

“A sickle a day?”

“She’d never be able to afford it.”

“What about a share of her profits?”

“Could work …”

“And remember what we were talking about before? We want people to think the Weasley Twins mean business. Surely other business people are even better for that than customers.”

“Too true, oh twin of mine.”

On the other side of the corridor, Sophie watched the older boys as they huddled together, still feeling as nervous as she feared she looked. This was, without a shadow of a doubt, one of the scariest things she’d ever done. There had been the troll last year, of course, but she hadn’t run into that, she’d just been there. The damsel in distress. This was her doing something scary of her own free will. A part of her mind was voicing the rather loud opinion that this was all not worth it just for a bit of extra spending money.

Her nerves were not helped when the twins simultaneously looked up from their huddle right at her and grinned.

“Miss Roper—” one started.

“—We’re impressed by your determination,” the other continued, “and would like to make a deal with you.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the headmaster’s office, Gilderoy Lockhart was busy. Very busy in fact. A small pile of parchment was stacked up on one side, but that could wait. This could not.

“I’ve written myself into a corner!” he exclaimed. “How do I get myself out of it? I can’t have the boy-who-lived kill his enemy! This is a children’s book! But I can’t use the power of love again—I used that last time. What if I have one of his friends produce an amulet that solves the problem? Yes! Genius! And I can justify it by setting it up as the MacGuffin of the next book! Oh, Gilderoy, you amazing man, you!”

“Ahem,” said a voice.

Gilderoy’s entire body jerked as he tried to recalibrate to not being alone, only to realise that he was being addressed by one of the many paintings that were sharing space with the many beaming visages of himself around the walls.

“Yes, Phineas?”

“I have a guest to see you, Headmaster,” the rather grouchy painting said. “She seems rather excited.”

“A painting?”

“Indeed.”

“What does she want?”

Phineas didn’t get to respond though, because at that moment, a rather thin woman wearing far too much jewellery appeared in Phineas’ painting, and started shrieking, “Crass commercialism! A den of smugglers and profiteers! Here! In the hallowed halls of education and learning!”

Gilderoy put his hands over his ears. “My dear lady, what are you talking about? And I’m using the word ‘talking’ in the loosest possible sense.”

“I was visiting an old friend of mine in one of the less visited parts of the castle, and what do I find there? Trade! Barter! A black market of wheeler-dealers plying their illicit craft, taking advantage of the innocent and hoodwinking the gullible!”

Lockhart looked at the woman with a tired expression. “You mean you found students selling sweets?”

“A nest of pirates and racketeers!”

“Oh, go away and shut up you crazy old bat.”

The woman’s expression froze, she seemed to struggle with herself, but did dip a small curtsey and say, “As you command, Headmaster.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Sally Smith, daughter of a branch line of the Ancient and Noble House of Smith carefully placed her miniature anvil on the floor in front of her with a defiant flourish. Down the corridor, on the other side of the Weasley twin’s trunk, Zacharias Smith, Heir of the main line of the Ancient and Noble House of Smith, placed his own miniature anvil on a large slice of tree trunk with a similarly defiant flourish. Neither looked at each other as they proceeded to populate their own tables with all manner of trinkets, necklaces, earrings, pendants, chokers, and other types of jewellery, mostly bronze and copper, but here and there, a few pieces in steel, silver and even gold.

Neither cousin looked at each other as they picked up tiny hammers from neat collections of tools, and continued not looking at each other as, with obvious expertise, they started tapping away at thin strips of metal on their respective anvils.

They weren’t alone. A small audience, mostly friends (different friends), were milling around to watch the show. Fred Weasley was watching the two new entrants to their little hidden space, while George was talking to an older Hufflepuff who wanted to take the tutoring space left by Sophie’s inability to service the older students. Sophie herself was busy with a first year, reviewing the basic theories of magical capacity in regards to transfiguration.

Even as Fred’s gaze passed back through the two Smiths’ tables, the thought occurred to him that he really should ask them about what family magics they had available, and if they’d be willing to charm other, more utilitarian objects.

“Excuse me.” He was being addressed by a fourth year Fred knew only by face. “I don’t suppose you’d have something more filling than sweets would you?”

Fred smiled. “Of course!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Headmaster Gilderoy Lockhart collapsed back in his chair and gazed out of the window, exhausted. He really needed an assistant or something. Someone to help him with all this work. But that wasn’t likely to happen. It wasn’t as though he’d be willing to spend the money himself, and the school board certainly wouldn’t.

Out on the grounds, Hagrid was busy hauling a stag towards his smokehouse through the frosty grass. The cloudy sky was a dark blue, stained with orange and purple. It was definitely getting darker earlier. He relaxed into his chair and let his senses float meaninglessly through the wards of Hogwarts. They were just so damn hard to read. So many senses, so many tastes. He had good taste, of that he was sure, but distinguishing between so many was way beyond him. He wouldn’t be surprised if that was why Dumbledore ate so many Bertie Botts Every Flavour Beans—to keep in practice.

He let his magic wander until it settled on an unusually large concentration of tastes, somewhere in the castle. None of the common rooms, he was pretty sure of that. There were four other concentrations for that. Nor the Great Hall—he was pretty sure he’d got that one down. Had even Dumbledore been able to do this? It was bloody difficult.

Gilderoy stood up and wandered down the stairs until he reached one of the portraits who he knew wouldn’t be staring at him all day every day until he stopped being headmaster. “Excuse me, my good man, could you tell me if there might be a large collection of students somewhere in the castle right now?”

“A large collection?” sniffed a knight in golden armour. “I don’t know, but I can ask around.”

“Please do so.”

The resulting magical mystery tour lasted a good hour and involved him getting lost several times as he made his way through parts of the castle he’d swear had never existed in his day. He’d had to ask directions back to the central staircase multiple times from paintings, ghosts, and even Lily Potter and Minerva McGonagall who he’d met separately, and Filius Flitwick, whose classroom he’d accidentally dropped in on, through the ceiling, twice. Finally he took directions from yet another painting, found a ridiculously large suit of armour, hummed three times while turning around, made his way back the other way, turned the corner, fully aware of the audible bustle of what could only be a large group of students, and stared.

Close to a dozen tables had been set up on one side of the corridor, full of all sorts and everything, each manned by a wizard or witch, each of whom was busy with something or other, whether reading, selling, or in the cast of a few, actually making products right in front of the eyes of their customers.

One witch was baking biscuits in a tiny magical oven. Another was knitting scarves, while two more pairs of knitting needles floated overhead, perfectly replicating her each and every movement. A boy was busy painting one of his classmates, while another was playing a wooden flute, filling the air with a soft melody and perfectly completing the market fete feeling. What had to be at least three dozen other students milled around the tables, chatting, laughing, watching, and generally just being a part of something.

The chatting slowed though as one-by-one the students noticed him standing there and went silent, eyes widening as the realisation that they might well be in serious trouble became apparent.

Gilderoy shook his head, gave them a roguish smile, and walked towards them. “What’s all this then? What’s all this then? Busy setting up a market? Students today, dear Merlin! Even I’d never have had the brass to try something like this when I was at Hogwarts, and if you’ve ever read of my many adventures, which of course you have, you’ll know that I wouldn’t say something like that lightly.”

He stopped at one girl’s stall. “What are you selling, little lady?” As if it wasn’t perfectly obvious.

“Magical Jewellery,” the girl said. “Imbued with my family magic.”

“And your family is?”

“Smith.”

“Smith.” Gilderoy stroked his chin. “Your head of house is on the board isn’t he?”

“He is.”

Gilderoy waggled a finger. “And what would he say if he learned about all this?”

“He’d say, ‘did you get a good price?’ and, ‘I hope you weren’t selling junk and disgracing the family name.’ Unlike some people.” She then turned and glared at a boy manning a similar stall who glared back.

Gilderoy considered this before deciding to go for an easier target. “Okay, okay, so who’s in charge here?”

The entire crowd, as one, turned to where two boys with red hair were busy trying to sneak away. There was a conspicuous hole in the table line up.

“Ahah! So these are the scallywags! The Weasley Twins! I should have known! You can’t just go around setting up shop in the middle of a school. You need all sorts of things. You need licenses. You need your family’s permission.”

The two boys had now turned around and straightened up, doing their best to look like they hadn’t been trying to sneak away. “Please, Headmaster,” one of them said, “We do have permission from our family.”

“You do?” He said doubtfully.

A little rummaging around later, he was reading a very official-looking document from the boy’s father giving them the right to set up a business in the family’s name. The terms were extremely vague and the scope of the business was ‘buying and selling,’ which meant just about anything.

“Okay,” he said giving them another roguish grin, “But you still need permission.” Behind him, Gilderoy was very aware of nearly fifty students all silently watching the proceedings.

The twins looked at each other. Then back at him. “Can we then?” one asked. “We did get someone asking to set up a small bookshop the other day, you know, impulse fiction, not the sort of thing you get in the library.”

“Bribery!” Lockhart laughed and waggled another finger under the boy’s noses. “Very naughty. And absolutely not,” and then more quietly said, “but perhaps we should go and talk about this in private anyway? Mmm?”

The boys both nodded and after a quick discussion up the corridor which certainly wasn’t about them also selling his books, he turned and addressed the still frozen students, “Boys and Girls, I am going to leave now. I’ve never been here. I have not seen anything. I’m sure you understand?”

They all nodded.

“But first, I really must try one of those lovely looking biscuits!”

It was amazing how quickly the hustle and bustle picked back up, even with the headmaster in their midst.

Fred leaned closer to George. “Close call there.”

“Indeed oh twin of mine.”

“What should we do now?”

“Make sure he gets as many biscuits as he wants, free of charge. It’s what Harry would do.”

“Where is Harry anyway?”

George smirked. “Over there getting his hair ruffled by Lockhart.”

“Oh wow—and Ginny?”

“Left half an hour ago.”

“Should we leave too? You know … hop away?”

George smirked. “An ice idea, but we’ve got to watch the nest.”

“Waddle I do without you?”

“Slip up far too often, that’s what.”

The two chuckled and made their way back to the tables, taking their role as the hosts of the party, finding their quidditch team-mates, and making sure everyone was fed and watered. There would be plenty of time for serious research with the big boys later. Now was just for them and their classmates.

—End of Chapter Forty-Seven—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: I hope you enjoyed this fluffy little bonus chapter. I wasn’t originally planning to write it. It just sort of happened. If you did enjoy it, please consider checking out my original projects. All support is appreciated. You can find the links through my website [www * leadvone * com].

A/N: This chapter was drafted and available early through the LeadVonE discord server. The next chapter is not yet available, but if you’d fancy discussing this chapter, or anything else to do with DP&SW, feel free to head over there anyway.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Soul Anchors—Part One

Harry’s trunk was still and silent.

Ginny Weasley sat in one of the armchairs, fiddling with the skirt of her robes, and occasionally glancing towards her current sole companion.

Opposite her, Daphne Greengrass sat in another armchair, silently staring into space. On the table between them, Daphne’s pet, Freekey, nibbled on a brazil nut.

Every few seconds, Ginny felt the acute squeezing sensation that always accompanied apparition. She’d been feeling it for many hours now. “We must be getting close,” she muttered, easily loudly enough for Daphne to hear.

Daphne nodded. “Soon,” she said, her eyes not leaving the small spot on the wall she’d been staring at for the last ten minutes.

Ginny took a deep, shuddery breath and gripped the armchairs tightly. When they’d left Hogwarts, her heart had been beating heavily, a rhythmic pounding she could feel in her ears. It faded down as they crossed the English Channel, and the journey since then had been calm, but focused. Daphne had gone over the plan with her again and again, until it felt like they’d both be able to recite it in their sleep.

“That’s enough,” Daphne had said, somewhere over the south of France. “Let’s get some rest before we arrive.”

But whatever rest the future Lady Slytherin had thought they’d get, hadn’t accounted for the sheer restlessness that would accompany doing nothing. Ginny felt the tension rising back up in her. She could feel her heart pumping blood. She could focus her brain on no one thing for more than a second or two before it jumped off again to some other small detail.

Her wand in its holster.

Her silk robes against her skin.

The dagger concealed under her skirts.

Would she be able to kill, if needed?

Would she hesitate?

Would she regret?

Would she let everyone down?

No.

Ginny’s heart pounded faster. She recognised this feeling. It was the feeling she always got whenever she was about to do something new and dangerous. She’d felt this way when first sneaking out of the Burrow to practice flying. When she’d first followed Harry away from home. When she’d stolen her broomstick back from Mum and Dad. And when she’d gone after the teenage version of Lord Voldemort. This feeling. This … rush.

Ginny took another deep breath and gripped the armrests tightly again. She shut her eyes.

Suddenly, something felt different. Something was missing. The apparition squeeze, which pressed in on them every so often—it wasn’t there any more.

She opened her eyes.

“We’re here,” Daphne murmured.

Ginny nodded.

They waited.

Eventually, a feeling of intense confusion swept over Ginny. She remained confused until Harry climbed in and told her the secret to the new fidelius charm he’d set up around the trunk. They all climbed out of the trunk and Ginny got her first ever view of the city of Rome—the former capital of the Roman Empire, and current seat of the International Confederation of Wizards.

It was a massive stone wall. She knew this was the first layer of defences of the Castel Sant’angelo, an almost most most ancient fortress, predating Hogwarts by almost a thousand years. There would be more defences inside.

“The time is seven o’clock,” Harry whispered into the darkness. “We have one hour left to plant the order.” He turned to Ginny. “Once phase one is complete you will have exactly fifteen minutes to get in and out before the area wards record your presence. But you can only move within the less warded area A.”

Ginny nodded.

“Are we all ready?” Harry asked.

Ginny nodded again, and beside her, Daphne did too.

“Alright.” Harry signalled Daphne for Freekey.

He then sat down, pointed his wand at the little monkey, and whispered, “Imperio.”

Harry, now controlling Freekey’s body, jerked, sat up, and looked around.

While this was going on, Ginny had fetched the long extendable pipe from the trunk and was busily setting it up. Moments later it was leaning against the outer wall of the castle.

Freekey jumped on the pipe, quickly shimmied up, and disappeared over the wall.

Ginny and Daphne quickly took the pipe back down.

They sat down next to Harry, whose eyes were tightly shut.

If everything went well, Freekey would be back in twelve minutes.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It actually took twenty minutes. Harry spoke infrequently, and the few times he had were variations of, ‘phew,’ or, ‘that was close’.

It wasn’t doing anything for Ginny’s heightened nerves, and by the time Freekey’s head poked back over the wall and jumped down, she just wanted to get on with it.

“You’re back,” Daphne mewed quietly, hugging the little monkey to her chest.

Harry had already opened his human eyes again. “All to plan,” he whispered. “Ginny, your turn. Earpieces on—potions, masks, everything.”

Ginny and Daphne slipped on the runic mirror earpieces Daphne and Hermione had used the previous year during the stone mission. Ginny grabbed the three potions she needed and drank them all. While her body changed, she firmly attached a flame-red mask to her face.

Ginny’s heart started to pound faster. This was it. There was only one person Harry knew who could theoretically pull this off, and she was that person.

Harry and Daphne both climbed back into the trunk, giving her one last good luck between them.

Ginny closed the lid, shrunk it down, and slipped it into her pocket.

Right, now.

She pulled the true cloak of invisibility out from her other pocket, wrapped it around herself, pooled magic at the tips of her fingers, picked up a small stone from the ground with her other hand, flicked it up the wall, aimed her spell at the ascending pebble, and switched.

Step.

Light as air, she arrived on top of the wall and looked around, eyes darting into the shadows for any kind of threat. She didn’t see one, so she ran along the wall towards the first tower, constantly tasting the air for unknown magics. The buildings inside the castle grounds were narrow and packed together. Stone arches across streets below made for easy traversal. One tightrope-like walk and a switched stone later found her alighted on the roof of her target building.

There was a door. It was open. She slipped inside, and made her way down the narrow spiral staircase, down, down, down.

She arrived at the bottom. She paused. The stone walls were rough and damp. The ceiling was low. This was certainly underground. In front of her, she could feel a magical barrier—a perimeter ward—nothing special yet, just a detection line.

“I’ve arrived,” she whispered.

Daphne’s voice whispered in her ear. “Eye of Kilrogg in five.”

Seconds later, Ginny sensed the divination magic of Daphne’s magic eye fade into being beside her.

“Green Mask says this is the place,” Daphne whispered.

“Guide me,” Ginny whispered back.

The eye-ball zipped off ahead, passing straight through the ward line as though it wasn’t even there.

“Forward until you reach the second left,” Daphne whispered.

Ginny ran forward, using the invisibility cloak to pass through the ward line without bothering to switch through it. She reached the second left and turned.

“Forward,” Daphne whispered. “Next right.”

Ginny turned right. Ever-burning torches flicked on the stone walls. The floor was damp with water.

“Next left. Third right. The stone angel is around the next corner—no! Contact from the stone angel!”

Ginny skidded to a halt and ducked back around the corner she’d just come around. She heard the grinding of stone against stone and then voices echoing down the corridor.

“I suggest Piazza Magico.”

“Bei Merlin, bitte nicht. The place is full of tourists.”

“We are tourists.”

“Och, nein. We are expats—big difference.”

The voices were heading away from her position so Ginny risked a peek around the corner. She was just in time to see two old wizards with beards almost as long as Dumbledore’s disappear around the opposite corner. The stone angel ground back into position, concealing a doorway that had momentarily been open.

“Go now,” Daphne whispered urgently. “Fifth brick to the left, thirteenth up,” she continued, as Ginny ran to a spot just off to the right of the stone angel. She counted the bricks and sent a pulse of magic into the stonework. A second door opened in front of her, unveiling a secret passageway.

“Go, go, go,” Daphne whispered. “You’re clear until you get to the end room.”

Ginny sped up the passageway parallel to the angel-guarded corridor as quickly as she could and stopped when she reached the wall at the end.

Muffled through the stonework next to her, a soft, female voice said, “Grazie per la visita. Thank you for visiting the ICW.”

“Stay here,” Daphne whispered. “Someone is standing in eyesight of the wall on the other side. Four bricks up, seven across.”

Ginny waited for what felt like forever, heart hammering. She was acutely aware of the time limit they had, and what was likely to happen should they fail to meet it.

“Go now!” Daphne hissed.

Ginny pulsed magic into the correct brick, let it swing open, and neatly stepped into the room beyond. The wall sealed itself up again almost the moment she was through.

A partition hid the section of wall she’d just come through from the rest of the room.

Safe.

Daphne’s voice whispered in her ear again. “Around the corner to your right are the four security stations for wand checking. Only one is occupied. There is a young witch standing in front of the occupied station and a wizard walking away from your position to the exit door to your left. None are reacting to the eye, so they don’t appear to be able to sense magic. Walk around the corner, to the centre of the room, and walk straight through the security checks to the open door at the far end. Do not stop unless you encounter a necromancy ward. Go, now!”

Ginny went. There were several perimeter wards in the security room—one for animagi, one for vampires, and another for demons. There was also another detection ward and the cloak made short work of all four just as it had done the one from before.

She reached the door at the end and slipped through. Then she stopped dead. There was another ward right in front of her, less than a foot from the tip of her nose. “Necromancy ward,” she whispered into her earpiece. She slipped the cloak off herself, trading the perfect invisibility of the cloak for the partial invisibility of her disillusionment charm. She tucked the cloak into her pocket, well aware of the security wizards in the room just behind her, and fished out a small ever-cold ice cube from another.

She chucked the ice-cube across the ward and switched with it a moment later, letting the cube fall to the floor where she’d been before. The cubes were ever-cold in name only and would be gone before too long. She hurried down the corridor again, taking care to follow Daphne’s directions, and after one more flight of stairs downwards, several more necromancy wards, and even one bottomless pit, which she’d had to switch over, she arrived at an unmarked door, which looked just like every other unmarked door.

“This is it,” Daphne whispered.

Ginny tried the handle, but it was locked, and she felt the magic was so strong that even Harry would have trouble opening it.

No matter.

Ginny reached into another pocket, pulled out a folded up piece of paper, unfolded it, and slipped it under the tiny crack at the bottom so only the very tip was visible on her side. Then she switched with the paper, and because most of the paper was on the other side of the door, that’s where she ended up.

She stumbled away from the door, got her balance back, and smirked.

The room was filled with paper. But not lifeless paper sitting in stacks, oh no. Thousands of tiny folded flying machines, each one no larger than the palm of her hand, flittered around the room in a swarm. There were two large holes in the wall on either side of the room through which dozens of the tiny enchantments zoomed in and out to where ever they were heading. The floor was covered with ripped and torn paper.

Ginny quickly reached into her pocket and let Harry and Daphne out of the trunk.

Harry looked around the room and nodded. “Yep, this looks about right.”

“Will you be able to do it?” Daphne asked.

“I think so. One moment.”

Harry snatched one of the airborne messages, and inspected it for a while. Then he produced a piece of paper of his own and cast some spells on it before tossing it into the air.

Two dozen of the other messages immediately dive-bombed the paper and shredded it to pieces.

Ginny winced.

“Yep, that’s what happens if you don’t get it right,” Harry said. He tried several more times, until he got one that wasn’t rejected by the room of vicious attack memos.

“White Mask, the official document.”

Daphne handed Harry the parchment that he’d prepared well in advance. It had all sorts of official looking seals and stamps all over it, and had cost quite a bit of gold. A few of the stamps were even genuine.

Harry carefully waved his wand over the parchment.

Ginny couldn’t help but admire the incredible display of skill as Harry weaved enchantments over it. It was like watching a master painter casually capture the essence of the world in simple clean strokes, none of them alone anything special, but combined to create something amazing. Slowly, the parchment became like the many paper ones circling the room. Harry held it up, and the folded parchment flying machine joined its fellows in the circling throng.

They didn’t attack it. Some even started following the parchment plane, bobbing along in its wake like ducklings following their mother.

It was such a simple plan, Ginny thought. If what they needed was locked down so tight that not even Harry stood a hope in hell of getting to it, then they’d just have to persuade the people with the keys to bring what they needed to them. A forged purchase order from the French Ministry of Magic would do that.

Of course, it would have to be a forged document that had already been through all the security checks that such documents had to go through, not just this one. Even the forgeries that Harry could get hold of wouldn’t stand up to that kind of scrutiny. No-one’s could. So don’t bother. Instead, simply give the document to the end reader directly.

Ginny waved impishly as their parchment flying machine zoomed down the ‘out’ pipe and down into the bowels of the ICW.

Daphne was already climbing back into Harry’s trunk.

Harry was about to follow when he stopped, one foot already in the trunk. He turned to the flying mail and gave it a thoughtful look. He pointed his wand. “Accio Dumbledore’s message!”

Ginny held her breath.

Nothing happened.

Harry smirked. “Well, it was worth a shot.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Ginny arrived back at their fidelius spot outside the walls of the Castel Sant’Angelo with time to spare.

She immediately opened the trunk to let Harry out. He spent five minutes taking down the fidelius charm, but just before he was done, a massive portal opened in the brickwork some twenty feet away, and a large black coach pulled by winged horses shot through the hole, roared across the bridge behind them, and plunged into the night traffic of Rome, seeming to not care one wit for other road users. Nor did it seem to need to, as most of the brightly lit cars and traffic just jumped out of its way.

Ginny cursed. She’d counted one barrel in the back, and five men on board, which was two more than they’d hoped.

Harry finished taking the fidelius down, threw her a broomstick, popped the trunk with Daphne in it into his pocket, mounted his own broom, and the two of them soared up into the sky.

They had to find the coach, which in the dark streets below wasn’t easy. The air whistled through the holes in her mask. The cold bit into her bare hands, even through the broom’s warming charms.

“There!” Harry yelled, and shot off heading north.

Ginny followed as best she could, keeping just in Harry’s slipstream. Harry really was a very good flyer, but Ginny had been training on the quidditch team all year. Together they kept the coach below in sight until it had left the city walls of Rome and pounded out into the country.

“Any moment now!” Harry shouted.

Ginny lay flat on her broom, the better to match the coach’s pace.

“There!”

Ginny looked down. Free of the city airspace, the horse-drawn coach had lifted off the ground, every horse spreading its wide, white wings, and soared up in front of them.

Without needing to say anything, both Harry and Ginny fell back.

They tracked the coach all the way from Rome to Tuscany, and just as it was passing Florence, they pounced.

It was supposed to be a surprise attack, but that went out of the window almost as soon as they got within twenty feet. An owl, perched on the back railing and invisible from its own disillusionment charm, let out an all-mighty HOOT, and took to the sky. It got all of ten feet before Harry transfigured it into a rubber ball, but by then the damage was done.

A man leapt onto the top of the flying carriage and cast a homenum revelio. He just had time to scream out, “Two!” before Harry’s stunner dropped him like a sack of potatoes onto the constantly rolling rooftop, and he rolled right off the edge.

Harry dived, and Ginny was left alone.

Someone screamed something in Italian, and Ginny had to start dodging and shielding like crazy as spell after spell hurtled in her direction from the top of the carriage.

Three men now stood there.

Not good.

Not easy.

A nasty purple curse passed bare inches from her nose and she growled. That one would have done serious damage if it had hit and was definitely not in the rule book.

Unable to dodge a stunner, she was forced to shield.

The next purple curse, she swatted—from the same guy, too!

She traded back and forth with them for a few moments longer, and when the purple cursing guy managed to set her broom on fire, Ginny snarled, and without even stopping to think about it, aimed at the purple cursing man, and switched.

She stood, crouched on top of the coach.

The two men on either side of her had just enough time to form expressions of horror, before red light jumped from the tips of her fingers and slammed into both of them, dropping them like lead.

A scream from behind her fell rapidly into the night.

Then Harry was at her side, transfiguring her stunned opponents into rubber balls and chucking them off the side. “Driver,” he commanded.

Ginny nodded and quickly stunned the driver too.

They steered the coach to a pre-planned spot, and brought it down to the ground.

Now that the adrenaline was wearing off, Ginny realised something.

“I killed him.”

“Mm?” Harry said.

“I killed him,” Ginny said. Her voice was shaking. Her hands trembled. “The purple cursing one—I switched him onto a burning broomstick. He fell clear out of the sky.”

“No,” Harry said, sharply. “You didn’t kill him. The broomstick was just on fire. It didn’t fail completely. I saw it. He would have been able to land it safely.”

That filtered through Ginny’s brain. “I didn’t kill him?”

Harry shook his head.

Suddenly, and against all reason, Ginny felt cheated. She’d been all geared up to accept the reality of becoming a killer, and now … “Merlin damn it!” she screamed into the night.

Harry started laughing.

“It’s not funny!”

“It really is.”

And Harry continued to laugh and laugh.

“It’s not that funny,” Ginny grumbled.

“Sorry, Red Mask.” Harry grinned. “I’m just really happy right now. I’ve been worried about how to do this for ages, but now we’ve done it! Our new forms will open so many doors for us. And stop other doors from being closed. As Brown Mask once so eloquently put it, ‘Oh, I could sing!’ ”

“Shouldn’t we make sure we actually have done it?”

“Excellent idea. Why don’t you go do that?”

Ginny leapt off the front and quickly opened the back.

There was the large wooden barrel.

She unscrewed the tap, dipped a finger inside, and drew it back out, covered in light-grey powder. Phoenix ash.

They had done it.

Harry appeared at her side, beaming. “I’ll take it from here. You need to take White Mask and get back home. You’ll be missed before I am.”

Ginny nodded and grinned. In all the time she’d known him, she was quite sure she’d never before seen Harry as joyful as this.

Several thousand kilometres away, Virgo sat bolt upright up in bed, panting. The covers fell around his waist. His nightdress slipped down one of his shoulders. An overwhelming feeling of happiness flooded through him—a feeling of happiness that was not his own.

What was that?! thought a shocked Julia in his head.

And the happiness clearly wasn’t hers either.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The first-year Gryffindor girls’ dormitory was dark and quiet. The scarlet-red bed drapes of the five four-poster beds were all closed. A beam of moonlight shone in through the window. If there had been a clock, it would have shown the time to be two in the morning. There wasn’t a clock. Hogwarts students were expected to actually use the magic they were taught.

Hidden in one of those four-poster beds, Virgo Malfoy was now very much awake and sitting up in bed, fists clenching hard at the bed’s silk sheets, eyes staring hard at nothing.

Seriously, what was that? Julia thought.

‘What was that,’ indeed. Tom Riddle had done a lot of research into soul magic before he’d made his first horcrux, but Virgo Malfoy was under no illusions that Lord Voldemort would be far more knowledgable on such matters—he might well have experimented even further and created Merlin knew only what effects. But there was little doubt that this was soul magic. He hadn’t felt any presence on his occlumency barriers, so it was unlikely to be mind magic.

So, this is a soul echo? Julia thought.

It could well be a soul echo. A vibration of sorts heading down the connection that held the horcruxes together. Didn’t have to be a horcrux though. There were other connections between souls. Fidelius charms, and marriage bonds were the two most well documented, although obviously, the connection between them was far weaker than between horcruxes, which were so strong they could literally anchor the soul to the world of the living.

I imagine a marriage bond would make someone quite happy, Julia thought.

Virgo scrunched up his little button nose in distaste. While it wasn’t impossible, he found that extremely unlikely. No, this was more likely to be another free soul fragment, although whether the original or a former Horcrux, he couldn’t know. And that was aggravating.

What are you going to do then? Julia thought in his head.

Nothing, Virgo thought back. I have no wish to entangle myself with any of my others. Their doings are their own. And more importantly, I do not wish to be imprisoned again. Revealing myself only risks that.

What would happen to me if that happened? Julia thought.

You’d probably die.

Julia let out a single mental laugh. It sounded almost hysterical. I’ve been feeling things ever since you stole my body. Rage, pride, resentment, jealousy. Won’t your other selves be able to feel them too?

They are all normal emotions. And no, I don’t think so.

How can you know?

That brought Virgo up short. He didn’t know. He had no way to judge how his own emotions might be broadcasted. But it shouldn’t be too bad. After all, this was the first time he’d ever felt emotions across the connections.

But your emotions are getting stronger, Julia thought. I can feel them more clearly—now more than ever.

Virgo tried to stop his mind from jumping to the automatic, obvious conclusion—that what she spoke of had nothing to do with the strength of his emotions and everything to do with the possibility of Julia’s soul being absorbed into his own—that her tiny spark would end up being nothing but a pinprick of light in his own dark soul—but with just how close they now were, he might as well have tried to stop water from flowing through a sieve.

Julia let out a huge mental sob. I don’t want it! I don’t! I don’t!

Quiet! Do I have to curse myself again?!

N—n—no.

Good then.

Virgo put his head back on his pillow (it had lace around the edges) and curled up under the covers.

B-But, Julia started, clearly hesitant.

But, what?Virgo snapped.

But it’s not good for you if that happens either is it? I know you don’t know how that would effect the soul connections. It might split you off for good. It might make you mortal. It might just outright kill you.

Virgo grunted into the pillow. He considered that last one to be a very low probability, but Julia wasn’t wrong. It was hard for her to be wrong, given that she had access to many, if not most, of his memories and knowledge.

At just that moment, another wave of unexplained happiness swept through the pair.

A promise?Julia wheedled. Promise you’ll try and stop it. Please, Tom.

Virgo growled in annoyance at her use of his muggle name. Fine, he thought. Now go back to sleep, girl.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Despite the late night incident, Virgo woke up early the next morning. Virgo always woke up early. Quickly and efficiently, he went through the motions required for a young witch as taught by Narcissa Malfoy, and soon found himself, as usual, standing by the dormitory window, looking down towards the great lake, where John Potter was training, as he did each and every day without fail.

While the Potter heir wasn’t the sharpest knife in the draw, he was dedicated and disciplined, something that Virgo could respect. He was also stupidly powerful—powerful to such a degree that if Virgo didn’t know better, he’d suspect the boy were an undercover agent using polyjuice. Julia just enjoyed that the boy had taken to include swimming in his routine, despite how cold the lake must be, and so tended to leave his shirt off.

Virgo just rolled his eyes at the pre-teen girl’s fantasies, which always revolved around knights in shining armour coming to save her from evil dark wizards.

He spent the rest of the time before breakfast in the Gryffindor common room, reading a book others would consider far too advanced for him, disguised as a book others would still consider far too advanced for him, but less so.

John Potter arrived in the tower wearing muggle exercise clothes and still-damp hair. He flashed Virgo a boyish grin and a thumbs up as he passed, to which Virgo responded with a curt nod. He disappeared up the stairs leading to the boys dormitory and reappeared minutes later in his expensive school robes. “Ready for your escort, Miss Malfoy?” He gave her what Julia thought was a charming smile.

Virgo closed the book with a snap. “Yes, Heir Potter. I am ready.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The Gryffindors of Hogwarts had long become accustomed to John Potter and Virgo Malfoy being practically glued at the hip. They walked together everywhere, and John was always waiting for Virgo after each and every class. Few of the girls had been happy about it, especially the ones from noble houses, but with rumours swirling around that someone had tried to kidnap or even kill the newly revealed Malfoy daughter, they didn’t grumble too loudly. There had also been rumours of a possible contract between the two. Virgo had squashed them all.

The great hall was still sparsely populated when they arrived. It took some time for it to fill up. Virgo sat so she could see the whole assemblage, including the Slytherin table. Now there was a difference of culture. Both were all about politics and power, but whereas Slytherin was a complex, multidimensional chessboard, Gryffindor felt more like a quidditch scrum. In Slytherin every wizard was part of a group, which was part of another group, often part of yet another group. Those groups had friends, enemies, allies, and competitors. The subsequent relationships constantly shifted, creating a complex web of favours and debts.

Gryffindor was nothing like that. In Gryffindor, the hierarchy was very simple. The loudest, most powerful, and most confident wizard was at the top. Everyone else competed in the general throng to be heard, shouting over each other like market traders—traders whose stock consisted of jokes, stories, and rumour. Information wasn’t hoarded. Instead, it was proudly displayed to the entire table with the air of hunters displaying their latest catch.

This would have greatly annoyed Virgo, if he hadn’t successfully managed to attach himself to a wizard who was clearly top of the pile, despite him only being a second year!

“Hey, John,” said Ronald Bilious Weasley, sitting down on John’s other side. “Double Defence Against the Dark Arts,” he announced. “I am not looking forward.”

John snorted. “It’ll be fine.”

“For you, maybe. Is it just me, or has Snape been going easier on you this year?”

“I’m sure it’s just your imagination,” John said.

Virgo swallowed a bite of toast. “Maybe Snape appreciates a student with enough power to go toe-to-toe with an adult wizard?”

“I doubt that,” John said darkly. “Snape cares only about his Slytherins.” He then turned away again and continued his conversation with Weasley.

Virgo frowned in annoyance. That was another thing he needed to crack. Even though John did give him the pretty witch treatment, it was clear he only did it out of force of habit rather than anything else. There was a distance there that Virgo needed to break.

Well, maybe if you acted a bit more girlish around him, Julia supplied, which Virgo promptly ignored.

“Don’t worry about it,” said Dean Thomas quietly from the other side of the table. “He’s like that with loads of people. I wouldn’t bother caring.”

Virgo swallowed another bite of toast. “I wasn’t aware that my personal life was anyone else’s‘ business.”

“Jeez, sorry.”

Oh, nice going, Julia snarked. Truly you are far better than John Potter at this.

There was a flurry of wings, and owls carrying letters filled the hall.

Virgo frowned. “I’m sorry. That probably came out wrong. What I meant to say was, I didn’t realise people were paying that much attention to me.”

“Why wouldn’t they? You’re practically John’s shadow now.”

“Oh, I wouldn’t say that.” She picked up one of John’s letters, which had just been delivered, and sliced it open with a knife.

On the other side of the table, Dean gave her a significant look, glancing between her and the envelope.

Virgo shrugged.

“Anything interesting?” John asked, turning briefly away from his conversation with Ron.

“Just one from your betrothed.”

John snorted into his pumpkin juice. “I don’t have a—! Oh, it’s from Susan—very funny.”

Virgo smirked at him. Over at the Hufflepuff table, Susan Bones was sitting in between the two first-year muggleborn twins. She gave Virgo a cheerful wave, which he returned.

“You’re probably closer to John Potter than anyone else at Hogwarts, apart from Ron and Susan,” Dean continued. “Any closer and you might as well be angling for an intention gift. That or people will think you’re in a life debt, or under the pax magus.”

“And what would you know about that?” Virgo asked. At a prompting from Julia he analysed how that sounded and added, “Sorry. I mean no disrespect, but you haven’t been living in the wizarding world long.”

Dean gave her a raised eyebrow “What about you? You haven’t been with us long either. You’re muggle raised too, aren’t you?”

“I am. But I got special training from my family before I arrived,” Virgo replied. “You didn’t.”

“Right.” A sudden flash of nervousness shot across Dean’s face. “So, what do you think about the duelling tryouts?” the muggleborn asked. “Are you entering? I expect you are, from what I’ve heard.”

This time it was Virgo’s turn to raise an eyebrow. That had not been a subtle subject change. “I will be entering, yes,” he said. “Seeing as the big guns are out of the running this year,”—she gestured John Potter next to him, and Harry Potter, on the other side of the hall—“The honour of Gryffindor will fall to me.”

“Shame. I wanted to see them fight again. That was so badass. But I can see why they they’d not let them. It was a bit unfair on everyone else.”

Virgo was about to reply when a shout from beside him stalled him.

John Potter had the daily prophet open and was staring at a story with wide-eyes.

“Mate?” Ron said. “You okay?”

“Yeah, yeah, I’m fine.” John put the newspaper down flat on the table. Virgo leaned over to read.

It was the report of a violent theft from an ICW transport convoy.

PHOENIX ASH STOLEN—SKY RAINS RUBBER

Last night, the ICW was hit by the worst incident of high-theft for nearly a hundred years. Sometime after mid-night, a crack team of scoundrels impersonated the French Ministry of Magic, snuck into the ICW, ordered a whole barrel of phoenix ash, and then intercepted the delivery over the skies of Tuscany. The security team guarding the cargo was overwhelmed by two powerful duellists, then transfigured into rubber balls, which were dropped over the side to bounce around the idyllic country-side until the magic wore off.

“I’ve never felt more dizzy in my life,” said one of the security wizards when asked for comment [name withheld for security reasons]. “I’ve duelled before,” said another, “and this was like duelling the wind.”

A third security wizard was asked for his comments, but his reply wasn’t fit to publish in a public paper.

“We’re taking this very seriously,” said a representative of the ICW. “And procedures will be put in place to ensure it can never happen again.”

Phoenix ash is used in many potions and rituals throughout the wizarding world, and its supply is tightly controlled. It has the properties to bend time and space, and is widely believed to be one of the secret ingredients used in floo powder, although this has always been denied by the British Ministry of Magic.

“Lord Slytherin,” muttered John Potter.

Virgo shot him a look. “What makes you think it was him?”

John jerked up to look at her, almost as if surprised she’d been listening. “No reason,” he said quickly. “It’s just the sort of thing he’d do.”

“Is it?” Virgo continued to stare at the younger boy. “I haven’t heard of Lord Slytherin doing anything like this.”

“No, I—ah …”

“I believe you,” Ron said. “My mum says he can’t be up to any good. Phoenix ash is supposed to be really useful stuff. Bill once told me he heard they even use it to make time-turner sand. And you never get anyone good from Slytherin. Nearly every one of you-know-who’s inner circle was in Slytherin.”

“Yes,” John said. “But maybe he wasn’t in Slytherin. I mean, he’s supposed to come from New-Zealand, isn’t he? Where the Albion Magics are weakest.”

“Are you saying he’s not up to something fishy?”

John laughed, hollowly. “No. He’s definitely up to something. I just wish I could find out what it is. It could be very important. What if he’s trying to bring Voldemort”—Ron flinched—“back again? Or take over magical Britain like Voldemort tried to?”

Ron was wide eyed now. “So what are you going to do?”

“I don’t know.” John frowned. “I’ve been thinking about it for months. But every option just doesn’t seem to go anywhere. I wish Hermione—” He stopped. “I wish I had a plan that actually stood a hope in hell of working.”

Virgo stared at John Potter with slightly narrowed eyes. That whole conversation had been odd. More than ever, he was now convinced that something was going on that he didn’t know about. Virgo needed many things. He needed John Potter to give up the portkey he carried, so he had freedom of movement again. He hadn’t been able to even try getting into the chamber even once since arriving. He needed to learn more about Lord Slytherin, just like John wanted to. And he needed to neutralise the threat of assassination, possibly in the rather improbable form of the eleven-year-old Ginny Weasley.

He needed all these things to lay the foundation for his ascendancy as the greatest wizard … no, the greatest witch, the world had ever seen. And to make sure he’d never be imprisoned again.

“Ronald,” Virgo said.

“Ummff?” Ronald said, his mouth full of food.

“What else can you tell me about your sister?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

If Virgo had realised what a can of worms he’d be opening up with that last question, he honestly would have left the lid on. Clearly, Ronald Weasley had issues about anyone and anything Slytherin related. He might have let up on Virgo being sorted into Gryffindor house, but Ginny’s Slytheriness was still a sore issue.

John also didn’t seem all that happy with the subject. Still infatuated, apparently. Although by this point, Virgo was beginning to suspect it was more a matter of sour grapes than anything real. John’s obsession with Ginny, and to a lesser extent Hermione Granger, just wasn’t something that gelled with everything else Virgo knew about him.

Granger in particular was a mystery, since John didn’t even have the excuse of being childhood friends. She was just a random muggleborn—a random muggle-born who was vassaled to the Most Ancient and Noble House of Slytherin—the house that should, by rights, be his—a random muggleborn who was by far the greatest academic achiever in her year, scoring ridiculously high grades, even by the standards Virgo set in his own time—a random muggleborn who was cultured, controlled, and who perfectly played the part of a pureblood heiress, despite not being one. And she was the most powerful witch in her year, had faced down Dumbledore at the duelling tournament the year before, and taken on a troll after having her wand for barely three months.

And from what he’d gleamed from his conversations with the likes of Lavender and Parvati, John had been mildly obsessed with her from the moment he’d first met her.

It does sound rather suspicious when you put it like that, Julia thought. Almost like they knew each other before Hogwarts.

And if that was true, did that mean that John knew more about Lord Slytherin than he was letting on? He had to find out.

“I need to go to the bathroom,” Ron said a few minutes later. They were on their way to Virgo’s charms class. “I’ll catch you there.”

“Be quick!” John called after him. “You know what Snape is like!”

Virgo quickly took Ron’s place at John’s side and matched his pace. Even though John was a little older than Virgo’s body, girls went through their growth spurt earlier, so they were actually exactly the same height.

Womanly! Julia thought. Be womanly!

“Thank you for walking me to classes, John,” Virgo said. “I don’t know what I’d do without you.”

“It’s fine. You know that.”

“Yes, but it’s still worth saying thank you.”

John flashed him a grin, then he sobered. “But that’s not what you really wanted to say is it?”

“No,” Virgo admitted.

“You always thank someone before you ask for a favour.”

Bat your eyelashes at him! Julia shouted in his head, Be playful!

Virgo tilted his head, smiled, and blinked rapidly.

John laughed darkly. “Okay, Miss Malfoy, what is it?”

“I also want to find out about Lord Slytherin.”

That brought Potter up short. “Why?”

“You know my father isn’t happy with me. In his letters to me, contracts have been brought up, and apparently, one of the people asking was Lord Slytherin.” And, except for the bit about Lord Malfoy being unhappy with him, it wasn’t even a lie.

John stared at Virgo, wide-eyed. “Seriously?”

Virgo nodded.

“Oh, damn—sorry. I now understand why you’re interested. Not that it helps. Unless you have some kind of plan.”

Virgo smiled. “Actually I might just have one. Interested?”

“Sure! Let’s hear it.”

“Have you noticed how … knowledgable the muggleborns seem to be around here?”

“Not really?”

“I was talking to Dean Thomas this morning,” Virgo continued, ignoring John’s reply. “He knew about intention gifts, life debts, and the pax magus, and got very evasive when I asked how he knew all that stuff. There are two muggleborn twins in my year—Marigold and Violet Chesterfield—you know, the ones from Hufflepuff Duelling Club—and they are far better in class than any muggleborn has any right to be—almost like they somehow already know occlumency. And then there’s Hermione Granger—”

“Hermione has always been a genius.”

Virgo shot John a sharp look. “You did know her before Hogwarts!”

John looked furious with himself. “I didn’t!”

“Liar.”

“I …” John deflated a bit. He looked around, now merely annoyed. “Alright, keep it down. Yeah, I kinda did, a little. But that’s not something you can tell anyone, got it?”

Virgo smiled. “Sure. Anyway, regardless of how smart Granger has always been. She’s a vassal of Slytherin House. That hasn’t been done for ages. So, Lord Slytherin apparently has an interest in muggleborns. And all of a sudden, all the muggleborns of Hogwarts start grouping up, getting better grades, getting smarter, and everything. Doesn’t that seem a little suspicious?”

John hesitated. “I did hear Hermione was doing something with some other muggleborns,” he admitted.

This time it was Virgo’s turn to be brought up short. “Really? You actually heard that?”

“On the Hogwarts Express, yeah.”

“But then that’s practically proof! Don’t you see?”

“You think Lord Slytherin is up to something with the muggleborns at Hogwarts?”

“Don’t you?”

“I admit it sounds suspicious. And I keep feeling that Dean is hiding something. Maybe we should follow him sometime? Find out where it is he always sneaks off to.”

“That’s a great idea,” Virgo said, bluntly. “We should do that.”

Girly! Julia thought. Be girly!

Nope …Virgo smirked. They’d arrived at the charms classroom. He nodded to Potter and walked to his seat at the front.… I’m done now.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A day passed. Virgo went to classes, dutifully did his homework, and continued to ponder the mystery that was both Potter twins and his Slytherin year-mates. The boys were nothing special, entitled purebloods to a man. The girls though … They were all good—extraordinarily good in the case of Black, Lovegood, and Weasley. The Carrow twins didn’t have the same talent, but what they lacked in raw ability, they more than made up for in viciousness. They followed Black everywhere with awe-like reverence.

And if Black was anywhere near as good as he suspected Ginny Weasley might be, it was an awe well deserved.

It was breakfast, and the red-headed witch in question had just dashed into the great-hall, seemingly giving not one hoot for Slytherin protocol or dignity, dressed the same muggle-like clothes she always wore for morning training, and plopped herself down firmly next to Lovegood. Virgo sometimes saw her avoiding John during his morning training. The girl was fast. Abnormally fast.

Could she really be the one that tried to kill us? Julia thought. She looks so normal.

It does seem incredible, Virgo thought back. But, on the other hand, if she had the temperament, she would make the perfect assassin. No one would suspect her. The fact that whoever attacked us ultimately couldn’t kill us, makes it even more likely that it was her. She still has the weakness of a child.

Not wanting to kill people isn’t a weakness,Julia thought back at him, sounding rather peevish in his head. You’re a horrible person.

I know.

I hate you.

I know that too.

Just then, a clinking of glassware echoed from the head table, and headmaster Lockhart stood up, as he quite often did. The hall slowly quietened, aided by glares from the other teachers.

“Boys and Girls!” Lockhart started with that stupid grin firmly planted on his face. “I have just a quick announcement to make before you all need to head off to classes. Don’t worry! I won’t keep you all here any longer than you need!” He gave them all another grin.

Many of the students looked down at their still-full breakfast plates with puzzlement.

Virgo rolled his eyes.

“Winter is upon us!” Lockhart continued, rather dramatically, “And I am pleased to announce that this year we will be celebrating the Winter Festival in our own unique Hogwarts way!”

Virgo mostly tuned out everything that came after that. He wouldn’t be staying here for the festival, so it was irrelevant, although the fact that Hogwarts was now celebrating the Winter Festival rather than Christmas was interesting. One thing he couldn’t help but notice, looking around the hall, was the older muggleborns looking rather confused, and, in a few cases, angry, while the younger ones all took the announcement with a certain equanimity.

Just another indicator that all was not as it seemed.

Of course, the Gryffindor thing to do at this point would be to do exactly as Potter suggested—start tailing a Gryffindor muggleborn—probably Dean Thomas or Colin Creevey—until one of them made an excuse and snuck away for some suspicious reason. Then follow them and learn both the when and the where of the hidden conspiracy.

But that would be the Gryffindor thing to do.

“Good morning, Susan.”

Everyone was leaving breakfast quite some time after Lockhart’s announcement had ended. Virgo had caught the Hufflepuff Heiress halfway to the door.

“Morning,” Susan chirped back. “Don’t you have classes now?”

“Yes, but I wanted to ask you something quickly. Do you know anything about the special muggleborn-only classes?” It was a random stab in the dark.

“Special muggleborn-only classes? Don’t know anything about that. You don’t mean the Founders Club, do you?”

The Founders Club? “Yes, that’s exactly what I mean.”

“In that case, sure. Justin and Kevin both go.”

It was a random stab in the dark that hit pay-dirt. “Do you know when and where it is?”

Susan looked thoughtful. “Saturday and Thursday evenings, I think. But they sometimes do stuff on other days too. I don’t know where though—they’re quite secretive about that. I can ask if you like.”

“No,” Virgo said, quickly. “Don’t do that.” He didn’t want them to know they were interested, yet. “I was just curious.”

Susan narrowed her eyes. “John isn’t up to something again, is he?”

“Again?”

“Again. He has this minor obsession with Lord Slytherin. I don’t think it’s a bad thing, but this is about that, isn’t it?”

A lie was on the tip of Virgo’s tongue as easily as if he were complimenting an older witch on her youthful beauty. But then he stopped himself. Susan was one of the keys to controlling Potter after-all, who was looking to be more and more important a chess piece.

“Tangentially?” he said, doing his best to sound a little contrite.

“Right—in that case, meet me after classes—there are some things you need to know.”

Need to know? Virgo raised one dainty eyebrow. “Okay,” he said. “I’ll see you then.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“And that’s everything,” Susan finished off. The Hufflepuff had just finished recounting everything she and John had gone through last year to try and track down Slytherin’s identity.

Virgo had listened to everything with rapt attention, and even a slight tinge of respect. These two had been on the trail far longer than he had. And their schemes might even have worked, if not for bad luck.

They were in an empty classroom after their first classes—She, the Bones Heiress, and John Potter. Potter hadn’t said much since they’d begun (apart from having a brief argument with Susan about why she hadn’t told him about the Founders Club before, to which she’d defended herself with the argument that he hadn’t asked, and she hadn’t known he’d be so interested, in any case). Instead, the Boy-Who-Lived just sat quietly watching Virgo and Susan with an expression Virgo couldn’t quite match, but which Julia insisted was romantic interest.

“The polyjuice identification ploy could have worked,” Virgo finally said, after a moment of silence. “That was inspired.”

“That was my idea,” Susan said proudly. “Auntie uses the same trick to catch rapists.”

“Trying to catch Greengrass out while polyjuiced as Granger was far riskier though.”

“We were a bit desperate by then.”

“Mmmm …” Virgo steepled his fingers. “I do think that we could infiltrate the Founders Club in the same way though. Once we find out where it is.”

“And how would that help?” Potter asked, suddenly entering the conversation. “Hermione’s been utterly brainwashed. I agree everything about this is suspicious, but I can’t see her just randomly blurting out Slytherin’s real name to the muggleborns—At least with Greengrass there was a chance.”

“Maybe so,” Virgo conceded, “but learning Slytherin’s identity is only one thing we need to learn about him. It would also be useful to learn his motives, his way of thinking, and, above all, what he’s actually doing.”

“And the Founders Club could be the perfect way to do that,” Susan said, sounding a lot more enthusiastic now.

“Exactly.”

“Right.” Potter sat a bit straighter. “I’ll get some polyjuice.”

“Hang on, hang on,” Virgo waved him down again. “That’s another thing I wanted to ask. How exactly did you get polyjuice last time?”

“I asked Fred and George. They’re really good for that sort of thing.”

Virgo smacked his forehead. “You just asked them? Straight up? Holy Merlin, Potter!”

“What? Fred and George are cool.”

“Yes, and even if you hadn’t been caught, if anyone had even suspected, they’d just have had to follow the polyjuice trail back to massively narrow down the number of possible suspects. Just how many students do you think have polyjuice in this school?”

Potter grumbled something Virgo didn’t quite catch. He ignored it.

“So, anyway,” Virgo continued. “Yes, we’ll need polyjuice—carefully acquired,” he added with a look towards Potter. “We’ll also need to learn a few new spells.”

“Ooo!” Susan said. “What spells?”

Virgo opened a book on the table. “I suggest the tergeo charm, the silencing charm, and the disillusionment charm for starters.”

“I can do the silencing charm already,” Susan said. “Hannah snores. The tergeo charm should be doable, but the disillusionment charm … isn’t that really high level?”

An interested John was now looking over Virgo’s shoulder. “It is,” the boy said. “But I bet I could learn it with a bit of practice.”

“Of course you could,” Susan snarked.

Virgo smiled a well-practiced smile. “I’m sure you can too, Susan.”

“Really?”

“Yes. One reason we don’t learn it sooner is we’re not considered mature enough yet. We are talking about invisibility. It is a complex piece of magic, yes, but spells are like music—if you put enough effort into an individual piece, it’s quite possible to learn an overture far ahead of your curve. It just takes longer.” Sometimes, much longer, he added in his head, to which Julia snorted.

“Then it’s decided,” John said. “We will find out Slytherin’s secrets, whatever it takes.”

They all nodded, and together they made to leave for lunch.

Just before they got to the door, though, John stopped. He smacked his forehead, much like Virgo had done not long before. “I’m an idiot!”

Virgo and Susan both looked at him with bemusement.

“I didn’t want to say anything,” Susan said with a smile.

“No! I mean, I really am an idiot.”

“For Merlin’s sake, Potter,” Virgo said. “What is it?”

“We don’t need disillusionment to find out where the Founders Club meeting is—we just need the map!”

Virgo’s eyes narrowed and his female voice lowered dangerously. “Map?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Let me get this straight,” Virgo said slowly.

Another day had passed. Herbology, charms, and potions. Professor Potter had given the first-years an extra two inches of homework on fire safety when one of the boys had nearly set Virgo’s skirt aflame. He’d been annoyed at that, but not nearly as annoyed as he was now.

“Let me get this absolutely straight,” he said again, trying not to snap out the words. “You say that there’s this map that can track anyone in the castle—a map that by all rights should not exist, given just how ridiculously illegal the magic to make it must be—I mean, for Merlin’s sake! Most of those enchantments will be exactly the same sort of thing Light Lord Dimwiddy used to build his empire! And you say that you can borrow this map whenever you want—in front of the head of the DMLE’s niece, no less—”

Susan was sitting uncomfortably off to one side.

“—And that the people you can borrow this map from are a pair of wizards whose only obvious motivation seems to be making as much gold as they can. And now you’re telling me that when you asked for another loan of it, they say they’ve LOST IT?” Virgo wanted to roar that last bit, but it came out far too squeaky for that.

John Potter was looking more than a bit uncomfortable. “Yes,” he said.

“They’re obviously lying!” Virgo shouted. “They’ve sold it! Or someone else doesn’t want them to let anyone else use it! I mean, Merlin! For all I know, that’s how whoever tried to kill me found me so easily!”

John winced.

“I could tell Auntie,” Susan suggested. “She could search and confiscate something like that, no problem.”

Deep in their head, Julia was projecting calming thoughts at Virgo over and over, just as she had been during the entirety of his rant.

Virgo calmed down. He took a deep breath. “Sicking your aunt on them might be a good idea at some point, but we need to check the legality first. You don’t know if usage or ownership of this kind of artefact would be as illegal as casting the spells to make it, do you?”

Susan shook her head.

Virgo cursed. “We’d look stupid if we brought this up only to find we’d also get in trouble.”

“But we’re all noble,” John pointed out. “The Weasleys aren’t. Wouldn’t that count for anything?”

“Yes, but not enough, I suspect. Not when it comes to divination magic. And if they have sold it, then we’d just be admitting to a crime that the Weasleys can then simply deny.”

“Veritaserum,” Susan said.

Virgo paused. He looked down at the Malfoy noble house ring on his right hand. That was actually a very good point. The Weasleys could be tried under veritaserum, but they couldn’t. He smiled and nodded at Susan. “Wonderful. If we ever need leverage over them, we can use that.”

“So,” Potter said. “Since we can’t use the map, let’s learn the other charms instead.” He seemed anxious to move away from this discussion.

Virgo and Susan both nodded and together the trio got to work.

Learning the tergeo and silencing charms wasn’t difficult, but the disillusionment charm was another matter entirely—at least for Susan. By the time curfew neared, the boy-who-lived was already well on the way to getting a basic cast down, much to Virgo’s utter shock. Potter was almost as quick on the uptake as he’d been when he’d learned the spell during his third year.

Potter escorted Virgo back to Gryffindor tower.

The next day after classes they were back again, and this time, Potter got it.

The day after that, Virgo allowed himself to ‘learn’ it, and the day after that, Susan got it. Honestly, as shocked as Virgo was with Potter, Susan was almost as surprising. Everything seemed to come effortlessly to Potter. It was as though he were several years ahead and just learning a new spell from the standard book. Susan on the other hand—she seemed to take both Potter and Virgo’s accomplishments as a personal insult. She said so herself just after she finally achieved the spell for the first time, sneaking up on Potter and poking him in the back, before reappearing with a huge grin on her face. “If both of you can do it, there is no reason why I can’t too.” Only the weariness in her eyes betrayed the utter monumental effort she’d put into keeping up with them—and even then, casting the charm took her over five seconds, and wasn’t exactly the best. If ever they actually needed to make Susan invisible, it would probably be better to have either Potter or himself cast the spell on her.

All that was academic though, because they had learned it, confirming Virgo’s suspicions, once again, that Susan could be just as useful to him in the future as Potter—not only for her noble connections, and influence over Potter, but as a wand in her own right.

Soon enough, Saturday rolled around, and the moment that Dean Thomas and Colin Creevey separately made for the door of the Gryffindor common room, both he and Potter made their separate excuses and left the tower.

Virgo cast the disillusionment on himself.

Now all he had to do was find Potter and catch up with the muggleborns.

An outline nearby moved and he felt a hand plant itself into his.

“C’mon,” said Potter’s voice, and started leading them away.

Virgo had to fight down the intense feeling of revulsion at the physical contact, even while Julia was feeling something very different.

They had to stop several times to let students and ghosts past, and by the time they arrived at the grand staircase, the two Gryffindor muggleborns had vanished.

“This would be a lot easier if I had my invisibility cloak,” Potter muttered.

Virgo wanted to scream. He settled instead for hissing, “You have an invisibility cloak?!”

“No,” Potter whispered back. “It was stolen from my family before I got it.” He sounded more than a little bit bitter. “I believe it was Lord Slytherin as well.”

Despite himself, Virgo’s grip on Potter’s hand tightened slightly. “Do you have proof?”

“None.”

“Then how do you know?”

“Because everything that goes wrong is always about him.”

Virgo didn’t say anything to that. Susan was right. Potter really did have a Lord Slytherin obsession. A movement from several stories up caught her attention. Potter had apparently seen it too—seen it and identified it. “It’s those Hufflepuff twins,” he whispered. “They’re muggleborn—c’mon.”

Virgo was unable to stop himself being dragged up the constantly shifting staircases and down one of the many corridors that led off from the main hallway. Amazingly, they were just in time to see the very Hufflepuff muggleborn twins that had helped tip Virgo off to something fishy going on, turning the next corner, each one practically hanging off the arm of a rather bemused-looking boy whom Virgo vaguely remembered from their classes, but had never bothered to learn the name of.

“But you’re doing so much better now, Alan,” one of the twins said, cheerfully.

“Yes,” said the other twin, rather more seriously, “soon, you’ll have to teach us.”

Virgo and John reached and turned the corner.

“Oh, I don’t know about that,” the boy—Alan, apparently—said with obvious modesty. Then his voice turned nervous, although Virgo thought the nervousness sounded put on. “This isn’t one of your jokes, is it? You two have a weird sense of humour.”

The cheerful sounding twin giggled. “No jokes this time. But we do know a shortcut.”

“Really?” Alan sounded intrigued, “Well, girls, I’d be happy to see that.”

The threesome reached and turned the next corner.

Virgo and John rounded the corner not long after, and when they did, they both stopped.

“They’re gone,” Potter said.

Virgo wanted to smack him. “That much is obvious, Potter. Don’t just stand there. We need to keep moving.” So they did. They passed countless tapestries, statues, and paintings while making a surprisingly comprehensive sweep of the floor, and despite not finding another muggleborn, Virgo couldn’t help but be grudgingly impressed again. Potter knew Hogwarts well for a second-year. Many of the passageways the boy-who-lived was leading him down he hadn’t found until much later on.

But despite the comprehensiveness of the search, they weren’t having any luck finding what they were ultimately looking for, although they did run into Susan being harangued by Professor McGonagall for loitering. They hung way back until their Hufflepuff conspirator was heading their way before grabbing her and casting a disillusionment on her too, well out of sight of the Gryffindor head of house.

“Merlin, you scared me!” Susan whispered. “Any luck finding anyone?”

“Not really,” Potter whispered back. “We’re thinking we’ll need to try another floor.”

Together they scanned the floor below and above for another half an hour, and were just about to give the whole thing up as a bad deal when they found something that, to Virgo’s utter contempt, neither Potter nor Susan were able to ignore.

A group of three Ravenclaws girls had another Ravenclaw girl surrounded and were taunting her while constantly transfiguring something on the floor into various shapes.

The three girls had to be at least a few years older than the one they were ganging up on—possibly sixth-years, or maybe even seventh.

“Hah! How’re those holiday plans working out for you now?” One of the girls snarked, turning the object into a teapot.

“Please, just stop,” the maybe fourth-year girl sobbed.

“Would you like us to wrap it up in a little bow?” One of the other girls added, flicking her wand and adding a red and green ribbon to the teapot.

Before Virgo could even curse the twin names of Gryffindor and Hufflepuff, his two allieshad dropped their disillusionment and were marching straight towards the group. Seeing nothing else to be done, he also dropped his disillusionment and followed.

“Hey,” Potter said in an aggressive tone of voice.

“Go away, little un’s,” one of the older girls said, without even looking around, clearly taking her cue from the pitch of Potter’s voice. The other girls, however, were looking in the right direction, and they both paled.

“Heir Potter!”

The older girl with her back to them squeaked and spun around.

“What are you doing?” Potter snarled.

“Nothing,” the girl squeaked.

Virgo couldn’t help but be miffed that despite being a daughter of the house of Malfoy, it wasn’t him getting the royal treatment. But then, he wasn’t in line for the Malfoy lordship, nor could he ever theoretically marry any of the girls in front of him, and finally, and perhaps most importantly, no one had seen him smack around an entire duelling team as a first-year.

Potter gave the squeaking girl a hard look. “Then I suggest you do nothing somewhere else.”

“Yes! I mean, look, you know, we’re not really doing anything wrong here. It was just a joke. I mean …” she trailed away under Potter’s glare. “Sorry!” And the three girls rapidly retreated.

Susan was already comforting the sobbing older witch. Virgo shrugged, and untransfigured the teapot with a casual flick of his wand. It turned into a small white kitten, which mewed.

That was horrid! Julia gasped in Virgo’s head. How could they?

It would not have hurt it, Virgo thought back.

Still!

“T-T-Thank you,” the girl stuttered.

“You’re welcome,” Potter said, grinning. “What was that about anyway?”

What it was about was the girl’s plans for the winter break—her Christmas plans.

“You’re a muggleborn?” Potter asked.

Virgo and Susan caught each other’s eyes, each clearly thinking the same thing.

“W-What if I am?” the girl said.

“You wouldn’t happen to know where the Founders Club meets, would you?” Susan asked.

The girl suddenly looked uncomfortable. “Yes, but we’re not really supposed to talk about it. It’s supposed to be a muggleborn only thing.”

“Please, Janet?” Potter asked, giving the girl his best charming smile. “We’d be ever so grateful.” Virgo couldn’t help but smirk, while Julia went into a mental sulk.

“Well, I guess it would be okay,” Janet said, sounding hesitant. “But don’t tell anyone I told you, okay?”

“Of course,” Virgo said, smoothly, “we wouldn’t have it any other way.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Somewhere deep in the maze of secret passageways and magical corridors that was Hogwarts Castle, two twin Gryffindors were inside a rather old and battered magical trunk, hard at work.

“Wow, this stuff gets everywhere,” Fred Weasley said. “If Mum called us to dinner like this, we’d be grounded for a month.” His hands were covered in slimy, wet clay. So were his forearms. Streaks of brown could be seen on his face.

“We will make it work,” said his twin brother. George Weasley’s hands and arms were equally messy.

The two were sitting on opposite sides of a large potter’s wheel, which was slowly turning by magic. A huge lump of clay sat between, like a dirty melted candle.

A pulse in the alert ward let them know that someone was nearby. Fred quickly rinsed his hands with water from his wand, and jogged up the stairs to the trunk’s lid. He poked his head through.

An older Slytherin girl was looking down at him, nervously. “Umm …” she said. “I need a potion.”

Fred beamed. “That’s what we do. What do you need?”

“It’s a bit sensitive.”

Fred chuckled. “We provide our customers with the most discreet services, guaranteed. There’s no one around, so you can speak freely.” And it was true. The occasional hustle and bustle of the new student market was limited to certain hours when everyone knew it was worthwhile to hang around. That gave them plenty of time to continue their own projects.

The girl smiled, apparently reassured. “I need polyjuice.”

The smile on Fred’s face froze. “One moment. I’ll be back with you in a second.” He closed the lid gently. “Oi, George,” he said in a low voice. “Who does the map say this girl is?”

“Kathrine Winks.”

“I’m sure she does,” Fred muttered. “I vaguely remember the name. Is she noble?”

“Not that I’ve heard.”

“Important?”

“No idea.”

“Right.” Fred creaked the lid back open just enough to talk through. “What did you say your name was, Miss?”

“Kathrine Winks.”

“Are you aware how expensive polyjuice is?”

“I am.”

“And you’re aware that possession is strictly against school rules?”

“Yes.”

“Well, I’m afraid you’re out of luck. We don’t have any polyjuice. We would never so fragrantly break school rules like that—would we George—?” he called back into the trunk.

“Not us!”

“—but perhaps I could interest you instead in our special skin-care potion for witches. Simply one dose, and you’ll feel like a whole new person.”

The Slytherin girl looked confused. “No, I want polyjuice.”

Fred stared at her for several long seconds. “Well, we don’t have any,” he said, and snapped the trunk-lid firmly behind him. He turned to his twin. “Merlin, I thought Slytherins were supposed to be quick on the uptake.”

George shrugged.

A few moments later, a knocking came from the trunk-lid.

Fred sighed and opened it. “Yes?” he asked.

The girl hesitated before speaking. “This, skin-care potion … it wouldn’t happen to be mud-coloured, would it?”

“Funny thing that, it is.”

“Oh. Oh!” the girl’s eyes widened. “Yes, then. I’d like some of this skin-care potion.”

“How many doses do you want?”

“Three?”

“You’re in luck. Three’s all we have left, isn’t that right, George?”

“That’s right, Fred. Very popular stuff, our skincare potion.” George appeared at Fred’s side holding three tiny vials, each filled with mud-coloured liquid.

Fred took the vials and turned back to the girl. “One dose lasts exactly one hour. Don’t try to split them up, that doesn’t work. And don’t try to combine doses, that doesn’t work either. Got it?”

“Yes, yes, I understand.”

“Good.”

They settled the trade and the girl vanished into the castle. Fred closed the lid and looked toward his brother. “Well?”

George was staring down at the map. “She’s heading straight for the great hall. There are, like, a hundred students there.”

Fred snorted. “Not quite as dumb as she made out.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Is all this really necessary?” John asked. He was crouching, invisible, next to one of the many moving staircases of Hogwarts that led towards the great hall.

Next to him, Virgo Malfoy said, “Yes, it is. We can’t assume we’re not under watch until we find and destroy that map. We don’t want polyjuice being tracked back to us if we can help it.”

John nodded and unconsciously scanned the hall again for threats. He couldn’t help but admit that the girl was right. Virgo was right about many things. In the brief time he’d known her, she’d come to be more useful to him than any of the other Gryffindors. She helped with his mail, advised him on how to deal with the other students, and even trained with Susan at the Duelling Club, despite being a Gryffindor. Maybe it was the time they were forced to spend together, but John couldn’t help feeling protective, despite her occasionally razor-sharp tongue.

“Here comes our mule,” Virgo muttered. An older student wearing a mask had just entered several floors up.

“Who is it?” John asked.

“I don’t know.”

“You don’t?”

“Of course not. That’s the point, you halfwit.”

On John’s other side, Susan giggled. “I don’t think I’ve ever met someone willing to call the great Boy-Who-Lived that. I think I like it.”

John groaned. “Susan, don’t encourage her.”

The masked-mule passed by on the stair opposite theirs, and John cast a summoning spell on the vials in the student’s open book bag. The vials flew into his outstretched hand. Ten minutes later, they were all bundled up against the cold, walking the path to the great lake where very few students went during weather this cold. John couldn’t help thinking just how cute Susan and Virgo both looked in their winter robes and scarves.

“So, what’s the plan?” Susan asked, looking between John and Virgo.

“I’m going too—” John started before realising that Virgo had said the exact same words at the exact same time. They both paused, but in the time left open, Virgo jumped in again with, “I’m going to sneak into the Founders Club and collect information, and yes, I am the best person to do this. No offence, Potter, but you’re not exactly the most subtle wizard in the world.”

John frowned. Before he could say anything, however, Susan beat him to it. “But, Virgo, it’s too dangerous for you. John’s been spending all this time with you to protect you. You can’t go around walking alone in the castle. You know that.”

John nodded. “I couldn’t have said it better myself. Yes, you’re smart, Virgo, but that doesn’t make it okay to put you in danger.”

Virgo smiled. “What if I wasn’t in danger?”

“What do you mean?” Susan asked.

“Potter here is so powerful and manly, I’m sure he could give up a little bit of his own protection for little old me.”

John knew full well that his ego was being massively stroked, but that didn’t make it feel any less good. After all, he was powerful and manly, and it was nice for people to recognise that. “What protection?”

Virgo smiled and pointed at where a small metal sphere hung around John’s neck by a golden chain, hidden under his robes.

His portkey. The portkey his father had given him to keep him safe at Hogwarts.

Doubt flickered across his mind. “I’m not sure I can do that,” he said.

“Why not?” Virgo asked.

“That’s actually a really good idea!” Susan said enthusiastically. “That would keep Virgo much safer, and it would mean you don’t have to tail her absolutely everywhere.”

John grimaced. He really didn’t want to give up his portkey. Apart from anything else, he’d come to see it as his own protection in case anything really bad went down—such as going up against a one-thousand-year-old basilisk, for example. In the last timeline, he’d been quite lucky, even if he didn’t like to admit it.

“C’mon John,” Susan said, looking at him with doe-eyes. “What could you possibly fear at Hogwarts?”

Looking into that trusting face, he blurted out the first thing that came to mind. “It’s a Potter artefact!” As he said the words, he realised that not only was that the perfect excuse not to give the portkey up, but it was even true! Lockhart had gifted this portkey to the House of Potter.

Virgo looked shocked and possibly even a little bit angry.

Susan was taken aback for a moment, but then a sly smile came across her face. “Oh dear. That is a shame.” The way she said it sent alarm bells ringing in John’s head.

Virgo looked sharply at Susan. “What?”

Susan giggled and waved John closer so that only she and he could hear, leaving Virgo looking on suspiciously. “If it is a Potter artefact, you could always gift it to her anyway,” Susan whispered. “I know your Mum and Dad cut off your gold for gift-giving to pretty witches, if you catch my meaning.” Susan innocently played with the citrine and onyx encrusted bracelet that John had given her last year, and which she still wore around her wrist.

She was talking about a declaration of intention gift. John’s thoughts screeched to a halt. It wasn’t that he hadn’t thought about Virgo in that way, but being put on the spot like this … and giving up his portkey … He straightened up. “Nope! No, no, no. Nope and double no.” He pointed at Virgo. “We are going back to Gryffindor Tower.” He pointed at Susan. “You are going back to your common room.” He pointed at himself. “And I am going to deal with the Founders Club. No arguments!” He turned and strode off.

“That fool will never be able to get anything useful out of them!” Virgo ranted, loud enough to make her ire known, but not loudly enough for John to hear. They were walking some way behind the Boy-Who-Lived, back to the castle, after doing a round trip of the lake. “And he’ll probably get himself caught! What a waste of time! What did you even tell him?”

Susan smirked. “I suggested that he should start courting you.”

Virgo looked at Susan in horror. “You, what?!”

“Oh come on—it’s not that strong a commitment—and you could do a lot worse. Do you even realise you’re in the position that most every witch in the castle, and quite a few outside, would kill to be in? You don’t, do you? You’re impossible. You just waltz in here, like it’s no big deal, and have the Boy-Who-Lived and heir to the most powerful house in Britain practically eating out of your hand, and you don’t even see him as a potential husband.”

Virgo seemed to be struggling with herself. Eventually, through gritted teeth, she said, “And you’re okay with Potter courting me?”

“Sure,” Susan replied. “You’re better than most of the other options here. And a lot better than him marrying some foreign princess who’d treat me like some kind of mistress.”

“I wasn’t aware you were already contracted to him.”

Susan felt herself blush a little. That had sounded a little presumptuous.

Virgo visibly calmed. When she spoke next, every word was clear and smooth. “I am not currently interested in pursuing romantic entanglements. I shall deal with such matters as they benefit me, as I see fit. Right now, I am far more interested in making sure that the idiot doesn’t screw up matters so badly that our freedom to investigate Lord Slytherin is curtailed. I think that we should see to matters by ourselves.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The time until the next Founders Club filled John with mild unease. Rather than being angry or giving him the cold shoulder, Virgo was instead acting extremely cordial, which actually unnerved him more. Susan too was acting differently, although she tried to hide it. He couldn’t shake the feeling they were conspiring, which could never be a good thing.

Events in the rest of the castle hardly made matters any better.

In defence class, Professor Snape had moved onto giving them one-on-one duelling training against himself. This apparently was an excuse for him to continually hex the students he least liked, and, on one occasion, when Lockhart had randomly dropped in, the headmaster too (although Snape had claimed that one to be an accident).

In potions, even though Snape was no longer teaching, class ironically felt almost exactly the same as in the last timeline. It was impossible to slack off or hide anything when your mother was the one in charge. She always knew. Even worse was the way she practically fawned over his brother. John had crushed two quills already this month. He still couldn’t understand how Harry could be so much better than he was. Virgo pointed out that this was only more reason to work harder to close the gap between them, and as much as it pained him, he couldn’t help but agree.

The Dark was getting more and more sure of itself, now that it had Alexandra Black all but in charge, backed up by Draco Malfoy, who, if the papers were to be believed, had summoned an actual basilisk! He hadn’t believed it until the Wizengamot had passed a law banning the blonde ponce from experimenting any further with that spell. Malfoy now walked with a definite strut.

And then there were the rumours about the Gray, swirling around the castle like the snow swirling outside the castle windows. Their children had been leaving the castle more and more often. It seemed that Greengrass, Lovegood, and Hermione left the castle almost every weekend now, and always arrived back for classes just in the nick of time. He’d heard grumbling among other students, envious of all the special treatment the three witches were being given. All kinds of ridiculous theories were circulating about what was up—everything from special auror training to political meetings with heads of state. Whatever it was, John assumed it was big. There was an energy about them—a kind of palpable excitement that not even their Slytherin masks could fully hide.

An excited enemy couldn’t be a good thing.

But all-in-all, one other thing wrangled him the most. There still hadn’t been any sign of the heir of Slytherin. He was starting to wonder if there ever would be.

“It’s time,” Virgo said, sitting opposite him.

John nodded and stood up. “Hey, listen, Virgo. It really is better for you to stay here, you understand that, don’t you?”

“Perfectly,” Virgo sniffed. “I’m sure you’ll be fine by yourself. Make sure to buy a pensieve while you’re out.”

John grimaced and made his way out of Gryffindor Tower.

Moments after Potter was gone, Virgo snapped the book he’d been reading shut and made to follow. He walked past the groups of laughing and giggling Gryffindors and stuck his head out of the portrait hole. “Susan?” he whispered. His noble partner in crime and possible meat shield waved a disillusioned hand.

Hey! Julia thought, Don’t call her that. Susan’s nice!

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

John Potter tried to hold in his scowl. Fate was on his side—there was no doubt about that, but he couldn’t help feeling that it would be nice if the evidence of this fact could stick around for more than five minutes. If it did, he might not currently be wearing a silken witches robe that Susan would probably describe as ‘fetching’.

His luck had started out so well. He’d quickly and quietly made his way through the corridors of Hogwarts, on the lookout for one of his preferred targets. He, of course, knew where the Hufflepuff common room was, and so it was no issue to position himself between it and the room Hermione used for the Founders Club. He heard the lone footsteps before he saw their owner. Alan Gage, the friend of the muggleborn twins, loped around the corner. He seemed to be in quite a hurry and wasn’t paying attention. Perfect. John quickly stunned the boy and dragged him into a nearby cupboard for safety.

One extracted hair, and a change of clothes later and John was indistinguishable from the plain looking muggleborn, right down to the tie.

In retrospect, he should have known it wouldn’t stay so easy.

“Alan!” cried a voice behind him.

He whirled around to find himself nose-to-nose with one of the muggleborn twins.

“Why’d you rush off?” the other one said, far too innocently. “Are you trying to get out of your responsibilities?”

“Errr …” John said.

“Don’t worry,” the first one said. “We’ve got it all set up. Just follow us!”

She grabbed John’s arm and started dragging him away. John let her, not daring to say anything that might blow his cover. Thankfully they were going in the direction of the Founders Club.

“Right,” The second twin said, pausing in the middle of what looked like a normal, boring corridor. “Just step over that line.” She grinned and pointed to a line on the floor.

“Umm …” John said.

“Now, Alan,” the first twin said more seriously. “You said you’d do it. Fair’s fair—you did try to steal our stuff.”

John had groaned inwardly. Taking the fall for whatever Gage had done had not been part of his master plan, but it wasn’t like he’d had a choice. Steeling himself, he had stepped over the line, and the moment he did, the robe he’d ‘borrowed’ had instantly changed, which was why he now was standing in a random corridor wearing a traditionally styled girl’s robe, all white, complete with delicate trim, lace, and even two pink ornamental hearts dangling from the string ties of the cowl.

“It worked!” The second twin clapped. A second line appeared. “One more, c’mon! We need to thoroughly test this out before club starts.”

John felt a sense of creeping dread. These twins felt far too much like another set of twins he’d known since childhood, but the best defence against them was just to get it over with. He stepped forward and instantly felt his underwear being switched. He was also now wearing a witches’ wrap around his chest. The sensations were unpleasantly constricting.

“You are going to switch this back, aren’t you?” he asked in a desperate voice.

“Yep,” the second twin chirped as a third line appeared. “That’s what the next line is.”

Oh, thank Merlin. John stepped forward over the third line and shrieked like the girl whose clothes he wore, as several buckets of cold water fell on him from nowhere.

“Whoops,” said the first twin, deadpan.

John choked and shook his now sopping clothes. The wet cloth clung to him in all the wrong places. “What the hell?!”

“Fair’s fair, Alan,” the first twin said, as though that explained everything. “But don’t worry, Hermione knows the drying charm.”

“Which is amazing because it’s a super advanced third-year spell,” the second twin added in a bright tone of voice.

John froze with his hand halfway to Alan’s wand. He’d fully intended to cast a drying charm on himself right there and then—he certainly didn’t want anyone seeing him in a see-through robe and certainly not while wearing girls’ underthings, even if it wasn’t his body—but if Alan Gage didn’t know the charm …

The second twin winked. “Don’t worry, we know you’re secretly really into this. C’mon!” And together the two twins hooked their arms around his and started dragging him towards the Founders Club. John did the only thing he could. He whimpered.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Meanwhile, in the Founders Club meeting room, Hermione and Harry were alone. Hermione was on tenterhooks. Ever since Harry had put up some proper warding around the sunken treasure ship, she’d redoubled her efforts to catalogue anything useful from all the books they’d found. Anything to help them move the mundane cargo of the magical ship to the jurisdiction of the muggle world, where it would be worth so much more. But what she’d just found might or might not be even more important—she wasn’t sure, but Harry would surely know.

“Hermione, you’ve been desperate to tell me something since we started talking,” Harry said. “If you fidget on that desk any harder you’re going to wear a hole through the floor. Let’s hear it.”

Hermione coloured before taking a deep breath. “Well, I was reading through Akna Slytherin’s diaries and I found … something. It might be nothing, but, well, I thought it might be.”

“Go on.”

“After Akna married Salazar’s grandson, they had a number of children together, the ones recorded in all the family trees. But her diaries count one more than the official records do.”

Harry quirked an eyebrow. “Okay …”

“Yes, so I read ahead to find out what happened to that extra child—it was a son—and he turned out he was a squib. The culture Akna came from was very clear on what to do with squibs and Salazar agreed with her logic, so when the son came of age, they banished him from the castle. They weren’t unkind about it, apparently, but they also didn’t give him much of a choice. The son travelled to the fens where Slytherin House originated from, and married the daughter of a local noble—one with Norman blood, if the diary is to be believed. This was before 1066, remember.” Hermione looked towards Harry.

“All very fascinating,” Harry said. “But why is this particularly noteworthy?”

“Well, because the Albion Family Magics stopped him from using the Slytherin name, and so he took the name of his new bride.”

“Which was?”

“Ridel.”

There was a moment of silence. Then Harry snorted. “Oh, that is rich. Oh, that explains so much.”

“You believe it could be true then?”

“Probably. It would explain a lot about our dear little Miss Malfoy. And about her psychopathic other self.”

“Does this change our plans for Virgo?”

Harry shook his head. “No, we shall continue as before. I’ll make sure to bring this up the next time we’re all together though. Alex will probably piss herself laughing. You just make sure everything goes well here and remember to ring me if anything goes down.”

Hermione nodded. Then, the door banged open, and several muggleborns waltzed in.

“And that’s my cue to leave,” Harry quipped.

“Bye, Potter,” Justin said as Harry swept towards the door. “Sorry for interrupting your courtship again.”

Hermione pointedly didn’t say anything while the rest of the group assembled, minus a few stragglers. Just as she was about to start, the door banged open again and Violet and Marigold Chesterfield barged in, dragging …

Oh dear, Hermione thought.

“We’re here!” Marigold announced.

“We are,” Violet confirmed.

Alan was blushing to the tips of his ears, dressed in a soaking wet robe that clung to his skin and concealed absolutely nothing. The twins had obviously been studying witch weekly.

Annoyingly, the drying spells Hermione aimed at the highly embarrassed boy only served to wring the water from the dress, and did nothing for the dampness. It still clung and was still see-through. “You can go change if you want,” Hermione offered. “We will wait for you.”

“No!” Alan said hurriedly. “I mean, no, I don’t want to hold everyone else up. Please let’s just get this over with.”

Hermione nodded, but kept one eye on the boy as she began to lecture. Was something about him different? He seemed a lot more … noticeable than before. Well, he was wearing very witchy clothing.

“Today we’ll be going over the rich tradition of extralegal settlements in the wizarding world. How wizards and witches settle disputes without resorting to the courts. Duels, games, tasks, favours, and magical arbitration. One by one into the pensieve.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

John could barely contain himself. For starters, he was sure everyone was laughing at him. It might not be his body, but that didn’t make it feel any better. Curse those girls.

For second, Hermione, his Hermione, had a bloody pensieve! In school! Who entrusts a thirteen-year-old with a pensieve?! And she had a shrinkable trunk with added expansion charms. He didn’t have one of those, and he was the heir of one of the richest Houses in the country!

And thirdly, and worst of all …

“Now keep your eyes on that corner,” Hermione said, pointing at one of the darkest recesses of the Slytherin common room. Moments later, a tall figure in a familiar mask materialised out of thin air, and every hostile Slytherin in the common room memory froze.

“That was soo cool,” Justin Finch-Fletchley whispered in awe.

“Soo cool!” Sophie clapped.

“You haven’t seen anything yet,” Hermione said, beaming. “Now, listen carefully. He’s about to propose the terms of the duel to Volf. Only noble houses can still do this, but a non-noble house can accept an honour duel, and, in some cases, is actually required to. This isn’t one of those, but notice how that girl has just stepped in to adjudicate? There are some families that make a tradition out of it.”

Lord Slytherin then beat the living shit out of Volf and his cronies so badly that John wanted to hurl. But, to his utter disgust, none of the muggleborns were disturbed or outraged by the man’s use of legilimency to torture the older student. Far from it.

“Lord Slytherin will always protect those he considers his,” Hermione said, as though uttering some deep fundamental truth of the universe.

And all the muggleborns just nodded along.

A chill ran down John’s spine. He couldn’t believe how right Virgo had been. If only he had started to listen to her sooner. And he suddenly wished that she and Susan were here with him—if only so he wouldn’t feel so much like a lone human trying to blend into a pack of zombies. Then he remembered what he was wearing and was thankful they weren’t.

Magic lifted them all off their feet, and then they were back outside the pensieve inside Hermione’s trunk again.

“Any questions?” Hermione asked.

As it happened there was a question that John really wanted to know the answer to after having watched that—one he was fairly sure Alan wouldn’t have already asked, and which wouldn’t be too suspicious. He raised an uncertain hand. “Can Lord Slytherin get into any of the common rooms like he can the Slytherin one? I mean, if he needed to ‘protect’ one of us …”

Hermione frowned at his question, and for a moment he thought he’d blown it. Then she smiled. “No, he cannot. He only has right of passage over the Slytherin dungeons and the general hallways of the castle.”

John let out a held breath. That was a relief. He did not want to wake up one day to find that mask hovering over his bed in Gryffindor Tower.

“Now, onto the next memory!”

They then plunged into several memories, each detailing an example of one of the other ways wizards settle disputes outside of the courts.

For settlement by game, they watched the ending of a blood feud in the 1500s by means of a chess match.

For settlement by task, they watched a former Lord Greengrass being sent to recover a particularly rare form of chimaera egg—half-man, half-bull, or what muggles would call a minotaur (Hermione also mentioned Lucius Malfoy, who’d recently been tasked, in court, to head a trade delegation to Japan, on behalf of Magical Britain, at his own expense. John couldn’t help smirking at that).

For settlement by magical arbitration, they covered Hogwarts’ Goblet of Fire, Black Book, and Sorting Hat, and the Ministry’s Scales of Judgement.

“There has long been lively debate in Wizarding politics about how much of our governance should be left to magic and how much should be in the hands of men,” Hermione lectured. “Theoretically, we could give far more of our decision making over to magic, and magic might well be able to make better decisions. There are people who would prefer that we do just that, but others say that to do such a thing would reduce our agency as a race, and that by giving up our control to a formless shapeless force, whose decisions we can neither comprehend, nor question, we give up a critical part of our humanity.

The Great Blood Feud, which took place immediately after the fall of Light Lord Dimwiddy, was largely a reactionary event by people who believed that magic should judge, since wizards had proved unsuitable.”

And not for the first time since they’d started, John felt a stab of pain in his chest as the girl who was so like his Hermione rattled on, and on, and on, just like she always had done. This was not helped in any way by the final pensieve memory, settlement by favour, which, to John’s horror, was the very incident that had caused Susan trouble the previous year—the time she’d used polyjuice to try and sniff out Slytherin secrets—just like he was doing now.

“Are you sure you’re okay, Alan?” Hermione asked.

“Yeah, sure, I’m fine!”

“Mmmm, okay then.” She didn’t look fully convinced. “Now, any questions?”

Sophie put a hand up. “If favours aren’t legally or magically binding, what’s to stop someone just reneging?”

“Honour,” Hermione answered. “The magical community is small. Word gets around. If you don’t keep your promises, you quickly become a social pariah.”

“That doesn’t sound very reliable,” Justin said.

“We don’t live in a very reliable world,” was Hermione’s response. “You should know that by now. That’s why the protection of someone honourable like Lord Slytherin is so valuable.”

John couldn’t help it. He let out a small snort. In the quiet of the classroom, the sound rang out like a gong.

Hermione sighed. “Perhaps refreshments are in order. We are all a little tired, I think.” She summoned a tray of glasses from a nearby desk with a flick of her wand (wordless too, John noticed). “Are there any other questions?”

John thought quickly while the drinks were poured. He still needed to get more out of this gathering if he could manage it. What he had was eye-opening, but maybe he could push it harder. He brought his glass to his lips, but stopped just before taking a sip. “

“If Lord Slytherin cares so much about us, then why is he betrothed to two of purest purebloods in the country?”

Hermione smiled. “Because they proved themselves …”

John sipped from his glass.

“… just like me.”

Slowly, the glass slipped from John’s fingers. He stared at Hermione in horror. Faster than he’d ever thought possible for her, Hermione had whipped her wand out and had it pointing straight at him. The glass hit the floor and smashed. Dizziness swept over him. Hermione had potioned him. His noble house ring didn’t protect against sleeping drafts, only mind control.

“We’ll see who you are soon enough,” Hermione scowled. “We just have to wait.”

“NOW!”

Before sleep took him, the last thing John saw was two familiar female figures in masks dropping disillusionments from a corner of the room, wands drawn.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“NOW!”

Virgo leapt into action the moment John went down.

Susan was already casting ropes at a startled Granger, while the rest of the muggleborns stood around in various states of shock. Good for her. Virgo had some serious heavy lifting to do.

Why don’t you try ventus divinum?Julia thought.

Casting levitate on someone John’s size wasn’t difficult, but doing it while keeping everyone else distracted was more tricky.

“Ventus divinum!”

Immediately the whole classroom was wracked by an elemental wind. Parchments were picked up in the maelstrom and flung around in a whirlwind of power. Chairs were knocked over. Students shouted in alarm and fought to keep their balance. In moments, Virgo had Potter by the magical scruff of the neck and was pulling him to the door.

Halfway to the door, some of the muggleborns had got their shit together and were levelling wands in her direction.

A quarter way to the door, spells were being shouted, and wands being flicked.

By the time he arrived at the door, three spells had bounced off a hastily cast shield, Susan right beside her.

A tied up Granger was shouting something about shield breakers.

Virgo grasped the door handle, flung it open, and dived through.

Or at least, that was the plan.

What actually happened was he slammed face first into an invisible shield right in front of her.

Head ringing, he looked up.

It was the other Potter, and he was smiling the smile of a cat looking at a mouse. “I don’t think we’ve been formally introduced, Miss Malfoy. Harry Potter, at your service.”

Then a spell caught her in the back and her legs turned to jelly.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Now, what have we all learned from this?” Granger was asking the muggleborns.

“Don’t casually drink offered drinks while spying?”

“Don’t use polyjuice when a mask could do almost as good a job?”

“Always have back up for your back up?”

“Dramatic one-liners don’t protect you from incarcerous?”

“Violet, we’re supposed to be dumping on team boy-who-lived.”

“Oops, sorry.”

Virgo kept a carefully neutral expression while Susan did her best at damage control. It was an hour later and the polyjuice had long worn off, leaving John totally exposed, and, much to his mortification, still wearing the clothes the Chesterfield twins had pranked him into.

I think it’s cute. Boys get so flustered when someone says they should wear something girls normally wear. Except you, but you basically are a girl now. You should start thinking of yourself properly as one.

So far, John had been forced to promise to show Harry where the Potter family magic was kept in the Potter Library, Granger had extracted a minor favour from Susan, and he, Virgo, had narrowly avoided having to do a minor task on behalf of the assembled muggleborns, only by virtue of John, who’d stepped in to gallantly take the hit for him. He certainly could be useful—even if his infiltration skills were atrocious.

“Just keep her with you,” Harry said, patting John on the shoulder. “You know, so that if I ever have need of her, I’ll know exactly where she is.”

“Harry, Virgo is not the diary.”

A chill went down Virgo’s spine.

“Of course she isn’t,” Harry said, lightly. “Just keep an eye on her, okay?”

He knew. He knew and he didn’t even care that he knew he knew. Or, at the very least, he suspected.

The walk back up to Gryffindor Tower was muted. Susan trailed off from them for the Hufflepuff common room, while John led Virgo back up through the castle.

“Lord Slytherin is brainwashing the muggleborns,” John said, once they were safe in a corner nook of the common room.

“Worse than that,” Virgo said. “He’s recruiting them. Just like you-know-who used to do with purebloods. He’s already a Gray Lord. It feels as though he wishes to become a Muggleborn Lord too.”

John frowned. “What good would that be?”

“I don’t know. But I don’t like it.”

“I don’t blame you. Ummm … Virgo?”

“Yes?”

“I just wanted to thank you for coming to help me, even when I told you not to.”

Inside his head, Julia made a kind of gasping noise.

“I mean, you still shouldn’t have, but I did appreciate it. When I was in there by myself, I felt alone, but I wasn’t because you were there … Crap, I’m no good at this.

Oh my god! He’s going to give you the thing!

“What I’m trying to say, is that I want you to have this.”

He’s giving you the thing!

Virgo’s eyes widened slightly as Heir Potter pulled up the ball of silver from around his neck and presented it to him. The portkey. Then her eyes narrowed.

“This way you can be safer around Hogwarts, like Susan said.”

Take it!

“Potter,” Virgo said slowly, dangerously. “You know there is only one way you can give this to me.”

John winced at her tone of voice. “We can just pretend?”

“Just pretend …”

Just pretend!

“Yes, just pretend.”

Virgo took the portkey. “If you ever get any ideas about contracts or courting into your head, I will find a sufficiently painful way to make you stop. It will not be pleasant.”

“Sure.”

His words say one thing, but his grin says another.

“I’m serious.”

“Sure.”

Later that night, Virgo was sitting up in bed, staring at the portkey. With this he had freedom. With this, he could finally do one of the tasks he’d been meaning to do since arriving at Hogwarts—learn whether or not Lord Slytherin knew of the chamber, and if he did, what he was doing with it.

—End of Chapter Forty-Eight—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: I swore I was going to try to make these chapters shorter, but it just never seems to work :( Anyway, if you enjoy my work, please consider checking out my original projects. All support is appreciated :) You can find the links through my website www.leadvone.com

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. That next chapter is not yet available, but if you fancy discussing this chapter, or anything else DP&SW with like-minded people, feel free to head over there anyway.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2017’s prices.

Soul Anchors—Part Two

The pub was dark and dingy. The smell of stale beer hung in the air. The reed floors were mattered with so many stains, it was impossible to tell their original colour. A dozen low-voices, scattered around the room, conversed in small groups. Another group stood near the burnt-out fire, betting knuts on snitch shooting. Over the bar, were mounted several decapitated human heads. The heads did not look pleased about this.

The door to the pub opened with a loud creak. All talk halted while the clientele inspected the new-comer.

The landlord used his wand to make a used glass less dirty before putting the glass aside. “Are you sure you don’t have the wrong place, Miss?” he said, not unkindly.

The woman ignored him and looked around. The dress she wore, alone, would probably have paid for enough rounds to keep the entire room drunk for a week, although the way many of the men were staring suggested that it wasn’t the dress they were interested in.

“No, I’m sure this is the place,” the woman said, walking to the bar, and sitting down on one of the stools. About half the room lost interest at this point, although that still left a sizeable number eyeing her up, down, and side-to-side.

“You can sit on my lap, darlin’!” one of the patrons called.

The woman ignored him and ordered an ice-liquor, which the landlord poured from a bottle so dirty it was a wonder plants hadn’t started growing off of it.

The woman took it and sipped. She shivered and put the glass back down on the bar. “Perhaps you can help me, Mister … ?” She trailed off, waiting for a name.

“Call me, Harry,” the landlord grunted.

The woman’s eye twitched. “Very well, Mister Harry. I am here on behalf of my lord. He is looking for people who share his view of the world.”

The landlord did not look impressed. “And you are?”

“I am Lady Alexandra Patricia Black.”

This caused a murmur from people near enough to hear what she’d said.

“You’re Lord Slytherin’s bird, ain’t ya?!” someone shouted. “What’s that posh nob want with us?!”

“He’s looking for people who believe the wizarding world can be more than it is.”

A wizard with the build of an ox and skin that looked as tough as old boot-leather lumbered over. “And what does that mean exactly?” he asked.

“It means people are going to have to make choices about whether they want to be on the side of progress or whether they want to be swept away by the flood that is coming. For those who lead everything will be given—power, gold, respect—a chance of a better life.”

“This isn’t the first time a dolled-up Black has waltzed into this pub singing those words.” The man glowered. “Following that insane bitch lost me two fingers and an ear. And in the end, even the Dark Lord wasn’t able to follow through on his promises. Get out, little girl.”

“You are not the master of this place, and I am nothing like Bellatrix Lestrange.” Alexandra glared, facing the room. “And I am not a little girl—does this look like a little girl?!” She swept a hand down her body.

Behind the bar, the landlord rolled his eyes.

Laughs filled the room.

The wizard standing in front of Alex also chuckled. “Okay, I’ll admit you are funnier than that bitch, at least.” His face hardened again. “But seriously, get out.”

“Look,” Alex said, a note of frustration edging into her voice “Just hear me out, okay? I assure you it will be worth your while.”

“Get out.”

“I have a job that needs doing—fifty galleons up front.”

“Get out.”

“You can’t just keep saying get out like that!”

“Do you want to be thrown out, bitch?” He took a step forward.

Alex took a step backwards. “I swear, you lay a single hand on me, and Bellatrix Lestrange will seem like a cake-walk!”

“I doubt it. Get her!”

Several wands were drawn from random groups and several hexes launched from all directions. The man in front of Alex lunged for her, hands outstretched. This turned out to be an unwise move. Black magic chains grabbed him and used him as an impromptu human shield, blocking every one of the hostile spells. Things quickly devolved from there. People dove for the floor, furniture was smashed, and magic flew everywhere, bouncing off each other and causing strange and unpredictable results. And in the middle of it all, was Alexandra, whirling around with her wand glowing a rainbow of colours as she swatted and shielded all the basic-level spells aimed at her. Her eyes were laser-focused, but her mouth was smiling. Any doubt the patrons had of her abilities had surely been dispelled. Perhaps they’d be more inclined to listen to her after this.

Then the room stopped. Not because everyone had been knocked unconscious, but rather because time itself had simply halted. One wizard was paused in the middle of casting a deep purple spell. One chair was floating halfway across the room. Even the flames in the torches on the walls were stalled in mid-lick.

Alex spun around. The landlord was staring at her with his arms folded.

“Hey!” Alex whined. “Why’d you stop me? I can still win this!”

“You actually lost about five seconds after you entered the pub, but I just wanted you to reflect on this moment before we continue.”

“Why? And what do you mean ‘I lost’?”

The landlord said nothing, but simply snapped his fingers.

Suddenly everything went back into action. Alex had only a split moment to sense the purple spell and swat it straight back to its caster. Another quick mental command and her chains wrapped themselves around the ankle of a wizard who was trying to scrabble away, flinging him into the last two wizards still standing with wands drawn.

Now, it was over.

Alex lowered her wand. “Does anyone have anything to say?”

The remaining patrons, who hadn’t reached for their wands, stared at her with stony-eyes.

“No one?” Alex asked. “Because I do still need help, you know.”

No one moved.

“Fine, then I’ll just sit here until someone with some balls decides to talk to me.” She hopped back onto her ball stool and sipped her ice-liquor, which, miraculously, had stayed intact throughout the entire exchange.

The landlord cleaned another glass and put it away.

Alex leaned forward. “They will talk to me, won’t they?”

The landlord shrugged. “Yes … technically.”

“Technically?”

Alex felt a presence beside her. A moment later, the stink of a man’s breath leaned in to whisper urgently. “My lady, you must leave quickly. The aurors are coming.”

Alex barely had time to register what the man had said before loud and fast footsteps could be heard coming from outside. Aurors? Panic welled up in her. As quick as she could, Alex had a curse on the tip of her tongue and her wand out. The door to the pub exploded. Her spell flew straight and true, into nothing. It simply passed through a cloud of empty dust. Then the windows exploded—both of them, on either side of the door, and two powerful, hooded wizards landed in the middle of the room, each holding round iron shields in front of them, their wands both pointed right at her. With a speed that would have been unbelievable to anyone who hadn’t regularly fought against Harry, spells of bright light shot towards her. Desperate, Alex swatted as many as she could away, but it was no use. The moment she’d bounced just one spell back towards them, the two aurors had adapted and leapt aside to encircle her with clockwork coordination—like a trap snapping shut on a mouse.

Alex’s world went red.

And then black.

When Alex came to, she sat up groggily, looking around the still-destroyed wreckage of the pub. No one was around now—no patrons and certainly no aurors. She looked down and realised that she wasn’t an adult anymore. She’d changed back into her true form.

“Okay, let’s begin, shall we?” said a cheerful voice from atop the bar. Alex clambered to her feet, and then climbed onto one of the bar stools to find Harry sitting cross-legged on the bar-counter, polishing a glass with a cloth, muggle-style, which produced a lot better result than the magic ‘Harry the landlord’ had used. “Firstly,” Harry began, “two out of ten.”

“What?!” Alex said indignantly. “I know it didn’t go amazingly well, but I did okay, considering how unreasonable they were all being! I deserve better than a two!”

“They were not being unreasonable.”

“Yes, they were!”

“No,” Harry said, firmly. “They were being adults, rather than the children you are used to dealing with—or the adults that you deal with as an eleven-year-old. I dare say you’d have had more luck if you’d tried with your true form.”

Alex looked at Harry with incredulity. “You think they’d have taken me more seriously like this?”

“Yes, because like that your attempts to be taken seriously would appear precocious, rather than immature and threatening. As a witch, as a child, and as the daughter of your parents, you’ve spent so much of your time learning to be taken seriously—to be someone that demands respect—that you haven’t learned how to use harmlessness as a weapon.”

Alex huffed, but didn’t argue further. “Okay, how do I do that, then?”

“You already know how. You did it in that very exchange.”

“I did?”

Harry waved his hand in the air and her voice, aged up by ten years, filled the room. “And I am not a little girl—does this look like a little girl?!”

Alex gritted her teeth. “But that was the worst bit! They all laughed at me!”

“They laughed because it was funny. No adult woman with looks like you’ll have would ever feel the need to defend her adulthood so emphatically. It’s something a child would do, so they assumed you were making a joke—at least, at first. But that’s the point. Even if you didn’t mean to, you made a joke, and reduced the tension in the room. For a single moment, you were less threatening, which made building repport more likely. That’s what you need to work on.”

“You want me to be a clown for them?!”

“Using jokes to appear less threatening does not make you a clown. It makes you cunning, like a true Slytherin should be. When you curtsey for an adult you do not respect, you are not truly submitting to them. When you dance with a boy you don’t care about, you still allow him to lead.”

“But those are things I must do because I am weak.”

“And this is something you must do because you are strong. Hasn’t Luna been teaching you wizarding poker? If you have a weak hand, bluff—if you have a strong hand, you still bluff. To crow about having a strong hand will just cause everyone else playing to fold. That’s what every wizard in this room was trying to do—they were trying to fold. There are lots of reasons noble children learn the game, you know.”

Alex stared at the bar top for a few moments before straightening up. “Okay, so how do I do this?”

Harry swung his legs off the bar top and landed, crouched, on the floor. A moment later, he stood in the figure of Lord Slytherin, looming over her, one of the most intimidating visages Alexandra knew.

“You watch me, and you learn.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Alex awoke the next morning to the sound of kelpies rustling against the windows to the great lake, and the sound of running water coming from the shower room. She grasped the lightning bolt pendant around her neck. Lord Slytherin was so cool, words couldn’t even begin to describe. By the time he was done, he’d had the whole pub practically eating out of his hand. Okay, she knew it was just a dream—it wasn’t real—but even that didn’t matter, she knew that in the real world, it would have still worked.

And what was even more ridiculous was that half the things Slytherin had done, were the exact opposite of what he’d told her should be done. Arriving with a large snake wrapped around his chest was not un-threatening. Shooting five snitches clean out of the air, from the other side of the room, without even using a wand, wasn’t exactly subtle either. And if she’d tried to buy the whole pub a round of drinks, she was sure the result would have been at best a grudging nod, not the boisterous cheer that Slytherin got.

And how?

A few minutes after sitting down, and not having said a word to anyone, except to order a drink, a dream version of Luna had run in, unwrapped the snake from around Slytherin’s chest, hugged it profusely, and then happily ran back out, calling out a thank you behind her. Slytherin had made some joke into the stunned silence and everyone had laughed. Suddenly, the snake had gone from threatening to funny. The fact that it wasn’t there any more probably helped, too.

His wandless performance at the snitch shooting, some time later, had been followed by a quip about how his mother had one day decided to try to get him to wake up earlier by putting his alarm clock on the other side of the room, and how it had never seemed to work. That had gotten quite a few laughs as well. Obviously, none of the dream patrons had known Harry’s real story, or if they did, they pretended not to. They were constructs, created from Harry’s experimentations into magically induced multiple-personality-disorder—they could be whatever Harry willed them to be.

Apparently that included people who would cheer a round of drinks if announced by someone who’d spent over an hour in their company sharing stories and jokes while waiting for his friend’s children to finish whatever it was they’d been up to in nearby Diagon Alley. Not long after that, Slytherin had started lamenting the state of the wizarding world and the troubles and difficulties of leadership. By the end of it all, they were encouraging him.

Just before leaving, he’d leaned into one of the men he’d been most engaged with and whispered something that Alex, watching invisible from a corner of the pub, couldn’t catch, but which Harry told her afterwards was a request for the details of people in need of coin, who’d support his cause, and could help him with a ‘sensitive matter.’ He’d succeeded in getting the list, which was the whole point of the game.

Truly, Alex had a lot to learn.

She pulled aside the covers of her bed, dropped her nightgown, ignored the still-closed beds of Luna and Ginny, however frustrating that was to do, and stepped into the shower room.

“Miss Heiress!” Hestia Carrow’s eyes widened slightly (if the hair ornament in the basket was to be trusted). The witch quickly hopped out of the shadow and ushered her inside. “It should be the perfect temperature for you.”

Alex nodded and let the water run over her. On second thought, she also couldn’t help feeling that many of the tricks Lord Slytherin had used only worked because he was a powerful man. Somehow, she couldn’t see Lady Black getting all back-slappingly chummy with men who’s breath smelled like the backside of a cow-shed—or them with her. Perhaps Harry didn’t quite appreciate all the advantages he had. Or perhaps, Alex thought with a sudden flash of insight, it wasn’t the exact methods she was supposed to copy, but rather the theory. She had to find a female way to do the same thing. Actually, being less threatening as a woman was probably the easy part, if she actually tried. She looked into the shower mirror, put on a pouting expression, and then deliberately let out the girliest giggle she could manage.

“Miss Heiress?” said a shocked voice from behind the wall.

Rats! Alex’s mind flew. “Err, I was just thinking about how surprised the other houses will be when the duelling tournament comes around,” she bullshitted. “They think that just because Potter and Potter are out, that means they stand a chance.”

“Oh, yes, Miss Heiress,” Hestia cooed from outside, far more enthusiastically. “You’ll crush the unworthy beneath your heeled feet.”

“My boots, Hestia. It is a duelling tournament.”

“Oh, right, yes, Miss Heiress, yes—your boots. And we have defence against the dark arts this morning. Snape is finally going to let us put those stupid Gryffindors in their proper place.”

Alex arrived at the Slytherin table in the great hall some time later, with Hestia on one side and Flora on the other. They’d insisted on doing her hair again. They always did. It didn’t matter that it basically looked fine—fine was never enough. She doubted even Daphne’s hair got the attention that her’s did.

“We’re ready, by the way, Miss Heiress,” Flora whispered to her over the boiled eggs. “We’re so sorry it took so long to find the formal declarations—we had to send off for them—but we have them now.”

Alex was totally lost at sea. “Declarations?”

“To swear ourselves to you for the time we’re at Hogwarts. We never thought we’d have to do it, so we never bothered to learn. Please forgive us, Miss Heiress.”

“Oh. Oh! I thought you were going to settle for the declaration you already gave me.”

“Oh no, we couldn’t do that,” said Hestia, sounding aghast.

“It would disgrace our proud pureblood traditions,” Flora chipped in.

“Right,” Alex said. “Of course.” Lord Slytherin had once mentioned in one of their letters how many non-noble purebloods were often more extreme sticklers for tradition than their noble counterparts. They had more to prove.

“Don’t let it faze you, you two,” Draco Malfoy said, sitting down opposite her while addressing the twins. “Everyone knows that Heiress Black does tradition like she does everything else, with the subtlety of a dragon in a china shop. Still, I can’t say I’m entirely surprised. There’s usually someone who’s pledged themselves to someone by this time of the school year—that’s what my father told me.”

Alexandra smirked.

Just then, the post arrived.

She was somewhat surprised to see a letter from her father. Surprised, because she’d written two letters already and hadn’t expected a response from the third either. If it sounded out of character for her to write multiple letters to Sirius without getting a response, that’s because it was. Lord Slytherin had ordered her to write them.

Alex,

My apologies for not responding earlier to your other two letters. I honestly wasn’t expecting you to start writing so frequently, but I’m happy you are. It sounds like you’re having a good time at Hogwarts. I can’t say I’m all that happy with what’s been going on—Merlin knows your antics have been giving me a hard time, what with all the people in the ministry who think I’ve been raising a secret Dark Lady—but Harry assures me that this is all part of some ‘Master Plan.’ And that he’s taking good care of you.

I’m still not all that happy if this has anything to do with the Gray, but better the Gray than the Dark, I suppose.

I’m sorry. I shouldn’t be talking about such heavy topics. Aren’t I always the one who says you’re supposed to be having fun? I hope you’re at least managing to play some good jokes on your current, ‘friends,’ *wink* *wink*.

Just make sure you take care of yourself. And if you ever find yourself in over your head, let me know at once, and I’ll be down there like a ton of bricks.

—Dad

Alex couldn’t help having mixed feelings as she quietly folded the parchment and slipped it into the folds of her robes. Despite all the crap their family had been through, she couldn’t deny that she did like it. On the other hand, it was rather annoying that her father seemed to trust Harry more than her. She did understand. This was Lord Slytherin they were talking about, but this was her father—her head of house—her lord. Surely, he was supposed to one-hundred per cent on her side. At least she could always rely on his overzealous protectiveness.

Alex looked across the table to where Draco was sitting and slicing into his own letter. She doubted he’d have anything as drama filled as hers.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Dear Draco,

Your father and I are pleased to hear of your progress in your studies. We are also immensely proud of your efforts to bring your cousin back into Dark. My family has too long been a dog of the Light. Above all else, do nothing that might jeopardise that relationship. I doubt you need me to tell you that, though. Alexandra has already shown herself to be a powerful witch, just like your Mother.

Your father is still in Japan, but will be back with plenty of time for the winter holidays. You will accompany your father and I to the Greengrass Winter Festival, as usual, but we have also been extended an invitation to a gala dinner at Slytherin Manor, along with many other respectable wizards. I expect you to be on your best behaviour and to do nothing which might reflect poorly on your House. If you do, I shall be extremely displeased.

We shall pick you and your sister up at Platform 9¾. Be sure not to forget anything at Hogwarts this year. We will not be sending Dobby to pick things up, again.

—Mum

Draco focused in-between his mother’s lines. ‘If you do, I shall be extremely displeased’ was code, which meant, ‘there is a code.’

After cycling through a few of the magical methods he’d been taught, and taking care not to alert any of the many students sitting around him in the great hall, a new set of lines appeared before his eyes, far fainter than the others.

Draco,

We are still unsure whether we will include your sister in this year’s festivities. I know you may believe that we are greatly displeased with her, but the truth is rather more complex than that. Your father and I have discussed this at length and have decided to entrust you with certain information. You must keep this to yourself. Obviously, this is a Malfoy family secret. We are telling you now because we have decided that keeping you in ignorance would expose you to more danger than to do otherwise.

Virgo is a spy—

With the seriousness of a star chaser handling a match-determining quaffle, Draco immediately stopped reading, folded the letter up, and tucked it away into the folds of his robes. The letter continued, but he wouldn’t risk reading any more in the Hogwarts Great Hall. Even going as far as he had, had been foolish.

“Bad news, Draco?” Black asked.

Draco shrugged. “Just news. Have you also been invited to Slytherin’s Gala?”

“No, but I’m sure my father has. I’ll be able to badger him into letting me go.”

“Maybe you should be in Hufflepuff,” joked a random older student.

Alexandra glared, and silenced him.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Their first class was Charms with Professor Flitwick. Draco filed into the classroom, head spinning through all the implications of the revelation that Virgo was just pretending to be a disgrace. He’d barely talked with his new sister all year—there had hardly ever been time. They didn’t share classes, common-rooms, or clubs. And whenever he did see her, she was stuck to John Potter like glue. Disgusting … but, if she was a spy …

The class was well underway now.

The half-goblin professor had clambered onto his book-tower and was now busy instructing. “Now, remember,” Flitwick called out to the assembled Slytherins and Ravenclaws, “You must correctly integrate the final two-thirds twirl movement at just the right moment or the spell won’t catch. Glass won’t just dance by itself, you know.”

Draco glanced over to where Harry Potter was sitting next to Heiress Greengrass. Obviously, he’d already mastered it. Draco gave his wand a twirl—to show everyone his utter confidence—and focused on the spell.

BOOM!

Just then, a massive shockwave shook the room. Draco dropped his wand with a clatter.

“My heavens!” On top of his pile of books, Professor Flitwick had been knocked off his feet. “I think that came from below us.”

What was below them? The Defence Against the Dark Arts Classroom. Draco’s mind raced. The Slytherin and Gryffindor first-years’ Defence Against the Dark Arts Classroom.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The story was all over the school by Lunch. Draco got it from Hobby Harper, one of the unquestionably Dark children among the first years, whose name wasn’t Black or Carrow.

“So, you know that the Headmaster likes to drop in on classes sometimes?”

Draco nodded.

“Well, he dropped in! But today was the first day Snape was letting us actually cast spells at each other. He had the classroom set up for narrow duelling. Merlin, you should have seen Snape’s face when Lockhart suggested he teach us all the protego charm before starting. I thought for sure he was going to burst a blood vessel. But that wasn’t the best thing.” Harper’s voice dropped as though about to impart some huge secret.

“What?” Draco asked.

“They duelled!” Harper whispered. And then much more loudly said, “I kid you not! Snape and Lockhart duelled! I think Snape was utterly fed up with him constantly poking his head around the door, so he suggested they do a ‘demonstration.’ Hah!”

“Is that what caused the explosion?” asked a fourth-year witch, one of many who was also listening in up and down the table. Alexandra Black was nowhere to be seen.

Harper shook his head. “No, I’m getting to that. And, yeah, I know what you’re thinking, but Lockhart actually handled himself rather well. Say what else you will about him, but he really does know his DADA.”

“So what happened next?” Draco asked.

“Snape looked like he’d swallowed a lemon. To be honest, I think Lockhart wants the Defence position as much as Snape did! Snape still won, but it wasn’t the steamrolling I think he’d hoped for. They started pairing up students for practice, and Lockhart put your sister on the big stage.”

Draco groaned. “Let me guess, did Snape put Black on the other side?”

“Yes! Well, no, actually he first called for Weasley, but she tripped on the way up and hurt her knee, so then he called for Black.”

Draco had his head in his hands now. “And what happened next?”

“They duelled! Magical Merlin’s left bollock, it was insane. I had no idea your sister was so advanced! The spells they were using! It didn’t start out all that impressive, but it … escalated. Snape and Lockhart tried to get them to tone it down, and they did, a bit, for a time, but then Black pulled out her chains and then it was all gloves off. I’d say your sister is more advanced than Black, but Black can spell swat, which massively evened things up. No one was paying attention to their own duels at this point. Everyone was focused on the main stage.”

Draco really wanted to get back to his dormitory so he could read the rest of his Mother’s letter. “And the explosion?”

“Your sister was getting really pissed off. I mean, really pissed off. And then Black cast … wait for it … you’ll never guess.”

“Go on.”

“Serpensortia.” Harper smirked. “Your favourite spell! Next thing everyone knew, there was a bloody great snake right in the middle of the platform. And your sister … your sister went kind of nuts.”

“How so?”

“I swear that snake didn’t even get a chance to let out one single hiss. Virgo used bombarda on it—instantly—wordlessly. To be honest, I think she might have a phobia of snakes. It certainly shook her.”

Everyone around the table who’d been listening in, had their mouths open in shock.

Draco’s mouth dried. “My sister used a wordless dark blasting curse, in the middle of a packed class-room?”

“No one was too badly hurt. Just broken bones and ruptured eardrums. The stage was wrecked though. The headmaster took both of them away. I swear that was the first time I’ve ever seen him not smiling. Snape didn’t look too happy either.”

Draco winced. ‘Snape didn’t look too happy,’ was student code for ‘so furious that boggarts would run away from him.’

Rumours continued to swirl all day. Word on the grapevine was that Black didn’t appear for Potions, and that Virgo hadn’t shown for History of Magic.

Draco had double Herbology and so hadn’t been able to verify anything. They were potting teenage mandrake and everyone had their fluffy ear-muffs on. This made discussion impossible.

It was with great relief that he was able to rush back to the common-room afterwards (with dignity, of course), to find out what exactly had happened.

He arrived in the common room to find a sight, that, while not unexpected, he had never-the-less been dreading.

Black was sitting in his chair. It was official, then. He, Draco Malfoy, was no longer leader of the Dark. She gave him a curt nod and motioned him forward. Holding his head high, Draco walked over and sat on her right side. Everyone was watching—even the Gray. No, especially the Gray. “What happened?” he whispered.

“Me and your sister were grilled for an hour. Minus one-hundred points from Slytherin and Gryffindor, and detentions for a week. My first one starts soon, so I need to make this quick.”

Black straightened imperiously in her chair. “Hestia and Flora Carrow. I believe you have something you wish to tell me.”

Fifteen minutes later, Draco was ensconced behind the safety of his dormitory’s bed curtains. If he’d thought the Carrow twins were a bit creepy before, it was nothing to what they were like now. With how she’d refused to back down against his sister, no matter what, Black might as well have tattooed Dark Lady on her forehead. It was just really, really annoying that she didn’t know Virgo was a spy for their side!

Draco pulled out his mother’s letter from his robes and finished reading.

Virgo is a spy. Dark magic is involved. She is acting under orders from your Father to infiltrate the Light on our behalf. While you can trust her, and she is your sister, donotantagonise her needlessly, and donotanger her. But above all, do not endanger her position by giving away her true alignment—even to those such as Theodore and Alexandra. What I told you at the start of the year still applies. Virgo may one day take on a far more prominent role in our fight against those who seek to destroy our way of life than you might ever suspect.

Love, Mum.

Draco crumpled the letter in his fist.

Don’t antagonise Virgo, but also don’t alienate Black. And don’t tell anyone, and most certainly not Black, that Virgo is a spy.

Fan-fucking-tastic.

Just then, the door to the dormitory slammed open. “Malfoy!”

Annoyed, Draco swung the curtains aside. “What?”

The visitor was a prefect. He looked frazzled. His breathing came short and fast. “It’s your sister. Something happened.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Virgo had left the headmaster’s office wanting to throttle someone, he was so infuriated. Seven days of detention! Seven! He’d never gotten even a single day of detention during his entire time at Hogwarts when he was Tom Riddle. So many of his plans to return to the chamber would have to be put on hold.

Maybe you should have kept your cool when the Slytherin girl shot that snake at you, Julia thought.

Virgo thumped the wall in frustration. Do you not realise how dangerous that situation was for us? If anyone had learned we can talk to snakes—

—Dangerous for you maybe. If people learned what you are, maybe I’d be set free!

Don’t be delusional. You know full well how badly that could go for you.

I only know what you know about soul magic. Which isn’t all that much! Who rips their soul apart on the directions of one badly written scrawl in an old book?

Enough!Virgo punched the wall again, harder this time, bringing a whimper of pain from the little Swede in his head. He brought himself back under control. Today hadn’t gone well. Snakes were one of the few ways he could be unmasked. He’d been careful to stay clear of anything snake-like or serpentine ever since regaining a body. Suddenly coming face-to-face with one had shaken him. He couldn’t afford to delay any longer.

Hey, where are we going? Julia asked.

We have an hour or two before detention. That’s enough time to at least ensure that the passageways I will use to return to the chamber are not blocked. And with most of the students still in class, the chances of being found are much lower.

Virgo marched down a side passageway, did a little jig before a statue, ducked into the passageway beyond, came out beside a glass-work grandfather clock, and set the time to five o’clock on a Thursday. He then hit the fourth brick down to the right, and marched back down the secret passageway he’d just walked up. He exited on a balcony overlooking the grand-staircase. There was the smallest of carvings in the wall next to him. A snake.

“Open,” he said.

The parsel-tongue only secret passageway … did not open.

Virgo frowned. That was odd. “Open!” he said, a bit more forcefully this time.

Again the passageway did not open. Grumbling, Virgo got down on his hands and knees to inspect the passageway. He couldn’t feel anything obviously out of place. There weren’t any wards protecting the passageway—certainly none like the detection wards he’d found in the bathroom entrance moments before the assassin had turned up.

Frowning, he stood back up.

Maybe try another?Julia suggested.

There’s no good reason why this one shouldn’t work, but …

He tried another—a trick doorway behind a normal door. Still nothing.

A feeling of great unease was starting to coil its way around his chest. Why weren’t the passageways responding to him?

I don’t know,Julia thought,you’re saying ‘open’ clearly enough.

Virgo stilled, suddenly hyperaware of his Swedish passenger. Open? He thought back.

Yes.

Not ‘Öppna’?

There was a moment of mental silence before Julia thought, No, you’re definitely saying ‘open’.

A kind of frozen dread sunk into Tom’s heart. And for just a few moments, it was Tom. All thoughts of Virgo were stripped away by blind emotional panic—the panic that grips a soul when the truth is evident, but the mind refuses to believe.

If Julia could understand Parseltongue then she’d hear it in her native language. If she couldn’t understand parseltongue, then she’d just hear a bunch of hissing. If she was hearing him say Open …

Frantic, he whipped up his wand. “Serpensortia!”

There was a loud bang, and a large black snake shot from the tip of his wand, landing with a thump only a dozen feet away.

“Stop!” he shouted.

The snake uncoiled itself and hissed at him. It hissed at him!

Tom’s eyes widened.

“Stop!”

The snake darted towards him.

“STOP! STOP I ORDER YOU! ARGHHH!”

The snake had bitten him on the wrist! With a blast of raw magic, the snake was ripped free and flew across the passageway. Another wand wave, and it was gone, leaving only several small puncture marks and ripped clothes behind. He recognised the snake that had bit him. Not venomous, but even a non-venomous snake could cause serious problems if left untreated.

A faint sobbing could be heard in the deepest recesses of his mind. The girl was crying.

Suddenly, something clicked. Anger roared through him. YOU! he mentally screamed.It must be you! You must be the reason! I’LL KILL YOU! “CRUCIO!”

Two screams lit up the dark Hogwarts passageway. One mental, the other out-loud. The body of an eleven-year-old girl writhed on the floor. Her wand clattered to the ground.

Bad idea. Bad idea.

P-P-P-P-Please, Tom. Don’t. Please.

Think! He couldn’t have lost his parseltongue ability. He couldn’t have!

His whole body was on fire. Even after that tiny jolt, every nerve felt like it was still being wrung. An idea occurred to him. Of course. That’s how he could restore the balance.

He concentrated, felt the familiar feeling of his occlumency coming into focus, and the dark Hogwarts corridor faded from view.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

A girl was crying.

Virgo stood up, once again in his old, male body. He stared down at the little whimpering mess beside him in disgust. “Get up.”

She looked up at him. “T-Tom.”

“My name is Virgo!” he spat. “And I said get up. We’ll soon find out if this is all your fault. And if it is, I swear, I will see to it that your filthy, tiny, mudblood soul is flushed from my body like the waste that it is.”

Julia got to her feet, still whimpering.

Tom stretched his arms out wide, shaking free any remains of the torture curse. It was all in the mind—literally. All around him, sat row after row of the Hogwarts library. His mindscape. Along with the whole of the rest of Hogwarts. His home. Where he was safe.

Without a backwards glance, he strode towards the doors. Julia trailed along behind him. She couldn’t keep far away from him. Not here. Not given what she was.

This was Hogwarts as he longed for it. Peaceful, and all his.

As he walked the silent corridors, suddenly, and against all expectation, he was overwhelmed with a foreign feeling—an alien feeling—guilt. Where the hell had that come from?

He shoved it down and carried on as though nothing had happened, hoping against hope that the girl hadn’t noticed. A quick glance behind him assured him that she hadn’t.

There was no room for such weak emotions in his soul.

A few more minutes passed.

“I believe you were right,” he eventually said as they walked down the grand staircase.

“Virgo?”

“I should have paid more attention to trying to keep us as separate as possible. I will make it a priority from now on. And if you are not the cause of my current predicament … I will even ensure that you are not destroyed.”

Julia looked at him with tears in her eyes. “Thank you.”

The path led them to one bathroom in particular on the third floor. They both stepped inside. Virgo smirked. A feeling of victory swam through him—of vindication. The entrance to the chamber of secrets in his mindscape was still open for him.

“You want me to go down there?” Julia asked.

Virgo smiled. “You have already been there in my memories, girl. Be honoured. Few see the greatest work of Salazar Slytherin. And now you will be one step closer to true greatness.”

“But you’re supposed to be able to fly to get down there. You never learned to fly before you split your soul.”

“Stop stalling. You know full well how I got down here the first time.”

Julia screamed all the way down, just as he’d known she would. Bones crunched when they reached the bottom. Technically it hadn’t been necessary to replicate the chamber in quite that level of detail, but he was nothing if not a perfectionist. The giant snake door, with its many animated snake locks was already open to him. He swept through with the air of a lord returning to the manor. With a wave of his hand, green flames sprung up across every wall, casting flickering shadows across the massive stone pillars.

He spread his hands as he walked down the massive cathedral-like centre. “Welcome to the Chamber of Secrets.” His voice echoed off the walls.

“Are you going to tell me why we’re here now?”

Virgo sighed. “So impatient. Very well, girl. Listen, and see how a superior wizard solves a problem that would bring a lesser mind to its knees. Every mindscape can have a guardian—an almost sentient-like being made to watch over the wizard, even when the wizard themselves may not be able to. I created the guardian of this place from a piece of myself when I could still speak Parseltongue. The guardian can speak parseltongue for that is its nature. And the guardian is still a part of me, so the guardian will be able to restore to me the ability to speak the noble language of Salazar Slytherin, or, failing that, will be able to speak on my behalf. QED.”

Julia gave a grudging nod. “So, what are you waiting for?”

Virgo just smirked and walked to the back of the chamber, to the huge statue which stood there. The statue wasn’t the only thing at the back of the chamber. A small bookcase was carved into the stone, full of books, instruments, and even a collection of wands in a pot.

Virgo glanced over and saw that Julia was actually eyeing up those wands.

He snorted and flicked his own wand, levitating the pot up and out of the reach of any little fingers that might get clever ideas. “And now!” he said, walking back to stand in front of the statue. “Let’s begin.” He rolled up his sleeves. “Speak to me, Slytherin, greatest of the Hogwarts four!”

Silence.

The silence went on for quite a long time.

“Is it just me,” Julia started.

“Shut up.”

“—or is there—”

“Shut up.”

“—a tiny flaw in your cunning plan?”

Virgo whirled around. “If you don’t be silent right this minute, girl, I swear—”

“Have you considered the possibility that you can no longer speak parseltongue because you are blood-adopted by the Malfoys and your only Slytherin ancestry, as recognised by the Albion Family Magics, comes not from the noble House of Gaunt, but through your filthy, muggle—”

“CRUCIO!”

A girl’s scream filled the cavern.

“P-Please, Virgo, I’m sorry! I won’t! I won’t!”

“You better not!” he snarled. “Don’t ever suggest that to me, ever again! Make no mistake, your continued survival depends on my goodwill. You are weak, and I hate weakness! Those that cannot find the will to strive for greatness deserve less than nothing—!”

He was cut off by a sudden rumbling sound. His snarl turned victorious. “You see! Never doubt—”

BOOM!

Virgo whirled around. The exit doorway had slammed shut. Even as he watched, a dozen stone snakes that had been sitting idle, slid into an intricate pattern on the door and snapped tight.

“Please tell me you can open that,” Julia whispered.

Virgo felt non-existent blood drain from his face. He ran up to the door, all the way across the chamber. “Open!” he shouted.

Nothing happened.

“OPEN!” he yelled, much louder this time.

Nothing happened.

Running back, he aimed his wand at the door, “Bombarda!”

A fantastic explosion rocked the chamber, but when the dust cleared, the door hadn’t suffered a scratch.

“Can’t we just will ourselves out?” Julia asked, her voice was becoming frantic. “This is just your mind, isn’t it?”

“Don’t you think I’d have done that already if that was an option?” Virgo spat back.

“What about drilling through the walls?”

“It’s all the same.”

“Can’t you change your mindscape while you’re in it?”

“In theory, yes! That was what I was going to try next!”

He concentrated, willing a hole in the door. Nothing happened. The door stayed totally solid.

“Why?” Julia wailed.

A cold certainty gripped Virgo’s heart. He knew why. He’d built this part of his mindscape to hide his most precious secrets. That’s why he’d used parseltongue defences. Only another parselmouth could master this space, and he was no longer a parselmouth. He’d never considered the possibility that he would lose the gift. He was trapped.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

It had been close to two hours.

Not far away, Professor Lily Potter was walking with Professor Aurora Sinistra. They were discussing the upcoming winter break when Aurora held up her hand to her mouth. “Lily!” she pointed. “Is that a student?”

Lily Potter gasped. There was indeed a slight figure laying on the ground. She rushed over and quickly confirmed the who. “Oh, no—not Virgo—not again.” She checked for a life sign. “Still alive—quick—we need to get her to the infirmary.”

One levitation spell and a minute of quick marching later got the young witch safely in the care of Madam Pomfrey. The healer gasped. “Oh, my!”

“What?”

“She’s been under the cruciatus!”

Aurora put a horrified hand to her mouth.

“Are you sure?” Lily asked.

“Positive. And that’s not all. Look, on her wrist. She’s been bitten.”

“What by?”

“A snake. I’m sure of it. Non-venomous, thank Merlin, but very definitely a snake”

Lily’s eyes darkened. “Aurora?”

“Yes?”

“Will you do me a favour and find out where Alexandra Black has been for the last two hours? I need to speak to the headmaster.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

As it turned out, Alexandra Black actually had a fairly good alibi. Only fairly good, because even if someone in the wizarding world is seen in a specific place at a specific time by over a dozen different people, that doesn’t necessarily mean it might not have been someone else under polyjuice, or self-transfiguration, or even some other, more esoteric magical deception.

It was generally accepted, however, that the chance of any of those capabilities being available to a first-year Hogwarts student was about as high as Lord Slytherin not using the upcoming gala evening at Slytherin Manor to further his own political agenda, something Chief Auror Lord Sirius Black was very quick to point out.

“Besides,” Sirius said, “there’s noway Alex could have done whatever that is. I’ve never seen anything like it. Learned anything else, Poppy?”

Alex was sitting on a chair with her back to her father, doing her best to look like how a budding dark lady accused of using an unforgivable believed she should look, uncertain and anxious, while still not quite managing to restrain a touch of indignation. For once, it wasn’t a hard act.

Her father had his hand on her shoulder, and, despite his words, she couldn’t quite shake the feeling that it was as much to restrain as to protect.

Madam Pomfrey straightened from where she, along with three healer trainees, stood on the other side of Virgo’s bed. Those trainees once again included Hermione who was doing an excellent job of not caring about her—a little too good a job, Alex couldn’t help feel.

“I can’t learn anything more until we get permission to use legilimency,” Poppy said. “Lady Malfoy has been informed and should be here soon, but until that time all I can say is that we’re dealing with some kind of mental lockdown. I wouldn’t be surprised if the crucio caused her to turn inwards to block out the pain. That spell has been known to manifest unusual side effects.”

Behind the healer, Lady Lily Potter stood with her arms folded. “Are you certain there isn’t any way it couldn’t have been her?”

“Lily,” Sirius said in a warning tone.

“Sorry Sirius,” she said, not particularly sounding it, “but I don’t recall you ever being that enthusiastic to look into the many skeletons in the many Black cupboards. Alex being a first year means little if she has family magic.”

“No.” Sirius said firmly. “I have looked into my family’s magic. I know full well what a Black can do. There is nothing in there that would cause this.”

“Would you let me look so I can verify?”

“I …” Sirius hesitated, looked confused for a moment, then shook his head. “No, I can’t do that. Because of … reasons.”

Lily sighed.

Alex did her best not to attract any attention while keeping her face as neutral as possible. That had been the fidelius at work. It had to be.

Just then, the door was pushed open and several more adults arrived—Snape and Lady Malfoy, led by Headmaster Lockhart.

“Ahh!” Lockhart grinned at them all. “I hope our sleeping beauty is still doing well?”

“Quite fine, Headmaster,” Pomfrey said in clipped tones. “She is just as unresponsive as the last time you asked.”

“Virgo!” gasped Lady Malfoy, looking for all the world like a distraught mother. She rushed to the girl’s side and started to pepper the healer with questions. It was a good performance. If Alex didn’t know the incredible truth, she would even have believed it.

“Black.” Snape nodded to her father, who grunted back.

“Well, I’m happy to say that this will all be over with soon enough,” Lockhart said to Lily and her father with another wide smile. “Lady Malfoy here has agreed not to hold Hogwarts responsible, and will even be removing her from school to get private treatment at home. Isn’t that a relief?”

“WHAT?!” Madam Pomfrey’s head whirled around, first to Lockhart and then back to Lady Malfoy. “Lady Malfoy, I must object. Your daughter needs first-rate mind treatment, either here or at St. Mungo’s.”

“I disagree, healer Pomfrey.”

“Don’t you trust St. Mungo’s? Your husband funds them!”

“That has nothing to do with this. I know a first-rate mind healer who will take excellent care of my daughter—certainly better than it appears she has been receiving here.” She said this last bit with a slight sneer while looking towards the students wearing healer robes, and Alex was sure, at Hermione in particular.

Hermione just gazed back levelly.

“I must also object,” Lily said with a new steel in her voice that Alex had never heard before. “This is the third time Virgo has been attacked. We don’t know who is attacking her, we don’t know what is attacking her. Until these attacks stop we must keep a close eye on her.”

“That’s even more reason for me to remove her. If there is a predator stalking Hogwarts, I will not allow my daughter to be prey.”

Lily’s voice dropped to barely a whisper. “This predator might not be one that comes from within the school, Narcissa.”

There was a moment of silence before Lady Malfoy scoffed. “You can make the muggleborn a lady, but she’ll always be a muggleborn. You have no right to keep my daughter from me, Lady Potter. I am not happy with Virgo, but to suggest I would try to do away with my child just because they were sorted into the wrong house …” She smirked. “Although, now that I think about it, I can understand why you’d suspect that.”

A split second later four wands had been drawn.

Sirius and Snape had been just a tiny bit faster than Narcissa and Lily, and had disarmed both of them before a hex could be fired.

“Really, Severus!” Narcissa snapped. “I was just going to give her a lizard tongue.”

Lily glared furiously at Sirius who looked back impassive.

“Um, yes!” Lockhart clapped his hands together. “Well, err, if that’s all sorted then I would very much like to continue our conversation, Lady Malfoy.”

Narcissa snatched her wand back from Snape, flicked it at Virgo, levitated her up, and swept out of the infirmary with the unconscious Dark Tween bobbing along behind her. The last thing Alex heard before the door closed was Lockhart saying, “So, I’m thinking a lighter green with lilac for the Slytherin Gala, but a darker green with mauve for your ball. What do you think?”

It wasn’t that much longer before they let her go—before Hermione even, thank Merlin.

Alex rushed off down the corridors of Hogwarts.

Lord Slytherin had to know about this.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In a magic trunk hidden in another part of the castle, Harry was bent over a rapidly spinning potter’s wheel. His hands were slick with wet clay, his clothes were smeared, and his nose had a dirty mark on the tip. A finger applied to the bottom of the pot made a slight adjustment, causing a ripple upwards. The pot wobbled, tilted, then collapsed in on itself.

Harry cursed under his breath. “It’s not as easy as it looks.”

On the other side of the trunk, Luna looked up from her own attempt. “You’ll get it. We have a whole month left before winter break. Harry?”

“Yes, Luna?”

“Why did Voldemort create this ritual and then never use it?”

Harry spelled his robes clean before starting to rebuild his pot. “That’s a very good question. Firstly, he didn’t fully create what we’re doing. He was trying to find a way to achieve the animagus transformation after splitting his soul. Animagi require a full soul, you see—just like being a lord of the Wizengamot. Tom was more than a little pissed off when he realised what he’d done. If he’d just waited for his seventeenth birthday, he’d have become Lord Slytherin himself.”

“How different history might have been,” Luna whispered.

“Indeed. The seven pots were for each piece of his soul that he intended to split off. He’d already done all the preparations needed to achieve the transformation, all he needed was that little extra push.”

“But it didn’t work,” Luna said.

“It couldn’t work,” Harry counted. “By the time Voldemort had seven horcruxes, he’d already lost the locket and the cup—although he didn’t know that he’d lost the locket.”

Harry took a sip of orange juice while Luna frowned.

“But having read a few books that Voldemort hasn’t,” he continued. “I’m pretty sure it wouldn’t have worked. It should work this time though. Voldemort’s animagus ritual was a variation on another important ritual he learned, and a space-time ritual owned by one of his then followers in school. My arithmancy isn’t the best, but I’m fairly certain this adjacent pattern is valid.”

Luna smiled. “Is Voldemort’s snake-like face because he never properly became an animagus, despite having done all the preparation? Ginny still feels cat-ish. Last week, I caught Alex trying to shake her hair dry when she got out of the shower.”

“I’m surprised you don’t already know that, Luna. Your family seems very knowledgable about animagi.”

Luna just smiled.

Harry chuckled. “And what feeling do I give off?”

Luna tilted her head. “You feel … regal, my lord.”

“You always did have good instincts.”

“Thank you, my lord.”

“Anything else?”

Luna frowned in concentration. “You feel … fractured.”

Harry raised an eyebrow. “Again, not bad.”

“It is not very clear,” Luna continued. “You feel like you could be many things. I have felt this feeling before, but I can’t remember where. It is very annoying.”

“I must admit I’m surprised. Part of me expected you to just know.”

“Mmm … maybe a nundu?”

“No, not a nundu.”

Luna pouted. “You are certainly not a dog.”

“If you get it right, I’ll give you pudding.”

“Basilisk?”

“Nope.”

“Feathered serpent?”

“You know your team position as the mysterious all-knowing one is under threat, right?”

“Oh, poo. When are you taking me on a date?”

“Your skill at changing the subject is as masterful as it is subtle.”

Luna beamed. “Thanks! Does that mean I get pudding?”

“At dinner.”

“But I want it now.”

“You’ll ruin your appetite.”

Luna pouted again. “I don’t want that.”

“Indeed.”

“The only kind of ruining I want is when you throw me down on your bed and shove your big fat—”

Thankfully for all concerned, Luna’s words were interrupted by a loud knocking on the lid of the trunk.

“Harry?” came Alex’s voice.

“Alexandra! Come in. I hope everything is well, and can I say, your sense of timing is getting better every day.”

“Umm, thank you?” Alex gave an innocent-looking Luna an inquisitive look before she seemed to remember herself. “Wait! I have news, it’s Virgo!”

One explanation later and Harry was all business. “This is interesting. You’re sure Pomfrey didn’t say anything other than she was under some kind of mental lock?”

“Nothing.”

“Could it be something to do with the muggleborn?” Luna asked.

“Maybe,” Harry mused. “It’s not unlikely. She is the one major uncertain variable. It’s a shame I haven’t had much time to continue my experiments with the obscurial. Either way, this could be a perfect opportunity. It all depends.”

“Opportunity for what?” Alex asked.

“If we could eject the diary from Miss Olsen, then we might be able to bring her to our side. I can’t imagine being a prisoner inside her own body can have been a happy experience. Having a spy so close to the Light could be invaluable. It’s possible the two are fighting for control right now. That particular Black ritual is not the most stable.”

Alex paused to consider all this before continuing. “But Lady Malfoy just took Virgo away. How are you going to get near enough to take a peek?”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Far up in the cold December air over the Hogwarts Quidditch Pitch, a slight figure in Slytherin Green robes dove for the quaffle, snatched it in free-fall, chucked it to another figure, then barrelled to the right and zipped off after the golden snitch like a petite missile. Thirty seconds later, Flint blew a whistle.

“Weasley! That break-away was pathetic! My grand-mother could focus-switch better than that! And you, Malfoy! Are you trying to get shocked?! I’ve told you time and again not to wait till the last moment to pass! I don’t care how good you think you are! We’re using a 3–2-3 pattern and to make that work we need everyone working together!”

Ginny swooped down to the team scrum with the snitch clutched firmly in her fist. “Oh, give it a rest, Flint. As much as I hate to say it, Malfoy has his timing down perfect.”

Malfoy smirked. “Of course I do.”

“That’s not the point!” Flint ranted. “The match with Gryffindor is in just a few weeks and we have to win. Wood’s team will be even better co-ordinated than they were last year, and last year they were good. It was only Potter’s unbelievably bad luck that gave us that win.”

Tamaron, now a beater, nudged Ginny in the side and smirked. “He swallowed the snitch while we were over ten per cent up.”

“And Fate isn’t going to give us one like that again!” Flint roared. “And with Potter off the duelling team, it falls to us to secure Slytherin pride and the house cup!”

“It’ll be fine, Flint,” Malfoy drawled. “As much as I hate to say it,”—Ginny smirked—“and as much of a blood traitor as she is,”—Ginny’s smirk vanished—“The Weaslette is quite good, although not as good as I’d be as seeker, obviously.”

“Still sore at playing second fiddle to not just one, but two first-year girls, Malfoy?”

“Not as sore as you must be knowing that your bribe to join the team was charity.”

“Malfoy! Weasley! Stop that right now.”

Draco and Ginny glared at Flint.

“We still have twenty minutes of practice left! Get back up there and I want to see 3–2-3 all the way this time! Bole, fly tighter. Tamaron and Pucey, I want those bludgers on point every—single—time! Get to it!”

As they all shot back up into the sky, Ginny felt a slight vibration on her lightning-bolt ring. Her heart leapt. She was being summoned.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Sorry-I-came-as-quickly-as-I-could!”

It would have shocked anyone who didn’t know her well, that Ginny was able to say this while in the middle of a mid-air dive-roll into Harry trunk.

Soon, she was filled in on the basics of what was going on, but not yet the plan.

“So, what’s the plan?” she asked. Hermione, Daphne, Alexandra, and Luna were already there.

“The plan is this,” Harry said. “I’m going to carefully, very carefully, make my way through the space between souls, just like Voldemort did when I was in Azkaban. The connection isn’t nearly as safe as between Horcruxes and the main soul piece, but right now it’s worth the risk. The diary’s defences should be low and I know from Voldemort’s memories that the Guardian is something I should be able to negotiate with.”

“So, what do we have to do?”

“You, Ginny, have to keep watch over my body. Daphne, you’re going to be on Harry Potter polyjuice duty if it’s needed, Hermione, you’re the second polyjuice backup. Luna will be coming with me, at least up until the chasm, and Alex, your job is to keep me tied down with your Black chains.”

Alex looked puzzled. “Why?”

Harry waved a vague hand. “In case I don’t wake up as me.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Harry’s mind was a fortress. To any that had sufficiently broken the law of Wizarding Britain, it was a very recognisable fortress. Gaunt, skeletal figures in tattered robes floated around the grounds, unmoving, but with an aura of purpose. Everywhere they moved, frost formed on the ground below.

Everything was quiet. The only sound that could be heard was the gentle lapping of the water against the rocks not far away. The sky was dark. The moon was full.

“I am surprised you didn’t make your guardian a snake,” Luna murmured.

“Are you?” Harry asked.

Luna appeared to think it. “No,” she finally replied.

“I suspected not.”

Together the two made their way through the massive double doors of the prison and up into the building proper. Mental dementors floated past as they went. Each hooded head turned to stare at Luna as they walked, but none made any movement towards her. Luna, for her part, had a slight grip on the cuff of Harry’s robes between thumb and forefinger.

“He’s scared of them, isn’t he?” she said.

“Yes.”

“They say the only thing he’s scared of is Albus Dumbledore.”

“Voldemort is scared of many things. He is scared of being disrespected, he is scared of being weak, he is scared of death, and he is certainly scared of monsters that can suck out a person’s soul.”

“You are also scared of being weak, Harry.”

Harry stiffened, then relaxed. “Yes.”

“But you are not scared of the truth of being afraid.”

“Am I not? I think I am terrified of that truth.”

“You do a good job hiding it.”

They came to a small door in a back-passageway deep down in the deepest depths of the structure.

“Do you know anything about the chasm between souls, Luna?”

Luna tilted her head to one side. “I know it is similar to the chasm between minds—that nothing experienced in the chasm can be seen by a legilimens or extracted as a memory, and that falling into the chasm is … inadvisable.”

“Unadvisable is one way to put it. You know I trust you, Luna.”

“Yes, Harry. And I trust you too.”

The door creaked open, one long note in the silence, revealing endless darkness over a moat of infinity.

Harry’s serious face cracked a smirk. “I learned theatrics from him too.”

“What about sex?”

“Maybe.”

“Rough? Gentle?”

“At school? As gentle as he needed to be, and then as rough as he wanted.”

“How many pretty witches did Tom bang in school, Harry?”

“A good number.”

“All willing?”

“Surprisingly, yes.”

“And later on?”

Harry’s smirk faded. “Not always.”

Luna pouted. “Well, that’s a mood killer.”

They both looked out over the dark expanse and over the tiny rickety bridge that led off into the distance, looking for all the world to be made of nothing but thoughts and fog.

Harry conjured a rope around himself and gave the other end to Luna who promptly tied it around the door handle while keeping a firm hold of the rest of it. He then transformed into the intimidating visage of Lord Slytherin, complete with mask.

He took a careful step onto the bridge. “I’ll send a pulse to your ring every thirty seconds. If I don’t pulse, start pulling.”

“Yes, my lord.”

And with that, Harry started walking across the bridge.

As he got further and further away from the safety of his own mindscape, Luna quietly whispered under her breath. “Please be safe.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Flying was not an option here. Every step Harry took was carefully calculated. The force of the movement, the magic in the bridge, the feeling that this was the right place to put his foot. As he ventured further over the narrow bridge, the abyss swallowed up the safe haven behind him. Almost the only light came from the bridge below him, which radiated like a hundred glowworms trapped in a scaffold of mist.

The rest of the light came from the strings. As he walked, tendrils of thin filaments—connected in his chest—flashed into view for naught but a second before winking back out again. These connected him to all the soul magics he had ever cast, or which had been cast on him. The horcruxes, his fidelius charms, his animagus form. Two of the faintest would even lead to Daphne and Luna. They were far too fleeting to count, and the journey to their souls would be harrowing. Even now, even with his knowing exactly where Virgo was in the real world, and what form this bridge should take to create a corporeal connection, it was still very dangerous making his way over the infinite depths towards the horcruxes defences, and that was with her being in a coma as she apparently was.

Eventually, a structure started to appear in front of him. Hogwarts Castle—the place where Tom Riddle called home, the place he felt safest.

Finally off the bridge, Harry stared at the solid gates, shut tightly against intruders—not the see-through iron bars of Hogwarts proper, but an opaque wooden gate which would have to be at least five times as strong. There was nothing for it. There would be no subtlety here, no fancy high-level legilimency tricks. There was only one way he was getting through Virgo’s soul and into her mind—with brute force.

Focusing his will into a sledge hammer, Harry sent a literal soul-pounding blow right into the gates which burst open with an all-mighty smash. He had only a moment before looking right into huge orange eyes, and his whole world went black.

As Harry’s petrified body fell backwards onto the bridge, a hissing voice spat into the darkness. “$Only one king!$”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Harry!” Ginny’s voice was shrill as Harry’s body, lying unconscious in front of her started to change colour.

“What’s happening?!” Alex shouted.

“I don’t know! I—no! He’s being petrified!”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Deep in Harry’s mindscape, Luna gazed with an alarmed expression at a rapidly approaching wave of petrification. Even as she stared, a dementor turned to stone and dropped to the ground with a crash. The blonde-haired girl took a look behind her at the empty expanse of nothing, then back at the approaching wave. Then she looked at the rope tied to the door, the door still inside Harry’s mindscape, and back out to where it ran out across the chasm.

There was no time for the girl to think. She cut the rope, and stepped backwards one crucial step.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Harry!” cried both Hermione and Daphne.

“Luna’s still okay,” Alex said.

“Yes, but Harry!”

“Calm down!” Daphne ordered, “We can cure this. It’s not fatal. My father deals in Mandrake. If anyone can find any, even with the current shortage, it’ll be him.”

“But what do we do with Harry?”

Daphne gripped a fist in her hair. “I don’t know. It depends how long it’ll take to get the restorative. But first things first, we have to get hold of my father. Hermione, get into your trunk and see if my grandmother’s portrait is there.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Time passed.

In the chasm between souls, it passed quickly.

A young witch, blonde hair, blue-eyes, radish earrings, carefully crept her way out across the chasm with absolutely nothing under her. For her, there was no bridge. Her steps were tiny. Her breath heaved. Every so often she would stop and wait, panting, until a tiny flash of light illuminated a strand of gold as thin as a human hair coming out of her chest. Then she would step again.

With nowhere to attach the rope, there would be no pulling.

Her senses strained. Every footstep was memorised.

Once, the girl misjudged, and almost fell, but she caught herself and carried on.

Eventually, she made her way to the mind scape of the heir of Slytherin.

There, she found Harry.

He must have weighed five times as much as normal, but she carried him back across the not-there bridge anyway—every footstep exactly the same as it had been on the way there.

Once back on the other side, the girl pushed Harry into the safety of his petrified mindscape, before taking a deep breath, scrunching up her face, and jumping in behind him.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Jacob says you were right to contact him, and he’ll be there shortly,” Elizabeth Greengrass said. “In the mean time, you should get Harry up to the hospital wing.”

Hermione nodded, thanked the elder Greengrass portrait, and made her way back to Harry’s trunk. There she found Alex, Daphne, and Ginny with extremely somber faces.

Daphne turned to look at her. “Luna’s just petrified, too.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

—Before—While Harry was closing in on Virgo’s side of the soul chasm—

Inside the mental chamber of Virgo’s secret mind, tensions were running high. Between the two of them, Tom and Julia had tried everything they could think of to escape. They tried summoning a snake with serpensortia and casting imperio on it. Hadn’t worked. They tried confundus, legilimens, and even trapping the snake in a box, pressing it up against the door in the hope that its insistent hissing would produce the right effect by chance—nothing worked.

Now, Tom fumed off to one side while Julia sat cross-legged towards the back of the cave, reading some of the books Tom had stored there. Apparently, the Gaunts had been rumoured parseltongue users for the better part of a millennium—something the histories always found puzzling as the Albion Family Magics should theoretically stop any other than the Slytherin line from possessing the ability.

Nevertheless, artefacts and enchantments requiring parseltongue could oft be found wielded by Gaunts right up until their line died out when the lord and all his family were wiped off the face of the map by an unknown dark wizard in the first half of the twentieth century.

Julia closed the book and regarded the still-fuming older boy by the locked snake door.

Unknown dark wizard, indeed.

She then glanced up to the wands Tom had stored well out of her reach.

So close, and yet …

Just then, the whole chamber was rocked by an explosion.

Tom was instantly on his feet, wand out and alert.

Julia cried out in surprise as water splashed down from disturbed pools in the stonework. “What was that?!” she shouted. Even though the explosion had sounded far away, it had smashed against something deep in her like a runaway train.

“It felt like soul magic,” Tom said. All the anger in his face had fled, replaced by a deadly calm. “Something was trying to get in.”

“Not legilimency?”

“No, not legilimency.”

Julia quietly made her way over to where Tom stood by the door.

Both of them strained to hear anything. It was too much to hope that a healer who was also a parselmouth was trying to get them out.

They waited for quite a while longer, hearing nothing but the drip, drip, drip of water down the walls.

Then Julia heard it—the sound of something huge moving closer on the other side of the door—one might so go far as to say, slithering.

A hundred thoughts passed through her head in a second. Ever since this nightmare had started, way back in summer, she’d gotten a lot smarter. She could feel her thoughts flowing like water, no doubt his infernal influence. She thought about the monster that Tom had created to guard his mind, and what would happen if it decided that, for whatever reason, it was done merely keeping them prisoner and was going to be active in its defence. She thought about a dozen possible consequences for that situation. Then, once she was done thinking about those possibilities, she opened her mouth and screamed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The girl screamed and ran away. Stupid little witch. Although given what might be about to happen, running for a more defendable position probably was the best thing to do.

Virgo darted after the muggleborn, caught up with her, and they both ducked behind separate pillars, hiding their bodies from the front of the chamber.

Something hissed.

Virgo gripped his wand tighter. He would only get one chance to get this right, and every spell would have to be perfect.

There was a loud grinding as the perfectly circular snake-door opened. Then the slithering got louder. It paused for a moment, there was another hiss, and the grinding sound repeated itself in reverse.

Virgo mentally swore. He’d been half hoping the guardian would leave the door open so he could run out and hopefully leave the girl trapped in here with it. That would have been perfect. Alas, it was not to be.

Steeling himself, he caught the girl’s eye behind the other pillar, who looked ready to pee herself with fright.

He then shut his eyes tightly, jumped out from around the pillar, aimed towards the slithering sound and shouted, “Obscuro!” A second later he opened his eyes. In front of him, slithered his guardian—a perfect model of the basilisk from the chamber of secrets, from the tip of its fifty-foot long tail to the crest of red adorning its massive head—hissing in fury with a blindfold covering its eyes.

Never deal with a monster you don’t know how to deal with.

Of course, being blind wasn’t going to slow down a monster that could smell and hear as well as it could see, and the basilisk was now rapidly closing the distance across the chamber.

Virgo grit his teeth. This was not going to be safe. This was, in fact, going to be incredibly dangerous—especially in his own mind—but he had no other choice. In his studies at Hogwarts he’d only encountered one magic that might stand a chance against the king of serpents, and that was only because Slughorn didn’t know how to say no. One so dangerous that few who used it lived to tell.

“Malus ignis totalus diabolus!”

What happened next occurred split second by split second, but seemed to last a lifetime.

The animalistic fire demons spewed from Virgo’s wand, roaring with rage and fury, as hot as the literal fires of hell, billowing up higher and greater.

The basilisk continued its headlong lunge towards him, and as it neared, the demonic fire finally took notice, and attacked. It roared towards the giant snake and that’s when everything went wrong.

The moment the fires got close, the blindfold burst into flames. A split second later, it was reduced to ash.

Virgo spotted the danger a moment before the danger spotted him and shut his eyes tightly. That didn’t save the demonic fire however.

A blood-curdling scream tore through the air of the chamber.

“Obscuro!” Virgo shouted. “Obscuro, obscuro, obscuro, obscuro!”

The screaming died, replaced by a smashing that shook the chamber. Virgo risked a glance and stared.

The basilisk, badly burned, but successfully blind-folded again, was smashing its way out of a tomb of rock, which now surrounded it in hideous shapes of beastile demonhood. A huge petrified dragon head was decapitated with a flick of the tail and sent flying. Virgo stood in awe. It had petrified the great magic fiendfyre. His basilisk. For truly such power could only be his. He had to get it back!

Unfortunately, that time would not be now. Even as he watched, the guardian smashed the final fiendfyre beast away from it, and retreated back towards the door, hissing loudly. The door slithered unlocked—the guardian slithered through it—and it then slithered shut.

Virgo snarled. It could only run for so long before he’d have it back under his thumb. He looked around. The chamber looked badly shaken. The huge snake thrashing around had knocked over quite a few statues, and badly damaged a pillar. It was a risky strategy, but maybe purposefully damaging his defences was the key to getting back out. Something he’d have to look into.

“Girl!” he shouted. “Come! We have work to do.”

Nothing.

Virgo frowned. “There’s no point in hiding anymore,” he shouted. “The snake is gone. Don’t make me come and get you.”

Still nothing.

Then Julia emerged from behind a pillar.

Something was different.

Her eyes were cold. Her stance was determined. And in her hand, she held a wand—one of the wands he’d put up out of reach. The fight with the basilisk must have knocked one of them down.

Virgo raised an eyebrow. “What are you planning to do with that?”

“Breaking free of my prison,” the girl spat.

Virgo sniffed. “Have you suddenly gained the ability to speak to snakes?”

“No, but I don’t care. Once I’m rid of you, I’ll figure out how to get out of here by myself. And then, get my body back!”

Then she attacked.

Virgo had to admit he was surprised. Yes, the girl had access to his memories for six months, but that she’d have reached this level of skill so quickly was a shock. As they duelled together, their movements were almost synchronised—their casts second nature. Every counter was counter-countered by the preparation of a mind that would never consider a strategy that it couldn’t itself beat. Julia weaved magic like a genius who’d been practising for years. They danced for ages, each totally focused on the other while the world around them narrowed down to just the flow of the moment.

It was a shame she hadn’t ambushed him instead of letting him prepare himself. Then she might have actually won.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

Pain screamed through Julia’s senses as she landed on her back and rolled, hard, across the floor of the chamber. The wand she’d been using clattered to the floor nearby.

“YOU DARE THINK YOU CAN BEST ME?!” Tom roared. “You think that because your perfect, untouched soul has been locked away for half a year that makes you worthy of freedom?! My soul, ripped and tattered, has been locked away for seventy years, girl! Seventy years!”

Julia looked to where the wand lay only a few feet away. It was so far away.

“I showed mercy,” Tom continued, suddenly much calmer, and all the worse for it. “I have been a most gracious host. But don’t believe I will allow this insult to pass, even though you are only a child. If you believe you have suffered, then it will be nothing compared to what I will inflict on you now.”

Julia trembled. This had been a mistake. She’d been so sure she could take him after he’d been weakened by the fight with the basilisk, but even after taking all his skills, she still hadn’t won. She just had enough time to gasp out, “Please,” before the boy levelled his wand at her and said those terrible words.

“Crucio.”

Pain. Her every nerve screamed in agony, burning, as she writhed around on the floor. It felt like it went on forever, until he eventually lifted the curse. She whimpered, curled up in the fetal position.

“Pathetic,” said the terrible voice above her.

She rolled over and looked up.

He was standing right over her looking down.

“You know, I really have to thank you,” he said. “I don’t think I’d have got nearly as far with John Potter and the Light as I have without you. As annoying as your constant yapping was, it at least served some use. Maybe I will push for a contract with the House of Potter—a bridge between the Dark and the Light. James and Lily Potter will have to die first, obviously, and when the boy follows them shortly after, that would leave me as Lady Potter—widow of the most powerful house in Magical Britain.”

Julia gasped. The pain was still almost unbearable.

“How does that sound, little girl? You have quite the crush on that boy. How does it feel knowing the girl he thinks is you is going to murder him?”

Julia couldn’t even bring herself to sass.

“No words? Oh, well. It’s a risk, but prolonged cruciatus can sometimes create permanent brain damage. Why don’t we test that your susceptibility, hmm?”

Just then, Julia saw something huge hover far above the nastily smirking face above her—a massive, blind-folded, snake-like something. Her eyes obviously betrayed her alarm, as Tom turned his head, just as the head lunged downwards.

She just had time to see his eyes widen in terrible realisation. Moments later, the basilisk clamped down around his torso. His shouts muffled, it raised its head and gulped him down in three powerful contractions, first to his waist, then his knees, and finally his feet, all drawn down into the powerful predator.

Julia lay there, terrified, hoping against hope that it was done.

It wasn’t.

Crying, she could do nothing as fangs like swords coated in liquid pain bit down into her, before throat muscles as strong as an elephant grasped her tightly and drew her down into the eternal darkness of the monster.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the hospital wing, Lord Jacob Greengrass looked down at his future son-in-law, fellow lord of the Wizengamot, and arguably, Gray Lord. “Two weeks, possibly longer,” he said.

His eldest daughter, the only other person with him, apart from Harry and Luna, looked up at him calmly, although he was sure he could detect a hint of desperation. “Two weeks, father? Can’t we get them quicker than that? What about however Harry got those leaves for our you-know-what?”

“You don’t want to know what Harry went through to get those leaves for your you-know-what. Magical disease is not something you can bargain with. The global mandrake supply is crippled across the whole world. Two weeks.”

“But it’s such a bad time for it,” Daphne said. “We have to finish the manor in time for the winter gala and we have this other really important project to oversee as well.”

“Is this really important project something I should know about?”

“Sorry, father, Slytherin family business.”

“Of course it is. Lucrative?”

“Perhaps a little bit.”

Just then, the door to the hospital wing banged open and a Harry look-alike barged in. “Virgo!”

He stopped when he saw him and Daphne.

“What are you doing here?”

Jacob raised an eyebrow. “Heir Potter. My business here is none of your concern.”

“I mean—” John stopped in mid-stride when he saw who it was on the bed, and the petrified condition they were in. “Harry!” A slew of emotions crossed over his features. Glee, distress, puzzlement, understanding, horror, and finally thoughtfulness. An odd mix to be sure, and worn so openly for anyone to read. If that had been Daphne, he and his daughter would have been having words. John also spared Luna a quick glance but he didn’t seem nearly as interested in her. The Potter Heir shook himself. “No, wait, Virgo! Where’s Virgo?”

“Mister Potter!” Madam Pomfrey chose that moment to enter from the back, possibly to see who was making all the noise. “This is a hospital wing, not your dining room! Kindly leave and take your shouting with you.”

“Not until I find out where Virgo is!”

“Miss Malfoy has been taken home by her mother, now please leave.”

“What?!” John looked horrified. “But they’ll hurt her! They might even kill her!”

“Mister Potter, I do not have the power to keep a mother from taking her daughter away. If you do not leave now, I will tie you up and deposit you outside myself.”

After John left, and after Madam Pomfrey had excused herself, Jacob turned back to his daughter. “He seemed awfully sure of himself. You don’t happen to know anything about the new Miss Malfoy’s situation, do you?”

Daphne grimaced. “I do, but …”

“I don’t believe for one moment that Miss Malfoy is a Slytherin family secret.”

Daphne muttered something that Jacob didn’t quite catch before she said, “She falls more under the category of plausible deniability.”

Jacob nodded. “Say no more.”

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

“Well?” Narcissa asked.

Andromeda scowled. “I can’t do anything more unless you let me use legilimency.”

“Absolutely not. The girl has not been trained to resist unconscious attacks.”

“You still don’t trust me?”

“I trust you enough to call on you, don’t I?”

They were standing at the foot of Virgo’s bed in Malfoy Manor. Andromeda scoffed. She had just finished her slightly less than standard healer check-up. “Your suspicion was correct, though,” she said. “There is soul magic at work here. Possibly even Black soul magic,” she shot Narcissa a calculating look. “You wouldn’t have any idea why that might be, would you?”

“Absolutely not.”

“Well, the good news is that the longer she stays alive, the better the chances are that she won’t die. I don’t know the real reason you don’t want her to go to St. Mungo’s, but I swear, Cissy, if your recalcitrance leads to this girl’s death, you can forget about ever calling on me again.”

“Oh, please. We both know you wouldn’t be able to stay away if someone’s life was on the line.”

Minutes later, Narcissa closed the door on her sister and turned back to the bed. She walked over to it and laid a hand on Virgo’s. Their little trojan horse was picking up more attention than it should be. Desperate times called for desperate measures.

“Dobby,” she called out.

Nothing happened.

She sighed. “Free Elf Dobby.”

A house elf in a dirty tea-cloth popped into being beside her. “Dobby has come, Lady Narcissa! Not because Dobby is having to, but because Dobby is choosing to! Dobby is a—”

“—Free house elf—yes, I know—we freed you—look, can you please have a look at my daughter and tell me if your magic can pick up anything that might give us a clue about what is going on?”

Dobby’s wide eyes widened even further when they fell on Virgo. “Lady Narcissa is having a new daughter! So long has Dobby been away! Dobby did not know witches could grow so fast!”

“They can not. You were on business over the summer. Virgo returned to us from the muggle world then.”

“Oh! Dobby sees now.” Although the frown on his face indicated he was still somewhat confused. “Then Dobby will be using his powerful, free-elf magic on Miss Virgo now.”

A faint blue glow surrounded Dobby’s hand and settled over Virgo.

“Anything?” Narcissa asked.

Dobby’s ears drooped. “Miss Virgo’s souls are being melted, my lady.”

Narcissa’s eyes bore into the elf’s. “Souls? As in, more than one?”

“Yes, my lady.”

Narcissa cursed.

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

In the belly of the basilisk, all was dark, tight, and hot—unbelievably hot—so hot, it felt like a furnace was burning away at everything that was anything or anyone and leaving them a molten puddle.

Tom! I’m scared! thought a thought in the pitch black.

That is because you are weak! Another thought thought back.

The only sound that could be heard was the loud gurgling and pulsing of the snake’s digestive system as it worked away on the two trapped and helpless victims who, by that point, were less bodies, than suggestions of bodies. Had they been in the real world, they would both certainly be dead already, but since this was not the real world, they weren’t.

Oh no, not again! Thought the first voice. It feels like that time in summer all over again! Please, Tom! Do something!

Mmmm,thought the second voice. But if it is like when I made your body my own, why bother stopping it? Your soul has been quite vexing, and if this will be rid of you, then so be it.

No! Please, Tom! I’ll do anything! I don’t want to die!

The world is not fair, little girl. It was a mistake stopping at just your body—Now I will take your soul too—yes, that would be most appropriate.

NO! Tom! Please!

The stomach around them continued to churn and press and gurgle, and soon the mental bodies of the two snake dinners had been reduced to a mental slurry. And out of the slurry, a small black slime oozed its way up.

I am free. The thought, along with a dark laugh pulsed throughout the snake’s insides. And now, where is my little muggleborn companion?That was as far as that thought got before the whole of the rest of the slurry activated like a torch being turned on made out of the sun.

The light washed over the dark ooze, causing it to scream in pain. Stop that!

It did not. Instead it intensified as the whole of the slurry started to change. Moments later, another ooze filled the tight space, but this one was made of shining liquid gold.

Though it could not see, the black ooze stared in mounting dread at its far larger sister.

I will get my own body back, the shining ooze thought. Gold tendrils started to snake towards the black ooze.

Wait! the black ooze mentally shouted. What are you doing?!

I will get my own body back!

No!The black ooze screamed back, panic filling its voice Wait! Stop! You don’t know what you’re doing!

I WILL GET MY OWN BODY BACK!The massive golden ooze gooped over the far smaller black one, submerging it whole. The black ooze screamed one last time, before dissolving into the gold, and the tiny dark little soul fragment, bereft of completeness for seventy years, became whole.

Light filled the still churning stomach.

From the outside, a visible, snake-shaped bulge appeared all along the snake’s belly. The basilisk looked down in puzzlement at its stomach before a faint voice spoke, or rather hissed, to it from inside its own guts.

$LET ME OUT OF HERE!$

—DP & SW: NRiCaD—

The blonde girl in the bed woke, slowly. The first thing she noticed, was that she wasn’t in a single bed, she was in three beds. Someone had moved two extra beds from some of the Malfoy spare rooms to create one massive bed—a bed just the right size for a …

The next thing the girl noticed was that her lower body didn’t feel right. She tried moving her legs, but instead, she just got a kind of writhing motion.

Memories flooded back. The chamber. The basilisk. Being slowly regurgitated as a—

She threw off the covers—or at least, one of the covers—and stared.

A long snake body and tail, scarlet red scales with a golden sheen, snaked out from her waist and on and on for what had to be three or four meters. Merging souls had allowed her to finalise her animagus form, but it wasn’t a snake, as she’d expected, but rather … “a lamia,” she whispered. “Half girl, half snake.”

Old thoughts, buried deep, and still brand new, whirled around in her head. Did Gaunt blood carry an increased chance of having a snake animagus form? Probably. Was that why no one ever saw them speak parseltongue? Quite likely. Did it truly have nothing to do with the Slytherin line? How can I be so brilliant and still so stupid? Even if she’d refused to believe it only a day ago, that desperate need for self-delusion was no longer so strong. It would explain the Gaunt parseltongue abilities. Lucky for her, lamia also had the gift, even if the top half was humanoid. Otherwise, she’d still be trapped. Half snake, half girl, indeed.

Focusing on her transformation, she changed back into her human form and swung her feet onto the floor. She stood up and padded over to the bedside mirror. She stared at herself. It was an odd thing to do after so long. If she’d been asked just a few days ago, she’d have said she’d be crying for joy right about now.

But that’s because I haven’t only been trapped.

Just then, the door opened, and Narcissa Malfoy, her mother(?) walked in. A stab of fear shot through her body, but she crushed it. She couldn’t let this woman know the truth.

“Virgo,” the older witch said, “I’m happy to see you awake. I see you succeeded in changing back.”

The girl looked back at the mirror. She pursed her lips.

Am I Virgo? I am not Tom! I cannot be Julia.

Virgo looked back. “Yes,” she said, trying not to sound uncertain. “I did.”

“Congratulations are in order,” Lady Malfoy said. She was carrying a tray of tea. “Once we get you registered you will be the youngest animagus in Britain.”

Another round of fear shot through Virgo. It took a moment for her to identify it before realising it was the thought of what John would say if he knew she could turn into a lamia.

A red and gold lamia! He should worship the ground I slither on!

“Um, can we hold off on registering for a while?”

Narcissa gave her an odd look, so she quickly continued, trying to sound more confident and firm. “It might break the trust I’ve built up in Gryffindor House if they find out without me preparing them first.”

Narcissa seemed to consider this before nodding. “Very well, Virgo, but if I decide it’s best I will take the steps to register you.”

Suddenly, from somewhere deep down inside, anger flared. Virgo’s eyes narrowed. “You’lldecide?” she hissed.

Narcissa froze.

How dare she? This woman hurt me. This woman tortured me.

“I meant no disrespect,” Narcissa said quickly. She looked like someone who had taken a gamble—an educated and well thought out gamble—and was just now realising she’d been one colour off. “I merely thought that you might not want the burden of dealing with all the paperwork. You still need to recover, and your condition isn’t—”

“You think me weak!?” Virgo shouted.

“No! My lord! Please.”

As quickly as her anger rose, it fled. Virgo calmed. “Lady.”

“Sorry?”

“Lady, not lord. You said yourself, didn’t you?”

Narcissa visibly settled. “My lady. Of course. My daughter. Please, excuse me. I need to contact Hogwarts to update them on your condition, by your leave.” And with that, the woman who was now her mother quickly put the tea tray down, and scurried out.

Virgo looked down at her now shaking hands. “I hate myself.”

—End of Chapter Forty-Nine—

Chapter End Notes

A/N: Phew, another long one! If you enjoy my work, please consider becoming checking out my original projects. All support is appreciated. You can find the links through my website www.leadvone.com.

A/N: This chapter was drafted and made available early through the LeadVonE discord server, as will the next one. That next chapter is not yet available, but if you fancy discussing this chapter, or anything else DP&SW with like-minded people, feel free to head over there anyway.

A special thank you to the following people for helping me catch mistakes on #dpasw-editorial: TrendyTreky, sfu, ASK, Dragonbait, drakonpie250, Modon, Caelwyn, JayEye, Strider (Ebony), Grimjaw, feauxen, nuclear death frog, and Captain Wyvern.

A/N: Conversion rate is:

1 Galleon to 50 British Pounds

1 Sickle to 3 British Pounds (roughly)

1 Knut to 10p (roughly)

All prices are normalised to 1991 values—about half of 2019’s prices.